<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.wtsp.com/_/20/108986382/wtsp/healthnews</forum>
<forum_title>WTSP - Health</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Obama moves money to fund Zika vaccine</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.wtsp.com/_/20/108986382/wtsp/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wtsp&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;health&amp;#x2f;obama-administration-moves-money-around-to-fund-zika-vaccine&amp;#x2f;295267734</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Obama administration moves money around to fund Zika vaccine Liz Szabo, USA TODAY , WTSP 4:31 PM. EST August 11, 2016 The experiment involved a traditional vaccine and two more cutting-edge ones. The traditional vaccine is expected to enter preliminary human studies this year. At least two other experimental Zika vaccines are in human studies already. CONNECT TWEET PINTEREST 
With money for Zika vaccine research set to run out at the end of the month, the Obama administration said Thursday it will transfer $81 million from other areas of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to keep the study on schedule. 
HHS Secretary Sylvia Mathews Burwell said she will transfer $34 million from the agency to the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and will also transfer $47 million to the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority, or BARDA. 
Money for the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID), which launched the first phase of a Zika vaccine trial last week, will come from other institutes within the NIH, Burwell said in a letter to House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi. The institutes tapped for money will include the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services and the Administration for Children and Families, which helps to fight poverty. 
NIH planned to begin the second, larger phase of the research in January. But the institute&apos;s Zika money runs out at the end of the month, said NIAID director Anthony Fauci. Without more funds, the second phase of the trial would have been delayed. 
Delays are a problem for a fast-moving epidemic such as Zika, Fauci said. Scientists have worked to expedite the vaccine research, given concerns about Zika&apos;s link to catastrophic birth defects in infants, Fauci said. 
Even with the new money, the NIH still needs $196 million in fiscal year 2017 to fully fund its Zika research, Burwell said. NIH researchers are developing three additional Zika vaccines, in addition to the one already in clinical trials. Developing multiple types of Zika vaccines is important, Fauci said, because each works in a different way, and scientists don&apos;t know which one will prove to be the safest and most effective. 
BARDA scientists also are working on Zika vaccines and will need an additional $342 million beyond the money transferred Thursday, Burwell wrote in her letter. 
Fauci praised Burwell for making a tough choice to continue the vaccine research. 
Burwell &quot;made a courageous decision to do something that she didn&apos;t really want to do,&quot; Fauci said. While transferring money from other institutes will help fight Zika, Fauci said, &quot;we&apos;re taking money away from cancer and diabetes and all these things. . . . All of that is extremely damaging.&quot; 
President Obama asked Congress for $1.9 billion to fight Zika in February, but Congress has not been able to agree on a funding package. In April, Obama transferred $510 million in unspent funds that had been earmarked for the Ebola outbreak. 
The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention will exhaust its Zika funds by the end of the year, Burwell wrote. Without more money, the CDC may have to reduce the staff it&apos;s dedicated to fighting Zika in Florida and Puerto Rico and preventing outbreaks in Texas. &quot;Allowing any of these scenarios to come to pass puts the American people needlessly at risk,&quot; Burwell wrote. 
South Florida is battling a Zika outbreak that has grown to 25 people, mostly in Miami, as well as one case in Palm Beach County. Doctors have diagnosed Zika in 1,825 people in the continental U.S., including 479 pregnant women, according to the CDC. Puerto Rico has confirmed 8,766 cases of Zika, including 901 pregnant women, according to the Puerto Rico Health Department. 
The real number of Zika cases could be much higher, given that four out of five people with the virus have no symptoms. Those who do develop symptoms — including a fever, rash and pink eye — usually have very mild illness. 
Fifteen U.S. women have given birth to babies with Zika-related birth defects and seven have lost pregnancies due to the virus. Texas health officials announced Tuesday that a baby died in that state with Zika-related microcephaly, a condition in which a baby is born with an abnormally small head and, in most cases, abnormal brain development. 
Burwell called on Congress to provide the rest of the money needed to fight Zika. 
&quot;With the actions described above, we&apos;ve exhausted our ability to provide even short-term financing to help fight Zika,&quot; Burwell wrote. Now, she said, &quot;our nation&apos;s ability to mount the type of Zika response that the American people deserve sits squarely with Congress.&quot; 
Speaker of the House Paul Ryan said Thursday that he&apos;s &quot;pleased that the Obama administration is finally activating funds it has to combat Zika.&quot; 
But Ryan said, &quot;It&apos;s a shame that it’s come after months of shameless political posturing. Democrats in the administration and Congress have shown over and over again that they’d rather mischaracterize history to demonize Republicans instead of swiftly address a public health crisis. That’s a new low.&quot;
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.wtsp.com/_/20/108986382/wtsp/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wtsp&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;health&amp;#x2f;obama-administration-moves-money-around-to-fund-zika-vaccine&amp;#x2f;295267734</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2131</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Obama administration moves money around to fund Zika vaccine Liz Szabo, USA TODAY , WTSP 4:31 PM. EST August 11, 2016 The experiment involved a traditional vaccine and two more cutting-edge ones. The traditional vaccine is expected to enter preliminary human studies this year. At least two other experimental Zika vaccines are in human studies already. CONNECT TWEET PINTEREST 
With money for Zika vaccine research set to run out at the end of the month, the Obama administration said Thursday it will transfer $81 million from other areas of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to keep the study on schedule. 
HHS Secretary Sylvia Mathews Burwell said she will transfer $34 million from the agency to the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and will also transfer $47 million to the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority, or BARDA. 
Money for the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID), which launched the first phase of a Zika vaccine trial last week, will come from other institutes within the NIH, Burwell said in a letter to House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi. The institutes tapped for money will include the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services and the Administration for Children and Families, which helps to fight poverty. 
NIH planned to begin the second, larger phase of the research in January. But the institute&apos;s Zika money runs out at the end of the month, said NIAID director Anthony Fauci. Without more funds, the second phase of the trial would have been delayed. 
Delays are a problem for a fast-moving epidemic such as Zika, Fauci said. Scientists have worked to expedite the vaccine research, given concerns about Zika&apos;s link to catastrophic birth defects in infants, Fauci said. 
Even with the new money, the NIH still needs $196 million in fiscal year 2017 to fully fund its Zika research, Burwell said. NIH researchers are developing three additional Zika vaccines, in addition to the one already in clinical trials. Developing multiple types of Zika vaccines is important, Fauci said, because each works in a different way, and scientists don&apos;t know which one will prove to be the safest and most effective. 
BARDA scientists also are working on Zika vaccines and will need an additional $342 million beyond the money transferred Thursday, Burwell wrote in her letter. 
Fauci praised Burwell for making a tough choice to continue the vaccine research. 
Burwell &quot;made a courageous decision to do something that she didn&apos;t really want to do,&quot; Fauci said. While transferring money from other institutes will help fight Zika, Fauci said, &quot;we&apos;re taking money away from cancer and diabetes and all these things. . . . All of that is extremely damaging.&quot; 
President Obama asked Congress for $1.9 billion to fight Zika in February, but Congress has not been able to agree on a funding package. In April, Obama transferred $510 million in unspent funds that had been earmarked for the Ebola outbreak. 
The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention will exhaust its Zika funds by the end of the year, Burwell wrote. Without more money, the CDC may have to reduce the staff it&apos;s dedicated to fighting Zika in Florida and Puerto Rico and preventing outbreaks in Texas. &quot;Allowing any of these scenarios to come to pass puts the American people needlessly at risk,&quot; Burwell wrote. 
South Florida is battling a Zika outbreak that has grown to 25 people, mostly in Miami, as well as one case in Palm Beach County. Doctors have diagnosed Zika in 1,825 people in the continental U.S., including 479 pregnant women, according to the CDC. Puerto Rico has confirmed 8,766 cases of Zika, including 901 pregnant women, according to the Puerto Rico Health Department. 
The real number of Zika cases could be much higher, given that four out of five people with the virus have no symptoms. Those who do develop symptoms — including a fever, rash and pink eye — usually have very mild illness. 
Fifteen U.S. women have given birth to babies with Zika-related birth defects and seven have lost pregnancies due to the virus. Texas health officials announced Tuesday that a baby died in that state with Zika-related microcephaly, a condition in which a baby is born with an abnormally small head and, in most cases, abnormal brain development. 
Burwell called on Congress to provide the rest of the money needed to fight Zika. 
&quot;With the actions described above, we&apos;ve exhausted our ability to provide even short-term financing to help fight Zika,&quot; Burwell wrote. Now, she said, &quot;our nation&apos;s ability to mount the type of Zika response that the American people deserve sits squarely with Congress.&quot; 
Speaker of the House Paul Ryan said Thursday that he&apos;s &quot;pleased that the Obama administration is finally activating funds it has to combat Zika.&quot; 
But Ryan said, &quot;It&apos;s a shame that it’s come after months of shameless political posturing. Democrats in the administration and Congress have shown over and over again that they’d rather mischaracterize history to demonize Republicans instead of swiftly address a public health crisis. That’s a new low.&quot;
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.wtsp.com/photo/2016/08/05/zika_1470442869057_4544783_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
