<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.dglobe.com//latest/rss/</forum>
<forum_title>| Daily Globe</forum_title>
<discussion_title>&quot;Got Spritz?&quot; set for Saturday at Worthington business</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.dglobe.com/news/business/4092859-got-spritz-set-saturday-worthington-business</topic_url>
<topic_text>
&quot;Got Spritz?&quot; set for Saturday at Worthington business By Ryan McGaughey Today at 10:02 p.m. WORTHINGTON -- A downtown Worthington business will host a Saturday event that is being billed as “featuring all things local.” Amanda Walljasper-Tate, owner of The Daily Apple, said “Got Spritz?” will take place from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m. at her business. The event will also support the work of Project Morning Star, a residential recovery facility located south of Worthington. The event began taking shape after Walljasper-Tate met Rachel Schromen, the co-owner of Spritz-Toilet Spray, which uses 100-percent-certified pure essential oils to conceal bathroom odors. Schromen will be at The Daily Apple on Saturday showing off her product, which is made in three different scents. What was at first a Spritz-Toilet Spray visit soon became a full-fledged event, Walljasper-Tate explained. “This kind of snowballed into something that’s much bigger than I first imagined,” she said, adding that she later contacted Beth Lynn Hoekstra of Project Morning Star to bring an array of their hand-made items to Saturday’s “Got Spritz?” event. Hoekstra will be at The Daily Apple showing products from 10 a.m. to 2 p.m. “Then I thought, if we’re going to do this, for every bottle of toilet spray and Project Morning Star item we sell Saturday, The Daily Apple will donate $1 to Project Morning Star,” Walljasper-Tate said. “We thought this would be a good way to give back to a local non-profit.” Additionally, Laker Honey of Heron Lake will be part of “Got Spritz?” as people visiting the store will have the opportunity to sample local honey fresh from the hive. The Lantern Coffeehouse and Roastery of Sibley, Iowa, will be providing complimentary coffee, and fresh food made with farm-fresh products and prepared by The Beach House of Sibley will be available. BodyWise Massage of Worthington will also be offering free chair massages. A local prize gift basket will be awarded, Walljasper-Tate stated. “We hope people come and buy some local gifts and at the same time support a local nonprofit,” she said.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.dglobe.com/news/business/4092859-got-spritz-set-saturday-worthington-business</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0302</post_time>
<username>Ryan McGaughey</username>
<post>
&quot;Got Spritz?&quot; set for Saturday at Worthington business By Ryan McGaughey Today at 10:02 p.m. WORTHINGTON -- A downtown Worthington business will host a Saturday event that is being billed as “featuring all things local.” Amanda Walljasper-Tate, owner of The Daily Apple, said “Got Spritz?” will take place from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m. at her business. The event will also support the work of Project Morning Star, a residential recovery facility located south of Worthington. The event began taking shape after Walljasper-Tate met Rachel Schromen, the co-owner of Spritz-Toilet Spray, which uses 100-percent-certified pure essential oils to conceal bathroom odors. Schromen will be at The Daily Apple on Saturday showing off her product, which is made in three different scents. What was at first a Spritz-Toilet Spray visit soon became a full-fledged event, Walljasper-Tate explained. “This kind of snowballed into something that’s much bigger than I first imagined,” she said, adding that she later contacted Beth Lynn Hoekstra of Project Morning Star to bring an array of their hand-made items to Saturday’s “Got Spritz?” event. Hoekstra will be at The Daily Apple showing products from 10 a.m. to 2 p.m. “Then I thought, if we’re going to do this, for every bottle of toilet spray and Project Morning Star item we sell Saturday, The Daily Apple will donate $1 to Project Morning Star,” Walljasper-Tate said. “We thought this would be a good way to give back to a local non-profit.” Additionally, Laker Honey of Heron Lake will be part of “Got Spritz?” as people visiting the store will have the opportunity to sample local honey fresh from the hive. The Lantern Coffeehouse and Roastery of Sibley, Iowa, will be providing complimentary coffee, and fresh food made with farm-fresh products and prepared by The Beach House of Sibley will be available. BodyWise Massage of Worthington will also be offering free chair massages. A local prize gift basket will be awarded, Walljasper-Tate stated. “We hope people come and buy some local gifts and at the same time support a local nonprofit,” she said.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.dglobe.com/sites/all/themes/dglobe_theme/images/touch-icon.png</main_image>
</document>
