<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.destinyconnect.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>DESTINY Magazine</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Round-up: Public Protector candidates in the hotseat</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.destinyconnect.com/2016/08/12/round-public-protector-interviews-2/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Print this article Public Protector Thuli Madonsela. Public Protector hopefuls were in the hotseat in Parliament on Thursday – we give you a round-up of the grilling 
This as the committee mandated with finding a replacement for Thuli Madonsela grilled the prospective candidates on their qualifications and why they thought they were the right candidate for the job. 
Candidates were put through their paces by the committee members, who wanted to know their views on the powers of the public protector, as well as independence and what that constituted. 
The first candidate, Advocate Michael Mthembu, was questioned about two civil suits he had not declared in the questionnaires, including one by Nedbank. 
Mthembu said he had made financial mistakes in the past, but had grown. 
Asked about his struggle credentials, the advocate said he had been a student during apartheid and therefore his involvement had been limited. 
He was also questioned about his political party affiliation. He said he had discontinued his ANC membership in 2007 when he had been appointed as an acting judge. 
He believed his passion for human rights made him an ideal candidate for the job. 
This is Mthembu’s second bid to become public protector. 
The second candidate, Judge Sharise Erica Weiner, was questioned on the accountability of the office of the public protector and how she would balance high-profile cases with ordinary ones. 
She told the committee she had been a National Union of South African Students member and founding member of Lawyers for Human Rights and had assisted in legal cases. 
She was also questioned about her language proficiencies. 
“Unfortunately, I don’t speak an African language. I only know Afrikaans and English and a bit of French.” 
Another candidate, 77-year-old advocate Chris Mokoditwa, said “not every Tom, Dick and Harry could challenge the decisions of the public protector”. 
He started by listing his struggle credentials, before launching into the history of the public protector. 
He was questioned about why, at his age, he wanted to be public protector. 
Chairperson Makhosi Khoza said: “I’m not being an ageist, but this is in consideration to the demands of the job.” 
Mokoditwa, whose questionnaire was handwritten, said he was a bodybuilder and was fit for the job. 
“I walked 15km in the Soweto Marathon. This is nothing,” he said. 
Spy tapes, President Jacob Zuma’s corruption charges and party affiliations and loyalties took centre stage during Willie Hofmeyer’s interview. 
More than 15 hours after the committee started with the interviews, Hofmeyer was grilled on some of the decisions he had made during his long career. 
This included an affidavit in which he called into question national head Shaun Abrahams’s version of the controversial decision to drop criminal charges against colleague Nomgcobo Jiba. 
Shivambu questioned the decisions behind the corruption case against businessman Schabir Shaik and asked him to explain why Zuma had not been charged at the same time. 
He asked why a decision had been made to drop the spy tapes saga, which was now being reinstated in court. 
“How should we trust you? How do we know you are not an extension of the person you have been avoiding to charge for a very long time? Aren’t you trying to come to the public protector’s office to continue with the protection of a possibly corrupt individual who steals public money for himself to enrich himself and his own family?” he asked. READ MORE: Don’t muzzle public protector watchdog: Supreme Court of Appeal 
He said Hofmeyer had a history of protecting one individual. 
Hofmeyer said he would not be coming into the public protector office to protect anyone except the public. 
He said his integrity mattered to him. 
Speaking about the withdrawal of charges against Zuma, he said initially he was probably the only person who felt strongly about the issue. 
“In the end, the decision was taken by consensus by top management of National Prosecuting Authority. So it was not me alone who took the decision,” he said.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.destinyconnect.com/2016/08/12/round-public-protector-interviews-2/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0554</post_time>
<username>Destiny Reporter</username>
<post>
Print this article Public Protector Thuli Madonsela. Public Protector hopefuls were in the hotseat in Parliament on Thursday – we give you a round-up of the grilling 
This as the committee mandated with finding a replacement for Thuli Madonsela grilled the prospective candidates on their qualifications and why they thought they were the right candidate for the job. 
Candidates were put through their paces by the committee members, who wanted to know their views on the powers of the public protector, as well as independence and what that constituted. 
The first candidate, Advocate Michael Mthembu, was questioned about two civil suits he had not declared in the questionnaires, including one by Nedbank. 
Mthembu said he had made financial mistakes in the past, but had grown. 
Asked about his struggle credentials, the advocate said he had been a student during apartheid and therefore his involvement had been limited. 
He was also questioned about his political party affiliation. He said he had discontinued his ANC membership in 2007 when he had been appointed as an acting judge. 
He believed his passion for human rights made him an ideal candidate for the job. 
This is Mthembu’s second bid to become public protector. 
The second candidate, Judge Sharise Erica Weiner, was questioned on the accountability of the office of the public protector and how she would balance high-profile cases with ordinary ones. 
She told the committee she had been a National Union of South African Students member and founding member of Lawyers for Human Rights and had assisted in legal cases. 
She was also questioned about her language proficiencies. 
“Unfortunately, I don’t speak an African language. I only know Afrikaans and English and a bit of French.” 
Another candidate, 77-year-old advocate Chris Mokoditwa, said “not every Tom, Dick and Harry could challenge the decisions of the public protector”. 
He started by listing his struggle credentials, before launching into the history of the public protector. 
He was questioned about why, at his age, he wanted to be public protector. 
Chairperson Makhosi Khoza said: “I’m not being an ageist, but this is in consideration to the demands of the job.” 
Mokoditwa, whose questionnaire was handwritten, said he was a bodybuilder and was fit for the job. 
“I walked 15km in the Soweto Marathon. This is nothing,” he said. 
Spy tapes, President Jacob Zuma’s corruption charges and party affiliations and loyalties took centre stage during Willie Hofmeyer’s interview. 
More than 15 hours after the committee started with the interviews, Hofmeyer was grilled on some of the decisions he had made during his long career. 
This included an affidavit in which he called into question national head Shaun Abrahams’s version of the controversial decision to drop criminal charges against colleague Nomgcobo Jiba. 
Shivambu questioned the decisions behind the corruption case against businessman Schabir Shaik and asked him to explain why Zuma had not been charged at the same time. 
He asked why a decision had been made to drop the spy tapes saga, which was now being reinstated in court. 
“How should we trust you? How do we know you are not an extension of the person you have been avoiding to charge for a very long time? Aren’t you trying to come to the public protector’s office to continue with the protection of a possibly corrupt individual who steals public money for himself to enrich himself and his own family?” he asked. READ MORE: Don’t muzzle public protector watchdog: Supreme Court of Appeal 
He said Hofmeyer had a history of protecting one individual. 
Hofmeyer said he would not be coming into the public protector office to protect anyone except the public. 
He said his integrity mattered to him. 
Speaking about the withdrawal of charges against Zuma, he said initially he was probably the only person who felt strongly about the issue. 
“In the end, the decision was taken by consensus by top management of National Prosecuting Authority. So it was not me alone who took the decision,” he said.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>ZA</country>
<main_image>http://www.destinyconnect.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/AV_00032717-e1454992849280.jpg</main_image>
</document>
