<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.wsj.com/public/page/news-sports-scores.html</forum>
<forum_title>Sports News - The Wall Street Journal - Wsj.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Games: It’s Not Easy Playing Water Polo in a Green Pool</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wsj.com/articles/rio-games-its-not-easy-playing-water-polo-in-a-green-pool-1470945091</topic_url>
<topic_text>
8 COMMENTS RIO DE JANEIRO—As Rio’s Olympic divers arrived at the pool for practice on Thursday afternoon, they all went through the same motions: walk up to the water, evaluate the color and grimace. For the third day in a row, it was a mouthwash shade of green instead of aqua blue.
“I don’t think anyone is angry, but it’s confusing,” Mexican diver Rodrigo Diego Lopez said during his training session on Thursday. “Every time, I take showers as soon as I get out because I don’t want to feel anything.”
Though Rio 2016 officials said the situation was being addressed, the diving water appeared to get darker and cloudier overnight. The adjacent water polo pool also displayed a greenish tint, just as it did Wednesday , leaving the players complaining of itchy eyes and reduced visibility underwater. All of them said that they had seen conditions like this before.
Why the Rio Olympics Pools Turned Green A second Rio Olympics pool turned green on Wednesday, after the diving pool became discolored on Tuesday. Photo: Associated Press “It stings your eyes,” France diver Matthieu Rosset said on his way to train on Thursday. “But your tattoos aren’t going to come off.…We’re not getting zits or anything.”
Officials on Thursday stood by their earlier explanation that the filtration system had run out of certain chemicals, creating the imbalance. But pool technicians tested water samples on Wednesday and visited the venue overnight to remix the cocktail of chemicals in the pool, according to Rio 2016 spokesman Mario Andrada.
“The water became alkaline.…That generated a green color, and it has been fixed, the levels are back to normal, the color has changed,” Andrada said. The divers said they noticed little difference.
He added that the number of people using the diving and water polo pools also had an impact.
On the competitive front, the divers have developed an affinity for it. They don’t see the reflection of the sky and they’re not thrown off by the floor of the pool—all they get is a big emerald target.
“Instead of aiming for blue, you’re aiming for green. It’s almost funny,” Rosset said. “It’s more of an advantage than anything else. After that, from a hygiene standpoint, I don’t know.”
To the water polo players, it was more than just uncomfortable.
ENLARGE A view of the Olympic water polo pool from Thursday. Photo: sergei ilnitsky/European Pressphoto Agency “I like to keep my eyes open under the water, alligator-style, to read my opponents, so it made it a little bit tougher,” U.S. water polo player Maggie Steffens said after her match against China on Thursday. “But at the end of the day, you’re at the Olympics. Anything can happen: storm, rain, green pool.”
That said, the situation was nothing they hadn’t dealt with before.
“If there’s any sort of debris floating around in there or even heavy chlorine, you can get burning in your eyes like that,” Steffens’s teammate Kami Craig said. “But this is something we’ve dealt with since we were babies in the pool. I remember getting done with swim meets and having to put milk in our eyes.”
Divers and water polo players alike said that they had received no information on precisely what the issue with the water was or when it might be resolved. But on Thursday morning, Andrada promised the pools would be back to their camera-ready, icy blue “later today.”
As of 4:45 p.m. local time Thursday, the diving pool remained a murky celadon green.
—Rebecca Davis O’Brien contributed to this article.
Write to Joshua Robinson at joshua.robinson@wsj.com
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>5</post_num>
<post_id>post-5</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wsj.com/articles/rio-games-its-not-easy-playing-water-polo-in-a-green-pool-1470945091</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0050</post_time>
<username>James Tomlinson</username>
<post>
They simply need to add 50kg of Sodium Bicarbonate per 10ppm of alkalinity below 150ppm.
I&apos;ll guess it is on the order of 500kg for the pool to be that green. Wow!
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-PJ102_GREENP_G_20160811153408.jpg</main_image>
</document>
