<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/rssfeeds/13352306.cms</forum>
<forum_title>Industry-The Economic Times</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Diesel vehicle curbs making customers uncertain: RC Bhargava, Chairman, Maruti Suzuki India</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/auto/news/industry/diesel-vehicle-curbs-making-customers-uncertain-rc-bhargava-chairman-maruti-suzuki-india/articleshow/53660978.cms</topic_url>
<topic_text>
NEW DELHI: Recent restrictions on diesel vehicles aimed at addressing environmental concerns are making investors lose confidence and seeding uncertainty in the minds of consumers, India&apos;s largest carmaker said. 

&quot;Not only are the measures being enforced unlikely to make any significant difference to the air quality, but the growth of the industry and the creation of jobs are likely to be adversely impacted,&quot; Maruti Suzuki India chairman RC Bhargava said in the company&apos;s annual report for 2015-16. 

The Supreme Court banned the registration of diesel vehicles with engine capacity of 2000 cc and above in the National Capital Region in December to help curb pollution levels. 

Toyota Motor Corporation said it will hold back the launch of its Lexus and Daihatsu brands in India and make no fresh investments in the country until the regulatory uncertainty shrouding the country&apos;s automobile industry is cleared. 

Bhargava said India seems to be applying &quot;Western remedies for pollution to our problem&quot;. Unlike in the West, where the main concern is emissions of nitrogen oxides, dust is the major cause of pollution in the National Capital Region (NCR). 

Citing a study by the Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur on sources of pollution in the NCR, he said cars are not a significant contributor to PM (particulate matter) 2.5. 

&quot;Yet, going by what has been happening, cars and especially diesel cars, are being treated as the main villain for our polluted air,&quot; he added. The positive factor, he said, is that the government recognises the dangers of the situation and is taking a firm stand in favour of growth, while dealing with the real pollution problem. 

Maruti Suzuki, too, is working on expanding hybridisation technology to address concerns over vehicular pollution. Sales at the maker of cars such as Alto, Dzire, Swift and WagonR increased 10.6 per cent to 1.42 million vehicles in the year ended March. 

A new plant in Gujarat will be ready in early 2017 to provide additional capacity as the company seeks to achieve its target of selling 2 million vehicles by 2020. Exports will play an important role in this growth, managing director Kenichi Ayukawa said. 

&quot;We are making a lot of market development efforts in exports so that in the next few years we are on a strong footing to provide cars to many countries of the world from India,&quot; Ayukawa said. 

Maruti Suzuki is investing in a stateof-the-art research &amp; development (R&amp;D) centre in Rohtak, Haryana. The facility will be expanded over the next three years. &quot;If we can design and develop in India, we will get global competitiveness in technology, cost and quality much faster. 

That will be our next leap — &apos;Create in India&apos;,&quot; Ayukawa said. The Vitara Brezza, developed by Indian engineers using parent Suzuki Motor Corporation&apos;s global development process and platform, was the first step in this direction. 

The compact urban SUV was launched in March this year. Maruti Suzuki has also set up a special team to invest in real estate so that growth of sales, service and spares facilities through its distribution network keeps pace with its sales target. 

Ayukawa said the government&apos;s policy for voluntary fleet modernisation will help the industry to develop in a sustainable manner and in employment generation. &quot;This infrastructure creation will truly make the Indian automobile ecosystem more comprehensive, more sustainable and also create jobs in the process.&quot;  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>5</post_num>
<post_id>post-5</post_id>
<post_url>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/auto/news/industry/diesel-vehicle-curbs-making-customers-uncertain-rc-bhargava-chairman-maruti-suzuki-india/articleshow/53660978.cms</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0610</post_time>
<username>Komatineni Komatineni</username>
<post>
Nothing to do with diesel but pollution. So why can&apos;&apos;t car companies make less polluting vehicles ahead or onpar with global standards? dont complian
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/thumb/msid-53660994,width-600,resizemode-4,imglength-42040/industry/auto/news/industry/diesel-vehicle-curbs-making-customers-uncertain-maruti/maruti-suzuki-reuters.jpg</main_image>
</document>
