<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.wbir.com/_/20/109872676/Wbir/national-world-news</forum>
<forum_title>WBIR - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Service &amp; Sacrifice: Graveside Reunion</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.wbir.com/_/20/109872676/Wbir/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wbir&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;local&amp;#x2f;military&amp;#x2f;service-sacrifice-graveside-reunion&amp;#x2f;295124654</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Close Service &amp; Sacrifice: Graveside Reunion A story that was on for less than a minute on air changed the life for one Vietnam veteran. John Becker, WBIR 11:05   CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
The Search: 
After searching on and off for almost five decades, a Vietnam veteran from East Tennessee stood next to the grave of a fellow soldier killed long ago in combat. 

“This is Richard, “said Ronald Green with tears welling in his eyes. 
HonorAir Knoxville Flight 21 in June helped jumpstart a connection lost in the late 1960s. 
Just prior to boarding that all-expenses-paid round trip flight to Washington, D.C. with 148 other veterans of the war in Vietnam, Mr. Green told 10News he had one mission on his trip to the nation’s capital: Find Richard Dunlap’s name on the memorial wall. 

The two became fast friends in basic training. They became so tight that they even talked about having a joint wedding with their girlfriends back home. The Army happen to put them in separate units but both went off to war. 
“My mother sent me word that he got killed and it just tore me apart. I think about him all the time - real, real, nice guy,” said Mr. Green. 
After the return flight and reflecting on that emotion-filled day in Washington, Mr. Green said he had one more wish: “I need to go to Richard’s gravesite and just sit and talk with him.” 
Richard Dunlap: KIA March 12, 1968 
Richard Dunlap’s brother Steve told 10News in an email his brother would not want to be called a hero. The brothers grew up in the foothills of the Great Smoky Mountains in Friendsville. 

“He would not have considered himself a hero,” said Steve Dunlap, who learned how to fish, work the tobacco fields and build rabbit traps from his older brother. Richard taught Steve to drive and served as part of his inspiration to join the Army. 
“…even though it hurt my parents deeply. I felt the need to prove myself that I was as strong and courageous as he was. After all he was my big brother,” wrote Steve. 
Richard Dunlap died in battle March 12, 1968, rushing an enemy machine gun encampment at age 21. 
The Reunion 

When Steve Dunlap’s wife caught the story of Mr. Green talking about his friendship with Richard on 10News, she emailed the station. Ms. Dunlap said her family wanted to meet Mr. Green and take him to Richard’s grave. 
A few weeks later Steve Dunlap greeted Ronald Green with a handshake and a hug in the parking lot of Mt. Zion Church in Blount County. Together, the two walked over to share a moment in front of the grave that held a brother, friend, and soldier. 
Ronald Green 
1. What one person influenced you most in life? My Mother who allowed me to grow but with stern direction. 
2. Do you feel honored and respected for serving your country? The HonorAir-Knoxville brought a sense of pride for me when we flew to D.C... Everywhere we went, we were treated with dignity and respect from old and young alike. Especially from the little children and youth. Arriving in Knoxville culminated the experience and placed everything in perspective for me. 
3. How can people thank you for your service? I thank God for protecting me in Viet Nam and for my safe return back home. I’m thankful for all He has done for me and continues to do for me in my everyday walk. 
4. How do you honor your fellow service men and women? I honor them with respect and a “Thank You” whenever I see one in uniform or wearing a symbol of their service. 
5. How do you think this generation of military men and women is different or similar to yours? The difference is that I was trained for Jungle Warfare and today’s Modern Army is trained for urban warfare mixed with technology far beyond what was available in the 60’s and 70’s. 
6. What influence did your military service have on the rest of your life? It enhanced the discipline taught by my parents and respect for leadership. 
7. Does your family have a history of military service? My Father was a WWI Veteran, my two older brothers served in the Air Force, my son served in the Navy (Gulf War Veteran), and two Grandsons in the U.S. Army (the oldest is still serving and have done tours of duty in Iraq, Afghanistan, Kuwait), the other is home and he did a tour in Afghanistan. 
8. Would you encourage younger generations in your family to join the service? I suggest that they consider the service because there are opportunities for everyone. 
9. How has your opinion of the war changed? I don’t have an opinion one way or another. 
10. How did your military experience shape your faith? I have always had faith in God and being in the military only enhanced that faith. 
Steve Dunlap Tribute to All Veterans of Vietnam: 
Medals and Memories 
By Steven Dunlap I was ready when you called on me so proud to fight your war But you sent me there to die not fight what the hell was it all for 
You slept at night in a soft swarm bed I slept in rain and mud As you laughed and spilled your wine and beer, I cried and spilled my blood
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.wbir.com/_/20/109872676/Wbir/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wbir&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;local&amp;#x2f;military&amp;#x2f;service-sacrifice-graveside-reunion&amp;#x2f;295124654</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0405</post_time>
<username>John Becker</username>
<post>
Close Service &amp; Sacrifice: Graveside Reunion A story that was on for less than a minute on air changed the life for one Vietnam veteran. John Becker, WBIR 11:05   CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
The Search: 
After searching on and off for almost five decades, a Vietnam veteran from East Tennessee stood next to the grave of a fellow soldier killed long ago in combat. 

“This is Richard, “said Ronald Green with tears welling in his eyes. 
HonorAir Knoxville Flight 21 in June helped jumpstart a connection lost in the late 1960s. 
Just prior to boarding that all-expenses-paid round trip flight to Washington, D.C. with 148 other veterans of the war in Vietnam, Mr. Green told 10News he had one mission on his trip to the nation’s capital: Find Richard Dunlap’s name on the memorial wall. 

The two became fast friends in basic training. They became so tight that they even talked about having a joint wedding with their girlfriends back home. The Army happen to put them in separate units but both went off to war. 
“My mother sent me word that he got killed and it just tore me apart. I think about him all the time - real, real, nice guy,” said Mr. Green. 
After the return flight and reflecting on that emotion-filled day in Washington, Mr. Green said he had one more wish: “I need to go to Richard’s gravesite and just sit and talk with him.” 
Richard Dunlap: KIA March 12, 1968 
Richard Dunlap’s brother Steve told 10News in an email his brother would not want to be called a hero. The brothers grew up in the foothills of the Great Smoky Mountains in Friendsville. 

“He would not have considered himself a hero,” said Steve Dunlap, who learned how to fish, work the tobacco fields and build rabbit traps from his older brother. Richard taught Steve to drive and served as part of his inspiration to join the Army. 
“…even though it hurt my parents deeply. I felt the need to prove myself that I was as strong and courageous as he was. After all he was my big brother,” wrote Steve. 
Richard Dunlap died in battle March 12, 1968, rushing an enemy machine gun encampment at age 21. 
The Reunion 

When Steve Dunlap’s wife caught the story of Mr. Green talking about his friendship with Richard on 10News, she emailed the station. Ms. Dunlap said her family wanted to meet Mr. Green and take him to Richard’s grave. 
A few weeks later Steve Dunlap greeted Ronald Green with a handshake and a hug in the parking lot of Mt. Zion Church in Blount County. Together, the two walked over to share a moment in front of the grave that held a brother, friend, and soldier. 
Ronald Green 
1. What one person influenced you most in life? My Mother who allowed me to grow but with stern direction. 
2. Do you feel honored and respected for serving your country? The HonorAir-Knoxville brought a sense of pride for me when we flew to D.C... Everywhere we went, we were treated with dignity and respect from old and young alike. Especially from the little children and youth. Arriving in Knoxville culminated the experience and placed everything in perspective for me. 
3. How can people thank you for your service? I thank God for protecting me in Viet Nam and for my safe return back home. I’m thankful for all He has done for me and continues to do for me in my everyday walk. 
4. How do you honor your fellow service men and women? I honor them with respect and a “Thank You” whenever I see one in uniform or wearing a symbol of their service. 
5. How do you think this generation of military men and women is different or similar to yours? The difference is that I was trained for Jungle Warfare and today’s Modern Army is trained for urban warfare mixed with technology far beyond what was available in the 60’s and 70’s. 
6. What influence did your military service have on the rest of your life? It enhanced the discipline taught by my parents and respect for leadership. 
7. Does your family have a history of military service? My Father was a WWI Veteran, my two older brothers served in the Air Force, my son served in the Navy (Gulf War Veteran), and two Grandsons in the U.S. Army (the oldest is still serving and have done tours of duty in Iraq, Afghanistan, Kuwait), the other is home and he did a tour in Afghanistan. 
8. Would you encourage younger generations in your family to join the service? I suggest that they consider the service because there are opportunities for everyone. 
9. How has your opinion of the war changed? I don’t have an opinion one way or another. 
10. How did your military experience shape your faith? I have always had faith in God and being in the military only enhanced that faith. 
Steve Dunlap Tribute to All Veterans of Vietnam: 
Medals and Memories 
By Steven Dunlap I was ready when you called on me so proud to fight your war But you sent me there to die not fight what the hell was it all for 
You slept at night in a soft swarm bed I slept in rain and mud As you laughed and spilled your wine and beer, I cried and spilled my blood
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.wbir.com/photo/2016/08/11/Courtesy%20Ronald%20Green_1470943352372_5083056_ver1.0_640_360.JPG</main_image>
</document>
