<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.kcchronicle.com/?rss=news/local</forum>
<forum_title>Local News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Shodeen seeks to raze Geneva Mill Race Inn</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.kcchronicle.com/2016/08/11/shodeen-seeks-to-raze-geneva-mill-race-inn/a9k3a8o/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Shodeen seeks to raze Geneva Mill Race Inn Published: Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016 5:37 p.m. CDT • Updated: Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016 5:46 p.m. CDT Caption Shodeen Construction Inc., has filed for a permit for the selective demolition of the shuttered Mill Race Inn at 4 E. State St., Geneva. By KANE COUNTY CHRONICLE - editorial@kcchronicle.com 
GENEVA – Shodeen Construction Co. has filed a permit application to the city of Geneva for the selective demolition of the long-vacant Mill Race Inn property at 4 E. State St., Geneva, city officials announced in a news release. 
The applicant is seeking approval for the removal of the superstructure and portions of the existing foundation that surround the circa 1846 limestone paper manufactory building, according to the release. 
The building was renovated in 1933 by August Wilson &amp; Son for the establishment of Ann Forsyth’s iconic Mill Race Inn restaurant, the release stated. 
The proposed, selective demolition work will retain the existing concrete foundation walls of the restaurant building and gazebo that lie within the floodplain, adjacent to the east bank of the Fox River, the release stated. 
The demolition work will also include asbestos abatement to be identified by a professional environmental engineering consultant, the release stated. 
The proposed work includes the disconnection of all on-site utility services and the removal of certain trees, primarily those in close proximity to the existing structure, the release stated. 
Upon completion of the demolition work, the site will be graded, seeded and fenced for safety and security while re-development investigation and planning continues, the release stated. 
Additionally, once the demolition is complete, the architectural and structural integrity of the limestone paper manufactory building will be professionally evaluated for consideration as a local or national historic landmark and feasibility for rehabilitation and incorporation into future redevelopment proposals for the Mill Race Inn site, the release stated. 
Demolition work is expected to commence immediately following review and approval by the Illinois Environmental Protection Agency, the Illinois Historic Preservation Agency and the city of Geneva.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.kcchronicle.com/2016/08/11/shodeen-seeks-to-raze-geneva-mill-race-inn/a9k3a8o/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2237</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Shodeen seeks to raze Geneva Mill Race Inn Published: Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016 5:37 p.m. CDT • Updated: Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016 5:46 p.m. CDT Caption Shodeen Construction Inc., has filed for a permit for the selective demolition of the shuttered Mill Race Inn at 4 E. State St., Geneva. By KANE COUNTY CHRONICLE - editorial@kcchronicle.com 
GENEVA – Shodeen Construction Co. has filed a permit application to the city of Geneva for the selective demolition of the long-vacant Mill Race Inn property at 4 E. State St., Geneva, city officials announced in a news release. 
The applicant is seeking approval for the removal of the superstructure and portions of the existing foundation that surround the circa 1846 limestone paper manufactory building, according to the release. 
The building was renovated in 1933 by August Wilson &amp; Son for the establishment of Ann Forsyth’s iconic Mill Race Inn restaurant, the release stated. 
The proposed, selective demolition work will retain the existing concrete foundation walls of the restaurant building and gazebo that lie within the floodplain, adjacent to the east bank of the Fox River, the release stated. 
The demolition work will also include asbestos abatement to be identified by a professional environmental engineering consultant, the release stated. 
The proposed work includes the disconnection of all on-site utility services and the removal of certain trees, primarily those in close proximity to the existing structure, the release stated. 
Upon completion of the demolition work, the site will be graded, seeded and fenced for safety and security while re-development investigation and planning continues, the release stated. 
Additionally, once the demolition is complete, the architectural and structural integrity of the limestone paper manufactory building will be professionally evaluated for consideration as a local or national historic landmark and feasibility for rehabilitation and incorporation into future redevelopment proposals for the Mill Race Inn site, the release stated. 
Demolition work is expected to commence immediately following review and approval by the Illinois Environmental Protection Agency, the Illinois Historic Preservation Agency and the city of Geneva.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.kcchronicle.com/_internal/cimg!0/qvkaailv9bu7sxhtum4jaihu5rph5f0</main_image>
</document>
