<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://edu.qq.com/edunew/rss_edunew.xml</forum>
<forum_title>教育新闻</forum_title>
<discussion_title>双语：为重获品牌声望 寇驰从北美商场大规模撤出</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://edu.qq.com/a/20160812/028915.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
0 [ 摘要 ]皮件制造商寇驰本周二宣布，将停止在“低端”的百货商店出售其手袋和钱包。此举是寇驰感到其产品在大众化商场出售，致使对有钱人的吸引力被削弱而做出的反应。 Coach is going First Class. 寇驰要走高端路线。 The leather-goods maker will no longer sell its handbags and purses at some &quot;lower volume&quot; department stores, the company announced Tuesday. The move comes in response to the brand&apos;s perceived diluted appeal to wealthier shoppers amid mass market access. 皮件制造商寇驰本周二宣布，将停止在“低端”的百货商店出售其手袋和钱包。此举是寇驰感到其产品在大众化商场出售，致使对有钱人的吸引力被削弱而做出的反应。 According to Tuesday&apos;s announcement, Coach will stop selling to around 250 locations in North America as of 2017, and also strictly control any discounts that department stores can offer. 根据周二的公告，2017年寇驰将在北美的约250个销售点停止销售，并且严格控制百货公司可以提供的任何折扣。 &quot;While we understand that customers may use department stores for trial and shopping across brands, the high level of promotional impressions created negatively impacts our long-term brand health,&quot; said Chief Executive Victor Luis during a conference call with analysts this week. 本周，寇驰首席执行官维克多 路易斯在与分析师的一次电话会议中表示：“尽管我们理解客户可在百货公司的不同品牌之间进行试用及购买，深刻的促销印象对我们品牌的长期健康产生了负面影响。” Once a category crusher, the 75-year-old company was forced to rethink its strategy in 2014 after reporting four straight quarterly losses, with shares falling a total of 39 percent that year. 这个拥有75年历史的公司曾是行业老大， 2014年却连续四个季度报告亏损且股价下跌39%，不得不重新考虑其品牌战略。 Those losses were partially attributed to the fact that Coach&apos;s loyal clientele had increasingly turned up its nose at the once-prestigious brand, whose less pricey CC line has been purchased in droves by younger consumers at steep discounts in malls and outlets. 这些亏损部分是因为，寇驰的忠实客户已经越来越对这个曾经著名的品牌嗤之以鼻。在各大商场和奥特莱斯，其相对低廉的CC系列产品因大幅度的折扣被成群结队的年轻消费者买走。 After the appointment of Stuart Vevers as executive creative director in 2013, Coach started a &quot;re-platforming&quot; of its brand. The company closed down one-fifth of its North American retail stores and renovated high-traffic, high-value stores (such as Rodeo Drive) to exude &quot;warmth&quot; and &quot;modern luxury,&quot; while returning to the company&apos;s original horse and coach logo — along with its upper crust equestrian connotations. 2013年，斯图尔特 维佛斯被任命为执行创意总监后，寇驰开始其品牌的“平台再造”。寇驰关闭了北美零售店的五分之一，并整修了其高流量、高价值的专卖店（如罗迪欧大道店），以彰显其“温暖”和“现代奢华”的风格，并重新使用寇驰原来的马和四轮马车的标志——及其上流社会座驾的内涵。 The company also cut 150 jobs and started to phase out its lower-priced purses and handbag lines.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://edu.qq.com/a/20160812/028915.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0929</post_time>
<username>www.qq.com</username>
<post>
0 [ 摘要 ]皮件制造商寇驰本周二宣布，将停止在“低端”的百货商店出售其手袋和钱包。此举是寇驰感到其产品在大众化商场出售，致使对有钱人的吸引力被削弱而做出的反应。 Coach is going First Class. 寇驰要走高端路线。 The leather-goods maker will no longer sell its handbags and purses at some &quot;lower volume&quot; department stores, the company announced Tuesday. The move comes in response to the brand&apos;s perceived diluted appeal to wealthier shoppers amid mass market access. 皮件制造商寇驰本周二宣布，将停止在“低端”的百货商店出售其手袋和钱包。此举是寇驰感到其产品在大众化商场出售，致使对有钱人的吸引力被削弱而做出的反应。 According to Tuesday&apos;s announcement, Coach will stop selling to around 250 locations in North America as of 2017, and also strictly control any discounts that department stores can offer. 根据周二的公告，2017年寇驰将在北美的约250个销售点停止销售，并且严格控制百货公司可以提供的任何折扣。 &quot;While we understand that customers may use department stores for trial and shopping across brands, the high level of promotional impressions created negatively impacts our long-term brand health,&quot; said Chief Executive Victor Luis during a conference call with analysts this week. 本周，寇驰首席执行官维克多 路易斯在与分析师的一次电话会议中表示：“尽管我们理解客户可在百货公司的不同品牌之间进行试用及购买，深刻的促销印象对我们品牌的长期健康产生了负面影响。” Once a category crusher, the 75-year-old company was forced to rethink its strategy in 2014 after reporting four straight quarterly losses, with shares falling a total of 39 percent that year. 这个拥有75年历史的公司曾是行业老大， 2014年却连续四个季度报告亏损且股价下跌39%，不得不重新考虑其品牌战略。 Those losses were partially attributed to the fact that Coach&apos;s loyal clientele had increasingly turned up its nose at the once-prestigious brand, whose less pricey CC line has been purchased in droves by younger consumers at steep discounts in malls and outlets. 这些亏损部分是因为，寇驰的忠实客户已经越来越对这个曾经著名的品牌嗤之以鼻。在各大商场和奥特莱斯，其相对低廉的CC系列产品因大幅度的折扣被成群结队的年轻消费者买走。 After the appointment of Stuart Vevers as executive creative director in 2013, Coach started a &quot;re-platforming&quot; of its brand. The company closed down one-fifth of its North American retail stores and renovated high-traffic, high-value stores (such as Rodeo Drive) to exude &quot;warmth&quot; and &quot;modern luxury,&quot; while returning to the company&apos;s original horse and coach logo — along with its upper crust equestrian connotations. 2013年，斯图尔特 维佛斯被任命为执行创意总监后，寇驰开始其品牌的“平台再造”。寇驰关闭了北美零售店的五分之一，并整修了其高流量、高价值的专卖店（如罗迪欧大道店），以彰显其“温暖”和“现代奢华”的风格，并重新使用寇驰原来的马和四轮马车的标志——及其上流社会座驾的内涵。 The company also cut 150 jobs and started to phase out its lower-priced purses and handbag lines.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>CN</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
