<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.dglobe.com//latest/rss/</forum>
<forum_title>| Daily Globe</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Candelight vigil is Sunday in Ludlow Park</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.dglobe.com/news/4092853-candelight-vigil-sunday-ludlow-park</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Candelight vigil is Sunday in Ludlow Park By Martina Baca Today at 9:59 p.m. WORTHINGTON -- A candlelight vigil prayer service will take place at 5:30 p.m. Sunday in Ludlow Park in response to tragic killings involving police officers and citizens across the nation. Manos Unidas, pastors and others in the community have coordinated the event to show sympathy toward those who lost their lives in recent shootings as well as their families. The vigil also represents an effort to allow Worthington police officers and citizens to air their concerns about issues related to those events. All community members are invited to join the gathering. Jim Krapf, a retired Presbyterian pastor, said there are two important issues to hear from community members -- their fears and hopes in regard to the topic, and to show support to the police department. Krapf said that even though he’s pleased to live in a safe community like Worthington, he thinks it’s important to take the time to do these kinds of events to cultivate trust among local residents. . “We have lots to be thankful for in this community, but let&apos;s not let that be in a way that dismisses addressing the concerns that people may have, because when we do that we get a deeper level of trust and a sense of this being a safe home,” Krapf said. Adyiam Kimbrough, who came up with the idea of the vigil, hopes the gathering will help the community further embrace its diversity. “I think the community needs to continue to focus on positivism and in community building,” Kimbrough said. Krapf added that the gathering is a great opportunity for community members to discuss their fears as well as to find ways to work together to keep improving Worthington’s safety. “It is a chance to continue having opportunities to build that sense of community unity and mutual trust,” Krapf said. “Some of that gets disrupted by the tragic killings that have taken place.” . Krapf, as well as Kimbrough, said people need to keep an open mind and heart when discussing issues at the vigil. “We don&apos;t always hear all the voices, and I think it takes a great deal of patience to hear some of the fear and pains of people without getting defensive,” Krapf said. “that really requires us to take a step back.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.dglobe.com/news/4092853-candelight-vigil-sunday-ludlow-park</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0259</post_time>
<username>Martina Baca</username>
<post>
Candelight vigil is Sunday in Ludlow Park By Martina Baca Today at 9:59 p.m. WORTHINGTON -- A candlelight vigil prayer service will take place at 5:30 p.m. Sunday in Ludlow Park in response to tragic killings involving police officers and citizens across the nation. Manos Unidas, pastors and others in the community have coordinated the event to show sympathy toward those who lost their lives in recent shootings as well as their families. The vigil also represents an effort to allow Worthington police officers and citizens to air their concerns about issues related to those events. All community members are invited to join the gathering. Jim Krapf, a retired Presbyterian pastor, said there are two important issues to hear from community members -- their fears and hopes in regard to the topic, and to show support to the police department. Krapf said that even though he’s pleased to live in a safe community like Worthington, he thinks it’s important to take the time to do these kinds of events to cultivate trust among local residents. . “We have lots to be thankful for in this community, but let&apos;s not let that be in a way that dismisses addressing the concerns that people may have, because when we do that we get a deeper level of trust and a sense of this being a safe home,” Krapf said. Adyiam Kimbrough, who came up with the idea of the vigil, hopes the gathering will help the community further embrace its diversity. “I think the community needs to continue to focus on positivism and in community building,” Kimbrough said. Krapf added that the gathering is a great opportunity for community members to discuss their fears as well as to find ways to work together to keep improving Worthington’s safety. “It is a chance to continue having opportunities to build that sense of community unity and mutual trust,” Krapf said. “Some of that gets disrupted by the tragic killings that have taken place.” . Krapf, as well as Kimbrough, said people need to keep an open mind and heart when discussing issues at the vigil. “We don&apos;t always hear all the voices, and I think it takes a great deal of patience to hear some of the fear and pains of people without getting defensive,” Krapf said. “that really requires us to take a step back.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.dglobe.com/sites/all/themes/dglobe_theme/images/touch-icon.png</main_image>
</document>
