<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/rssfeeds/13352306.cms</forum>
<forum_title>Industry-The Economic Times</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Times Internet partners HDFC Bank to launch co-branded Debit Card</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/banking/finance/times-internet-partners-hdfc-bank-to-launch-co-branded-debit-card/articleshow/53661044.cms</topic_url>
<topic_text>
MUMBAI: Times Internet (part of Bennett, Coleman &amp; Co that owns The Economic Times), in partnership with HDFC Bank , announced the launch of a co-branded card on Thursday called the Times Points Debit Card. 

The card marries the concept of Times Points, an online loyalty product with over 18 million users, and Times Card, a co-branded credit card currently used by 3.5 lakh customers that was launched in 2013 by Times Internet in association with HDFC Bank. 

While describing the gamut of services the new co-branded card offers, Archana Vohra , COO of Times Cards, said, &quot;It&apos;s actually a card on steroids. But the Olympics are on, so maybe we won&apos;t go there.&quot; 

Its services include: opportunity to earn points while browsing and commenting on any Times Internet sites, discounts while purchasing online, welcome offers on over 350 e-commerce sites, and offline shopping destinations across nine Tier 1cities. 

The target group for the card is users in the 18-30 age-group. Present at the press conference as chief guest was Vineet Jain , MD, Times Group. He said, &quot;News has become a commodity now and readers have multiple options to consume it from. This move will build some sort of loyalty with the readership of all Times sites and increase their engagement with our content.&quot; 

Parag Rao, country head - card payment products, merchant acquiring services, and marketing, at HDFC Bank, highlighted how spends and the growth rate in the debit cards segment was double of that in credit cards, rationalising the need for yet another co-branded card to serve the market. 

On the marketing front, Vohra, said, &quot;We like to get the products scale in the market first. Having nearly 4 lakh Times credit cards, and 19 million Times Points users is huge scale. The marketing initiatives will begin now.&quot; She denied any overlaps with HDFC&apos;s existing Debit Card services or any competition with payment wallet companies.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/banking/finance/times-internet-partners-hdfc-bank-to-launch-co-branded-debit-card/articleshow/53661044.cms</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>1048</post_time>
<username>indian</username>
<post>
EXCELLENT INITIATIVE
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/thumb/msid-53661067,width-600,resizemode-4,imglength-547733/industry/banking/finance/times-internet-partners-hdfc-bank-to-launch-co-branded-debit-card/timescard.jpg</main_image>
</document>
