<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.wbir.com/_/20/109872676/Wbir/national-world-news</forum>
<forum_title>WBIR - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Greene Co. Fair ends contract</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.wbir.com/_/20/109872676/Wbir/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wbir&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;local&amp;#x2f;greene-co-fair-terminates-contract-with-ride-company&amp;#x2f;293500613</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Close Greene Co. Fair terminates contract with ride company 10 Investigates further examines the ride operators involved in the Greene County Fair Ferris wheel accident that put 3 girls in the hospital. August 10, 2016. Mike Donila and Michael Crowe, WBIR 8:32   Federal investigators from the U.S. Product Safety Commission inspect a Ferris wheel at the Greene County Fair on Aug. 10, 2016. (Photo: WBIR) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
GREENEVILLE - Greene County Fair officials announced they will terminate their contract with South Georgia company owners who provided a malfunctioning Ferris wheel that seriously injured three girls. 
Neither the company or the fair will recieve compensation for the 2016 or 2017 fair years. In a press release, the Greene County Fair Board said it wanted to send its best wishes to the two injured children who were released from the hospital Thursday. 
The company, Valdosta-based Family Attractions Amusement, had one year left on its contract. 
The fair board released a copy of the carnival&apos;s five-year contract with Greene County. 
The contract was signed in September 2011, taking effect in 2012. It stated that in the event of an accident or disaster, neither party is at fault and the amusement company could cancel the contract without penalty with written notice. 
&quot;In case of accident or delay, strike, fire, cyclone, epidemic or any unforeseen occurrence over which (either party) has no control, neither party will be held liable for damages,&quot; the contract reads. 
According to the contract, the county receives a portion of the company&apos;s ticket sales. That portion is based on a percentage scale that increases as ticket sales increase. For example, the county receives 30 percent of all sales up to $100,000, but gets 32.5 percent if sales reach between $100,000 and $125,000. After that, the county earns 35 percent of sales. 
The contract also states that the county is to pay for utilities including electricity, water and restrooms required to run the fair. 
Holt said the 20-member non-profit board plans to meet “soon” after the fair ends. The fair is slated to wrap up Saturday. 
10News has requested a copy of the contract between the fair and Family Attractions. Holt refused to provide that contract, citing an unnamed attorney’s advice. The fair board is subject to the state Open Records Act. 
On Monday night, three girls fell 35-45 feet from the gondola of a Ferris wheel at the Greene County Fair in Greeneville. The gondola flipped due to a “mechanical failure,” according to investigators, and pitched the girls out of it. 
“Car number 9 got caught on a bar and caused car to turn over,” Greene County Fair officials wrote in an accident report submitted Monday to the state Department of Labor and Workforce Development. “At the time of the fall, the gondola was tipped to the interior of the ride approximately 90 degrees and the gondola was located at the 3 o’clock position of the ride.” 
A 6-year-old-girl who fell suffered a traumatic brain injury, while injuries suffered by a 10-year-old and 16-year-old were not life threatening. 
The girls are receiving treatment at a Johnson City hospital. 
A 10News investigation found that Family Attractions was previously involved in an incident where a ride seriously injured five people at the 2013 North Carolina State Fair. 
The state has since shut down all mechanical rides at the fair. 
The Ferris wheel, manufactured in January 2005, was last inspected on June 21 of this year in Marion, Ind., according to records. Tennessee recognizes another state’s inspection for up to three months when it determines whether to allow a company to renew its permit within the state. 
Prior to the accident, Tennessee granted Family Attractions a permit good through this Saturday – the last day of the Greene County Fair, state records show. 
However, due to the accident the company will need a third party inspection done before the state will issue a new permit, Department of Labor spokeswoman Jennifer Farrar told WBIR 10News. 
Officials say they are working to re-open them by Wednesday evening. 
“We want to be sure that everything is up to speed and (there are) no other safety issues,” Holt said. “None have been identified to date. We want it to be a no-question issue on our behalf and for the community.” 
Federal investigators from the U.S. Product Safety Commission arrived early Wednesday afternoon. No timeline is available for their report. 
“We don’t know the circumstances of the accident and that’s one of the things we’re looking to determine,&quot;, said Patty Davis, spokeswoman for the federal agency. 
Davis said if inspectors find a defect with the wheel they will issue a safety notice to the manufacturers and users. 
But, she said state and local officials – not federal investigators – have the ultimate authority over whether the fair reopens. 
Greene County signed its contract with Family Attractions prior to the accident. 
Holt said after the 2013 North Carolina incident, board members did talk about it, but he declined to elaborate on the conversation. 
This story will be updated as more information is available.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.wbir.com/_/20/109872676/Wbir/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wbir&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;local&amp;#x2f;greene-co-fair-terminates-contract-with-ride-company&amp;#x2f;293500613</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0132</post_time>
<username>Mike Donila</username>
<post>
Close Greene Co. Fair terminates contract with ride company 10 Investigates further examines the ride operators involved in the Greene County Fair Ferris wheel accident that put 3 girls in the hospital. August 10, 2016. Mike Donila and Michael Crowe, WBIR 8:32   Federal investigators from the U.S. Product Safety Commission inspect a Ferris wheel at the Greene County Fair on Aug. 10, 2016. (Photo: WBIR) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
GREENEVILLE - Greene County Fair officials announced they will terminate their contract with South Georgia company owners who provided a malfunctioning Ferris wheel that seriously injured three girls. 
Neither the company or the fair will recieve compensation for the 2016 or 2017 fair years. In a press release, the Greene County Fair Board said it wanted to send its best wishes to the two injured children who were released from the hospital Thursday. 
The company, Valdosta-based Family Attractions Amusement, had one year left on its contract. 
The fair board released a copy of the carnival&apos;s five-year contract with Greene County. 
The contract was signed in September 2011, taking effect in 2012. It stated that in the event of an accident or disaster, neither party is at fault and the amusement company could cancel the contract without penalty with written notice. 
&quot;In case of accident or delay, strike, fire, cyclone, epidemic or any unforeseen occurrence over which (either party) has no control, neither party will be held liable for damages,&quot; the contract reads. 
According to the contract, the county receives a portion of the company&apos;s ticket sales. That portion is based on a percentage scale that increases as ticket sales increase. For example, the county receives 30 percent of all sales up to $100,000, but gets 32.5 percent if sales reach between $100,000 and $125,000. After that, the county earns 35 percent of sales. 
The contract also states that the county is to pay for utilities including electricity, water and restrooms required to run the fair. 
Holt said the 20-member non-profit board plans to meet “soon” after the fair ends. The fair is slated to wrap up Saturday. 
10News has requested a copy of the contract between the fair and Family Attractions. Holt refused to provide that contract, citing an unnamed attorney’s advice. The fair board is subject to the state Open Records Act. 
On Monday night, three girls fell 35-45 feet from the gondola of a Ferris wheel at the Greene County Fair in Greeneville. The gondola flipped due to a “mechanical failure,” according to investigators, and pitched the girls out of it. 
“Car number 9 got caught on a bar and caused car to turn over,” Greene County Fair officials wrote in an accident report submitted Monday to the state Department of Labor and Workforce Development. “At the time of the fall, the gondola was tipped to the interior of the ride approximately 90 degrees and the gondola was located at the 3 o’clock position of the ride.” 
A 6-year-old-girl who fell suffered a traumatic brain injury, while injuries suffered by a 10-year-old and 16-year-old were not life threatening. 
The girls are receiving treatment at a Johnson City hospital. 
A 10News investigation found that Family Attractions was previously involved in an incident where a ride seriously injured five people at the 2013 North Carolina State Fair. 
The state has since shut down all mechanical rides at the fair. 
The Ferris wheel, manufactured in January 2005, was last inspected on June 21 of this year in Marion, Ind., according to records. Tennessee recognizes another state’s inspection for up to three months when it determines whether to allow a company to renew its permit within the state. 
Prior to the accident, Tennessee granted Family Attractions a permit good through this Saturday – the last day of the Greene County Fair, state records show. 
However, due to the accident the company will need a third party inspection done before the state will issue a new permit, Department of Labor spokeswoman Jennifer Farrar told WBIR 10News. 
Officials say they are working to re-open them by Wednesday evening. 
“We want to be sure that everything is up to speed and (there are) no other safety issues,” Holt said. “None have been identified to date. We want it to be a no-question issue on our behalf and for the community.” 
Federal investigators from the U.S. Product Safety Commission arrived early Wednesday afternoon. No timeline is available for their report. 
“We don’t know the circumstances of the accident and that’s one of the things we’re looking to determine,&quot;, said Patty Davis, spokeswoman for the federal agency. 
Davis said if inspectors find a defect with the wheel they will issue a safety notice to the manufacturers and users. 
But, she said state and local officials – not federal investigators – have the ultimate authority over whether the fair reopens. 
Greene County signed its contract with Family Attractions prior to the accident. 
Holt said after the 2013 North Carolina incident, board members did talk about it, but he declined to elaborate on the conversation. 
This story will be updated as more information is available.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.wbir.com/photo/2016/08/10/Ferris%20wheel_1470850936430_4952578_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
