<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://swampscott.wickedlocal.com/lifestyle?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Lifestyle - The Swampscott Reporter</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Religion News: California Christian colleges face closure</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://swampscott.wickedlocal.com/news/20160811/religion-news-california-christian-colleges-face-closure</topic_url>
<topic_text>
subscribe 
WEEK IN RELIGIONTeaching the biblical view of sexuality could cost Christian colleges in California their very existence. Recently, the California state legislature introduced a bill that would prevent federal funding from going to Christian colleges in the state if they continue to maintain a biblical view of sexuality. In response to the bill, a group of religious leaders — including university presidents, professors and pastors — issued a joint statement encouraging the legislature to drop the bill that could potentially end Christian higher education in California. The call to drop the legislation is being led by the Southern Baptist Convention’s Ethics and Religious Liberty Commission who include Russell Moore (President of the Ethics and Religious Liberty Commission), Rick Warren (Pastor and founder of Saddleback Church), Jim Daly, Barry Corey (President of Biola University) and Al Mohler (President of the Southern Baptists Theological Seminary). Jewish and Muslim leaders have also joined the petition for fear the bill could lead to censorship of other forms of religious education. Currently, there are more than 40 religious colleges in California.— More Content NowSURVEY SAYSPolitics from the pulpitThe pulpit has become a source of politics during the 2016 election season, according to a new survey. The Pew Research Center recently released a survey in which 64 percent of the respondents said their clergy have addressed at least one political or social issue in the last six months. The survey also found that although churches can be stripped of their tax-exempt status for endorsing or opposing a candidate, 14 percent of the respondents said their pastors have spoken about a specific presidential candidate. — More Content NowGOOD BOOK?“Jesus Speaks: Learning to Recognize and Respond to the Lord’s Voice” by Leonard Sweet and Frank ViolaCountless Christians today are hungry to hear God’s voice. The trouble is, many don’t know how. In a warm and practical way, “Jesus Speaks” teaches readers how to listen for the voice of Jesus. The book explores the various ways in which Christ speaks today and how His sheep can grow in their ability to recognize and respond to His voice daily. By exploring how the disciples interacted with the risen Jesus — from the Gospels to Revelation — Sweet and Viola unpack the myriad of ways the Lord speaks to His people today. They demystify the process, providing practical handles on how you can recognize the voice of Jesus in your own life.—Thomas NelsonTHE WORDgentile: In Judaism, anyone who is not a Jew. It is usually a reference to Christians.— ReligionStylebook.comAccording to the CIA World Factbook, the religious makeup of Uganda is:— Roman Catholic: 41.9 percent
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://swampscott.wickedlocal.com/news/20160811/religion-news-california-christian-colleges-face-closure</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>0701</post_time>
<username>More Content Now</username>
<post>
subscribe 
WEEK IN RELIGIONTeaching the biblical view of sexuality could cost Christian colleges in California their very existence. Recently, the California state legislature introduced a bill that would prevent federal funding from going to Christian colleges in the state if they continue to maintain a biblical view of sexuality. In response to the bill, a group of religious leaders — including university presidents, professors and pastors — issued a joint statement encouraging the legislature to drop the bill that could potentially end Christian higher education in California. The call to drop the legislation is being led by the Southern Baptist Convention’s Ethics and Religious Liberty Commission who include Russell Moore (President of the Ethics and Religious Liberty Commission), Rick Warren (Pastor and founder of Saddleback Church), Jim Daly, Barry Corey (President of Biola University) and Al Mohler (President of the Southern Baptists Theological Seminary). Jewish and Muslim leaders have also joined the petition for fear the bill could lead to censorship of other forms of religious education. Currently, there are more than 40 religious colleges in California.— More Content NowSURVEY SAYSPolitics from the pulpitThe pulpit has become a source of politics during the 2016 election season, according to a new survey. The Pew Research Center recently released a survey in which 64 percent of the respondents said their clergy have addressed at least one political or social issue in the last six months. The survey also found that although churches can be stripped of their tax-exempt status for endorsing or opposing a candidate, 14 percent of the respondents said their pastors have spoken about a specific presidential candidate. — More Content NowGOOD BOOK?“Jesus Speaks: Learning to Recognize and Respond to the Lord’s Voice” by Leonard Sweet and Frank ViolaCountless Christians today are hungry to hear God’s voice. The trouble is, many don’t know how. In a warm and practical way, “Jesus Speaks” teaches readers how to listen for the voice of Jesus. The book explores the various ways in which Christ speaks today and how His sheep can grow in their ability to recognize and respond to His voice daily. By exploring how the disciples interacted with the risen Jesus — from the Gospels to Revelation — Sweet and Viola unpack the myriad of ways the Lord speaks to His people today. They demystify the process, providing practical handles on how you can recognize the voice of Jesus in your own life.—Thomas NelsonTHE WORDgentile: In Judaism, anyone who is not a Jew. It is usually a reference to Christians.— ReligionStylebook.comAccording to the CIA World Factbook, the religious makeup of Uganda is:— Roman Catholic: 41.9 percent
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://swampscott.wickedlocal.com/storyimage/WL/20160811/NEWS/160819337/AR/0/AR-160819337.jpg</main_image>
</document>
