<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.remate.ph/category/opinions/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Opinions – Remate</forum_title>
<discussion_title>NAVOTAS’ ELA-CAPDEV</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.remate.ph/2016/08/navotas-ela-capdev/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
VITAL programs and projects that have been lined up by the administration of Navotas City Mayor John Rey Tiangco have been assured to be carried out without delay following the signing of a pledge of commitment between the former and the city’s lawmaking body. 
Mayor Tiangco and Vice Mayor Clint Nicholas Geronimo, presiding officer of the Sangguniang Panlunsod, inked the pledge with the entire city council members and witnessed by key local officials. 
The historic signing paves the way for the unhampered implementation of the so-called Executive-Legislative Agenda (ELA)-Capacity Development (CAPDEV) for the next three years. Mayor Tiangco says, ELA contained the priority projects and programs of the city government identified based on the most pressing issues affecting local residents. 
The CAPDEV Agenda, on the other hand, included plans and programs designed to enhance the local government’s capacity and performance in implementing the ELA successfully. 
VALENZUELA’S PLAN FOR SURRENDEREES 
Since the implementation of Project Tokhang in July 1, nearly 2,000 individuals in Valenzuela City involved in illegal drug activities have turned themselves in. 
As a standard operating procedure, surrenderees would undergo biometrics process and are made to sign an affidavit attesting that they’ll cease to have any involvement with illegal drugs. 
They then will be subjected drug test and if found positive, they’ll be referred to the Department of Health for assessment and rehabilitation. 
The overwhelming number of surrenderees, however, has slowed down the national agencies in fulfilling the procedures, according to Mayor Rex Gatchalian. 
“The city government, as a partner for change, therefore, decides to mobilize local resources through local innovative initiatives to complement the Project Tokhang with, thus launching, the yet most responsive, most complete and sustainable rehabilitation program that guarantees full moral and economic support to identified drug suspects, from the moment they surrender – the VC (Valenzuela City) Cares Plus,” he says. 
Under the program, he says, right after a drug offender turns himself in, (1) his drug dependence will be assessed by local medical doctors for appropriate treatment or rehabilitation; (2) either the patient will be referred to a 6-month long rehab program in Central Luzon Rehabilitation Center in Pampanga; (3) or the patient will be endorsed for out-patient Community-Based Rehab to be set up by the local government in Barangay Maysan, City Treatment and Psycho-social Support; (4) and once the person is already cleared of drug dependence, he shall be assisted by the Public Employment Service Office for job placement. 
It’s also preparing a reward system for the anti-narcotics teams that shall commit and dedicate themselves to convict drug offenders. Each team will receive P100,000 incentive per successful conviction. 
Those who shall be proven to have committed negligence in the performance of their duty will be dealt with administrative complaint at the People’s Law Enforcement Board. 
Barangay officials who don’t support the implementation of the campaign and VC Cares Plus will be sanctioned by the City Council. GOOD RIDDANCE/ARLIE CALALO loading...
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.remate.ph/2016/08/navotas-ela-capdev/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1046</post_time>
<username>Gilbert</username>
<post>
Tweet 
VITAL programs and projects that have been lined up by the administration of Navotas City Mayor John Rey Tiangco have been assured to be carried out without delay following the signing of a pledge of commitment between the former and the city’s lawmaking body. 
Mayor Tiangco and Vice Mayor Clint Nicholas Geronimo, presiding officer of the Sangguniang Panlunsod, inked the pledge with the entire city council members and witnessed by key local officials. 
The historic signing paves the way for the unhampered implementation of the so-called Executive-Legislative Agenda (ELA)-Capacity Development (CAPDEV) for the next three years. Mayor Tiangco says, ELA contained the priority projects and programs of the city government identified based on the most pressing issues affecting local residents. 
The CAPDEV Agenda, on the other hand, included plans and programs designed to enhance the local government’s capacity and performance in implementing the ELA successfully. 
VALENZUELA’S PLAN FOR SURRENDEREES 
Since the implementation of Project Tokhang in July 1, nearly 2,000 individuals in Valenzuela City involved in illegal drug activities have turned themselves in. 
As a standard operating procedure, surrenderees would undergo biometrics process and are made to sign an affidavit attesting that they’ll cease to have any involvement with illegal drugs. 
They then will be subjected drug test and if found positive, they’ll be referred to the Department of Health for assessment and rehabilitation. 
The overwhelming number of surrenderees, however, has slowed down the national agencies in fulfilling the procedures, according to Mayor Rex Gatchalian. 
“The city government, as a partner for change, therefore, decides to mobilize local resources through local innovative initiatives to complement the Project Tokhang with, thus launching, the yet most responsive, most complete and sustainable rehabilitation program that guarantees full moral and economic support to identified drug suspects, from the moment they surrender – the VC (Valenzuela City) Cares Plus,” he says. 
Under the program, he says, right after a drug offender turns himself in, (1) his drug dependence will be assessed by local medical doctors for appropriate treatment or rehabilitation; (2) either the patient will be referred to a 6-month long rehab program in Central Luzon Rehabilitation Center in Pampanga; (3) or the patient will be endorsed for out-patient Community-Based Rehab to be set up by the local government in Barangay Maysan, City Treatment and Psycho-social Support; (4) and once the person is already cleared of drug dependence, he shall be assisted by the Public Employment Service Office for job placement. 
It’s also preparing a reward system for the anti-narcotics teams that shall commit and dedicate themselves to convict drug offenders. Each team will receive P100,000 incentive per successful conviction. 
Those who shall be proven to have committed negligence in the performance of their duty will be dealt with administrative complaint at the People’s Law Enforcement Board. 
Barangay officials who don’t support the implementation of the campaign and VC Cares Plus will be sanctioned by the City Council. GOOD RIDDANCE/ARLIE CALALO loading...
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>PH</country>
<main_image>http://www.remate.ph/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/arlie-calalo413-2.jpg</main_image>
</document>
