<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://swampscott.wickedlocal.com/lifestyle?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Lifestyle - The Swampscott Reporter</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Networx: 10 Summertime Water Saving Tips</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://swampscott.wickedlocal.com/news/20160810/networx-10-summertime-water-saving-tips</topic_url>
<topic_text>
subscribe 
Summer is such a wonderful season — a time to feel free and easy. But if you’ve spent the past months working on saving precious water (or even if you’ve only thought about it), please don’t give up your good green intentions now. It’s actually easy and pretty painless to practice summertime H2O conservation. You can even take the opportunity to teach your kids to save water — in a fun way, of course.In the Bathroom and KitchenCut down on kids’ bath time. If your offspring have spent the day at the local pool, do they really need full tub baths before bed? Try hosing them down quickly with a handheld spray to rinse off leftover chlorine. When youngsters are old enough to bathe themselves, encourage the use of showers, which consume much less water than baths.Don’t run water uselessly. To wash those fresh picked berries you just brought home from the farm stand (mmm), place them in a bowl filled with water to cover, instead of running the faucet over them. Then pour the rinse water on your houseplants. In the shower — even the outdoor campsite variety — temporarily stop the flow before you soap up or shave. Keep a pitcher of drinking water in the fridge so you won’t have to keep the faucet going till the water gets cold.Track down and repair household plumbing leaks — even the tiniest drip from a toilet or other fixture can add up to big time water wastage. If you don’t want to give up even a few hours of your precious vacation time for this task, call in a plumber. You’ll end up saving water and money on your utility bills.Cook the water-smart way. Boil or steam summery vegetables in a minimal amount of liquid. This preserves nutrients and flavor, while conserving H2O. You get extra credit for recycling the cooking water in a soup or sauce. Prepping frozen meat for tomorrow night’s barbecue? Thaw it on the bottom shelf of your refrigerator, rather than under the hot water tap. BONUS: This method will defrost your ground beef or chicken wings safely, as per the USDA guidelines.OutdoorsLet your lawn grow — just a little. When you allow the grass in your yard to go an additional few days between mowings, the happy result is that you’ll need to water less frequently. The slightly longer blades of grass will help protect the underlying soil against drying out too quickly.Reduce your garden’s watering needs. When you select new seeds or plantlets to try — whether vegetables, flowers, or shrubs — focus on low-water species. Mulch your garden beds for a double-barreled benefit: To cut down on weed growth and hold in moisture.Sprinkle sensibly. Direct your sprinklers to water the lawn or garden, NOT the side of your house or unwary passersby on the sidewalk. Set your automatic sprinkler system to work early in the morning (before 9 a.m.), when the flow will be best absorbed, and fit it with a sensor to shut it off in case of rain.Prevent pool evaporation. Don’t let your swimming pool water literally disappear into thin air. Top your in-ground or aboveground pool or hot tub with a specially fitted cover in between uses. Obviously, this will also keep out dead bugs, leaves, and other debris.When You Go on VacationTurn off the main water valve before you leave for the cottage. This won’t harm your plumbing in any way, and it could save thousands of gallons of water if the supply line should happen to spring a leak. Of course, it will also spare you the nightmare scenario of returning from vacation to a home totally destroyed by water damage.Don’t take a vacation from your praiseworthy water-saving habits while you’re away.— Laura Firszt writes for networx.com. 


About Us
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://swampscott.wickedlocal.com/news/20160810/networx-10-summertime-water-saving-tips</post_url>
<post_date>20160810</post_date>
<post_time>1700</post_time>
<username>Laura Firszt More Content Now</username>
<post>
subscribe 
Summer is such a wonderful season — a time to feel free and easy. But if you’ve spent the past months working on saving precious water (or even if you’ve only thought about it), please don’t give up your good green intentions now. It’s actually easy and pretty painless to practice summertime H2O conservation. You can even take the opportunity to teach your kids to save water — in a fun way, of course.In the Bathroom and KitchenCut down on kids’ bath time. If your offspring have spent the day at the local pool, do they really need full tub baths before bed? Try hosing them down quickly with a handheld spray to rinse off leftover chlorine. When youngsters are old enough to bathe themselves, encourage the use of showers, which consume much less water than baths.Don’t run water uselessly. To wash those fresh picked berries you just brought home from the farm stand (mmm), place them in a bowl filled with water to cover, instead of running the faucet over them. Then pour the rinse water on your houseplants. In the shower — even the outdoor campsite variety — temporarily stop the flow before you soap up or shave. Keep a pitcher of drinking water in the fridge so you won’t have to keep the faucet going till the water gets cold.Track down and repair household plumbing leaks — even the tiniest drip from a toilet or other fixture can add up to big time water wastage. If you don’t want to give up even a few hours of your precious vacation time for this task, call in a plumber. You’ll end up saving water and money on your utility bills.Cook the water-smart way. Boil or steam summery vegetables in a minimal amount of liquid. This preserves nutrients and flavor, while conserving H2O. You get extra credit for recycling the cooking water in a soup or sauce. Prepping frozen meat for tomorrow night’s barbecue? Thaw it on the bottom shelf of your refrigerator, rather than under the hot water tap. BONUS: This method will defrost your ground beef or chicken wings safely, as per the USDA guidelines.OutdoorsLet your lawn grow — just a little. When you allow the grass in your yard to go an additional few days between mowings, the happy result is that you’ll need to water less frequently. The slightly longer blades of grass will help protect the underlying soil against drying out too quickly.Reduce your garden’s watering needs. When you select new seeds or plantlets to try — whether vegetables, flowers, or shrubs — focus on low-water species. Mulch your garden beds for a double-barreled benefit: To cut down on weed growth and hold in moisture.Sprinkle sensibly. Direct your sprinklers to water the lawn or garden, NOT the side of your house or unwary passersby on the sidewalk. Set your automatic sprinkler system to work early in the morning (before 9 a.m.), when the flow will be best absorbed, and fit it with a sensor to shut it off in case of rain.Prevent pool evaporation. Don’t let your swimming pool water literally disappear into thin air. Top your in-ground or aboveground pool or hot tub with a specially fitted cover in between uses. Obviously, this will also keep out dead bugs, leaves, and other debris.When You Go on VacationTurn off the main water valve before you leave for the cottage. This won’t harm your plumbing in any way, and it could save thousands of gallons of water if the supply line should happen to spring a leak. Of course, it will also spare you the nightmare scenario of returning from vacation to a home totally destroyed by water damage.Don’t take a vacation from your praiseworthy water-saving habits while you’re away.— Laura Firszt writes for networx.com. 


About Us
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://swampscott.wickedlocal.com/Global/images/head/nameplate/swampscott_logo.png</main_image>
</document>
