<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://badkitty.com/news/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Bad Kitty Blog | Pole Dancing Fitness Lifestyle News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>How Pole Can Help You Persevere on a Project</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.badkitty.com/news/how-pole-can-help-you-persevere-on-a-project/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Home &gt; Goals and Challenges &gt; How Pole Can Help You Persevere on a Project How Pole Can Help You Persevere on a Project By Lisa Faulkner + on August 11, 2016 Tweet 
We all face challenges in life that sometimes feel insurmountable. We have a goal that we desperately want to accomplish; however we face obstacles, opposition and even failure. 
It can be particularly challenging to persevere when what we desire is something life changing like quitting smoking, running a marathon, starting a business or writing a book. 
These activities take commitment, effort and time; often multiple attempts and months (or years) to accomplish. 
For years, I’ve been writing a book about how pole dancing changed my life. For the last six months, I’ve been working with an editor to polish it. The finish line is in sight. Best of all I’m proud of it. It’s vulnerable, funny and inspiring. 
What’s fascinating to me is that pole dancing is not only the subject of the book, but it’s been an instrumental tool that’s nudged me through blocks and doubts along the way. Without pole dance, I would never have gotten to this point. 
Here are six pole dance activities to help you persevere on your project! 1. Play 
Cue up your favorite song. One that amuses you or lets you cut loose and have fun. 
“Better When I’m Dancin’” by Meghan Trainor “Try Everything” by Shakira or “Sweet Home Alabama” by Lynyrd Skynyrd 
This last song inspired a symbolic keg party in a recent class. I actually felt tipsy after dancing to it. This brings up an important point, sometimes dancing with a buddy or a group can increase the play playoff as you engage with each other’s energy and “talk” to each other with your bodies. 
When we’re working hard, we often forget that play needs to be part of work for us to feel rejuvenated. Play restores us, fuels our creativity and helps us produce with sense of ease. 
In play we express our truest selves. Our essence. Our magic. 
“Play is not frivolous. Play is essential. For bonobos and humans alike, life is not just red in tooth and claw. In times when it seems least appropriate to play, it might be the times when it is most urgent.” ~ Isabel Behncke Ted2011 

Do something in pole dance that scares you. Wear six inch or eight inch stilettos. Dance to an instrumental song, or acapella, or dirty Hip-Hop, whatever stretches you. Include your nemesis trick in your next competition or performance. Dance for your lover or your mother. Make eye contact the whole time. Or dance blind folded. Dance in the dark. Or in the light. Or outdoors at dawn or under a new moon. 
Facing a pole fear can motivate you to tackle something you’ve been avoiding or reveal a hidden block that you weren’t aware of. 
3. Dance With Your Fear 
Create a pole dance activity or assignment that embodies your fear. 
For example, one day while warming-up to “Hey Now” by London Grammar, this big-bad-wolf fear howled out of hiding: “What if I stay stuck forever and never finish my book?” 
I faced my fear by tying both ankles to a pole, out of reach of a lap dance chair, which symbolized my completed manuscript. As I moved on the floor, it feels like I’m swimming in the ocean, tugged by the undertow. I could drown. 
I stood, widened my stance, circled my hips and slowly stripped off my top while the ropes were pulled taught. I felt magic the moment. It taught me to share more of my work along the way. To inspire readers before the book is done. It also nudged me to reclaim my power by becoming more vulnerable, reveal more of myself and my writing process and struggles to readers and friends. 
What activity or assignment can you give yourself in pole dancing that reflects a current struggle in your life on your big project? 
4. Explore the Power of Gentleness 
Dance to “Svefn-G-Englar” by Sigur Ros while imagining you are a sea nettle. Move as slowly and gently as you can. Drift through the space. Swirl around the pole. Float up it. 
Dance to the same song with a group of six to ten women. Circumnavigate your pole studio as if each of you is one of the sea nettle’s tentacles. Take turns flowing to different poles. Be one with the current. 
While at the pole choose a movement or sequence of movements in which you’d like to improve or get past a limitation. Reduce the force you use by 50 percent, 75 percent, 90 percent and then use the least amount possible. According to Anat Baniet, author of Move Into Life: the Nine Essentials for Lifelong Vitality (from whom this part of the exercise is adapted) “subtlety is the “it’ that brings you to the be here now.” 
How can you persist with more ease and gentleness on your project? 
5. Accept Help (Receive) 
Most women I know are fiercely independent givers. It can be hard for us to know what help we need, to ask for it and to receive. 
It’s almost impossible to persevere without receiving help. 
Last fall after dancing on the beach under the full moon eclipse I turned down two offers of help carrying damp, sandy towels up a hill. The next day it dawned on me, How could I expect to receive abundant gifts from the universe, if I couldn’t receive help carrying towels up a hill? 
That Friday I pole danced to “I Want You to Want Me” by Chase Holfelder. As I moved at a back pole while others danced with me, I heard clapping and loud cheers. I opened my eyes to investigate what the others were doing, because I couldn’t imagine the cheers were for me I wasn’t doing anything. The other dancer were watching me, captivated my by vulnerability and open-heartedness. 
This dance helped me become more vulnerable in my writing. And lead me to my editor who’s help has been invaluable to me and my manuscript. And perhaps most importantly, to turning up the dial on my strengths. 
6. Fake it ‘Til You Make It 
When all else fails, fake it until you make it. 
Sometimes when you feel afraid, stuck, defeated and ready to give up the best gift you can give yourself is to dance to a song that reflects how you wish you felt. 
So, dance to the bravest, most epic song you know. Or the most fiery. Or the one that grounds you and makes you feel invincible. Or simply the most determined. 
Here are few songs that have worked for me over the years: “Lose Yourself” by Eminem “I Want It All/We Will Rock You (ft. Armageddon) by Queen “Neva Give Up” by Mishka “I Don’t Ever Give Up” by Patty Griffin “True Colors” by Zedd “‘Til the Day I Die” by Toby Mac “I Lived” by Caleb and Kelsey 
And sometimes music alone can work magic, so here’s a link to a Perseverance Playlist of all the songs mentioned above that are on Spotify.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.badkitty.com/news/how-pole-can-help-you-persevere-on-a-project/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0520</post_time>
<username>Lisa Faulkner</username>
<post>
Home &gt; Goals and Challenges &gt; How Pole Can Help You Persevere on a Project How Pole Can Help You Persevere on a Project By Lisa Faulkner + on August 11, 2016 Tweet 
We all face challenges in life that sometimes feel insurmountable. We have a goal that we desperately want to accomplish; however we face obstacles, opposition and even failure. 
It can be particularly challenging to persevere when what we desire is something life changing like quitting smoking, running a marathon, starting a business or writing a book. 
These activities take commitment, effort and time; often multiple attempts and months (or years) to accomplish. 
For years, I’ve been writing a book about how pole dancing changed my life. For the last six months, I’ve been working with an editor to polish it. The finish line is in sight. Best of all I’m proud of it. It’s vulnerable, funny and inspiring. 
What’s fascinating to me is that pole dancing is not only the subject of the book, but it’s been an instrumental tool that’s nudged me through blocks and doubts along the way. Without pole dance, I would never have gotten to this point. 
Here are six pole dance activities to help you persevere on your project! 1. Play 
Cue up your favorite song. One that amuses you or lets you cut loose and have fun. 
“Better When I’m Dancin’” by Meghan Trainor “Try Everything” by Shakira or “Sweet Home Alabama” by Lynyrd Skynyrd 
This last song inspired a symbolic keg party in a recent class. I actually felt tipsy after dancing to it. This brings up an important point, sometimes dancing with a buddy or a group can increase the play playoff as you engage with each other’s energy and “talk” to each other with your bodies. 
When we’re working hard, we often forget that play needs to be part of work for us to feel rejuvenated. Play restores us, fuels our creativity and helps us produce with sense of ease. 
In play we express our truest selves. Our essence. Our magic. 
“Play is not frivolous. Play is essential. For bonobos and humans alike, life is not just red in tooth and claw. In times when it seems least appropriate to play, it might be the times when it is most urgent.” ~ Isabel Behncke Ted2011 

Do something in pole dance that scares you. Wear six inch or eight inch stilettos. Dance to an instrumental song, or acapella, or dirty Hip-Hop, whatever stretches you. Include your nemesis trick in your next competition or performance. Dance for your lover or your mother. Make eye contact the whole time. Or dance blind folded. Dance in the dark. Or in the light. Or outdoors at dawn or under a new moon. 
Facing a pole fear can motivate you to tackle something you’ve been avoiding or reveal a hidden block that you weren’t aware of. 
3. Dance With Your Fear 
Create a pole dance activity or assignment that embodies your fear. 
For example, one day while warming-up to “Hey Now” by London Grammar, this big-bad-wolf fear howled out of hiding: “What if I stay stuck forever and never finish my book?” 
I faced my fear by tying both ankles to a pole, out of reach of a lap dance chair, which symbolized my completed manuscript. As I moved on the floor, it feels like I’m swimming in the ocean, tugged by the undertow. I could drown. 
I stood, widened my stance, circled my hips and slowly stripped off my top while the ropes were pulled taught. I felt magic the moment. It taught me to share more of my work along the way. To inspire readers before the book is done. It also nudged me to reclaim my power by becoming more vulnerable, reveal more of myself and my writing process and struggles to readers and friends. 
What activity or assignment can you give yourself in pole dancing that reflects a current struggle in your life on your big project? 
4. Explore the Power of Gentleness 
Dance to “Svefn-G-Englar” by Sigur Ros while imagining you are a sea nettle. Move as slowly and gently as you can. Drift through the space. Swirl around the pole. Float up it. 
Dance to the same song with a group of six to ten women. Circumnavigate your pole studio as if each of you is one of the sea nettle’s tentacles. Take turns flowing to different poles. Be one with the current. 
While at the pole choose a movement or sequence of movements in which you’d like to improve or get past a limitation. Reduce the force you use by 50 percent, 75 percent, 90 percent and then use the least amount possible. According to Anat Baniet, author of Move Into Life: the Nine Essentials for Lifelong Vitality (from whom this part of the exercise is adapted) “subtlety is the “it’ that brings you to the be here now.” 
How can you persist with more ease and gentleness on your project? 
5. Accept Help (Receive) 
Most women I know are fiercely independent givers. It can be hard for us to know what help we need, to ask for it and to receive. 
It’s almost impossible to persevere without receiving help. 
Last fall after dancing on the beach under the full moon eclipse I turned down two offers of help carrying damp, sandy towels up a hill. The next day it dawned on me, How could I expect to receive abundant gifts from the universe, if I couldn’t receive help carrying towels up a hill? 
That Friday I pole danced to “I Want You to Want Me” by Chase Holfelder. As I moved at a back pole while others danced with me, I heard clapping and loud cheers. I opened my eyes to investigate what the others were doing, because I couldn’t imagine the cheers were for me I wasn’t doing anything. The other dancer were watching me, captivated my by vulnerability and open-heartedness. 
This dance helped me become more vulnerable in my writing. And lead me to my editor who’s help has been invaluable to me and my manuscript. And perhaps most importantly, to turning up the dial on my strengths. 
6. Fake it ‘Til You Make It 
When all else fails, fake it until you make it. 
Sometimes when you feel afraid, stuck, defeated and ready to give up the best gift you can give yourself is to dance to a song that reflects how you wish you felt. 
So, dance to the bravest, most epic song you know. Or the most fiery. Or the one that grounds you and makes you feel invincible. Or simply the most determined. 
Here are few songs that have worked for me over the years: “Lose Yourself” by Eminem “I Want It All/We Will Rock You (ft. Armageddon) by Queen “Neva Give Up” by Mishka “I Don’t Ever Give Up” by Patty Griffin “True Colors” by Zedd “‘Til the Day I Die” by Toby Mac “I Lived” by Caleb and Kelsey 
And sometimes music alone can work magic, so here’s a link to a Perseverance Playlist of all the songs mentioned above that are on Spotify.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.badkitty.com/news/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/warrior-625002_960_720-300x336.jpg</main_image>
</document>
