<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.dglobe.com//latest/rss/</forum>
<forum_title>| Daily Globe</forum_title>
<discussion_title>2016 MCAs show how ISD 518 measures up</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.dglobe.com/news/education/4092860-2016-mcas-show-how-isd-518-measures</topic_url>
<topic_text>
2016 MCAs show how ISD 518 measures up By Jane Moore Today at 10:04 p.m. WORTHINGTON -- The Minnesota Department of Education (MDE) released the results of the 2016 Minnesota Comprehensive Assessments (MCAs) in the waning days of July, and ISD 518 administrators are considering what the latest scores mean for local students and their teachers. “We’re taking it one step at a time,” said Katie Clarke, ISD 518’s Director of Teaching and Learning. “This is the time of year we’re looking at the MCA data. It’s important to remember that no school or district in the state has a 100 percent proficiency rate, and our teachers work extremely hard, every day, to help and instruct their students.” Annually, from late February through April, Minnesota students in specific grade levels are assessed in different subject areas. “Third- through eighth-grade takes reading and math tests, 11th grade takes math, grade 10 takes reading, grades five and eight take science, and a third science test is also taken after students have completed their high school biology class, so that could be at grade 10, 11 or 12,” detailed Clarke. The MCAs came into use during the 2000s, partly in response to the federal “No Child Left Behind” dictate of 2002. Statewide, Minnesota students sitting for the 2016 MCAs managed proficiency levels of 59.9 percent in reading, 55.0 percent in science and 59.5 percent in math. In ISD 518, one of the state’s most diverse districts, overall proficiency ratings this year were notched at 47.3 percent in reading, 42 percent in science and 41.8 percent in math -- statistically equivalent to the 2015 scores. “The scores are pretty similar overall,” affirmed Clarke. “There’s not much deviation; it looks similar to what we had last year.” Demographically, ISD 518’s student population is currently recorded as .2 percent American Indian, 11.6 percent Asian/Pacific Islander, 50.1 percent Hispanic, 5.8 percent black and 32.3 percent white. “A few different things are at play here,” Clarke observed. “We have some students who come to Worthington Middle School (WMS) or Worthington High School (WHS) with non-grade equivalent educations -- for instance, we might get a new seventh-grader who is effectively operating at a second-grade level -- so that may be one factor in our scores.” Clarke references the presence of several educational intervention specialists in the district (at WMS and at Prairie Elementary) who work intensively with struggling students or those who may need extra, one-on-one academic assistance. Despite MCA proficiencies lagging 12 to 18 percent below statewide points, District 518’s graduation rate has been trending upward, with the MDE noting its 2015 ranking (the most recent available) stands at 87.9 percent. “The MCAs are state-based standards, and we don’t always know what those questions will be,” clarified Clarke. “A student can be a relatively fluent reader and still not pass the MCA reading test because the state standards are broader and assess different strands and benchmarks than students necessarily need for graduation.” Citizens curious enough to comb through MDE’s website to review the various statistics might be surprised to see a sizeable drop in reading proficiency between 2013 and 2014. “The reading test changed in 2013, so you cannot effectively compare those scores to what comes after,” said Clarke. Clarke cautions that the MCAs are only one small mark indicating students’ academic progress. “We look at this data, keeping in mind it’s only one snapshot in time, and we use that as a starting point,” said Clarke. “We look for any anomalies or discrepancies, any area that is going way up or not, then we drill down, analyze the sub-groups, the grade levels, the buildings and the programming. “Last spring the district adopted a new five-year improvement plan, with five smart goals, and we really hope our focus and work on those goals will help improve some of the student achievement scores, and that other formative assessment data available throughout the year will allow classroom teachers to adjust their instruction to best help our students.” Loosely, the five ISD 518 goals include: having 80 percent of identified preschoolers involved in an early childhood experience to ensure better kindergarten readiness; achieving 80 percent MCA reading proficiency for all grade three and four students who are enrolled on or before Oct. 1; reducing the student achievement gap; helping all students identify individual career goals and options by 12th grade; and achieving a 100 percent graduation rate. “On Aug. 23, we’re bringing in the ISD 518 teacher leadership team and they’ll have the day to review this (the MCA) data, look at the school site improvement plan and use the combined information to determine how we’ll adjust accordingly,” explained Clarke. “Then, from Day One, teachers will collect data on their students so they can see where kids are succeeding or struggling.” Clarke cited the built-in professional learning communities that exist at all ISD 518 buildings as another means for teachers to strengthen their own teaching skills. “This occurs on an on-going basis and is a really collaborative approach, letting teachers share ideas that can help them assist their students,” noted Clarke. Ultimately, the MCAs are only one means for teachers, in ISD 518 and throughout the state, to monitor their students’ progress. “We want to give all of our students a chance to be successful,” assured Clarke. “We want to connect with all of our families so that every student can get a world-class education.” 
To view the 2016 MCA outcomes, state and district demographic data, school performance, graduation rates, academic standards and more, visit rc.education.state.mn.us.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.dglobe.com/news/education/4092860-2016-mcas-show-how-isd-518-measures</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0304</post_time>
<username>Jane Moore</username>
<post>
2016 MCAs show how ISD 518 measures up By Jane Moore Today at 10:04 p.m. WORTHINGTON -- The Minnesota Department of Education (MDE) released the results of the 2016 Minnesota Comprehensive Assessments (MCAs) in the waning days of July, and ISD 518 administrators are considering what the latest scores mean for local students and their teachers. “We’re taking it one step at a time,” said Katie Clarke, ISD 518’s Director of Teaching and Learning. “This is the time of year we’re looking at the MCA data. It’s important to remember that no school or district in the state has a 100 percent proficiency rate, and our teachers work extremely hard, every day, to help and instruct their students.” Annually, from late February through April, Minnesota students in specific grade levels are assessed in different subject areas. “Third- through eighth-grade takes reading and math tests, 11th grade takes math, grade 10 takes reading, grades five and eight take science, and a third science test is also taken after students have completed their high school biology class, so that could be at grade 10, 11 or 12,” detailed Clarke. The MCAs came into use during the 2000s, partly in response to the federal “No Child Left Behind” dictate of 2002. Statewide, Minnesota students sitting for the 2016 MCAs managed proficiency levels of 59.9 percent in reading, 55.0 percent in science and 59.5 percent in math. In ISD 518, one of the state’s most diverse districts, overall proficiency ratings this year were notched at 47.3 percent in reading, 42 percent in science and 41.8 percent in math -- statistically equivalent to the 2015 scores. “The scores are pretty similar overall,” affirmed Clarke. “There’s not much deviation; it looks similar to what we had last year.” Demographically, ISD 518’s student population is currently recorded as .2 percent American Indian, 11.6 percent Asian/Pacific Islander, 50.1 percent Hispanic, 5.8 percent black and 32.3 percent white. “A few different things are at play here,” Clarke observed. “We have some students who come to Worthington Middle School (WMS) or Worthington High School (WHS) with non-grade equivalent educations -- for instance, we might get a new seventh-grader who is effectively operating at a second-grade level -- so that may be one factor in our scores.” Clarke references the presence of several educational intervention specialists in the district (at WMS and at Prairie Elementary) who work intensively with struggling students or those who may need extra, one-on-one academic assistance. Despite MCA proficiencies lagging 12 to 18 percent below statewide points, District 518’s graduation rate has been trending upward, with the MDE noting its 2015 ranking (the most recent available) stands at 87.9 percent. “The MCAs are state-based standards, and we don’t always know what those questions will be,” clarified Clarke. “A student can be a relatively fluent reader and still not pass the MCA reading test because the state standards are broader and assess different strands and benchmarks than students necessarily need for graduation.” Citizens curious enough to comb through MDE’s website to review the various statistics might be surprised to see a sizeable drop in reading proficiency between 2013 and 2014. “The reading test changed in 2013, so you cannot effectively compare those scores to what comes after,” said Clarke. Clarke cautions that the MCAs are only one small mark indicating students’ academic progress. “We look at this data, keeping in mind it’s only one snapshot in time, and we use that as a starting point,” said Clarke. “We look for any anomalies or discrepancies, any area that is going way up or not, then we drill down, analyze the sub-groups, the grade levels, the buildings and the programming. “Last spring the district adopted a new five-year improvement plan, with five smart goals, and we really hope our focus and work on those goals will help improve some of the student achievement scores, and that other formative assessment data available throughout the year will allow classroom teachers to adjust their instruction to best help our students.” Loosely, the five ISD 518 goals include: having 80 percent of identified preschoolers involved in an early childhood experience to ensure better kindergarten readiness; achieving 80 percent MCA reading proficiency for all grade three and four students who are enrolled on or before Oct. 1; reducing the student achievement gap; helping all students identify individual career goals and options by 12th grade; and achieving a 100 percent graduation rate. “On Aug. 23, we’re bringing in the ISD 518 teacher leadership team and they’ll have the day to review this (the MCA) data, look at the school site improvement plan and use the combined information to determine how we’ll adjust accordingly,” explained Clarke. “Then, from Day One, teachers will collect data on their students so they can see where kids are succeeding or struggling.” Clarke cited the built-in professional learning communities that exist at all ISD 518 buildings as another means for teachers to strengthen their own teaching skills. “This occurs on an on-going basis and is a really collaborative approach, letting teachers share ideas that can help them assist their students,” noted Clarke. Ultimately, the MCAs are only one means for teachers, in ISD 518 and throughout the state, to monitor their students’ progress. “We want to give all of our students a chance to be successful,” assured Clarke. “We want to connect with all of our families so that every student can get a world-class education.” 
To view the 2016 MCA outcomes, state and district demographic data, school performance, graduation rates, academic standards and more, visit rc.education.state.mn.us.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.dglobe.com/sites/all/themes/dglobe_theme/images/touch-icon.png</main_image>
</document>
