<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://feeds.foxnews.com/foxnews/latest?format=xml</forum>
<forum_title>FOXNews.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Phelps routs rival Lochte for 22nd Olympic gold News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.foxnews.com/sports/2016/08/11/phelps-routs-rival-lochte-for-22nd-olympic-gold.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Published August 11, 2016 Associated Press Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print United States&apos; Michael Phelps wins the gold medal in the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley ahead of fifth placed United States&apos; Ryan Lochte, right, during the swimming competitions at the 2016 Summer Olympics, Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016, in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (AP Photo/Natacha Pisarenko) 
Michael Phelps wasn&apos;t about to be stopped. Not even by his biggest rival.

Phelps blew away Ryan Lochte -- and everyone else, for that matter -- to win his fourth gold medal of the Rio Olympics and 22nd overall with a victory in the 200-meter individual medley Thursday night.

This was touted as the last showdown between two of America&apos;s greatest swimmers, though there&apos;s never been any question about which one had the upper hand.

Phelps became the first swimmer ever to win the same event at four straight Olympics, and he always left Lochte trailing in his wake. Phelps finished a full body-length ahead of the field with total dominance on the breaststroke and freestyle legs, finishing in 1 minute, 54.66 seconds.

Lochte didn&apos;t even make it to the podium this time, after taking two silvers and a bronze behind Phelps at the last three Olympics. He led at the midway point but faded to fifth.

Japan&apos;s Kosuke Hagino took the silver, while China&apos;s Wang Shun claimed the bronze.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>26</post_num>
<post_id>post-26</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.foxnews.com/sports/2016/08/11/phelps-routs-rival-lochte-for-22nd-olympic-gold.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0545</post_time>
<username>Caden1830</username>
<post>
Sew a needle pulling thread
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>CH</country>
<main_image>http://a57.foxnews.com/images.foxnews.com/content/fox-news/sports/2016/08/11/phelps-routs-rival-lochte-for-22nd-olympic-gold/_jcr_content/par/featured-media/media-0.img.jpg/0/0/1470968539948.jpg?ve=1</main_image>
</document>
