<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://alldolledup.co.za/feed</forum>
<forum_title>All Dolled Up</forum_title>
<discussion_title>NEW: Restylane Skincare</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://alldolledup.co.za/2016/08/new-restylane-skincare/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
No Comments 
If the term “Restylane” sounds familiar, it’s because you’re probably familiar with the Swedish brand of dermal fillers used to reduce wrinkles and fine lines, create fuller lips and accentuate contours. Well now the range has been expanded to include some luxurious at-home skincare designed to complement their injectables or if, like me, you’re not that way inclined, just form the base of a nourishing daily skincare routine. 
The USP of the range is its use of “unique NASHA TM technology”, which is basically a stabilized form of hyaluronic acid in maximum concentration that helps to bind water and naturally improve hydration. The particles are also very light-reflective, so they give the skin an added glow. The range is complemented with high doses of proven active ingredients such as retinol , antioxidants , ceramides, niacinamide and exclusive emollients. 
It claims to be suitable for normal, combination, dry and/or sensitive skins (basically everyone except oily/acne-prone) and for those concerned with early ageing and fine lines. We were sent a few of the products to trial so while I put them to the test over the next few weeks, here is an overview of the items we received: Restylane Facial Cleanser 
Gentle cleansers are my jam, so I was pleased to learn that this mild formulation is designed to remove impurities while helping to protect the skin’s barrier function. This means that the skin isn’t stripped of its natural moisturisers, which can lead to inflammation and over-production of sebum. Key ingredients include Organic sunflower oil and Ceramide 3 for moisturising, while Vitamin E provides antioxidant protection. 
Price: R395 for 100ml Restylane Day Cream SPF15 
The daytime moisturiser in the range with added SPF (there’s also one without SPF ) is a classic “protection” product, helping to improve structure and elasticity while defending against sun damage. After “swatching” it on my hands, I can tell you that the texture is quite lightweight but with a certain amount of richness that leaves the skin very nourished and “fresh” feeling, but not greasy. It contains a good dose of glycerin, hyaluronic acid and squalane so it’s bound to be very hydrating, plus niacinamide (vitamin B3) tackles uneven skin tone and collagen depletion. There’s also added antioxidant protection from Co-enzyme Q10 (read about why that’s important here ). 
Price: R600 for 50ml Restylane Night Cream 
As night creams go, this one is lovely and light, but like the day cream, leaves the skin feeling nicely moisturised without being sticky. Again, the main aim with this formulation is maintaining the skin’s barrier function with the added bonus of plumping up fine lines. Aside from the usual “stabilized hyaluronic acid within NASHA TM technology” liquorice and oat extracts soothe and calm the skin. Together with the Restylane Night Serum, which contains retinol, it addresses signs of ageing, uneven skin tone and rough texture. In theory, you should wake with softer, glowing skin with improved elasticity! 
Price: R575 for 50ml Restylane Night Serum 
If you’re looking for an entry-level retinol serum and/or your skin is usually a bit sensitive to the stuff, then this might be for you. It contains 0.4% (the retinol products I use are 1%) but it’s also microencapsulated which tends to mean less irritation, and makes it stable and highly absorbable. As you’ll know by now, retinol is a powerful anti-ageing ingredient that works to reverse the effects of sun damage, reduce fine lines and wrinkles, and improve the skin’s elasticity. It also helps brown spots, uneven skin tone, rough texture and collagen production – in other words, if you’re 30+, it’s time to get on the retinol train! Retinol can be quite drying but the added hyaluronic acid in this product helps to provide deep and lasting hydration. Read this to find out more about how to introduce retinol into your routine. 
Price: R560 for 15ml 
The range also includes an Eye Serum , Recover Cream (for use after aesthetic treatments) and Hand Cream . 
Restylane Skincare is exclusively available in South Africa at Dermastore . Share this:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://alldolledup.co.za/2016/08/new-restylane-skincare/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0600</post_time>
<username>Jules</username>
<post>
No Comments 
If the term “Restylane” sounds familiar, it’s because you’re probably familiar with the Swedish brand of dermal fillers used to reduce wrinkles and fine lines, create fuller lips and accentuate contours. Well now the range has been expanded to include some luxurious at-home skincare designed to complement their injectables or if, like me, you’re not that way inclined, just form the base of a nourishing daily skincare routine. 
The USP of the range is its use of “unique NASHA TM technology”, which is basically a stabilized form of hyaluronic acid in maximum concentration that helps to bind water and naturally improve hydration. The particles are also very light-reflective, so they give the skin an added glow. The range is complemented with high doses of proven active ingredients such as retinol , antioxidants , ceramides, niacinamide and exclusive emollients. 
It claims to be suitable for normal, combination, dry and/or sensitive skins (basically everyone except oily/acne-prone) and for those concerned with early ageing and fine lines. We were sent a few of the products to trial so while I put them to the test over the next few weeks, here is an overview of the items we received: Restylane Facial Cleanser 
Gentle cleansers are my jam, so I was pleased to learn that this mild formulation is designed to remove impurities while helping to protect the skin’s barrier function. This means that the skin isn’t stripped of its natural moisturisers, which can lead to inflammation and over-production of sebum. Key ingredients include Organic sunflower oil and Ceramide 3 for moisturising, while Vitamin E provides antioxidant protection. 
Price: R395 for 100ml Restylane Day Cream SPF15 
The daytime moisturiser in the range with added SPF (there’s also one without SPF ) is a classic “protection” product, helping to improve structure and elasticity while defending against sun damage. After “swatching” it on my hands, I can tell you that the texture is quite lightweight but with a certain amount of richness that leaves the skin very nourished and “fresh” feeling, but not greasy. It contains a good dose of glycerin, hyaluronic acid and squalane so it’s bound to be very hydrating, plus niacinamide (vitamin B3) tackles uneven skin tone and collagen depletion. There’s also added antioxidant protection from Co-enzyme Q10 (read about why that’s important here ). 
Price: R600 for 50ml Restylane Night Cream 
As night creams go, this one is lovely and light, but like the day cream, leaves the skin feeling nicely moisturised without being sticky. Again, the main aim with this formulation is maintaining the skin’s barrier function with the added bonus of plumping up fine lines. Aside from the usual “stabilized hyaluronic acid within NASHA TM technology” liquorice and oat extracts soothe and calm the skin. Together with the Restylane Night Serum, which contains retinol, it addresses signs of ageing, uneven skin tone and rough texture. In theory, you should wake with softer, glowing skin with improved elasticity! 
Price: R575 for 50ml Restylane Night Serum 
If you’re looking for an entry-level retinol serum and/or your skin is usually a bit sensitive to the stuff, then this might be for you. It contains 0.4% (the retinol products I use are 1%) but it’s also microencapsulated which tends to mean less irritation, and makes it stable and highly absorbable. As you’ll know by now, retinol is a powerful anti-ageing ingredient that works to reverse the effects of sun damage, reduce fine lines and wrinkles, and improve the skin’s elasticity. It also helps brown spots, uneven skin tone, rough texture and collagen production – in other words, if you’re 30+, it’s time to get on the retinol train! Retinol can be quite drying but the added hyaluronic acid in this product helps to provide deep and lasting hydration. Read this to find out more about how to introduce retinol into your routine. 
Price: R560 for 15ml 
The range also includes an Eye Serum , Recover Cream (for use after aesthetic treatments) and Hand Cream . 
Restylane Skincare is exclusively available in South Africa at Dermastore . Share this:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>ZA</country>
<main_image>http://alldolledup.co.za/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/restylane_1.png</main_image>
</document>
