<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://blogs.arynews.tv/feed</forum>
<forum_title>ARY NEWS</forum_title>
<discussion_title>‘Iran, Pakistan have no option other than to work together’</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://arynews.tv/en/iran-pakistan-have-no-option-other-than-to-work-together/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
‘Iran, Pakistan have no option other than to work together’ By Web Desk August 12, 2016 10:53 Related Articles 
KARACHI: Deputy Foreign Minister of Iran Dr. Seyed Mohammad Kazem Sajjadpour has said that Pakistan and Iran have no other alternative but to work together despite the problems being created by “third parties”. 
Iranian deputy foreign minister made the statement while delivering a lecture at Pakistan Institute of International Affairs. 
He said that the region can be transformed in a better way as per the strategic interests of the two Islamic countries with bilateral cooperation and expanding that cooperation. 
The Iranian diplomat added, “We have no option other than to work together for our security, survival and preservation of our heritage.” 
“We and Pakistan are neighbours. Do we have any other option than to be carefully watching our interests and minimising the impacts of the global trends against our interests? We have no other option.” 
Sajjadpour added that the bilateral ties between Pakistan and Iran should be appreciated. He said that the two countries are “special neighbours”. 
“We are good neighbours with Armenia; but it can’t be compared with Pakistan. We have 15 neighbours but our bonds with Pakistan are unique — regional, civilisational, linguistic, political, economic, strategic bonds, the list goes on. Our bonds need to be taken more seriously; they should be nurtured at this time of transition,” he added. 
Sajjadpour went on to explain the issues prevailing in the world through Ts. 
He said that the first ‘T’ was turmoil. He said that there is turmoil in all levels as well as turmoil in institutions. He said that the exit of Britain from the European Union caused shocks. 
“There is turmoil in mentalities; today politicians have one position, tomorrow they have another,” he said. 
Sajjadpour said that the second T was transition, which is a painful process in the current scenario. 
“There is transition in the global system in many dimensions. There is transition in the concept of power. Is the US powerful? Yes. Can it exert its power? No, military power is not enough. Power-holders are becoming multiple. Now non-state actors are sometimes more powerful than states; ISIS is one of them. Individuals have become powerful. Look at what Edward Snowden did. He challenged a great power, of which he is a citizen. The power locale is also changing,” he said. 
According to the Iranian deputy minister, the third and final T stood for trends of conflicting nature. He said, “Globalisation is everywhere. But also, there is narrow-minded localisation, much lower than tribal mentality. There is purely personal and factional interest along with global interest. There is closeness of the world today, but it is also [growing] apart,” he added. Facebook Comments
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://arynews.tv/en/iran-pakistan-have-no-option-other-than-to-work-together/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0553</post_time>
<username>Web Desk</username>
<post>
‘Iran, Pakistan have no option other than to work together’ By Web Desk August 12, 2016 10:53 Related Articles 
KARACHI: Deputy Foreign Minister of Iran Dr. Seyed Mohammad Kazem Sajjadpour has said that Pakistan and Iran have no other alternative but to work together despite the problems being created by “third parties”. 
Iranian deputy foreign minister made the statement while delivering a lecture at Pakistan Institute of International Affairs. 
He said that the region can be transformed in a better way as per the strategic interests of the two Islamic countries with bilateral cooperation and expanding that cooperation. 
The Iranian diplomat added, “We have no option other than to work together for our security, survival and preservation of our heritage.” 
“We and Pakistan are neighbours. Do we have any other option than to be carefully watching our interests and minimising the impacts of the global trends against our interests? We have no other option.” 
Sajjadpour added that the bilateral ties between Pakistan and Iran should be appreciated. He said that the two countries are “special neighbours”. 
“We are good neighbours with Armenia; but it can’t be compared with Pakistan. We have 15 neighbours but our bonds with Pakistan are unique — regional, civilisational, linguistic, political, economic, strategic bonds, the list goes on. Our bonds need to be taken more seriously; they should be nurtured at this time of transition,” he added. 
Sajjadpour went on to explain the issues prevailing in the world through Ts. 
He said that the first ‘T’ was turmoil. He said that there is turmoil in all levels as well as turmoil in institutions. He said that the exit of Britain from the European Union caused shocks. 
“There is turmoil in mentalities; today politicians have one position, tomorrow they have another,” he said. 
Sajjadpour said that the second T was transition, which is a painful process in the current scenario. 
“There is transition in the global system in many dimensions. There is transition in the concept of power. Is the US powerful? Yes. Can it exert its power? No, military power is not enough. Power-holders are becoming multiple. Now non-state actors are sometimes more powerful than states; ISIS is one of them. Individuals have become powerful. Look at what Edward Snowden did. He challenged a great power, of which he is a citizen. The power locale is also changing,” he said. 
According to the Iranian deputy minister, the third and final T stood for trends of conflicting nature. He said, “Globalisation is everywhere. But also, there is narrow-minded localisation, much lower than tribal mentality. There is purely personal and factional interest along with global interest. There is closeness of the world today, but it is also [growing] apart,” he added. Facebook Comments
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>TV</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
