<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.wfmynews2.com/_/20/109512250/wmfynews2-watercooler</forum>
<forum_title>WFMY - Weird</forum_title>
<discussion_title>MillerCoors Buys Revolver Brewing</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.wfmynews2.com/_/20/109512250/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wfmynews2&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;money&amp;#x2f;millercoors-buys-granbury-based-revolver-brewing&amp;#x2f;295673977</topic_url>
<topic_text>
MillerCoors buys Granbury-based Revolver Brewing Beer Giant Acquires North Texas craft brewery Landon Haaf and Lauren Zakalik, WFAA 10:55   Blood and Honey American Ale from Revolver Brewing. Credit: Richard W. Rodriguez, Star-Telegram CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
Beer giant MillerCoors is making a big move in North Texas. 
Tenth and Blake Beer Company, MillerCoors’ craft and import arm, has agreed to acquire a majority interest in Granbury-based Revolver Brewing. 
Revolver, famous in Texas for its flagship brew, Blood &amp; Honey, is a four-year-old company founded by father-son duo Ron and Rhett Keisler. They’ll continue to operate out of Granbury, according to a press release . 
“We are excited to be joining the Tenth and Blake family, which shares our commitment to brewing great craft beer,” said Rhett Keisler in a statement. “This partnership will allow us to maintain our brewery and operations in Granbury, while providing us with the additional resources to invest in and accelerate the growth of the Revolver brand in Texas.” 
In an interview with News 8, Rhett thought back on how much has changed in those four years. 
&quot;We were digging ditches to hook up water pipes to feed the brewery with the well water we use here, and just trying to put the pieces together in hopes of some day brewing beer,&quot; Keisler said. 
Now, they&apos;re indeed brewing craft beer -- and they&apos;re about to start getting it into the hands of a lot more people. Through the deal with MillerCoors, Keisler and Wood say they&apos;re looking to double capacity at their brewery and increase distribution. 
Since news broke of the deal Thursday, the craft beer community has been thirsty for details. 
Brian Brown, who runs the web site Beer in Big D , says it&apos;s been non-stop. &quot;Texts, emails, private messages, ‘What do you think?’‘Who do you think is next?&apos;&quot; 
Brown said companies like MillerCoors and Anheuser-Busch have been losing market share as craft beer grows in popularity. Moves like this one, he says, allow them to get in on the game. 
&quot;I think we’re just on the cusp of seeing Texas breweries being bought out by big beer,&quot; Brown said. 
Brown says there will be some who dislike the idea of big beer buying the little guys, but Keisler offers this sentiment: &quot;We can&apos;t change who we are,&quot; he said. &quot;We’re Revolver Brewing. We’re out in the country. We’re going to remain who we are. we’re going to continue to brew the same beers using the same recipes with the same people.&quot; 
The release says Revolver will “operate as a separate business unit” from Tenth and Blake. 
Tenth and Blake is already home to popular beer brands like Blue Moon, Leinenkugel, and Saint Archer. Earlier this year, it added two more craft breweries in Georgia’s Terrapin Beer Company and Oregon’s Hop Valley Brewing Company. 
“We have tremendous respect for the quality and innovation that Revolver Brewing has brought to the Texas craft community and are thrilled to have such a terrific team and portfolio join Tenth and Blake,” said Scott Whitley, president and CEO of Tenth and Blake, in a statement. “Our main priority will be to work with the Revolver team to support its continued success and make sure its beer is enjoyed by even more consumers in Texas.” 
No terms for MillerCoors&apos; acquisition of Revolver were immediately announced. The transaction is set to be complete in the third quarter of 2016, according to the release. 
%
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.wfmynews2.com/_/20/109512250/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wfmynews2&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;money&amp;#x2f;millercoors-buys-granbury-based-revolver-brewing&amp;#x2f;295673977</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0411</post_time>
<username>Landon Haaf</username>
<post>
MillerCoors buys Granbury-based Revolver Brewing Beer Giant Acquires North Texas craft brewery Landon Haaf and Lauren Zakalik, WFAA 10:55   Blood and Honey American Ale from Revolver Brewing. Credit: Richard W. Rodriguez, Star-Telegram CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
Beer giant MillerCoors is making a big move in North Texas. 
Tenth and Blake Beer Company, MillerCoors’ craft and import arm, has agreed to acquire a majority interest in Granbury-based Revolver Brewing. 
Revolver, famous in Texas for its flagship brew, Blood &amp; Honey, is a four-year-old company founded by father-son duo Ron and Rhett Keisler. They’ll continue to operate out of Granbury, according to a press release . 
“We are excited to be joining the Tenth and Blake family, which shares our commitment to brewing great craft beer,” said Rhett Keisler in a statement. “This partnership will allow us to maintain our brewery and operations in Granbury, while providing us with the additional resources to invest in and accelerate the growth of the Revolver brand in Texas.” 
In an interview with News 8, Rhett thought back on how much has changed in those four years. 
&quot;We were digging ditches to hook up water pipes to feed the brewery with the well water we use here, and just trying to put the pieces together in hopes of some day brewing beer,&quot; Keisler said. 
Now, they&apos;re indeed brewing craft beer -- and they&apos;re about to start getting it into the hands of a lot more people. Through the deal with MillerCoors, Keisler and Wood say they&apos;re looking to double capacity at their brewery and increase distribution. 
Since news broke of the deal Thursday, the craft beer community has been thirsty for details. 
Brian Brown, who runs the web site Beer in Big D , says it&apos;s been non-stop. &quot;Texts, emails, private messages, ‘What do you think?’‘Who do you think is next?&apos;&quot; 
Brown said companies like MillerCoors and Anheuser-Busch have been losing market share as craft beer grows in popularity. Moves like this one, he says, allow them to get in on the game. 
&quot;I think we’re just on the cusp of seeing Texas breweries being bought out by big beer,&quot; Brown said. 
Brown says there will be some who dislike the idea of big beer buying the little guys, but Keisler offers this sentiment: &quot;We can&apos;t change who we are,&quot; he said. &quot;We’re Revolver Brewing. We’re out in the country. We’re going to remain who we are. we’re going to continue to brew the same beers using the same recipes with the same people.&quot; 
The release says Revolver will “operate as a separate business unit” from Tenth and Blake. 
Tenth and Blake is already home to popular beer brands like Blue Moon, Leinenkugel, and Saint Archer. Earlier this year, it added two more craft breweries in Georgia’s Terrapin Beer Company and Oregon’s Hop Valley Brewing Company. 
“We have tremendous respect for the quality and innovation that Revolver Brewing has brought to the Texas craft community and are thrilled to have such a terrific team and portfolio join Tenth and Blake,” said Scott Whitley, president and CEO of Tenth and Blake, in a statement. “Our main priority will be to work with the Revolver team to support its continued success and make sure its beer is enjoyed by even more consumers in Texas.” 
No terms for MillerCoors&apos; acquisition of Revolver were immediately announced. The transaction is set to be complete in the third quarter of 2016, according to the release. 
%
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.wfaa.com/photo/2016/08/11/Revolver_8_1470932797602_5073239_ver1.0_640_360.jpeg</main_image>
</document>
