<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.somersetcountygazette.co.uk/news/rss/</forum>
<forum_title>Somerset County Gazette | News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Firepool development &apos;won&apos;t increase flood risks&apos;</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.somersetcountygazette.co.uk/news/14677272.Firepool_development__won_t_increase_flood_risks_/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Have you got a local story, picture or video you would like to send to us? Send it to us now for a chance to get published. Services Firepool development &apos;won&apos;t increase flood risks&apos; Firepool development &apos;won&apos;t increase flood risks&apos; 0 comments 
HOMEOWNERS and businesses near Taunton town centre have been promised flooding in their area won’t be worse once the Firepool development is built. 
As reported in last week’s County Gazette, there are fears that homes and premises could be underwater during heavy rain due to a scheme to cut flooding risk on the homes, offices, shops and leisure facilities at the former livestock market. 
Developer St Modwen plans to raise the height of Firepool to combat the possibility of flooding there, but causing overflow from a stream to be diverted to North Town. 
Planning manager Mark Thorne said: “Further to additional flood risk analysis and reporting conducted by St Modwen, the Environment Agency is satisfied the Firepool development can be progressed safely and as a result doesn’t object to the proposed development. 
“The Firepool proposals won’t cause the River Tone defences to overtop and would therefore not increase the probability or likelihood of flooding to North Town. 
“Notwithstanding this, a longer-term permanent solution to reducing existing flood risks in Taunton is currently being developed by the EA and Taunton Deane Borough Council will address long-term flood risk. 
“In the event Firepool is constructed in advance of these works being completed, St Modwen will enter into an agreement, in line with EA recommendations, to provide interim temporary flood defences in key locations along the River Tone frontage so that the potential effects of flooding in North Town aren’t made worse.” 
A planning application for Firepool outlines how temporary steel flood defences could be deployed to defend homes in North Town, although they would not protect commercial properties. 
A district council spokesman said several flood prevention measures have been installed since devastating floods in 1960 left large swathes of Taunton under water, with more works proposed in the future. 
She said: “With the continued impacts of climate change, Studies show that we can expect more frequent and severe weather events. 
“If no action is taken, there is an increased risk that the River Tone and tributaries will over-top the existing defences and flow into the North Town area.” 
She added: “For the Firepool site, studies show clearly that the raising of land at the site for redevelopment purposes won’t cause any increase in the scale or frequency of over-topping of flood defences in Taunton, which are already at risk in the event of the ‘worst case’ flooding scenario. 
“Neither would development at Firepool increase the probability or likelihood of flooding to the North Town area of Taunton.” 
Among dozens who have written to the council expressing their concerns at the potential knock-on effect of raising Firepool, Sarah Burrows, of Clarence Street, said: “We’d expect a permanent solution to the flooding risk before there is any development at Firepool. “The temporary flood barriers wouldn’t be sufficient to cope with the increased flood risk.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.somersetcountygazette.co.uk/news/14677272.Firepool_development__won_t_increase_flood_risks_/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0510</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Have you got a local story, picture or video you would like to send to us? Send it to us now for a chance to get published. Services Firepool development &apos;won&apos;t increase flood risks&apos; Firepool development &apos;won&apos;t increase flood risks&apos; 0 comments 
HOMEOWNERS and businesses near Taunton town centre have been promised flooding in their area won’t be worse once the Firepool development is built. 
As reported in last week’s County Gazette, there are fears that homes and premises could be underwater during heavy rain due to a scheme to cut flooding risk on the homes, offices, shops and leisure facilities at the former livestock market. 
Developer St Modwen plans to raise the height of Firepool to combat the possibility of flooding there, but causing overflow from a stream to be diverted to North Town. 
Planning manager Mark Thorne said: “Further to additional flood risk analysis and reporting conducted by St Modwen, the Environment Agency is satisfied the Firepool development can be progressed safely and as a result doesn’t object to the proposed development. 
“The Firepool proposals won’t cause the River Tone defences to overtop and would therefore not increase the probability or likelihood of flooding to North Town. 
“Notwithstanding this, a longer-term permanent solution to reducing existing flood risks in Taunton is currently being developed by the EA and Taunton Deane Borough Council will address long-term flood risk. 
“In the event Firepool is constructed in advance of these works being completed, St Modwen will enter into an agreement, in line with EA recommendations, to provide interim temporary flood defences in key locations along the River Tone frontage so that the potential effects of flooding in North Town aren’t made worse.” 
A planning application for Firepool outlines how temporary steel flood defences could be deployed to defend homes in North Town, although they would not protect commercial properties. 
A district council spokesman said several flood prevention measures have been installed since devastating floods in 1960 left large swathes of Taunton under water, with more works proposed in the future. 
She said: “With the continued impacts of climate change, Studies show that we can expect more frequent and severe weather events. 
“If no action is taken, there is an increased risk that the River Tone and tributaries will over-top the existing defences and flow into the North Town area.” 
She added: “For the Firepool site, studies show clearly that the raising of land at the site for redevelopment purposes won’t cause any increase in the scale or frequency of over-topping of flood defences in Taunton, which are already at risk in the event of the ‘worst case’ flooding scenario. 
“Neither would development at Firepool increase the probability or likelihood of flooding to the North Town area of Taunton.” 
Among dozens who have written to the council expressing their concerns at the potential knock-on effect of raising Firepool, Sarah Burrows, of Clarence Street, said: “We’d expect a permanent solution to the flooding risk before there is any development at Firepool. “The temporary flood barriers wouldn’t be sufficient to cope with the increased flood risk.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://www.somersetcountygazette.co.uk/resources/images/4183470/</main_image>
</document>
