<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>It’s time to prepare kids to return to class</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Editorials/Its_time_to_prepare_kids_to_return_to_class.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
It’s time to prepare kids to return to class commentary /// Back to school 
A TV ad for school supplies shows parents dancing and jumping for joy as the narrator declares, “They’re going back!” 
Yes, it’s time for Moorpark students to return to school. And there are no shortage of tips and tricks to help your children prepare for success both emotionally and practicably. 
Here are some suggestions for parents to help adjust in their transition back to school: 
Students will be bringing home numerous documents: health forms, emergency contact forms, school and classroom rules, course syllabuses, etc. 
Please help your child’s teacher by completing these documents in a timely manner. In many cases, students can earn points by promptly returning these items. 
Want to know more about your child’s teacher and all the great things going on in the classroom? Plan on attending Back to School Night, scheduled during the first two weeks of school for all the elementary schools. 
Middle schools will meet Sept. 1. Moorpark and Community High will both meet Sept. 24. The High School at Moorpark College will meet Aug. 31. Check your school’s webpage for exact dates and times. 
Research shows that getting adequate sleep before the big day is beneficial for students and maybe even more so for parents. 
Help your child and yourself by laying out clothes and backpacks the night before in order to avoid having to rush in the morning. 
And if you drive your child to school, give yourself extra time these first weeks. Please observe the speed limit in school zones and follow the directions of teachers and campus aides in student loading areas. Patience and courtesy go a long way towards ensuring the safety and staff. 
Moorpark teachers have already been back in their classrooms preparing for another great school year. They share a common goal of providing exceptional educational experiences for students and being responsive to the community they serve. 
Welcome back!
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Editorials/Its_time_to_prepare_kids_to_return_to_class.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0219</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
It’s time to prepare kids to return to class commentary /// Back to school 
A TV ad for school supplies shows parents dancing and jumping for joy as the narrator declares, “They’re going back!” 
Yes, it’s time for Moorpark students to return to school. And there are no shortage of tips and tricks to help your children prepare for success both emotionally and practicably. 
Here are some suggestions for parents to help adjust in their transition back to school: 
Students will be bringing home numerous documents: health forms, emergency contact forms, school and classroom rules, course syllabuses, etc. 
Please help your child’s teacher by completing these documents in a timely manner. In many cases, students can earn points by promptly returning these items. 
Want to know more about your child’s teacher and all the great things going on in the classroom? Plan on attending Back to School Night, scheduled during the first two weeks of school for all the elementary schools. 
Middle schools will meet Sept. 1. Moorpark and Community High will both meet Sept. 24. The High School at Moorpark College will meet Aug. 31. Check your school’s webpage for exact dates and times. 
Research shows that getting adequate sleep before the big day is beneficial for students and maybe even more so for parents. 
Help your child and yourself by laying out clothes and backpacks the night before in order to avoid having to rush in the morning. 
And if you drive your child to school, give yourself extra time these first weeks. Please observe the speed limit in school zones and follow the directions of teachers and campus aides in student loading areas. Patience and courtesy go a long way towards ensuring the safety and staff. 
Moorpark teachers have already been back in their classrooms preparing for another great school year. They share a common goal of providing exceptional educational experiences for students and being responsive to the community they serve. 
Welcome back!
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/9p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
