<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Hearts of champions</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Schools/Hearts_of_champions.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Water polo team wins gold at nationals despite not having a pool in town By Caitlin Trude 
WINNERS!— The Moorpark-based U-12 Sharks Water Polo team took first place out of 24 teams from across the country at the USA National Water Polo Junior Olympics held at Stanford University last month. Courtesy of Moorpark Sharks Water Polo Club The boys of the Sharks Water Polo team didn’t need to travel to Rio to strike gold this summer. 
The Moorpark-based U-12 took first place out of 24 teams from across the country at the USA National Water Polo Junior Olympics, a four-day tournament held at Stanford University late last month. 
The win marked the team’s first gold medal, a big improvement over last year’s 13th-place finish. 
Team members are: Jorge Arevalo ( 12), Bryce Biglin (12), Boaz Biglin (10), William Brown (10), Theo Chambers (9), Andrew Crockatt (12), Riley Crockatt (11), Gunner Lanquist (12), Benjamin Marrache (11), Tyler White (12), Sean O’Shea (12) and Liam Escusa (12). 
Sharks head coach Gary O’Brien said it was the dedication of both the players and their parents that made the big win possible. 
“Our U-12 team has had an amazing bonding year,” he said. “Many parents and players rallied and (the parents) brought their (sons) to training every week no matter what, and the team began to gel months prior to Junior Olympics.” 
What made their triumph even more special, he said, is that the Sharks managed to beat out the other teams without having a pool to call their own. 
Beginning in 2012, the Sharks used the pool at Body Xchange Sports Club in Moorpark. Last August they learned their contract with the gym would end, leaving the water polo and swim teams to seek out new practice facilities. 
The Sharks have held their practices at Westlake High School since leaving the sports club. 
The setback did not keep the team from training hard, O’Brien said. 
“The dedication and hard work the young athletes put in is a true indication of their performance and accomplishments at Junior Olympics,” the coach said. “I look forward to seeing what they can do in the years to come.” 
Edward Chambers, a father of three Sharks athletes, was proud to see the team get the gold. 
“They had been through so much, not having a real consistent place to call home,” he said. “I never imagined that they were going to rise to that level of competition to win that tournament.” 
Although driving his sons from Moorpark to Westlake and back several times each week was sometimes a challenge, he said, it’s been well worth it. 
“When the boys lost their pool, they became more determined to pull together to fight for what they wanted,” Chambers said. “In the end, it clearly showed they were dedicated to their sport.” 
His youngest son, Theo, a member of the U-12 team, tried to describe his elation at winning. 
“I just felt really, really good,” the 9-year-old said. “I couldn’t even explain how I felt.” 
Theo’s father hopes the success of the team will encourage city leaders and the school district to continue efforts to build a community pool. 
“When we bring our pool to (Moorpark High School), there’s going to be a lot of continued water polo success,” Chambers said. 
Although the Sharks team has set the bar high for next year’s Junior Olympics, Theo is confident his team can win the gold again with more practice. 
“Practice is pretty hard work, but it’s worth it,” he said. “We’ll get more advanced by the next year and we’ll probably be undefeated again.” 
Teammate Gunner Lanquist said at first it was difficult to adjust to a new practice location, but the Sharks quickly got into the swing of things. 
“After a couple months at (the Westlake) pool, we kind of got used to it like it was no big deal,” he said. “After months of coming together . . . I believed that we would get first place (at Junior Olympics).” 
Like Theo, Gunnar expects the Sharks will be just as successful at next year’s tournament. 
“ I’m looking forward to playing new teams and different people,” he said. 
Founded in 2005, the year-round Sharks aquatics program started out with about 20 swimmers and now numbers about 70. 
For more information about the Sharks Water Polo Club, visit www.sharkswaterpolo.com .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Schools/Hearts_of_champions.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
Water polo team wins gold at nationals despite not having a pool in town By Caitlin Trude 
WINNERS!— The Moorpark-based U-12 Sharks Water Polo team took first place out of 24 teams from across the country at the USA National Water Polo Junior Olympics held at Stanford University last month. Courtesy of Moorpark Sharks Water Polo Club The boys of the Sharks Water Polo team didn’t need to travel to Rio to strike gold this summer. 
The Moorpark-based U-12 took first place out of 24 teams from across the country at the USA National Water Polo Junior Olympics, a four-day tournament held at Stanford University late last month. 
The win marked the team’s first gold medal, a big improvement over last year’s 13th-place finish. 
Team members are: Jorge Arevalo ( 12), Bryce Biglin (12), Boaz Biglin (10), William Brown (10), Theo Chambers (9), Andrew Crockatt (12), Riley Crockatt (11), Gunner Lanquist (12), Benjamin Marrache (11), Tyler White (12), Sean O’Shea (12) and Liam Escusa (12). 
Sharks head coach Gary O’Brien said it was the dedication of both the players and their parents that made the big win possible. 
“Our U-12 team has had an amazing bonding year,” he said. “Many parents and players rallied and (the parents) brought their (sons) to training every week no matter what, and the team began to gel months prior to Junior Olympics.” 
What made their triumph even more special, he said, is that the Sharks managed to beat out the other teams without having a pool to call their own. 
Beginning in 2012, the Sharks used the pool at Body Xchange Sports Club in Moorpark. Last August they learned their contract with the gym would end, leaving the water polo and swim teams to seek out new practice facilities. 
The Sharks have held their practices at Westlake High School since leaving the sports club. 
The setback did not keep the team from training hard, O’Brien said. 
“The dedication and hard work the young athletes put in is a true indication of their performance and accomplishments at Junior Olympics,” the coach said. “I look forward to seeing what they can do in the years to come.” 
Edward Chambers, a father of three Sharks athletes, was proud to see the team get the gold. 
“They had been through so much, not having a real consistent place to call home,” he said. “I never imagined that they were going to rise to that level of competition to win that tournament.” 
Although driving his sons from Moorpark to Westlake and back several times each week was sometimes a challenge, he said, it’s been well worth it. 
“When the boys lost their pool, they became more determined to pull together to fight for what they wanted,” Chambers said. “In the end, it clearly showed they were dedicated to their sport.” 
His youngest son, Theo, a member of the U-12 team, tried to describe his elation at winning. 
“I just felt really, really good,” the 9-year-old said. “I couldn’t even explain how I felt.” 
Theo’s father hopes the success of the team will encourage city leaders and the school district to continue efforts to build a community pool. 
“When we bring our pool to (Moorpark High School), there’s going to be a lot of continued water polo success,” Chambers said. 
Although the Sharks team has set the bar high for next year’s Junior Olympics, Theo is confident his team can win the gold again with more practice. 
“Practice is pretty hard work, but it’s worth it,” he said. “We’ll get more advanced by the next year and we’ll probably be undefeated again.” 
Teammate Gunner Lanquist said at first it was difficult to adjust to a new practice location, but the Sharks quickly got into the swing of things. 
“After a couple months at (the Westlake) pool, we kind of got used to it like it was no big deal,” he said. “After months of coming together . . . I believed that we would get first place (at Junior Olympics).” 
Like Theo, Gunnar expects the Sharks will be just as successful at next year’s tournament. 
“ I’m looking forward to playing new teams and different people,” he said. 
Founded in 2005, the year-round Sharks aquatics program started out with about 20 swimmers and now numbers about 70. 
For more information about the Sharks Water Polo Club, visit www.sharkswaterpolo.com .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/33p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
