<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mariachi opera es bueno</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/On_The_Town/Mariachi_opera_es_bueno.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
By Hector Gonzalez hector@theacorn 
BIG PRODUCTION—The Moorpark College Foundation will host “El Bracero,” a mariachi opera, featuring Mariachi Aguilas de Oxnard at 7:30 p.m. Fri., Aug. 26 at the college’s Performing Arts Center. Photo courtesy Marie Gregorio-Oviedo Backed by a popular local mariachi and staged before audiences sprinkled with farm workers and their extended families, Miguel Orozco’s production of “El Bracero,” a mariachi opera, played to a sold-out audience and two standing-room-only encore performances earlier this year in Oxnard. 
“El Bracero’s” stylized plot uses Mexican ballads to humanize the story of the workers who came here by the train-loads during the labor shortage of World War II, some settling near the fields of Oxnard. 
After Oxnard, “El Bracero” played a standing-room-only performance in March in Santa Paula and then sold out again at East Los Angeles College for Cinco de Mayo. 
It connected, Orozco said. 
“It was multi-generational,” the Camarillo film producer and marketer said. “You had abuelita (grandmother), tia (aunt), mom, and dad. You had multi-generations going to this play. The bracero program has deep roots in the community, so practically everyone in the Latino community has a bracero in their family. What’s awesome is that in attendance, we also had former braceros as well.” 
Orozco licensed and adapted the show, basing it on an outdoor operetta written by his friend, playwright Rosalinda 
Verde of Visalia. 
Now “El Bracero” is coming to Moorpark. 
This month, the one-act drama will launch Moorpark 
College’s yearlong 50th anniversary celebration at 7:30 p.m. Fri., Aug. 26 at the college’s performing arts center at 7075 Campus Road. For tickets, call (805) 553-4760 or go to www.moorparkcollege.edu/community/foundation/events . 
“We’re delighted to bring ‘El Bracero’ to Moorpark College,” college President Luis Sanchez said in a release. “It kicks off a year of special events leading to the 50th anniversary gala on Aug. 26, 2017, at the Reagan Library.” 
Opened Sept. 11, 1967, on 134 acres of former farmland on the city’s eastern boundary, Moorpark College today has around 14,500 students, nearly 60 percent of them white and less than 20 percent Latino, a figure that has stayed constant for at least the past five years. 
“Moorpark, it’s a different location than what we’ve done,” Orozco said. “This will be the ultimate test for the play. It’s a different audience, so now let’s see how it translates. Will it bring in a large percentage of non-Latinos? That’s what we’re hoping.” 
College scholarships for high school students are riding on the box office draw for “El Bracero” in Moorpark. 
“All the money we raise goes to scholarships,” Orozco said. “In Oxnard, we were fortunate to have the college foundation partner with us, and they matched the amount we raised.” 
Presented in Spanish with English subtitles projected on a screen, the opera’s story retraces a grandfather’s recollections of his journey north as a bracero, as told by the old man to his grandson for a school project. 
“The grandfather in the play becomes the grandson, who then goes through this journey,” Orozco said. 
Filled with singing, traditional dances by Ballet Folklorico Mestizo and a musical score performed by Mariachi Aguilas de Oxnard, one of Southern California’s premier mariachis, “El Bracero” features 26 participants, several scene changes and fantasy sequences. 
In adapting Verde’s play, Orozco said, he added more lighting and a couple of new scenes that tie together the show’s beginning and ending. 
“At the end, it comes full circle,” he said. “We embellished the ending, where the last scene is given more of a conclusion.” 
In the cast for the upcoming performance will be students from Oxnard and Moorpark colleges. Many of the stagehands as well as the stage director are Oxnard College theater arts students getting their first crack at a real production. 
It took months for Orozco to train the inexperienced stagecraft workers and weeks of rehearsals with the musicians and actors to pull off the show’s successful debut in Oxnard, he said. 
But when the curtain falls at the Moorpark College auditorium it will be the last bow for “El Bracero” in Ventura County. 
Orozco is moving on. 
His next project is a collaboration with “El Bracero” musical director Juan Carlos Ozuna, a graduate of Adolfo Camarillo High School. It’s a mariachi musical called “Ay, Chihuahua!” 
Written by Orozco and inspired in part by playwright Lin-Manuel Miranda’s “Hamilton” and Rogers and Hammerstein’s “Oklahoma,” the musical is Orozco’s latest attempt “at bringing culture and history back to the community through entertainment.” 
Several sponsors are already on board. Casting is set to start next month, and Orozco plans to stage the play in early December “somewhere in Oxnard,” he said. 
“It’s set in the 1960s, during the golden era of mariachi music. It’s about a man traveling through Mexico en route to Juarez when his car breaks down in Cuauhtémoc, Chihuahua. He ends up learning about the three cultures that make up Cuauhtémoc: the Mennonite, the Tarahumara and the mestizo cultures,” Orozco said. “And there’s also a love story involved. I think it’s going to be very entertaining.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/On_The_Town/Mariachi_opera_es_bueno.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
By Hector Gonzalez hector@theacorn 
BIG PRODUCTION—The Moorpark College Foundation will host “El Bracero,” a mariachi opera, featuring Mariachi Aguilas de Oxnard at 7:30 p.m. Fri., Aug. 26 at the college’s Performing Arts Center. Photo courtesy Marie Gregorio-Oviedo Backed by a popular local mariachi and staged before audiences sprinkled with farm workers and their extended families, Miguel Orozco’s production of “El Bracero,” a mariachi opera, played to a sold-out audience and two standing-room-only encore performances earlier this year in Oxnard. 
“El Bracero’s” stylized plot uses Mexican ballads to humanize the story of the workers who came here by the train-loads during the labor shortage of World War II, some settling near the fields of Oxnard. 
After Oxnard, “El Bracero” played a standing-room-only performance in March in Santa Paula and then sold out again at East Los Angeles College for Cinco de Mayo. 
It connected, Orozco said. 
“It was multi-generational,” the Camarillo film producer and marketer said. “You had abuelita (grandmother), tia (aunt), mom, and dad. You had multi-generations going to this play. The bracero program has deep roots in the community, so practically everyone in the Latino community has a bracero in their family. What’s awesome is that in attendance, we also had former braceros as well.” 
Orozco licensed and adapted the show, basing it on an outdoor operetta written by his friend, playwright Rosalinda 
Verde of Visalia. 
Now “El Bracero” is coming to Moorpark. 
This month, the one-act drama will launch Moorpark 
College’s yearlong 50th anniversary celebration at 7:30 p.m. Fri., Aug. 26 at the college’s performing arts center at 7075 Campus Road. For tickets, call (805) 553-4760 or go to www.moorparkcollege.edu/community/foundation/events . 
“We’re delighted to bring ‘El Bracero’ to Moorpark College,” college President Luis Sanchez said in a release. “It kicks off a year of special events leading to the 50th anniversary gala on Aug. 26, 2017, at the Reagan Library.” 
Opened Sept. 11, 1967, on 134 acres of former farmland on the city’s eastern boundary, Moorpark College today has around 14,500 students, nearly 60 percent of them white and less than 20 percent Latino, a figure that has stayed constant for at least the past five years. 
“Moorpark, it’s a different location than what we’ve done,” Orozco said. “This will be the ultimate test for the play. It’s a different audience, so now let’s see how it translates. Will it bring in a large percentage of non-Latinos? That’s what we’re hoping.” 
College scholarships for high school students are riding on the box office draw for “El Bracero” in Moorpark. 
“All the money we raise goes to scholarships,” Orozco said. “In Oxnard, we were fortunate to have the college foundation partner with us, and they matched the amount we raised.” 
Presented in Spanish with English subtitles projected on a screen, the opera’s story retraces a grandfather’s recollections of his journey north as a bracero, as told by the old man to his grandson for a school project. 
“The grandfather in the play becomes the grandson, who then goes through this journey,” Orozco said. 
Filled with singing, traditional dances by Ballet Folklorico Mestizo and a musical score performed by Mariachi Aguilas de Oxnard, one of Southern California’s premier mariachis, “El Bracero” features 26 participants, several scene changes and fantasy sequences. 
In adapting Verde’s play, Orozco said, he added more lighting and a couple of new scenes that tie together the show’s beginning and ending. 
“At the end, it comes full circle,” he said. “We embellished the ending, where the last scene is given more of a conclusion.” 
In the cast for the upcoming performance will be students from Oxnard and Moorpark colleges. Many of the stagehands as well as the stage director are Oxnard College theater arts students getting their first crack at a real production. 
It took months for Orozco to train the inexperienced stagecraft workers and weeks of rehearsals with the musicians and actors to pull off the show’s successful debut in Oxnard, he said. 
But when the curtain falls at the Moorpark College auditorium it will be the last bow for “El Bracero” in Ventura County. 
Orozco is moving on. 
His next project is a collaboration with “El Bracero” musical director Juan Carlos Ozuna, a graduate of Adolfo Camarillo High School. It’s a mariachi musical called “Ay, Chihuahua!” 
Written by Orozco and inspired in part by playwright Lin-Manuel Miranda’s “Hamilton” and Rogers and Hammerstein’s “Oklahoma,” the musical is Orozco’s latest attempt “at bringing culture and history back to the community through entertainment.” 
Several sponsors are already on board. Casting is set to start next month, and Orozco plans to stage the play in early December “somewhere in Oxnard,” he said. 
“It’s set in the 1960s, during the golden era of mariachi music. It’s about a man traveling through Mexico en route to Juarez when his car breaks down in Cuauhtémoc, Chihuahua. He ends up learning about the three cultures that make up Cuauhtémoc: the Mennonite, the Tarahumara and the mestizo cultures,” Orozco said. “And there’s also a love story involved. I think it’s going to be very entertaining.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/30p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
