<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.record-bee.com/section?template=RSS&amp;profile=4005426&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>RSS Feed from Lake County Record-Bee: http://www.record-bee.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Group says Brown, Dems got $9.8M from energy companies for favorable legislation</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.record-bee.com/article/NQ/20160811/NEWS/160819973</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Group says Brown, Dems got $9.8M from energy companies for favorable legislation By Kevin Smith, Southern California News Group Posted: # Comments 
SANTA MONICA &gt;&gt; Twenty-six energy companies with business before the state donated nearly $10million to Gov.Jerry Brown and the California Democratic Party over the past eightyears — donations that often were made within days or weeks of winning favors. 
That’s the contention of “Brown’s Dirty Hands” a report released this week by the SantaMonica-based public interest group Consumer Watchdog. 
Those 26companies included California’s three major investor-owned utilities — Edison International, the parent company of Southern California Edison, Pacific Gas &amp; Electric and Sempra Energy, the parent of Southern California Gas and SanDiego Gas &amp; Electric — which collectively contributed nearly $6million of the more than $9.8million that was donated. 
Liza Tucker, who authored the report, said the information raises “troubling questions about whether quid pro quos are routine for this administration.” 
An extensive review of campaign records, publicly released emails and other documents at PUCPapers.org, court filings and media reports shows that Brown allegedly intervened in regulatory decisions favoring companies in the energy industry, Consumer Watchdog said. 
The report alleges that Brown and his operatives have used the California Democratic Party as “a political slush fund” to receive contributions from unpopular energy companies in amounts greater than permitted to his candidate committee. The group has logged its report as an official complaint with the Fair Political Practices Commission. 
“The report really paints a troubling picture,” ConsumerWatchdog President Jamie Court said when the findings were unveiled at a press conference on Wednesday. “There are a couple of years left in this administration and Gov.Brown needs to do a little housecleaning in his office and an inventory check on what his priorities are.” 
Evan Westrup, a spokesman for the governor’s office, disputed the information. 
“The governor’s leadership on climate is unmatched — these claims are downright cuckoo,” he said via email. 
Westrup noted that Brown has set a variety of aggressive climate goals, including a 50percent reduction of petroleum use in cars and trucks by 2030, putting 1.5million zero-emission vehicles on California roads by 2025, and a 40percent reduction in greenhouse gas emissions by 2030, among others. 
Court acknowledged that Brown has spoken out about the negative impacts of climate change. But the Consumer Watchdog study, he said, clearly shows that between 2011 and 2014, energy companies tracked in the report donated $4.4million to the DemocraticParty, and the DemocraticParty gave $4.7million to Brown’s re-election. Advertisement 
Southern California Edison was cited as an example. The Rosemead-based utility donated $130,000 to the California Democratic Party on March26, 2013. That was the same day Public Utilities Commission President Michael Peevey cut a deal with an SCE executive in a Warsaw, Poland, hotel room to make ratepayers — not shareholders — cover 70percent of the $4.7billion cost to close the fatally flawed SanOnofre nuclear plant, according to Consumer Watchdog. 
Peevey is now under criminal investigation for conspiring to obstruct justice by illegally engaging in and concealing ex parte communications, and by inappropriately interfering with the SanOnofre settlement process by pushing SCE to fund $25million of greenhouse gas research at UCLA in exchange for the deal, the report said. 
Edison International issued a statement in response to the report. 
“Like many companies, Edison International exercises its civic responsibility and participates in the political process by supporting candidates and committees in both major parties,” the company said. “All political contributions comply with applicable campaign finance laws and the company’s political contributions policy, and are fully disclosed.” 
Edison further noted that the Center for Political Accountability, a nonpartisan, nonprofit organization dedicated to bringing transparency to corporate political spending, last year placed Edison in the top two rankings among S&amp;P500 companies for disclosure and accountability. 
Consumer Watchdog additionally alleges that Chevron donated $135,000 to the California DemocraticParty the same day lawmakers exempted a common method of well stimulation from legislation meant to regulate fracking. 
Officials with Chevron declined to comment on the report. 
The report also alleges that power plant developer NRG wasn’t a Brown donor until the company cut a “sweetheart deal” with the PUC to settle the state’s case over its 2001electricity price manipulation, touted as a win by the governor’s office. 
Rather than paying back the state, the company was allowed to spend $100million of its $120million fine to install electric vehicle charging stations. And two months later, NRG began donations to Brown, his causes and his party that would come to $105,000, the report said. A lawsuit against the PUC, filed by electric charging station competitor Ecotality, called the deal illegal because it awarded a monopoly to an out-of-state company. 
NRG didn’t respond to requests for comment.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.record-bee.com/article/NQ/20160811/NEWS/160819973</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0534</post_time>
<username>Kevin Smith Southern California News Group</username>
<post>
Group says Brown, Dems got $9.8M from energy companies for favorable legislation By Kevin Smith, Southern California News Group Posted: # Comments 
SANTA MONICA &gt;&gt; Twenty-six energy companies with business before the state donated nearly $10million to Gov.Jerry Brown and the California Democratic Party over the past eightyears — donations that often were made within days or weeks of winning favors. 
That’s the contention of “Brown’s Dirty Hands” a report released this week by the SantaMonica-based public interest group Consumer Watchdog. 
Those 26companies included California’s three major investor-owned utilities — Edison International, the parent company of Southern California Edison, Pacific Gas &amp; Electric and Sempra Energy, the parent of Southern California Gas and SanDiego Gas &amp; Electric — which collectively contributed nearly $6million of the more than $9.8million that was donated. 
Liza Tucker, who authored the report, said the information raises “troubling questions about whether quid pro quos are routine for this administration.” 
An extensive review of campaign records, publicly released emails and other documents at PUCPapers.org, court filings and media reports shows that Brown allegedly intervened in regulatory decisions favoring companies in the energy industry, Consumer Watchdog said. 
The report alleges that Brown and his operatives have used the California Democratic Party as “a political slush fund” to receive contributions from unpopular energy companies in amounts greater than permitted to his candidate committee. The group has logged its report as an official complaint with the Fair Political Practices Commission. 
“The report really paints a troubling picture,” ConsumerWatchdog President Jamie Court said when the findings were unveiled at a press conference on Wednesday. “There are a couple of years left in this administration and Gov.Brown needs to do a little housecleaning in his office and an inventory check on what his priorities are.” 
Evan Westrup, a spokesman for the governor’s office, disputed the information. 
“The governor’s leadership on climate is unmatched — these claims are downright cuckoo,” he said via email. 
Westrup noted that Brown has set a variety of aggressive climate goals, including a 50percent reduction of petroleum use in cars and trucks by 2030, putting 1.5million zero-emission vehicles on California roads by 2025, and a 40percent reduction in greenhouse gas emissions by 2030, among others. 
Court acknowledged that Brown has spoken out about the negative impacts of climate change. But the Consumer Watchdog study, he said, clearly shows that between 2011 and 2014, energy companies tracked in the report donated $4.4million to the DemocraticParty, and the DemocraticParty gave $4.7million to Brown’s re-election. Advertisement 
Southern California Edison was cited as an example. The Rosemead-based utility donated $130,000 to the California Democratic Party on March26, 2013. That was the same day Public Utilities Commission President Michael Peevey cut a deal with an SCE executive in a Warsaw, Poland, hotel room to make ratepayers — not shareholders — cover 70percent of the $4.7billion cost to close the fatally flawed SanOnofre nuclear plant, according to Consumer Watchdog. 
Peevey is now under criminal investigation for conspiring to obstruct justice by illegally engaging in and concealing ex parte communications, and by inappropriately interfering with the SanOnofre settlement process by pushing SCE to fund $25million of greenhouse gas research at UCLA in exchange for the deal, the report said. 
Edison International issued a statement in response to the report. 
“Like many companies, Edison International exercises its civic responsibility and participates in the political process by supporting candidates and committees in both major parties,” the company said. “All political contributions comply with applicable campaign finance laws and the company’s political contributions policy, and are fully disclosed.” 
Edison further noted that the Center for Political Accountability, a nonpartisan, nonprofit organization dedicated to bringing transparency to corporate political spending, last year placed Edison in the top two rankings among S&amp;P500 companies for disclosure and accountability. 
Consumer Watchdog additionally alleges that Chevron donated $135,000 to the California DemocraticParty the same day lawmakers exempted a common method of well stimulation from legislation meant to regulate fracking. 
Officials with Chevron declined to comment on the report. 
The report also alleges that power plant developer NRG wasn’t a Brown donor until the company cut a “sweetheart deal” with the PUC to settle the state’s case over its 2001electricity price manipulation, touted as a win by the governor’s office. 
Rather than paying back the state, the company was allowed to spend $100million of its $120million fine to install electric vehicle charging stations. And two months later, NRG began donations to Brown, his causes and his party that would come to $105,000, the report said. A lawsuit against the PUC, filed by electric charging station competitor Ecotality, called the deal illegal because it awarded a monopoly to an out-of-state company. 
NRG didn’t respond to requests for comment.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://local.record-bee.com/common/dfm/assets/logos/small/record-bee.png?082016</main_image>
</document>
