<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.khou.com/_/20/110104950/khou/sports</forum>
<forum_title>KHOU - Sports</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Spring&apos;s Simone Biles clinches gold</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.khou.com/_/20/110104950/khou/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;khou&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;springs-simone-biles-wins-all-around-gold&amp;#x2f;295233070</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Spring&apos;s Simone Biles clinches gold in all-around Rachel Axon, USA TODAY Sports , KHOU 5:54 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Gold medalist Simone Biles of the United States poses for photographs after the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) (Photo: Elsa, 2016 Getty Images) 
Spring&apos;s Simone Biles flipped and flew to the Olympic all-around gold medal Thursday in Rio. 
Teammate Aly Raisman came from behind to clinch the silver. Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina took the bronze. 
Biles&apos; win gave the American’s the Olympic all-around title for the fourth consecutive time, extending a streak that began in 2004. 
It was the first major international meet where she trailed at any point, but it hardly mattered as she scored 62.198 to win by 2.1 points. 
Raisman said she knew Biles would take the title by a comfortable margin. 

“Just to be able to have that with her and to experience it, it’s really going to be special,” Raisman said after qualifying on Sunday. “I go into it knowing that I hope that she wins just because she wins every single competition.” 
That’s no exaggeration. Biles’ Olympic all-around gold is the latest in a long line that have made her the greatest gymnast in her sport’s history. 
Biles helped the Final Five to team gold here on Tuesday. It was one of three team golds that she’s been part of since the London Olympics. Loading... US gymnast Simone Biles (L) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman celebrate after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND (L-R) Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina, US gymnast Simone Biles and US gymnast Alexandra Raisman celebrate on the podium of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX (R-L) Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina, US gymnast Simone Biles and US gymnast Alexandra Raisman celebrate on the podium of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman celebrate after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman (L) celebrate with their coaches after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Gold medalist Simone Biles (L) of the United States and silver medalist Alexandra Raisman (R) of the United States pose for photographs after the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman celebrate with their coach Mihai Brestyan after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Gold medalist Simone Biles (L) of the United States and silver medalist Alexandra Raisman of the United States are seen on the podium at the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Gold medalist Simone Biles of the United States poses for photographs after the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the floor event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the floor event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX US gymnast Simone Biles celebrates after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Gold medalist Simone Biles of the United States poses for photographs after the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (C) of the United States is embraced by Alexandra Raisman after competing on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles celebrates after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (L) of the United States waits for the score after competing on the floor with Alexandra Raisman (R) during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles celebrates after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the floor event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX US gymnast Simone Biles (L) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (L) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman celebrate after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (C) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman (hidden) celebrate with their coaches after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the vault event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the floor event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: (EDITORS NOTE: Multiple exposures were combined in camera to produce this image.) Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Mike Ehrmann/Getty Images) Mike Ehrmann, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States reacts after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (C) of the United States is seen prior to the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (C) of the United States is seen prior to the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles reacts after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States looks on while waiting for moving to the next apparatus during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States looks on during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States reacts after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States is congratulated by her coach Mihai Brestyan after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States is congratulated by her coach Mihai Brestyan after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States reacts after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (L) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions 
Biles herself as won the past three all-around competitions at the world championships. During that run, she won a record 10 gold medals and 14 overall. 
Biles, 19, has won every all-around competition she has entered since August 2013, a streak that includes four consecutive U.S. titles. 
As she has throughout that run, Biles stayed far ahead of the field by performing the most difficult gymnastics with some of the best execution. Her margin of victory was nearly double the largest she’s had in winning the major international all-around competition each year. 
Biles trailed Mustafina by 0.034 after the second rotation, during which both were on uneven bars. That’s Mustafina’s best event and Biles’ worst. 
She pulled away from there, taking first place by more than 1.8 points after balance beam. On floor, she was spectacular, putting together her usual soaring, technically difficult routine to earn the highest score of the day. 
Raisman, meanwhile, was fourth after two rotations, but moved into third on beam and took silver thanks to a floor routine that was second only to Biles’. 
The Americans finished first and second for the first time since 2008 when Nastia Liukin and Shawn Johnson claimed gold and silver, respectively. It was Raisman’s first Olympic all-around medal after she lost a tiebreaker for third in London four years ago. 
As Raisman came off floor, she sobbed and waved to the crowd. When Biles came off, the teammates embraced each other, the persistently bubbly Biles crying in Raisman’s arms. 
The Americans are and have been the best in the world for quite some time. They were expected to go home with these medals, but those expectations couldn’t make this feel any less sweet. 
Biles will compete for three individual gold medals in floor exercise, beam and vault. 
Raisman competes in floor and beam. Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: (L to R) Gold medalists Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, Lauren Hernandez, Simone Biles and Gabrielle Douglas of the United States pose for photographs. (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA waves to fans during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Aly Raisman (USA) and her teammates react during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, Custom US gymnast Lauren Hernandez competes in the Floor event during the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 9, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND EMMANUEL DUNAND, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Aly Raisman (USA) competes during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final on Day 4 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Aly Raisman (USA) competes during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports US gymnast Gabrielle Douglas competes in the Uneven Bars event during the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena. / AFP / Antonin THUILLIER (Photo credit should read ANTONIN THUILLIER/AFP/Getty Images) ANTONIN THUILLIER, Custom Aug 4, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; USA Team head coach Marta Karolyi (L) with Simone Biles during artistic gymnastics training in preparation for the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, Custom US gymnast Lauren Hernandez competes in the Vault event during the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 9, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND EMMANUEL DUNAND, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Gabby Douglas (USA) during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final on Day 4 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena. (Photo by Quinn Rooney/Getty Images) Quinn Rooney, Custom US gymnast Lauren Hernandez competes in the Vault event during the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Alexandra Raisman (R) of the United States is embraced by her team mate Gabrielle Douglas (L) after competing on the vault during the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final. (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, Custom US supporters attend the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 9, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Gabrielle Douglas of the United States looks on before the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final on Day 4 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena. (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Lauren Hernandez of the United States competes on the vault during the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final on Day 4. (Photo by Quinn Rooney/Getty Images) Quinn Rooney, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, Custom Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Vault event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Floor event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Floor event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Beam event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Beam event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Floor event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro(Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Floor event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, 2016 Getty Images of Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions Loading... SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes in the floor exercise during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles warms up on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Ashton Locklear, Gabrielle Douglas, and Simone Biles hug one another following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes in the floor exercise during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles waits to warm up on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes in the floor exercise during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: A close up of the hands of Simone Biles during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles warms up on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles warms up on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: MyKayla Skinner hugs Simone Biles following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes in the floor exercise during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas and Simone Biles celebrate after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Simone Biles, Ragan Smith, Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas celebrates after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Maggie Nichols hugs Simone Biles following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas, Lauren Hernandez and Simone Biles hug after being named to represent the USA at the 2016 Olympics in Rio during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles (center) celebrates with Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Ragan Smith, Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) (Front Row:) Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Simone Biles, Ragan Smith (Back Row) Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas pose for a team photo after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Simone Biles, Ragan Smith, Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas celebrates after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas and Simone Biles celebrate after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas and Simone Biles hug after being named to represent the USA at the 2016 Olympics in Rio during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Lauren Hernandez, Madison Kocian, Gabrielle Douglas, and Simone Biles celebrate after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles hugs her team after named to the US Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics team during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles (center) celebrates with Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Ragan Smith, Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas and Simone Biles celebrate after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the uneven bars during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the uneven bars during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the vault during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the floor exercise during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the uneven bars during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the balance beam during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the floor exercise during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images of
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.khou.com/_/20/110104950/khou/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;khou&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;springs-simone-biles-wins-all-around-gold&amp;#x2f;295233070</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2254</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Spring&apos;s Simone Biles clinches gold in all-around Rachel Axon, USA TODAY Sports , KHOU 5:54 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Gold medalist Simone Biles of the United States poses for photographs after the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) (Photo: Elsa, 2016 Getty Images) 
Spring&apos;s Simone Biles flipped and flew to the Olympic all-around gold medal Thursday in Rio. 
Teammate Aly Raisman came from behind to clinch the silver. Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina took the bronze. 
Biles&apos; win gave the American’s the Olympic all-around title for the fourth consecutive time, extending a streak that began in 2004. 
It was the first major international meet where she trailed at any point, but it hardly mattered as she scored 62.198 to win by 2.1 points. 
Raisman said she knew Biles would take the title by a comfortable margin. 

“Just to be able to have that with her and to experience it, it’s really going to be special,” Raisman said after qualifying on Sunday. “I go into it knowing that I hope that she wins just because she wins every single competition.” 
That’s no exaggeration. Biles’ Olympic all-around gold is the latest in a long line that have made her the greatest gymnast in her sport’s history. 
Biles helped the Final Five to team gold here on Tuesday. It was one of three team golds that she’s been part of since the London Olympics. Loading... US gymnast Simone Biles (L) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman celebrate after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND (L-R) Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina, US gymnast Simone Biles and US gymnast Alexandra Raisman celebrate on the podium of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX (R-L) Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina, US gymnast Simone Biles and US gymnast Alexandra Raisman celebrate on the podium of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman celebrate after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman (L) celebrate with their coaches after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Gold medalist Simone Biles (L) of the United States and silver medalist Alexandra Raisman (R) of the United States pose for photographs after the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman celebrate with their coach Mihai Brestyan after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Gold medalist Simone Biles (L) of the United States and silver medalist Alexandra Raisman of the United States are seen on the podium at the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Gold medalist Simone Biles of the United States poses for photographs after the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the floor event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the floor event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX US gymnast Simone Biles celebrates after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Gold medalist Simone Biles of the United States poses for photographs after the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Individual All Around on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (C) of the United States is embraced by Alexandra Raisman after competing on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles celebrates after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (L) of the United States waits for the score after competing on the floor with Alexandra Raisman (R) during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles celebrates after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the floor event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX US gymnast Simone Biles (L) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (L) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman celebrate after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (C) and her compatiot Alexandra Raisman (hidden) celebrate with their coaches after the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. US gymnast Simone Biles won the event ahead of her compatiot Alexandra Raisman and Russia&apos;s Aliya Mustafina. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the vault event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the floor event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: (EDITORS NOTE: Multiple exposures were combined in camera to produce this image.) Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Mike Ehrmann/Getty Images) Mike Ehrmann, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States reacts after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (C) of the United States is seen prior to the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (C) of the United States is seen prior to the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles reacts after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States looks on while waiting for moving to the next apparatus during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States looks on during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States reacts after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States is congratulated by her coach Mihai Brestyan after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States is congratulated by her coach Mihai Brestyan after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States reacts after competing on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND US gymnast Simone Biles (L) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions 
Biles herself as won the past three all-around competitions at the world championships. During that run, she won a record 10 gold medals and 14 overall. 
Biles, 19, has won every all-around competition she has entered since August 2013, a streak that includes four consecutive U.S. titles. 
As she has throughout that run, Biles stayed far ahead of the field by performing the most difficult gymnastics with some of the best execution. Her margin of victory was nearly double the largest she’s had in winning the major international all-around competition each year. 
Biles trailed Mustafina by 0.034 after the second rotation, during which both were on uneven bars. That’s Mustafina’s best event and Biles’ worst. 
She pulled away from there, taking first place by more than 1.8 points after balance beam. On floor, she was spectacular, putting together her usual soaring, technically difficult routine to earn the highest score of the day. 
Raisman, meanwhile, was fourth after two rotations, but moved into third on beam and took silver thanks to a floor routine that was second only to Biles’. 
The Americans finished first and second for the first time since 2008 when Nastia Liukin and Shawn Johnson claimed gold and silver, respectively. It was Raisman’s first Olympic all-around medal after she lost a tiebreaker for third in London four years ago. 
As Raisman came off floor, she sobbed and waved to the crowd. When Biles came off, the teammates embraced each other, the persistently bubbly Biles crying in Raisman’s arms. 
The Americans are and have been the best in the world for quite some time. They were expected to go home with these medals, but those expectations couldn’t make this feel any less sweet. 
Biles will compete for three individual gold medals in floor exercise, beam and vault. 
Raisman competes in floor and beam. Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: (L to R) Gold medalists Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, Lauren Hernandez, Simone Biles and Gabrielle Douglas of the United States pose for photographs. (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA waves to fans during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Aly Raisman (USA) and her teammates react during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, Custom US gymnast Lauren Hernandez competes in the Floor event during the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 9, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND EMMANUEL DUNAND, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Aly Raisman (USA) competes during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final on Day 4 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Aly Raisman (USA) competes during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports US gymnast Gabrielle Douglas competes in the Uneven Bars event during the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena. / AFP / Antonin THUILLIER (Photo credit should read ANTONIN THUILLIER/AFP/Getty Images) ANTONIN THUILLIER, Custom Aug 4, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; USA Team head coach Marta Karolyi (L) with Simone Biles during artistic gymnastics training in preparation for the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, Custom US gymnast Lauren Hernandez competes in the Vault event during the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 9, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND EMMANUEL DUNAND, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Gabby Douglas (USA) during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final on Day 4 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena. (Photo by Quinn Rooney/Getty Images) Quinn Rooney, Custom US gymnast Lauren Hernandez competes in the Vault event during the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Alexandra Raisman (R) of the United States is embraced by her team mate Gabrielle Douglas (L) after competing on the vault during the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final. (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, Custom US supporters attend the women&apos;s team final Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 9, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Gabrielle Douglas of the United States looks on before the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final on Day 4 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena. (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 09: Lauren Hernandez of the United States competes on the vault during the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Team Final on Day 4. (Photo by Quinn Rooney/Getty Images) Quinn Rooney, Custom Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) during the women&apos;s team finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, Custom Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Vault event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Floor event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Floor event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Beam event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Beam event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Floor event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro(Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the qualifying for the women&apos;s Floor event of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 7, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 07: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during Women&apos;s qualification for Artistic Gymnastics on Day 2 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Rio Olympic Arena on August 7, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by David Ramos/Getty Images) David Ramos, 2016 Getty Images of Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions Loading... SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes in the floor exercise during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles warms up on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Ashton Locklear, Gabrielle Douglas, and Simone Biles hug one another following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes in the floor exercise during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles waits to warm up on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes in the floor exercise during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: A close up of the hands of Simone Biles during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles warms up on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles warms up on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: MyKayla Skinner hugs Simone Biles following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes in the floor exercise during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas and Simone Biles celebrate after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Simone Biles, Ragan Smith, Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas celebrates after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Maggie Nichols hugs Simone Biles following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas, Lauren Hernandez and Simone Biles hug after being named to represent the USA at the 2016 Olympics in Rio during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles (center) celebrates with Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Ragan Smith, Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) (Front Row:) Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Simone Biles, Ragan Smith (Back Row) Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas pose for a team photo after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Simone Biles, Ragan Smith, Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas celebrates after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas and Simone Biles celebrate after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas and Simone Biles hug after being named to represent the USA at the 2016 Olympics in Rio during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Lauren Hernandez, Madison Kocian, Gabrielle Douglas, and Simone Biles celebrate after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles hugs her team after named to the US Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics team during day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: Simone Biles (center) celebrates with Lauren Hernandez, MyKayla Skinner, Ragan Smith, Ashton Locklear, Alexandra Raisman, Madison Kocian, and Gabrielle Douglas after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 10: (L-R) Gabrielle Douglas and Simone Biles celebrate after they were selected for the Olympic Team following Day 2 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 10, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the uneven bars during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the uneven bars during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the uneven bars during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the vault during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the floor exercise during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the uneven bars during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the balance beam during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the floor exercise during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles competes on the balance beam during day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Olympic Women&apos;s Gymnastics Team Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez, 2016 Getty Images SAN JOSE, CA - JULY 08: Simone Biles is competes in the floor exercise during Day 1 of the 2016 U.S. Women&apos;s Gymnastics Olympic Trials at SAP Center on July 8, 2016 in San Jose, California. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images of
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.khou.com/photo/2016/08/11/simone%20biles%20all%20around%20_OP_25_CP__1470952400154_5097066_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
