<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Dwayne Wade&apos;s Ex-Wife Wants More Of His Money Will She Have It?</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.360nobs.com/2016/08/dwayne-wade-ex-wife-wants/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Cancel 
Dwyane Wade will be losing some of his wealth to his ex-wife, Siohvaughn Funches, who is taking the saying “behind every successful man there is a woman” literally. 
Miss Siohvaughn has decided to reopen her divorce case against her ex as she’s laying claim to $10M in her new divorce settlement. 
She stated that she had sowed a seed in Wade both before he was a basketballer and after he became one of the greatest and now wants return on investment. 
We understand the fifty percent that believes she deserves what she wants then the plot seems too suspect as their divorce was finalized in 2010 and just as Wade just signed a new two-year $47 million contract with the Chicago Bulls, Funches is reopening the case. Fishy! 
Wade and Funches were married in 2002 and separated in 2007. Their divorce was finalized in 2010 after a lengthy process which had the NBA star getting sole custody of his sons, Zaire and Zion, from Siohvaughn a year later. Wade and Funchess 
He is presently married to actress Gabrielle Union whom he wed in 2014. 
Funchess didn’t let Wade take a breathe of fresh air as two years after he married his new bride, she’s suing his cute ass although in their initial divorce settlement he had left their home for her. 
Dwayne Wade’s ex asserts part of the reason for her new claim is “ignorance to Wade’s true worth”– pun intended – as she insists “her former lawyer, Brian Hurst, never showed her Wade’s business contracts.” 
She didn’t know his worth and so she probably got less than she should have taken as hers. 
Funchess isn’t here to play as she sued Hurst “for pressuring’ her into taking the settlement instead of going to trial, “another blame on “ignorance to Wade’s true value”, so she probably got less. And now she wants double the previous divorce settlement. 
Like that wasn’t enough.she also alleged that “her primary demands weren’t met, including getting their marital home appraised, paying travel expenses for their sons and paying her law school tuition.” 
Siohvaughn is so savage Huffington Post reported she went through 16 attorneys in her initial divorce and made Wade pay for the lawyers that were trying to help his ex-wife have a share of his material wealth. 
He better prepare, Fuchess wants a new piece of Dwayne Wade’s pie and a judge has ruled she can have it by reopening the case. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.360nobs.com/2016/08/dwayne-wade-ex-wife-wants/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Wendiva Blaze</username>
<post>
Cancel 
Dwyane Wade will be losing some of his wealth to his ex-wife, Siohvaughn Funches, who is taking the saying “behind every successful man there is a woman” literally. 
Miss Siohvaughn has decided to reopen her divorce case against her ex as she’s laying claim to $10M in her new divorce settlement. 
She stated that she had sowed a seed in Wade both before he was a basketballer and after he became one of the greatest and now wants return on investment. 
We understand the fifty percent that believes she deserves what she wants then the plot seems too suspect as their divorce was finalized in 2010 and just as Wade just signed a new two-year $47 million contract with the Chicago Bulls, Funches is reopening the case. Fishy! 
Wade and Funches were married in 2002 and separated in 2007. Their divorce was finalized in 2010 after a lengthy process which had the NBA star getting sole custody of his sons, Zaire and Zion, from Siohvaughn a year later. Wade and Funchess 
He is presently married to actress Gabrielle Union whom he wed in 2014. 
Funchess didn’t let Wade take a breathe of fresh air as two years after he married his new bride, she’s suing his cute ass although in their initial divorce settlement he had left their home for her. 
Dwayne Wade’s ex asserts part of the reason for her new claim is “ignorance to Wade’s true worth”– pun intended – as she insists “her former lawyer, Brian Hurst, never showed her Wade’s business contracts.” 
She didn’t know his worth and so she probably got less than she should have taken as hers. 
Funchess isn’t here to play as she sued Hurst “for pressuring’ her into taking the settlement instead of going to trial, “another blame on “ignorance to Wade’s true value”, so she probably got less. And now she wants double the previous divorce settlement. 
Like that wasn’t enough.she also alleged that “her primary demands weren’t met, including getting their marital home appraised, paying travel expenses for their sons and paying her law school tuition.” 
Siohvaughn is so savage Huffington Post reported she went through 16 attorneys in her initial divorce and made Wade pay for the lawyers that were trying to help his ex-wife have a share of his material wealth. 
He better prepare, Fuchess wants a new piece of Dwayne Wade’s pie and a judge has ruled she can have it by reopening the case. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://www.360nobs.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/dwayne-wade-378x283.jpg</main_image>
</document>
