<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://whiteville.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>The News Reporter</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Persistence brings man’s best friend home — and gives him a cause</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://nrcolumbus.com/news/persistence-brings-mans-best-friend-home-gives-cause/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Persistence brings man’s best friend home — and gives him a cause filed under News by Jefferson Weaver reported 9 hours ago 
Blake Evans knew something was wrong when he pulled into his driveway in Hallsboro when Big Boy didn’t come to greet him. 
“He’s always there when he hears my voice,” Evans said. 
On this particular hot Sunday afternoon, Big Boy’s collar lay loose in the yard. The dog wasn’t in the shed. The dog’s fan was still on, his food and water were untouched, and the half-pit, half-boxer was nowhere to be found. 
Evans had been gone from home for a little over an hour, but his 80-pound pooch had disappeared. 
“That dog is my baby,” he said unashamedly. “If you have a good dog, they can be closer to you than your children sometimes.” 
Big Boy’s lead had been unclipped, Evans said. He tripped the latch on the brass clasp to show its strength. 
“He’s a big dog, and needs a big hook,” Evans said. “There’s no way he popped that.” 
Although he’d heard the reports of dogs being stolen throughout the county, allegedly for dogfighting, Evans said he hadn’t been worried. 
“He’s a friendly boy when you’re with me,” he said, “but strangers aren’t welcome. He won’t just go out and hurt somebody, but a dog knows if you’re up to something.” 

Big Boy has never been a roamer, Evans said. When the family isn’t home, Big Boy is tethered on a long runner that allows him access to the entire backyard, as well as his heated and cooled shed. He likes sleeping in a cool hole in the dirt, or standing atop a plastic bench that he often shares with Evans. Big Boy isn’t allowed to run around the Hallsboro neighborhood, Evans said. 
“Responsible people don’t let their dogs run around loose,” he said. “There’s a chance somebody could get hurt, or the dog will get into something. Dogs are dogs. They’re going to get in trouble if you don’t have control of them. 
“I was brought up to do the right thing, and you don’t let your animals run loose.” 
Even when Big Boy is off his lead, Evans said, he stays close to his master. He greets Evans every morning and evenings after work, or anytime the Ash native is working in the yard or on his excavation equipment. 
“I always have treats for him,” he said. “He especially likes the sausages and ham from Pierce and Company.” 
So when Big Boy didn’t even bark or whine in greeting, Evans knew something was wrong. 
He searched the entire property, then began to suspect someone had snatched the dog. 
“The right person might be able to get him,” Evans said. 
On Monday, Evans said he contacted Animal Control and the Columbus County Sheriff’s Office. A relative had already told him about the dog thefts in the area, and he was even more concerned to find out that many of the alleged thefts hadn’t been reported. 
“The police can’t do anything about stuff they don’t is happening,” Evans said. “That just makes the criminals bolder. People read about it in the newspaper, or see someone arrested for a crime, they pay more attention to what’s happening around them.” 
Evans immediately took one of the many photos he has of Big Boy, and made up fliers. He posted them on utility poles and at area businesses, and following a hunch, he went to Bolton. 
That’s where he got his first break. 

“I saw that dog” 
Big Boy is an intimidating dog at first glance, and that’s one reason he was set to be euthanized when Evans adopted him. 
“I had a female dog, and she wasn’t like him – she could be mean,” Evans said. “She didn’t look like much, but she was tough. I wanted a dog that would take care of my property and family, but not be dangerous, so I went to the Animal Shelter just to see.” 
Big Boy was scared, a little snappy and alone in the kennel when Evans saw him. When the two made eye contact, Big Boy wagged his tail and cam to Evans. 
“I knew that was my dog,” he said. “When I said I wanted him, they said he was set to be killed. I asked them why – there wasn’t anything wrong with him. I wasn’t leaving without him.” 
Big Boy immediately became a part of both the Evans family and Evans Excavation Services. Although too big to ride on most pieces of equipment, he often rides in the pickup or dump truck with Evans. 
“He loves to be in the truck,” Evans said. “Soon as he gets in there, he settles down in the passenger floor board. He about fills it up, but that’s his place.” 
While Big Boy is courteous to visitors who are with his family, he’s a different dog at night, Evans said. “At night, he’s in charge of the place,” Evans said. “I don’t have to worry, because he’s guarding it.” 
Big Boy is light brown and white, with startling green eyes. The eye color is reportedly prized by dogfighters and breeders of fighting dogs, in the same way that the “blue” color phase is said to be preferred for pit bulls heading for the fighting ring. 
“I didn’t know anything about that,” Evans said, but when a relative showed him a photo of a blue pit that was up for sale in the area, he became suspicious. 
“That dog—he didn’t belong around here,” Evans said. “It made me wonder what all was going on.” 
Although he said he knew deputies were trying to develop leads in the theft case, Evans said he understands dogs often take priority over crimes involving people. 
So the 6’4” heavy equipment operator began asking around. He drove through several neighborhoods, where people were less than helpful, even when told there was a reward for Big Boy’s safe return. 
“People are scared of the crooks,” he said, “and some of them are crooks. They lied to me, and I could tell, but I understood they were scared. 
“I wasn’t scared. I just wanted my dog back.” 
He placed fliers around Hallsboro, Lake Waccamaw and was in Bolton when a clerk in a store said she was sure she’d seen Big Boy. She gave Evans a little bit of information, and promised to help more. 
He then went to a few other businesses and began asking questions. On a return trip to another store, he said, he saw where the flier had been torn down in the hour or so since he’d left. The reception he got at the store was also a lot different, Evans said. 
“I knew then that I was on the right path,” Evans said. 
Evans then began a door-to-door campaign, and said he was shocked to find out how many people suspected there was dogfighting in the area – not to mention people he said acted “like they knew a lot more than they should. 
“I saw some pretty rough dogs in some places, and there were places blocked off behind houses,” he said. “I don’t know if it’s cause they were worried about their neighbors, or because they were hiding something.” 
While doing his own detective work, Evans said, he discovered women were more willing to talk than most of the men. 
“The ladies I talked to, they led me in the right direction,” he said. “They finally hooked me up with somebody.” 

Fearless 
Evans isn’t afraid of hard work – nor it seems, of much of anything else. 
As a long-distance truck driver, he said he visited most of the country. He earned a reputation of being willing to make deliveries to places in Northern cities that other drivers didn’t want to visit. 
“One place in Boston, I walked up the street and found the man I needed to speak to,” he said, “and when I walked back down the street, there was a puddle of blood there.” 
In other places, he said, “people told me I was different. 
“I didn’t back down when I was right,” he said. “That’s how I was raised. People recognized that, and when they heard me talk, they’d say, ‘You’re not from here.’ I told them that was right – I was from the backwoods, and proud of it. They could have their cities. I didn’t try to start anything, and I’d help anyone I could, but I wasn’t going to take anything, either.” 
Despite receiving an attractive offer to run a small fleet of trucks for a distributor, Evans said he wanted to come home. 
“I didn’t belong there,” he said. “Some of the companies, you couldn’t even carry a dog with you. I saw a lot of places, even the Pacific Ocean, but it wasn’t like home. 
“Besides,” he laughed, “the dirt moved under you out there. I didn’t like that. Dirt is supposed to stay still.” 
Evans returned to the area, and started his excavation business, maintaining logging roads through the Green Swamp and handling other heavy equipment jobs. One of his main pieces of equipment is a late 1950s model Galion road grader that was purchased new by an uncle. 
“The new stuff is nice,” he said, “but there’s nothing wrong with doing something the old way as long as it works right.” 
He hauled nearly 180 loads of debris from the former Whiteville teacherage when the home was being renovated and turned into an accounting office. 
“I ain’t afraid to work,” he said. “That’s how we were brought up. You work to earn what you want. That’s one other thing that got me about Big Boy being stolen – you don’t steal from people. If you want something, you earn it.” 
Working in and around tough places taught Evans how not to be easily cowed. 
“I am not saying people should take the law into their own hands,” he said. “that’s not right, either. You don’t need to be a bully or want to fight everybody, but you need to be solid. You need people to realize you’re good to your word. 
“It used to be where if somebody was causing trouble, the leaders in the community or maybe somebody form the church would have a talk with them, or the parents if it was a young person. Now? It seems a lot of parents don’t even try. That’s what leads to a lot of trouble – parents won’t be mamas and daddys.” 
Evans said that even though he just worked the suspect neighborhood in Bolton for a few days, “people began recognizing my truck. 
“They knew I wasn’t scared of them,” he said, “and that I wasn’t going to quit.” 
Big Boy’s owner knocked on doors and spoke to people in their yards and driveways before and after work, trying to canvass every home for any information about his beloved companion. On the Wednesday after Big Boy disappeared on Sunday, Evans said, he got a call from a man with some information. 
“He was worried I was going to take him out in the country and hurt him,” Evans said. “I told him, man, I just want my dog back.” 

Rescue 
Evans said the man directed him to a home near town, and as they pulled in the driveway, Big Boy lifted his head from under a utility trailer. 
“He was tied up to the trailer on a yellow rope,” Evans said. “He saw me and began crying and wagging his tail.” 
Evans didn’t hesitate. Despite warnings from the informant, he stepped out of the truck and picked up his dog, cutting the yellow rope with his pocketknife. No one appeared to be home, Evans said, “but I didn’t care if they were. 
“Maybe I should have called the sheriff’s office,” Evans admitted. “The deputies told me that would have been smarter. But my dog was coming home.” 
Big Boy was badly beaten, dehydrated and hungry, Evans said. The dog was stiff and had trouble walking, but was enthusiastic about getting back into his favorite pickup truck. Evans dropped the informant off, and took Big Boy home for a dinner of ham and sausage. 
That evening, Evans said, Big Boy once again joined his favorite human on his beloved bench in the backyard. He’s now healed up, Evans said, and back to being the big, happy dog he was before the incident. Evans’ truck regularly has scratches and pawprints on the windowsill where Big Boy jumps up to greet his owner. 
Big Boy is also a little more concerned when he can’t see Evans. The dog stays as close as possible when Evans is repairing on a piece of equipment or working in the yard. 
Evans said Big Boy’s adventure opened his eyes about how common dog thefts and dogfighting may actually be in the county, and he wants other people to avoid his experience. 
“We need to bring back the old Community Watch,” he said. “The sheriff, he can’t do anything if he doesn’t have information, and he’s got to have it so he can take it to the court. If people know they’re being watched, they’ll go somewhere else to break into somebody’s home.” 
Dogfighting has become something of a cause for Evans, he said. He said he isn’t doing anything different than anyone else who loves dogs. He’d like to see penalties stiffened, and more funding for investigations involving animal cruelty. 
Still, the problem is rooted in people, he said. 
“I can’t understand why anybody would enjoy watching dogs kill each other,” Evans said. “That ain’t a sport. It’s cruel. I think there’s so much of it because we’ve gotten into such bad shape as a society. We have no values left, and sometimes it’s the animals that suffer.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://nrcolumbus.com/news/persistence-brings-mans-best-friend-home-gives-cause/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2109</post_time>
<username>Jefferson Weaver</username>
<post>
Persistence brings man’s best friend home — and gives him a cause filed under News by Jefferson Weaver reported 9 hours ago 
Blake Evans knew something was wrong when he pulled into his driveway in Hallsboro when Big Boy didn’t come to greet him. 
“He’s always there when he hears my voice,” Evans said. 
On this particular hot Sunday afternoon, Big Boy’s collar lay loose in the yard. The dog wasn’t in the shed. The dog’s fan was still on, his food and water were untouched, and the half-pit, half-boxer was nowhere to be found. 
Evans had been gone from home for a little over an hour, but his 80-pound pooch had disappeared. 
“That dog is my baby,” he said unashamedly. “If you have a good dog, they can be closer to you than your children sometimes.” 
Big Boy’s lead had been unclipped, Evans said. He tripped the latch on the brass clasp to show its strength. 
“He’s a big dog, and needs a big hook,” Evans said. “There’s no way he popped that.” 
Although he’d heard the reports of dogs being stolen throughout the county, allegedly for dogfighting, Evans said he hadn’t been worried. 
“He’s a friendly boy when you’re with me,” he said, “but strangers aren’t welcome. He won’t just go out and hurt somebody, but a dog knows if you’re up to something.” 

Big Boy has never been a roamer, Evans said. When the family isn’t home, Big Boy is tethered on a long runner that allows him access to the entire backyard, as well as his heated and cooled shed. He likes sleeping in a cool hole in the dirt, or standing atop a plastic bench that he often shares with Evans. Big Boy isn’t allowed to run around the Hallsboro neighborhood, Evans said. 
“Responsible people don’t let their dogs run around loose,” he said. “There’s a chance somebody could get hurt, or the dog will get into something. Dogs are dogs. They’re going to get in trouble if you don’t have control of them. 
“I was brought up to do the right thing, and you don’t let your animals run loose.” 
Even when Big Boy is off his lead, Evans said, he stays close to his master. He greets Evans every morning and evenings after work, or anytime the Ash native is working in the yard or on his excavation equipment. 
“I always have treats for him,” he said. “He especially likes the sausages and ham from Pierce and Company.” 
So when Big Boy didn’t even bark or whine in greeting, Evans knew something was wrong. 
He searched the entire property, then began to suspect someone had snatched the dog. 
“The right person might be able to get him,” Evans said. 
On Monday, Evans said he contacted Animal Control and the Columbus County Sheriff’s Office. A relative had already told him about the dog thefts in the area, and he was even more concerned to find out that many of the alleged thefts hadn’t been reported. 
“The police can’t do anything about stuff they don’t is happening,” Evans said. “That just makes the criminals bolder. People read about it in the newspaper, or see someone arrested for a crime, they pay more attention to what’s happening around them.” 
Evans immediately took one of the many photos he has of Big Boy, and made up fliers. He posted them on utility poles and at area businesses, and following a hunch, he went to Bolton. 
That’s where he got his first break. 

“I saw that dog” 
Big Boy is an intimidating dog at first glance, and that’s one reason he was set to be euthanized when Evans adopted him. 
“I had a female dog, and she wasn’t like him – she could be mean,” Evans said. “She didn’t look like much, but she was tough. I wanted a dog that would take care of my property and family, but not be dangerous, so I went to the Animal Shelter just to see.” 
Big Boy was scared, a little snappy and alone in the kennel when Evans saw him. When the two made eye contact, Big Boy wagged his tail and cam to Evans. 
“I knew that was my dog,” he said. “When I said I wanted him, they said he was set to be killed. I asked them why – there wasn’t anything wrong with him. I wasn’t leaving without him.” 
Big Boy immediately became a part of both the Evans family and Evans Excavation Services. Although too big to ride on most pieces of equipment, he often rides in the pickup or dump truck with Evans. 
“He loves to be in the truck,” Evans said. “Soon as he gets in there, he settles down in the passenger floor board. He about fills it up, but that’s his place.” 
While Big Boy is courteous to visitors who are with his family, he’s a different dog at night, Evans said. “At night, he’s in charge of the place,” Evans said. “I don’t have to worry, because he’s guarding it.” 
Big Boy is light brown and white, with startling green eyes. The eye color is reportedly prized by dogfighters and breeders of fighting dogs, in the same way that the “blue” color phase is said to be preferred for pit bulls heading for the fighting ring. 
“I didn’t know anything about that,” Evans said, but when a relative showed him a photo of a blue pit that was up for sale in the area, he became suspicious. 
“That dog—he didn’t belong around here,” Evans said. “It made me wonder what all was going on.” 
Although he said he knew deputies were trying to develop leads in the theft case, Evans said he understands dogs often take priority over crimes involving people. 
So the 6’4” heavy equipment operator began asking around. He drove through several neighborhoods, where people were less than helpful, even when told there was a reward for Big Boy’s safe return. 
“People are scared of the crooks,” he said, “and some of them are crooks. They lied to me, and I could tell, but I understood they were scared. 
“I wasn’t scared. I just wanted my dog back.” 
He placed fliers around Hallsboro, Lake Waccamaw and was in Bolton when a clerk in a store said she was sure she’d seen Big Boy. She gave Evans a little bit of information, and promised to help more. 
He then went to a few other businesses and began asking questions. On a return trip to another store, he said, he saw where the flier had been torn down in the hour or so since he’d left. The reception he got at the store was also a lot different, Evans said. 
“I knew then that I was on the right path,” Evans said. 
Evans then began a door-to-door campaign, and said he was shocked to find out how many people suspected there was dogfighting in the area – not to mention people he said acted “like they knew a lot more than they should. 
“I saw some pretty rough dogs in some places, and there were places blocked off behind houses,” he said. “I don’t know if it’s cause they were worried about their neighbors, or because they were hiding something.” 
While doing his own detective work, Evans said, he discovered women were more willing to talk than most of the men. 
“The ladies I talked to, they led me in the right direction,” he said. “They finally hooked me up with somebody.” 

Fearless 
Evans isn’t afraid of hard work – nor it seems, of much of anything else. 
As a long-distance truck driver, he said he visited most of the country. He earned a reputation of being willing to make deliveries to places in Northern cities that other drivers didn’t want to visit. 
“One place in Boston, I walked up the street and found the man I needed to speak to,” he said, “and when I walked back down the street, there was a puddle of blood there.” 
In other places, he said, “people told me I was different. 
“I didn’t back down when I was right,” he said. “That’s how I was raised. People recognized that, and when they heard me talk, they’d say, ‘You’re not from here.’ I told them that was right – I was from the backwoods, and proud of it. They could have their cities. I didn’t try to start anything, and I’d help anyone I could, but I wasn’t going to take anything, either.” 
Despite receiving an attractive offer to run a small fleet of trucks for a distributor, Evans said he wanted to come home. 
“I didn’t belong there,” he said. “Some of the companies, you couldn’t even carry a dog with you. I saw a lot of places, even the Pacific Ocean, but it wasn’t like home. 
“Besides,” he laughed, “the dirt moved under you out there. I didn’t like that. Dirt is supposed to stay still.” 
Evans returned to the area, and started his excavation business, maintaining logging roads through the Green Swamp and handling other heavy equipment jobs. One of his main pieces of equipment is a late 1950s model Galion road grader that was purchased new by an uncle. 
“The new stuff is nice,” he said, “but there’s nothing wrong with doing something the old way as long as it works right.” 
He hauled nearly 180 loads of debris from the former Whiteville teacherage when the home was being renovated and turned into an accounting office. 
“I ain’t afraid to work,” he said. “That’s how we were brought up. You work to earn what you want. That’s one other thing that got me about Big Boy being stolen – you don’t steal from people. If you want something, you earn it.” 
Working in and around tough places taught Evans how not to be easily cowed. 
“I am not saying people should take the law into their own hands,” he said. “that’s not right, either. You don’t need to be a bully or want to fight everybody, but you need to be solid. You need people to realize you’re good to your word. 
“It used to be where if somebody was causing trouble, the leaders in the community or maybe somebody form the church would have a talk with them, or the parents if it was a young person. Now? It seems a lot of parents don’t even try. That’s what leads to a lot of trouble – parents won’t be mamas and daddys.” 
Evans said that even though he just worked the suspect neighborhood in Bolton for a few days, “people began recognizing my truck. 
“They knew I wasn’t scared of them,” he said, “and that I wasn’t going to quit.” 
Big Boy’s owner knocked on doors and spoke to people in their yards and driveways before and after work, trying to canvass every home for any information about his beloved companion. On the Wednesday after Big Boy disappeared on Sunday, Evans said, he got a call from a man with some information. 
“He was worried I was going to take him out in the country and hurt him,” Evans said. “I told him, man, I just want my dog back.” 

Rescue 
Evans said the man directed him to a home near town, and as they pulled in the driveway, Big Boy lifted his head from under a utility trailer. 
“He was tied up to the trailer on a yellow rope,” Evans said. “He saw me and began crying and wagging his tail.” 
Evans didn’t hesitate. Despite warnings from the informant, he stepped out of the truck and picked up his dog, cutting the yellow rope with his pocketknife. No one appeared to be home, Evans said, “but I didn’t care if they were. 
“Maybe I should have called the sheriff’s office,” Evans admitted. “The deputies told me that would have been smarter. But my dog was coming home.” 
Big Boy was badly beaten, dehydrated and hungry, Evans said. The dog was stiff and had trouble walking, but was enthusiastic about getting back into his favorite pickup truck. Evans dropped the informant off, and took Big Boy home for a dinner of ham and sausage. 
That evening, Evans said, Big Boy once again joined his favorite human on his beloved bench in the backyard. He’s now healed up, Evans said, and back to being the big, happy dog he was before the incident. Evans’ truck regularly has scratches and pawprints on the windowsill where Big Boy jumps up to greet his owner. 
Big Boy is also a little more concerned when he can’t see Evans. The dog stays as close as possible when Evans is repairing on a piece of equipment or working in the yard. 
Evans said Big Boy’s adventure opened his eyes about how common dog thefts and dogfighting may actually be in the county, and he wants other people to avoid his experience. 
“We need to bring back the old Community Watch,” he said. “The sheriff, he can’t do anything if he doesn’t have information, and he’s got to have it so he can take it to the court. If people know they’re being watched, they’ll go somewhere else to break into somebody’s home.” 
Dogfighting has become something of a cause for Evans, he said. He said he isn’t doing anything different than anyone else who loves dogs. He’d like to see penalties stiffened, and more funding for investigations involving animal cruelty. 
Still, the problem is rooted in people, he said. 
“I can’t understand why anybody would enjoy watching dogs kill each other,” Evans said. “That ain’t a sport. It’s cruel. I think there’s so much of it because we’ve gotten into such bad shape as a society. We have no values left, and sometimes it’s the animals that suffer.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://nrcolumbus.com/wp-content/uploads/blake.bigboy.close0185-e1470949740987.jpg</main_image>
</document>
