<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.wallstreet-online.de/rss/nachrichten-weitere-nachrichten.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Nachrichten Ticker  - Kategorie: Weitere Nachrichten - www.wallstreet-online.de</forum_title>
<discussion_title>DGAP-News: Carl Zeiss Meditec AG: Carl Zeiss Meditec AG grows in Ophthalmology and Microsurgery</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wallstreet-online.de/nachricht/8842627-dgap-news-carl-zeiss-meditec-ag-carl-zeiss-meditec-ag-grows-ophthalmology-and-microsurgery</topic_url>
<topic_text>
| 12.08.2016, 07:00 | 105 | 0 | 0 DGAP-News: Carl Zeiss Meditec AG / Key word(s): 9-month figures Carl Zeiss Meditec AG: Carl Zeiss Meditec AG grows in Ophthalmology and Microsurgery The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement. Carl Zeiss Meditec AG grows in Ophthalmology and Microsurgery Revenue, EBIT and earnings per share show positive development JENA, 12 August 2016 In the first nine months of fiscal year 2015/16 medical technology company Carl Zeiss Meditec AG increased its revenue by 6.7 percent to EUR 798.6 million (adjusted for currency effects: 4.5 percent). All Strategic Business Units (SBU) and regions contributed to growth in the reporting period, however, at varying rates. Earnings before interest and taxes (EBIT) at EUR 110.5 million (prior year: EUR 89.5 million) developed positively, corresponding to an EBIT margin at 13.8 percent (prior year: 12.0 percent). Earnings per share were EUR 0.83 (prior year EUR 0.64). Substantial growth was posted by the two strategic business units of Ophthalmology: The Ophthalmic Systems SBU (OPH) increased revenue after nine months by 7.5 percent to EUR 304.9 million compared to EUR 283.5 million in the same period of the previous year. Adjusted for currency effects, revenue increased by 5.0 percent. The Surgical Ophthalmology SBU (SUR) increased its revenue by 8.6 percent (adjusted for currency effects: 7.1 percent) to EUR 280.8 million (prior year: EUR 258.5 million). In the Microsurgery SBU, revenue growth was 3.0 percent and mainly due to favorable exchange rates. Revenue climbed to EUR 212.8 million, compared with EUR 206.7 million in the same period of the previous year. Based on constant exchange rates, growth would have been 0.6 percent. Asia once again growth engine In the reporting regions, the major part of growth was accounted for by the APAC region in the first three quarters of the current fiscal year. In the EMEA region, a slight increase in revenue was reported by 0.2 percent to EUR 262.5 million (prior year: EUR 261.9 million), whereas Germany and France enjoyed growth. However, the business trend in Middle East and Africa was declining. Revenue in the Americas region increased by 0.9 percent to EUR 257.3 million (prior year: EUR 255.2 million). The strength of the US dollar had a positive effect in this region. After adjustment for currency effects, a decline by -2.9 percent was reported compared to the previous year, which was due to continued strong pressure from competition and difficult economic conditions in parts of South America. The APAC region generated revenue of EUR 278.7 million which is significantly higher than the year-ago figure of EUR 231.6 million - an increase by 20.3 percent. Adjusted for slight currency effects, growth would still have been 17.1 percent. The lion&apos;s share of the increase came from the Chinese market as well as from Southeast Asia and South Korea; the Japanese market exhibited a sideways trend. Dr. Ludwin Monz, CEO of Carl Zeiss Meditec AG, believes the Company is on the right track and - in view of the 9-month figures - confirmed the forecast for the current fiscal year with an annual revenue in the range of EUR 1,080 - 1,120 million. &quot;The result of the first three quarters endorses our growth strategy. In particular the innovations launched recently supported us to expand our market position, especially in Asia.&quot; In view of the recently announced consolidation to focus the organizational structure on the two core markets of the company, microsurgery and ophthalmology, he said: &quot;We want to improve service for our customers and tap into potentials in various regional markets.&quot; Revenue by strategic business unit Figures in EUR k 9 Months 9 Months Change Change from 2014/15 2015/16 compared to previous year prior year (adjusted for
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wallstreet-online.de/nachricht/8842627-dgap-news-carl-zeiss-meditec-ag-carl-zeiss-meditec-ag-grows-ophthalmology-and-microsurgery</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0500</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
| 12.08.2016, 07:00 | 105 | 0 | 0 DGAP-News: Carl Zeiss Meditec AG / Key word(s): 9-month figures Carl Zeiss Meditec AG: Carl Zeiss Meditec AG grows in Ophthalmology and Microsurgery The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement. Carl Zeiss Meditec AG grows in Ophthalmology and Microsurgery Revenue, EBIT and earnings per share show positive development JENA, 12 August 2016 In the first nine months of fiscal year 2015/16 medical technology company Carl Zeiss Meditec AG increased its revenue by 6.7 percent to EUR 798.6 million (adjusted for currency effects: 4.5 percent). All Strategic Business Units (SBU) and regions contributed to growth in the reporting period, however, at varying rates. Earnings before interest and taxes (EBIT) at EUR 110.5 million (prior year: EUR 89.5 million) developed positively, corresponding to an EBIT margin at 13.8 percent (prior year: 12.0 percent). Earnings per share were EUR 0.83 (prior year EUR 0.64). Substantial growth was posted by the two strategic business units of Ophthalmology: The Ophthalmic Systems SBU (OPH) increased revenue after nine months by 7.5 percent to EUR 304.9 million compared to EUR 283.5 million in the same period of the previous year. Adjusted for currency effects, revenue increased by 5.0 percent. The Surgical Ophthalmology SBU (SUR) increased its revenue by 8.6 percent (adjusted for currency effects: 7.1 percent) to EUR 280.8 million (prior year: EUR 258.5 million). In the Microsurgery SBU, revenue growth was 3.0 percent and mainly due to favorable exchange rates. Revenue climbed to EUR 212.8 million, compared with EUR 206.7 million in the same period of the previous year. Based on constant exchange rates, growth would have been 0.6 percent. Asia once again growth engine In the reporting regions, the major part of growth was accounted for by the APAC region in the first three quarters of the current fiscal year. In the EMEA region, a slight increase in revenue was reported by 0.2 percent to EUR 262.5 million (prior year: EUR 261.9 million), whereas Germany and France enjoyed growth. However, the business trend in Middle East and Africa was declining. Revenue in the Americas region increased by 0.9 percent to EUR 257.3 million (prior year: EUR 255.2 million). The strength of the US dollar had a positive effect in this region. After adjustment for currency effects, a decline by -2.9 percent was reported compared to the previous year, which was due to continued strong pressure from competition and difficult economic conditions in parts of South America. The APAC region generated revenue of EUR 278.7 million which is significantly higher than the year-ago figure of EUR 231.6 million - an increase by 20.3 percent. Adjusted for slight currency effects, growth would still have been 17.1 percent. The lion&apos;s share of the increase came from the Chinese market as well as from Southeast Asia and South Korea; the Japanese market exhibited a sideways trend. Dr. Ludwin Monz, CEO of Carl Zeiss Meditec AG, believes the Company is on the right track and - in view of the 9-month figures - confirmed the forecast for the current fiscal year with an annual revenue in the range of EUR 1,080 - 1,120 million. &quot;The result of the first three quarters endorses our growth strategy. In particular the innovations launched recently supported us to expand our market position, especially in Asia.&quot; In view of the recently announced consolidation to focus the organizational structure on the two core markets of the company, microsurgery and ophthalmology, he said: &quot;We want to improve service for our customers and tap into potentials in various regional markets.&quot; Revenue by strategic business unit Figures in EUR k 9 Months 9 Months Change Change from 2014/15 2015/16 compared to previous year prior year (adjusted for
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>DE</country>
<main_image>http://assets.wallstreet-online.de/frontend/img/wso-news-default-645x355.jpg</main_image>
</document>
