<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Monogram Residential Trust Inc. (MORE) Upgraded by Zacks Investment Research to “Buy” - WKRB News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wkrb13.com/markets/1624002/monogram-residential-trust-inc-more-upgraded-by-zacks-investment-research-to-buy/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Monogram Residential Trust Inc. (NYSE:MORE) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a research report released on Thursday. They currently have $12.00 target price on the stock. 
According to Zacks, “Monogram Residential Trust, Inc. is a self-managed real estate investment trust. It invests in, develops and operates multifamily communities offering location and lifestyle amenities. The Company invests in stabilized operating properties and properties in various phases of development, with a focus on communities located in the top 50 Metropolitan Statistical Areas of the United States. Monogram Residential Trust, Inc. is based in Addison, Texas. “ 
In related news, Director Tammy Jones acquired 7,470 shares of the firm’s stock in a transaction that occurred on Wednesday, May 18th. The shares were acquired at an average price of $10.04 per share, with a total value of $74,998.80. Following the completion of the purchase, the director now directly owns 7,470 shares in the company, valued at $74,998.80. The purchase was disclosed in a document filed with the SEC, which is available through this link . Also, Director David Fitch acquired 5,000 shares of the firm’s stock in a transaction that occurred on Monday, May 16th. The shares were bought at an average cost of $10.14 per share, for a total transaction of $50,700.00. Following the purchase, the director now owns 23,225 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $235,501.50. The disclosure for this purchase can be found here . 
Several hedge funds recently bought and sold shares of MORE. Norges Bank bought a new stake in Monogram Residential Trust during the fourth quarter worth approximately $15,383,000. Teachers Advisors Inc. raised its stake in Monogram Residential Trust by 105.2% in the first quarter. Teachers Advisors Inc. now owns 2,321,535 shares of the company’s stock worth $22,890,000 after buying an additional 1,190,000 shares during the last quarter. Commonwealth Bank of Australia bought a new stake in Monogram Residential Trust during the fourth quarter worth approximately $10,933,000. BlackRock Institutional Trust Company N.A. raised its stake in Monogram Residential Trust by 10.2% in the first quarter. BlackRock Institutional Trust Company N.A. now owns 6,361,532 shares of the company’s stock worth $62,725,000 after buying an additional 587,054 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Marshall Wace LLP raised its stake in Monogram Residential Trust by 191.2% in the fourth quarter. Marshall Wace LLP now owns 773,623 shares of the company’s stock worth $7,551,000 after buying an additional 507,939 shares during the last quarter. 
Shares of Monogram Residential Trust ( NYSE:MORE ) opened at 10.29 on Thursday. The company has a 50-day moving average of $10.40 and a 200 day moving average of $9.83. The stock has a market capitalization of $1.72 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 257.25. Monogram Residential Trust has a one year low of $7.67 and a one year high of $10.80. 
Monogram Residential Trust (NYSE:MORE) last released its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, August 4th. The company reported $0.09 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, hitting the Thomson Reuters’ consensus estimate of $0.09. The business earned $68.55 million during the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $67.40 million. Equities research analysts forecast that Monogram Residential Trust will post $0.35 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
Several other research firms have also recently issued reports on MORE. Morgan Stanley cut Monogram Residential Trust from an overweight rating to an equal weight rating and cut their price objective for the stock from $12.00 to $11.00 in a research report on Wednesday, May 11th. BMO Capital Markets began coverage on Monogram Residential Trust in a research report on Friday, June 17th. They issued an outperform rating and a $12.50 price objective for the company. Finally, Canaccord Genuity began coverage on Monogram Residential Trust in a research report on Tuesday, June 28th. They issued a hold rating and a $11.00 price objective for the company. One equities research analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, three have given a hold rating and four have given a buy rating to the company’s stock. The company has an average rating of Hold and an average target price of $11.64. 
Monogram Residential Trust, Inc (Monogram) is an integrated self-managed real estate investment trust (REIT) that invests in, develops and operates multifamily communities offering location and lifestyle amenities. The Company focuses on increasing earnings, long-term shareholder value and cash flow through the acquisition, development, and operation of its multifamily communities and the disposition of selected multifamily communities in its portfolio. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Monogram Residential Trust (MORE) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com This story was originally published by WKRB News (http://www.wkrb13.com) and is the sole property of WKRB News. If you are reading this article on another website, that means this article was illegally copied and re-published to this website in violation of U.S. and International copyright law. You can view the original version of this story at http://www.wkrb13.com/markets/1624002/monogram-residential-trust-inc-more-upgraded-by-zacks-investment-research-to-buy/ Receive News &amp; Ratings for Monogram Residential Trust Inc. Daily - Enter your email address below to receive a concise daily summary of the latest news and analysts&apos; ratings for Monogram Residential Trust Inc. and related companies with MarketBeat.com&apos;s FREE daily email newsletter . 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wkrb13.com/markets/1624002/monogram-residential-trust-inc-more-upgraded-by-zacks-investment-research-to-buy/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Kristian Gore</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Monogram Residential Trust Inc. (NYSE:MORE) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a research report released on Thursday. They currently have $12.00 target price on the stock. 
According to Zacks, “Monogram Residential Trust, Inc. is a self-managed real estate investment trust. It invests in, develops and operates multifamily communities offering location and lifestyle amenities. The Company invests in stabilized operating properties and properties in various phases of development, with a focus on communities located in the top 50 Metropolitan Statistical Areas of the United States. Monogram Residential Trust, Inc. is based in Addison, Texas. “ 
In related news, Director Tammy Jones acquired 7,470 shares of the firm’s stock in a transaction that occurred on Wednesday, May 18th. The shares were acquired at an average price of $10.04 per share, with a total value of $74,998.80. Following the completion of the purchase, the director now directly owns 7,470 shares in the company, valued at $74,998.80. The purchase was disclosed in a document filed with the SEC, which is available through this link . Also, Director David Fitch acquired 5,000 shares of the firm’s stock in a transaction that occurred on Monday, May 16th. The shares were bought at an average cost of $10.14 per share, for a total transaction of $50,700.00. Following the purchase, the director now owns 23,225 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $235,501.50. The disclosure for this purchase can be found here . 
Several hedge funds recently bought and sold shares of MORE. Norges Bank bought a new stake in Monogram Residential Trust during the fourth quarter worth approximately $15,383,000. Teachers Advisors Inc. raised its stake in Monogram Residential Trust by 105.2% in the first quarter. Teachers Advisors Inc. now owns 2,321,535 shares of the company’s stock worth $22,890,000 after buying an additional 1,190,000 shares during the last quarter. Commonwealth Bank of Australia bought a new stake in Monogram Residential Trust during the fourth quarter worth approximately $10,933,000. BlackRock Institutional Trust Company N.A. raised its stake in Monogram Residential Trust by 10.2% in the first quarter. BlackRock Institutional Trust Company N.A. now owns 6,361,532 shares of the company’s stock worth $62,725,000 after buying an additional 587,054 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Marshall Wace LLP raised its stake in Monogram Residential Trust by 191.2% in the fourth quarter. Marshall Wace LLP now owns 773,623 shares of the company’s stock worth $7,551,000 after buying an additional 507,939 shares during the last quarter. 
Shares of Monogram Residential Trust ( NYSE:MORE ) opened at 10.29 on Thursday. The company has a 50-day moving average of $10.40 and a 200 day moving average of $9.83. The stock has a market capitalization of $1.72 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 257.25. Monogram Residential Trust has a one year low of $7.67 and a one year high of $10.80. 
Monogram Residential Trust (NYSE:MORE) last released its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, August 4th. The company reported $0.09 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, hitting the Thomson Reuters’ consensus estimate of $0.09. The business earned $68.55 million during the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $67.40 million. Equities research analysts forecast that Monogram Residential Trust will post $0.35 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
Several other research firms have also recently issued reports on MORE. Morgan Stanley cut Monogram Residential Trust from an overweight rating to an equal weight rating and cut their price objective for the stock from $12.00 to $11.00 in a research report on Wednesday, May 11th. BMO Capital Markets began coverage on Monogram Residential Trust in a research report on Friday, June 17th. They issued an outperform rating and a $12.50 price objective for the company. Finally, Canaccord Genuity began coverage on Monogram Residential Trust in a research report on Tuesday, June 28th. They issued a hold rating and a $11.00 price objective for the company. One equities research analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, three have given a hold rating and four have given a buy rating to the company’s stock. The company has an average rating of Hold and an average target price of $11.64. 
Monogram Residential Trust, Inc (Monogram) is an integrated self-managed real estate investment trust (REIT) that invests in, develops and operates multifamily communities offering location and lifestyle amenities. The Company focuses on increasing earnings, long-term shareholder value and cash flow through the acquisition, development, and operation of its multifamily communities and the disposition of selected multifamily communities in its portfolio. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Monogram Residential Trust (MORE) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com This story was originally published by WKRB News (http://www.wkrb13.com) and is the sole property of WKRB News. If you are reading this article on another website, that means this article was illegally copied and re-published to this website in violation of U.S. and International copyright law. You can view the original version of this story at http://www.wkrb13.com/markets/1624002/monogram-residential-trust-inc-more-upgraded-by-zacks-investment-research-to-buy/ Receive News &amp; Ratings for Monogram Residential Trust Inc. Daily - Enter your email address below to receive a concise daily summary of the latest news and analysts&apos; ratings for Monogram Residential Trust Inc. and related companies with MarketBeat.com&apos;s FREE daily email newsletter . 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.wkrb13.com/logos/monogram-residential-trust-inc-logo.jpg</main_image>
</document>
