<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>What to expect from the Thunderbirds’ first season | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/what-to-expect-from-the-thunderbirds-first-season/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
What to expect from the Thunderbirds’ first season The new team&apos;s first home game will be played on October 22. Rachel Fazio Published: August 11, 2016, 6:10 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) Logo of the Springfield Thunderbirds AHL team 
SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (WWLP) – When the Springfield Falcons were sold to the Arizona Coyotes, the future of hockey in Springfield was unclear. But western Massachusetts hockey fans have will have a new team to root for in Springfield: the Thunderbirds. 
Western Massachusetts hockey fans are excited about the new team and the new name. “The Falcons is a basic name,” Josue Alvarado said. “the Thunderbirds? That’s a better name for it, more unique. Not many names that are being combined like that.” 
While the full schedule hasn’t been released, there are six definitive dates that the Thunderbirds will be playing games on. The home opener will take place on October 22nd and the first Thunderbirds game will be an away game. 
The Springfield Falcons games had the lowest attendance in the AHL. But Thunderbirds Executive Vice President Nathan Costa told 22News that his team will make sure games will be well attended with price deals and community engagement through social media. “There’s going to be a complete focus on reengaging with the local community,” Costa said. “And really focusing on the game night experience. And connecting with the community and focusing on ticket packages and giving people the most offerings.” 
Instead of having one set price for tickets, membership packages and special offers will now allow fans to buy tickets for as little as $10 a game and will provide fans with more options. 
The Thunderbirds’ full schedule, including both home and away games, will be announced when the AHL releases full schedules in the coming weeks. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/what-to-expect-from-the-thunderbirds-first-season/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Rachel Fazio</username>
<post>
What to expect from the Thunderbirds’ first season The new team&apos;s first home game will be played on October 22. Rachel Fazio Published: August 11, 2016, 6:10 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) Logo of the Springfield Thunderbirds AHL team 
SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (WWLP) – When the Springfield Falcons were sold to the Arizona Coyotes, the future of hockey in Springfield was unclear. But western Massachusetts hockey fans have will have a new team to root for in Springfield: the Thunderbirds. 
Western Massachusetts hockey fans are excited about the new team and the new name. “The Falcons is a basic name,” Josue Alvarado said. “the Thunderbirds? That’s a better name for it, more unique. Not many names that are being combined like that.” 
While the full schedule hasn’t been released, there are six definitive dates that the Thunderbirds will be playing games on. The home opener will take place on October 22nd and the first Thunderbirds game will be an away game. 
The Springfield Falcons games had the lowest attendance in the AHL. But Thunderbirds Executive Vice President Nathan Costa told 22News that his team will make sure games will be well attended with price deals and community engagement through social media. “There’s going to be a complete focus on reengaging with the local community,” Costa said. “And really focusing on the game night experience. And connecting with the community and focusing on ticket packages and giving people the most offerings.” 
Instead of having one set price for tickets, membership packages and special offers will now allow fans to buy tickets for as little as $10 a game and will provide fans with more options. 
The Thunderbirds’ full schedule, including both home and away games, will be announced when the AHL releases full schedules in the coming weeks. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/springfield-thunderbirds-logo.jpg</main_image>
</document>
