<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://gloucester.wickedlocal.com/opinion/columns?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Columns - Wicked Local Gloucester</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mark L. Hopkins: The Olympics: Be all you can be</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://gloucester.wickedlocal.com/news/20160811/mark-l-hopkins-olympics-be-all-you-can-be</topic_url>
<topic_text>
subscribe 
This all happened in the Tokyo Olympics in 1964. Bob Hays was in the lane to my left. The Russian was one lane further in. The starter’s gun cracked. Twenty yards down the track the group had come out of their blocks and were upright with legs reaching for every inch of turf. Another 60 yards passed and the group was beginning to separate with three straining for the lead. Five yards now with two of us still neck and neck. Then the lean, the stretch with the upper body straining for the tape. Then it was over. Who won.? Who hit the tape first? A quick look at the timer showed my name first. Someone gave me an American flag and I began the victory lap around the track waving at the people. Yes, this happened … in my dreams.Wouldn’t we all want to be an Olympian, to compete against the best in the world with the chance to be known as an Olympian, as a gold medal winner. Who wouldn’t want to experience that feeling of ultimate accomplishment after years of commitment, dedication, and hard work? Unfortunately, God doesn’t bless all of us with 100-yard dash speed. All of us can’t clear the high bar at 7-feet-8 and some can’t even throw that iron ball 70 feet. Drat. We weren’t so blessed. Oh, but we were. As the kindergartener said, “I know I’m good because God don’t make no junk.” We all have talents and abilities. We all have capabilities. The first secret to success in life is to get them identified so we know what they are.Unfortunately, that is just step one. Once we know “what?”, then we have to deal with “how?” High jumpers aren’t born with the ability to jump a 7-foot bar, nor stock brokers with the ability to pick a “winning” stock. As normal and natural as parenthood is, one is not born with the ability to be a great mother or father. In every case you have to study and think, and then work at it with dedication and commitment. Perseverance becomes the last key piece of the puzzle. You must hang in there. Talent without dedication, commitment and perseverance is talent wasted.Consider this a challenge. As you watch the Olympics over the next couple of weeks think of all the key ingredients that must come together to make an Olympic athlete.Then look at your own possibilities to succeed in your job, your family, in life. Think of the key ingredients of talent, dedication, commitment and perseverance. Ask yourself this question, “Am I all that I can be?” Yes, we all have work to do.— Dr. Mark L. Hopkins writes for More Content Now and Scripps Newspapers. He is past president of colleges and universities in four states and currently serves as executive director of a higher-education consulting service. You will find Hopkins’ latest book, “Journey to Gettysburg,” on Amazon.com. Contact him at presnet@presnet.net. 


About Us
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://gloucester.wickedlocal.com/news/20160811/mark-l-hopkins-olympics-be-all-you-can-be</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1718</post_time>
<username>Mark L. Hopkins More Content Now</username>
<post>
subscribe 
This all happened in the Tokyo Olympics in 1964. Bob Hays was in the lane to my left. The Russian was one lane further in. The starter’s gun cracked. Twenty yards down the track the group had come out of their blocks and were upright with legs reaching for every inch of turf. Another 60 yards passed and the group was beginning to separate with three straining for the lead. Five yards now with two of us still neck and neck. Then the lean, the stretch with the upper body straining for the tape. Then it was over. Who won.? Who hit the tape first? A quick look at the timer showed my name first. Someone gave me an American flag and I began the victory lap around the track waving at the people. Yes, this happened … in my dreams.Wouldn’t we all want to be an Olympian, to compete against the best in the world with the chance to be known as an Olympian, as a gold medal winner. Who wouldn’t want to experience that feeling of ultimate accomplishment after years of commitment, dedication, and hard work? Unfortunately, God doesn’t bless all of us with 100-yard dash speed. All of us can’t clear the high bar at 7-feet-8 and some can’t even throw that iron ball 70 feet. Drat. We weren’t so blessed. Oh, but we were. As the kindergartener said, “I know I’m good because God don’t make no junk.” We all have talents and abilities. We all have capabilities. The first secret to success in life is to get them identified so we know what they are.Unfortunately, that is just step one. Once we know “what?”, then we have to deal with “how?” High jumpers aren’t born with the ability to jump a 7-foot bar, nor stock brokers with the ability to pick a “winning” stock. As normal and natural as parenthood is, one is not born with the ability to be a great mother or father. In every case you have to study and think, and then work at it with dedication and commitment. Perseverance becomes the last key piece of the puzzle. You must hang in there. Talent without dedication, commitment and perseverance is talent wasted.Consider this a challenge. As you watch the Olympics over the next couple of weeks think of all the key ingredients that must come together to make an Olympic athlete.Then look at your own possibilities to succeed in your job, your family, in life. Think of the key ingredients of talent, dedication, commitment and perseverance. Ask yourself this question, “Am I all that I can be?” Yes, we all have work to do.— Dr. Mark L. Hopkins writes for More Content Now and Scripps Newspapers. He is past president of colleges and universities in four states and currently serves as executive director of a higher-education consulting service. You will find Hopkins’ latest book, “Journey to Gettysburg,” on Amazon.com. Contact him at presnet@presnet.net. 


About Us
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://gloucester.wickedlocal.com/storyimage/WL/20160811/NEWS/160819001/AR/0/AR-160819001.jpg</main_image>
</document>
