<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Muslim woman files suit against Chicago police after being mistaken for terrorist | Fox News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/08/12/muslim-woman-files-suit-against-chicago-police-after-being-mistaken-for-terrorist.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Muslim woman files suit against Chicago police after being mistaken for terrorist Published August 12, 2016 Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print 
CHICAGO – A young Muslim woman on Thursday sued Chicago police who mistakenly identified her briefly as a potential &quot;lone wolf&quot; terrorist as she was leaving a city subway station last year on the Fourth of July wearing a headscarf, face veil and carrying a backpack. 
Itemid Al-Matar says officers violated her civil rights by pulling off her religious garb as they arrested her on subway station stairs, then strip-searched her later at a police station, according to the federal lawsuit filed in Chicago on her behalf. 
&quot;Several (officers) ran up the stairs and grabbed the Plaintiff and threw her down upon the stair landing, then pulling at her and ripping off her hijab,&quot; it says. 
Security-camera video made public shows several minutes of the arrest in the subway. Several officers can be seen pushing through a crowd on a stairway to reach Al-Matar, but soon move out of view of the camera. 
The fact that Al-Matar was wearing a headscarf, known as a hijab, and the face veil, called a niqab, &quot;was the impetus behind the actions&quot; of the officers, the court filing alleges. In a statement Thursday, Phil Robertson, a lawyer for the Chicago chapter of the Council on American-Islamic Relations, or CAIR, and a co-counsel in the civil case, argued that &quot;blatant xenophobia, Islamophobia, and racial profiling&quot; underpinned the officers&apos; actions. 
A police report filed the night of the incident says officers had been &quot;on high alert of terrorist activity&quot; on the Fourth of July holiday when they spotted Al-Matar exhibiting what they believed was &quot;suspicious behavior,&quot; including walking at &quot;a brisk pace, in a determined manner.&quot; It also says officers saw what they thought could be &quot;incendiary devices&quot; around her ankles and were also suspicious of her backpack, which was clutched to her chest. 
&quot;(Officers) believed that subject might be a lone wolf suicide bomber and decided to attempt to take subject into custody,&quot; it says. 
A K-9 unit searched for explosive materials, the report says, &quot;with negative results,&quot; while &quot;the objects strapped around arrestee&apos;s ankles&quot; turned out to be &quot;ankle weights.&quot; But Al-Matar was still charged, including with obstructing justice after police accused her of resisting and refusing to comply with orders. She was acquitted on all charges at a state trial earlier this year. 
Thursday&apos;s lawsuit names six officers and the city of Chicago as defendants, accusing them of excessive force, false arrest, violation of freedom of religious expression and malicious prosecution. 
A police spokesman declined to comment specifically on the suit, saying the department doesn&apos;t comment on pending litigation. But police issued a brief written statement that says &quot;officers work hard each day to investigate suspicious activity and fight crime and we strive to treat all individuals with the highest levels of dignity of respect.&quot; The city&apos;s law department, which represents officers in civil litigation, declined comment. 
The case comes amid heightened scrutiny of city police. The release last year of a video showing a white officer fatally shooting black teenager Laquan McDonald 16 times sparked weeks of protests and led to an ongoing Department of Justice investigation of Chicago Police Department practices. Advertisement 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/08/12/muslim-woman-files-suit-against-chicago-police-after-being-mistaken-for-terrorist.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Muslim woman files suit against Chicago police after being mistaken for terrorist Published August 12, 2016 Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print 
CHICAGO – A young Muslim woman on Thursday sued Chicago police who mistakenly identified her briefly as a potential &quot;lone wolf&quot; terrorist as she was leaving a city subway station last year on the Fourth of July wearing a headscarf, face veil and carrying a backpack. 
Itemid Al-Matar says officers violated her civil rights by pulling off her religious garb as they arrested her on subway station stairs, then strip-searched her later at a police station, according to the federal lawsuit filed in Chicago on her behalf. 
&quot;Several (officers) ran up the stairs and grabbed the Plaintiff and threw her down upon the stair landing, then pulling at her and ripping off her hijab,&quot; it says. 
Security-camera video made public shows several minutes of the arrest in the subway. Several officers can be seen pushing through a crowd on a stairway to reach Al-Matar, but soon move out of view of the camera. 
The fact that Al-Matar was wearing a headscarf, known as a hijab, and the face veil, called a niqab, &quot;was the impetus behind the actions&quot; of the officers, the court filing alleges. In a statement Thursday, Phil Robertson, a lawyer for the Chicago chapter of the Council on American-Islamic Relations, or CAIR, and a co-counsel in the civil case, argued that &quot;blatant xenophobia, Islamophobia, and racial profiling&quot; underpinned the officers&apos; actions. 
A police report filed the night of the incident says officers had been &quot;on high alert of terrorist activity&quot; on the Fourth of July holiday when they spotted Al-Matar exhibiting what they believed was &quot;suspicious behavior,&quot; including walking at &quot;a brisk pace, in a determined manner.&quot; It also says officers saw what they thought could be &quot;incendiary devices&quot; around her ankles and were also suspicious of her backpack, which was clutched to her chest. 
&quot;(Officers) believed that subject might be a lone wolf suicide bomber and decided to attempt to take subject into custody,&quot; it says. 
A K-9 unit searched for explosive materials, the report says, &quot;with negative results,&quot; while &quot;the objects strapped around arrestee&apos;s ankles&quot; turned out to be &quot;ankle weights.&quot; But Al-Matar was still charged, including with obstructing justice after police accused her of resisting and refusing to comply with orders. She was acquitted on all charges at a state trial earlier this year. 
Thursday&apos;s lawsuit names six officers and the city of Chicago as defendants, accusing them of excessive force, false arrest, violation of freedom of religious expression and malicious prosecution. 
A police spokesman declined to comment specifically on the suit, saying the department doesn&apos;t comment on pending litigation. But police issued a brief written statement that says &quot;officers work hard each day to investigate suspicious activity and fight crime and we strive to treat all individuals with the highest levels of dignity of respect.&quot; The city&apos;s law department, which represents officers in civil litigation, declined comment. 
The case comes amid heightened scrutiny of city police. The release last year of a video showing a white officer fatally shooting black teenager Laquan McDonald 16 times sparked weeks of protests and led to an ongoing Department of Justice investigation of Chicago Police Department practices. Advertisement 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>EU</country>
<main_image>http://www.foxnews.com/content/dam/fox-news/logo/og-fn-foxnews.jpg</main_image>
</document>
