<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.eco-business.com/feeds/all/</forum>
<forum_title>Eco-Business</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Senior ESD Consultant</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.eco-business.com/jobs/senior-esd-consultant-5/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Apply now 
The Team 
Cundall’s ESD team’s mission is to play a key role in making the built environment a positive contributor to our social, environmental and economic needs. The ESD team works with Cundall’s wider global sustainable design practice which has delivered some of the most innovative and ecologically positive projects in a number of countries providing opportunities of knowledge sharing. 
The Role 
This is an excellent opportunity for a talented Senior ESD Consultant to strengthen and desirably lead our sustainable design team in our Perth office, to work on some of the most exciting projects in Australia and across the world. 
As part of our established multi-disciplinary team, and working closely with colleagues across multiple offices, you will analyse, report, model and document ESD strategies on projects and present to clients with the aim of achieving real sustainable outcomes. 
The role will include managing projects of all sizes, including day-to-day delivery, client relationships, financial performance, technical excellence and QA. With support from the rest of the leadership team, you will also take responsibility for securing work and positively contributing to strengthening our position as the pre-eminent ESD consultant in Perth and nationally, as well as developing our capabilities, our people and our business. 
Your work will span all sectors and offer a high degree of autonomy, based on the level of experience already gained in the industry. 
The Skills 
You will be educated to degree level in Engineering, the Built Environment or a related area, and have gained significant and broad-ranging experience in an ESD Consulting role (including thermal transfer, daylight, electrical lighting, fluid dynamics, thermal comfort, HVAC performance etc). You have practical experience in using Green Star and NABERS, and a good understanding of other ESD rating tools such as LEED and LBC, and have a passion for creative and intuitive design. You will also have experience of leading and managing projects and teams, and project financial performance. 
Given the collaborative and client focussed nature of this role, excellent communication skills and experience of using your initiative to overcome challenges are essential. Experience with energy modelling software (both Thermal and HVAC) and CFD modelling are desirable. Why this is a green job 
Cundall is committed to providing people with the knowledge, skills and enthusiasm to make a difference: in our homes, our offices, our projects, our industry and our community. We are the world’s first consultancy to be formally endorsed as a One Planet Company by sustainability charity BioRegional. 
Over the years, we have delivered many exemplar green buildings and have built up an international sustainable design expertise that is second to none. Share
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.eco-business.com/jobs/senior-esd-consultant-5/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0515</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Apply now 
The Team 
Cundall’s ESD team’s mission is to play a key role in making the built environment a positive contributor to our social, environmental and economic needs. The ESD team works with Cundall’s wider global sustainable design practice which has delivered some of the most innovative and ecologically positive projects in a number of countries providing opportunities of knowledge sharing. 
The Role 
This is an excellent opportunity for a talented Senior ESD Consultant to strengthen and desirably lead our sustainable design team in our Perth office, to work on some of the most exciting projects in Australia and across the world. 
As part of our established multi-disciplinary team, and working closely with colleagues across multiple offices, you will analyse, report, model and document ESD strategies on projects and present to clients with the aim of achieving real sustainable outcomes. 
The role will include managing projects of all sizes, including day-to-day delivery, client relationships, financial performance, technical excellence and QA. With support from the rest of the leadership team, you will also take responsibility for securing work and positively contributing to strengthening our position as the pre-eminent ESD consultant in Perth and nationally, as well as developing our capabilities, our people and our business. 
Your work will span all sectors and offer a high degree of autonomy, based on the level of experience already gained in the industry. 
The Skills 
You will be educated to degree level in Engineering, the Built Environment or a related area, and have gained significant and broad-ranging experience in an ESD Consulting role (including thermal transfer, daylight, electrical lighting, fluid dynamics, thermal comfort, HVAC performance etc). You have practical experience in using Green Star and NABERS, and a good understanding of other ESD rating tools such as LEED and LBC, and have a passion for creative and intuitive design. You will also have experience of leading and managing projects and teams, and project financial performance. 
Given the collaborative and client focussed nature of this role, excellent communication skills and experience of using your initiative to overcome challenges are essential. Experience with energy modelling software (both Thermal and HVAC) and CFD modelling are desirable. Why this is a green job 
Cundall is committed to providing people with the knowledge, skills and enthusiasm to make a difference: in our homes, our offices, our projects, our industry and our community. We are the world’s first consultancy to be formally endorsed as a One Planet Company by sustainability charity BioRegional. 
Over the years, we have delivered many exemplar green buildings and have built up an international sustainable design expertise that is second to none. Share
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SG</country>
<main_image>http://www.eco-business.com/media/cache/cb/f4/cbf4121487381d376802a0f355db3c1f.png</main_image>
</document>
