<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news</forum>
<forum_title>News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Political violence is no joke</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/opinion/political-violence-is-no-joke/ar-BBvuwwe</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Political violence is no joke The Washington Post 18 hrs ago William Kennedy Smith, Jean Kennedy Smith © John R. Fulton Jr./Associated Press Then-Sen. Robert F. Kennedy (D- N.Y.) informed people gathered in Indianapolis of the assassination of Martin Luther King Jr. on that day, April 4, 1968. William Kennedy Smith and Jean Kennedy Smith are the nephew and sister of President John. F. Kennedy and Sen. Robert F. Kennedy, who was assassinated on June 6, 1968.
On April 4, 1968, the day the Rev. Martin Luther King Jr. was shot and killed, Robert Kennedy was campaigning for the presidency in Indianapolis. Bobby conveyed the news of King’s death to a shattered, mostly black audience. He took pains to remind those whose first instinct may have been toward violence that President John F. Kennedy had also been shot and killed. Bobby went on , “What we need in the United States is not division; what we need in the United States is not hatred; what we need in the United States is not violence and lawlessness, but is love, and wisdom, and compassion toward one another, and a feeling of justice toward those who still suffer within our country, whether they be white or whether they be black.”
That speech has crystallized into the single most enduring portrait of Bobby’s candidacy. Because it was extemporaneous, it conveyed directly, and with raw emotion, his own vulnerability, his aspirations for his country and a deep compassion for the suffering of others. Bobby concluded his remarks that night by urging those listening to return home and say a prayer for our country and for our people. Those words mattered. While there were riots in cities across the nation that night, Indianapolis did not burn.
Today, almost 50 years later, words still matter. They shape who we are as a people and who we wish to be as a nation. In the white-hot cauldron of a presidential campaign, it is still the words delivered extemporaneously, off the cuff, in the raw pressure of the moment that matter most. They say most directly what is in a candidate’s heart. So it was with a real sense of sadness and revulsion that we listened to Donald Trump, the Republican nominee for president, as he referred to the options available to “ Second Amendment people ,” a remark widely, and we believe correctly, interpreted as a thinly veiled reference or “joke” about the possibility of political assassination.
Political violence is a terrible inherent risk to any free society. Dictators and strongmen like Vladimir Putin have an answer. They are surrounded and shielded by force at all times. They do not brook dissent. In democracies, we expect our leaders to be accessible and, by and large, they want to be. Inevitably, that makes them vulnerable and the loss of a leader at a crucial time impacts family, country and even the world, for generations. Anyone who loves politics, the open competition of ideas and public participation in a free society, knows that political violence is the greatest of all civic sins. It is not to be encouraged. It is not funny. It is not a joke.
By now, we have heard enough dark and offensive rhetoric from Trump to know that it reflects something fundamentally troubled, and troubling, about his candidacy. Trump’s remarks frequently, if not inevitably, spark outrage, which is followed by a clarification that, in lieu of an apology, seeks to attribute the dark undertones of his words to the listener’s twisted psyche. This fools no one. Whether you like what he is saying or, like a growing segment of the electorate, you reject it, it is easy to grasp Trump’s meaning from his words. But what to make of a candidate who directly appeals to violence, smears his opponents and publicly bullies a Gold Star family, a decorated prisoner of war and a reporter with a disability, among others? To borrow the words of Army Counsel Joseph Welch, directed at another dangerous demagogue : “Have you no sense of decency, sir, at long last? Have you left no sense of decency?”
The truth remains that words do matter, especially when it comes to presidential candidates. On that basis alone, Donald Trump is not qualified to be president of the United States.
Read more:
Paul Waldman: Trump’s latest outrageous statement wasn’t a ‘gaffe.’ It was something much worse.
Joe Scarborough: The GOP must dump Trump
The Post’s View: Donald Trump is a unique threat to American democracy
Go to MSN Home
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>4</post_num>
<post_id>post-4</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/opinion/political-violence-is-no-joke/ar-BBvuwwe</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1930</post_time>
<username>Anthony Deangelo</username>
<post>
I do not understand the mentality of the crump supporters. I now truly feel scared. Do you realize that all he has done is show the rest of the country who the racists are? I would have never believed that in this day and age that almost 14 million people are truly racist. It blows my mind that this many people have no empathy, kindness, tolerance, or good will towards anyone. The hate that this con artist generates should make all of you crump supporters cringe. Do you realize that your friends, family, co-workers now know just how you truly are behind closed doors. Is this what you truly feel? Is this how you want your children to feel? Hate everyone tolerate no one. Do you realize that all this guy did was expose you for who you truly are. Now I am sure most of you feel that this is not who you truly are but guilt by association is hard to overcome. Now your children will have that home grown racism that you project. Is this what you want to show your kids and grandkids? You will make your children embarrassed by your actions and words. Also remember unless you are Native American you are an immigrant. So you’re disgusted with Washington, so am I and everyone else. But that does not give anyone the right to bully, scream, shout, and pick fights with everyone who disagrees with you. Nor does it give anyone to incite violence to anyone. He calls them names and do everything he can to deflect from his own failures. You have been sold a bill of goods and the rest of the country knows it. But this is not about the crumpster it is about you his followers. My question to you is when did you get so much hate in your heart? Why do you go to extremes to make a point even down to calling someone you do not know names? Can any of you make a valid point without name calling? It’s ok to disagree it is not okay to try and degrade someone who does not agree with you. Ask yourself this, is this how I want my kids to behave when someone disagrees with them? Will this make them look strong or weak? It sure as hell is not helping the crumpster. All it does is deflect from the fact that he has no plans to benefit you his supporters. The things he says cannot happen and he cannot do any of those things without approval from the house and senate. Stop a minute, talk to someone who knows you and ask them was I always this way or did I change suddenly? But if this is who you truly are then ignore all the above. This is not an endorsement of any one this is a ides that we should all look at our own behavior and see if it is worthy of us as a person. It’s time to get away from the hatred and racism and get back to what is good for all of us now and in the future. By the way aren’t you tired of all the conspiracy theories that come out of his mouth without any credibility. The world is totally tired of it so I wonder why all of your aren’t. He puts forth words without showing how it will be completed. All he says is believe me. Well I now believe that with him in office (god forbid) this country will become the laughing stock of the world. He is too dangerous to be in office and more and more people are seeing it. Come November I want you to ask yourself why did I back this man? Was it worth all the humiliation he has put me and my family thru? Now everyone knows I am a racist, bigot, and prone to violence. How do you think your friends and family will view you in the future? And like your candidate do you support his call to violence? You cannot sweep away what comes out of his own mouth. But all of you do get a gold star in deflection
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
