<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.wsj.com/public/page/news-sports-scores.html</forum>
<forum_title>Sports News - The Wall Street Journal - Wsj.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Olympic Rugby’s Tiny Superpower</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wsj.com/articles/olympic-rugbys-tiny-superpower-1470957347</topic_url>
<topic_text>
3 COMMENTS Rio de Janeiro
After its appearance at the 1924 Summer Games, rugby spent 92 years in the Olympic wilderness. No one expected that when it finally returned, the sport’s undeniable superpower would be Fiji.
The South Pacific archipelago—population 880,000—didn’t just earn rugby sevens gold here on Thursday night, its first Olympic medal of any kind. It confirmed what Fiji coach Ben Ryan has been saying all along: the Fiji national team is the Harlem Globetrotters of rugby sevens.
With boundless style, Fiji pulverized Great Britain, inventors of the sport, 43-7. Great Britain, which had been undefeated in this tournament, was helpless in the face of the Fijian storm. Just nine minutes in, Britain was down 29-0.
“They get the ball and they’re absolutely wonderful with it,” Great Britain coach Simon Amor said of Fiji.
Rugby has been Fiji’s national sport for nearly a century. Nothing else even comes close. Though it has a competent 15-man team, which reached last year’s World Cup, the sevens game is its great love.
The secret is in the approach kids develop growing up in Fiji, some on the beach, some in concrete parking lots. Often using a plastic bottle full of sand instead of a ball, they spend their childhoods with a version of rugby called “one-touch”—if you get tackled, it’s an automatic turnover. “You have to keep the ball alive all the time,” Ryan said. “That’s why they play the high-risk.”
It’s also why they play with such flair. Fiji is, to all intents and purposes, the rugby world’s greatest ever pickup team.
“Before we go out, we always say to each other, ‘Hey, smile, smile, smile,’” said captain Osea Kolinisau. “When we’re smiling and enjoying ourselves, we play good rugby.”
Related
Rio 2016: Aly Raisman Defies Expectations, Except Her Own Aug. 11, 2016 The Shifting Fortunes of the 2012 London Stars Aug. 11, 2016 Team USA Owes Its Swimmers a Beer Aug. 11, 2016 It Would Be Dangerous if Phelps Wore All His Golds Aug. 11, 2016 Olympic Rugby’s Tiny Superpower Aug. 11, 2016 Rugby sevens already lends itself to a looser style of improvisational rugby that rewards speed, flair, and individual creativity. With only seven players per team and a 109-yard field usually occupied by 30 men, space is everywhere.
The challenge for Fiji has never been about talent but logistics. The team’s base is located on one of Fiji’s main islands called Viti Levu, but the other 350 islands that make up the country make scouting a logistical nightmare. Ryan relies on the networks created by Fiji’s main club teams, which are operated by the army, the prison service, the police, and the fire department.
“If they see someone playing on a far-flung island, they’ll probably give them a job on the mainland as a fireman or a policeman and then I get to see them play,” Ryan said. “In many ways you don’t have many to choose from, you don’t miss many either.”
A Cambridge graduate who coached Great Britain from 2007 to 2013, Ryan joined the Fijian program three years ago. And, like the sport itself, his setup is bare bones. Ryan even spent his first few months in the gig working for free due to the Fijian Rugby Union’s financial woes.
In addition to being the head coach, Ryan is the self-appointed team nutritionist, psychologist and fitness coach. There are no video analysts, the way there were during Ryan’s time in England, he said, because a 14-minute game requires barely any tape study.
“My whole philosophy is to keep things simple and empower your team,” Ryan said. “We have a very simple framework. We have an unstructured-structured game.”
Unlike teams like South Africa or the U.S., Fiji doesn’t have a playbook. It doesn’t rehearse routines either. Ryan said he sets out three or four general principles and lets the players take it from there. He declined to say what those principles were, but watch Fiji play and they won’t stay secret.
Run for days, break through the lines, and don’t overthink it.
“They’re all celebrating [back home]. They’ve been celebrating for three days,” Fiji’s prime minister Frank Bainimarama said in the stadium. “We hope the brand of rugby we played today has justified its inclusion.”
Write to Joshua Robinson at joshua.robinson@wsj.com
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wsj.com/articles/olympic-rugbys-tiny-superpower-1470957347</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2032</post_time>
<username>Joshua Robinson</username>
<post>
3 COMMENTS Rio de Janeiro
After its appearance at the 1924 Summer Games, rugby spent 92 years in the Olympic wilderness. No one expected that when it finally returned, the sport’s undeniable superpower would be Fiji.
The South Pacific archipelago—population 880,000—didn’t just earn rugby sevens gold here on Thursday night, its first Olympic medal of any kind. It confirmed what Fiji coach Ben Ryan has been saying all along: the Fiji national team is the Harlem Globetrotters of rugby sevens.
With boundless style, Fiji pulverized Great Britain, inventors of the sport, 43-7. Great Britain, which had been undefeated in this tournament, was helpless in the face of the Fijian storm. Just nine minutes in, Britain was down 29-0.
“They get the ball and they’re absolutely wonderful with it,” Great Britain coach Simon Amor said of Fiji.
Rugby has been Fiji’s national sport for nearly a century. Nothing else even comes close. Though it has a competent 15-man team, which reached last year’s World Cup, the sevens game is its great love.
The secret is in the approach kids develop growing up in Fiji, some on the beach, some in concrete parking lots. Often using a plastic bottle full of sand instead of a ball, they spend their childhoods with a version of rugby called “one-touch”—if you get tackled, it’s an automatic turnover. “You have to keep the ball alive all the time,” Ryan said. “That’s why they play the high-risk.”
It’s also why they play with such flair. Fiji is, to all intents and purposes, the rugby world’s greatest ever pickup team.
“Before we go out, we always say to each other, ‘Hey, smile, smile, smile,’” said captain Osea Kolinisau. “When we’re smiling and enjoying ourselves, we play good rugby.”
Related
Rio 2016: Aly Raisman Defies Expectations, Except Her Own Aug. 11, 2016 The Shifting Fortunes of the 2012 London Stars Aug. 11, 2016 Team USA Owes Its Swimmers a Beer Aug. 11, 2016 It Would Be Dangerous if Phelps Wore All His Golds Aug. 11, 2016 Olympic Rugby’s Tiny Superpower Aug. 11, 2016 Rugby sevens already lends itself to a looser style of improvisational rugby that rewards speed, flair, and individual creativity. With only seven players per team and a 109-yard field usually occupied by 30 men, space is everywhere.
The challenge for Fiji has never been about talent but logistics. The team’s base is located on one of Fiji’s main islands called Viti Levu, but the other 350 islands that make up the country make scouting a logistical nightmare. Ryan relies on the networks created by Fiji’s main club teams, which are operated by the army, the prison service, the police, and the fire department.
“If they see someone playing on a far-flung island, they’ll probably give them a job on the mainland as a fireman or a policeman and then I get to see them play,” Ryan said. “In many ways you don’t have many to choose from, you don’t miss many either.”
A Cambridge graduate who coached Great Britain from 2007 to 2013, Ryan joined the Fijian program three years ago. And, like the sport itself, his setup is bare bones. Ryan even spent his first few months in the gig working for free due to the Fijian Rugby Union’s financial woes.
In addition to being the head coach, Ryan is the self-appointed team nutritionist, psychologist and fitness coach. There are no video analysts, the way there were during Ryan’s time in England, he said, because a 14-minute game requires barely any tape study.
“My whole philosophy is to keep things simple and empower your team,” Ryan said. “We have a very simple framework. We have an unstructured-structured game.”
Unlike teams like South Africa or the U.S., Fiji doesn’t have a playbook. It doesn’t rehearse routines either. Ryan said he sets out three or four general principles and lets the players take it from there. He declined to say what those principles were, but watch Fiji play and they won’t stay secret.
Run for days, break through the lines, and don’t overthink it.
“They’re all celebrating [back home]. They’ve been celebrating for three days,” Fiji’s prime minister Frank Bainimarama said in the stadium. “We hope the brand of rugby we played today has justified its inclusion.”
Write to Joshua Robinson at joshua.robinson@wsj.com
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-PJ273_OLYFIJ_G_20160811185052.jpg</main_image>
</document>
