<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Bill seeks to protect pets from suffering in hot cars | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/bill-seeks-to-protect-pets-from-suffering-in-hot-cars/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Bill seeks to protect pets from suffering in hot cars The bill would also tighten restrictions on chaining up dogs outside Andy Metzger, State House News Service Published: August 11, 2016, 11:03 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
BOSTON (STATE HOUSE NEWS SERVICE) — As a dog owner, Gov. Charlie Baker agrees in concept with one of the major aspects of an animal protection bill sent his way Thursday. 
The bill would allow first-responders encountering a pet in a hot or cold car to break the window before the situation becomes completely dire for the animal, and it would allow passersby to break those car windows after calling 911 if the animal is in “imminent danger,” according to Kara Holmquist, director of advocacy for the Massachusetts Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. 
“We have rules in state law with respect to hot cars and child endangerment associated with that. I certainly think as a dog owner that there probably ought to be similar standards for animals as well,” Baker told reporters on Thursday after the bill was sent to his desk. “I think our hope and our expectation is that nobody ever has to break anybody’s window for anybody – child or an animal.” 
The governor said his “adorable” dog Lucy is schnauzer-poodle mix known as a schnoodle. 
Holmquist said Florida, Ohio, Tennessee, Vermont and Wisconsin all already allow non-first responders to step in and take action when animals are enclosed in dangerously hot cars. 
According to Holmquist, the bill would also tighten restrictions on chaining up dogs outside, making it “more enforceable.” The current law bans tethering pooches for 24 hours, meaning animal control officers would need to watch that whole time, according to Holmquist. The bill bans tethering dogs between 10 p.m. and 6 a.m., which Holmquist said is a time period particularly dangerous in the depths of winter. The night hours also introduce dangers posed by wild animals and increase the nuisance factor of chained-up dogs keeping neighbors up in the night with their barking, Holmquist noted. 
The bill would also allow MSPCA and Animal Rescue League officers to write civil citations for certain offenses against animals, such as keeping them in cruel conditions, Holmquist said. 
Overall, Holmquist said, the bill aims to help animals “out of situations before they escalate.” 
“In some of these cases, animals die,” Holmquist told the News Service. 
The animal protection legislation originally filed by New Bedford Democrat Sen. Mark Montigny was among a crush of bills lawmakers raced to finish the last weekend in July before the final formal session of the year. The animal-protection bill wasn’t finished then, but House and Senate lawmakers were able to wrap it up and send it to the governor in lightly attended informal sessions in August. 
Other priorities of animal advocates remain unfinished so far this session – including bills passed by the Senate regulating puppy and kitten sales and seeking to protect animals left behind at vacant properties after foreclosures. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/bill-seeks-to-protect-pets-from-suffering-in-hot-cars/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Andy Metzger</username>
<post>
Bill seeks to protect pets from suffering in hot cars The bill would also tighten restrictions on chaining up dogs outside Andy Metzger, State House News Service Published: August 11, 2016, 11:03 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
BOSTON (STATE HOUSE NEWS SERVICE) — As a dog owner, Gov. Charlie Baker agrees in concept with one of the major aspects of an animal protection bill sent his way Thursday. 
The bill would allow first-responders encountering a pet in a hot or cold car to break the window before the situation becomes completely dire for the animal, and it would allow passersby to break those car windows after calling 911 if the animal is in “imminent danger,” according to Kara Holmquist, director of advocacy for the Massachusetts Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. 
“We have rules in state law with respect to hot cars and child endangerment associated with that. I certainly think as a dog owner that there probably ought to be similar standards for animals as well,” Baker told reporters on Thursday after the bill was sent to his desk. “I think our hope and our expectation is that nobody ever has to break anybody’s window for anybody – child or an animal.” 
The governor said his “adorable” dog Lucy is schnauzer-poodle mix known as a schnoodle. 
Holmquist said Florida, Ohio, Tennessee, Vermont and Wisconsin all already allow non-first responders to step in and take action when animals are enclosed in dangerously hot cars. 
According to Holmquist, the bill would also tighten restrictions on chaining up dogs outside, making it “more enforceable.” The current law bans tethering pooches for 24 hours, meaning animal control officers would need to watch that whole time, according to Holmquist. The bill bans tethering dogs between 10 p.m. and 6 a.m., which Holmquist said is a time period particularly dangerous in the depths of winter. The night hours also introduce dangers posed by wild animals and increase the nuisance factor of chained-up dogs keeping neighbors up in the night with their barking, Holmquist noted. 
The bill would also allow MSPCA and Animal Rescue League officers to write civil citations for certain offenses against animals, such as keeping them in cruel conditions, Holmquist said. 
Overall, Holmquist said, the bill aims to help animals “out of situations before they escalate.” 
“In some of these cases, animals die,” Holmquist told the News Service. 
The animal protection legislation originally filed by New Bedford Democrat Sen. Mark Montigny was among a crush of bills lawmakers raced to finish the last weekend in July before the final formal session of the year. The animal-protection bill wasn’t finished then, but House and Senate lawmakers were able to wrap it up and send it to the governor in lightly attended informal sessions in August. 
Other priorities of animal advocates remain unfinished so far this session – including bills passed by the Senate regulating puppy and kitten sales and seeking to protect animals left behind at vacant properties after foreclosures. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/parked-cars.jpg?w=1200</main_image>
</document>
