<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.motorsportchannel.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>MotorsportChannel.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Audi DTM Star Mortara joins R8 LMS Cup run at Sepang</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.motorsportchannel.com/audi-dtm-star-mortara-joins-r8-lms-cup-run-sepang/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
12 Aug. 2016 | Ernest C. Domestic Motorsports News , Motorsport All sights are set on the Sepang International Circuit as the Audi R8 LMS Cup returns to Malaysia’s one and only Formula One track. Qualifying is slated for tomorrow, followed by the two races on Sunday. Audi DTM driver Edoardo Mortara is set to join Reigning Audi R8 LMS Cup Champion Alex Yoong and the rest of the series’ drivers on track, over the weekend. 
Competing on home ground as defending champion,Yoong is set to square off against Mortara and current standings leader Alessio Picariello. Picariello currently leads the standings by a hairline (65 points total) as only four points separate the top three contenders. The MGT Team by Absolute driver has pulled into an overall points lead with three second-place finishes from the first four races of the Cup ’s fifth season. 
Mortara, Audi Hong Kong’s representative, will look for a win in the series at the 5.5 kilometer long Sepang track. In his previous appearance, Mortara won the first race of the triple-header in Taiwan in 2015. The Italian is known in motorsport as “Mr. Macau” for winning the Macau GP Formula 3 race twice, before securing an Audi R8 LMS Cup race win and a hat trick (2011-2013) of GT Cup victories on the demanding street circuit. Mortara is currently third in the DTM drivers’ standings. His main competitor Yoong, the former F1 driver, captured his first win of the year at Round 3 in Thailand, finishing ahead of Picariello. The Malaysian is currently just 3 points behind Picariello, therefore the local round should present a good chance for Yoong to snatch the standings lead from the rookie R8 LMS Cup driver. 
Rounding up the top three, Martin Rump (61 points) of Champion Racing Team travels to Sepang as the only driver to have recorded two wins this year. Hailing from Estonia and having won last year’s Formula Masters China Series (FMCS) championship, this series contender has managed the transition from single-seater racing to GT3 cars in remarkable fashion thus far. Fourth overall is Marchy Lee (49 points) of team Audi Hong Kong. 
After sweeping back-to-back wins in Thailand, Jeffrey Lee of Team Audi Volkswagen leads the Amateur Cup classification ahead of Sun Jingzu and Johnson Huang, both of Absolute Racing. Qualifying starts on Saturday afternoon, then the two rounds on Sunday. 
The R8 LMS Cup one-make series is organized by Audi China and is part of the Audi Sport customer racing Asia program. The championship is run in cooperation with FAW-Volkswagen Audi, Audi Hong Kong, Audi Korea, Audi Taiwan and Audi Malaysia. Link to this post!
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.motorsportchannel.com/audi-dtm-star-mortara-joins-r8-lms-cup-run-sepang/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0535</post_time>
<username>Ernest C.</username>
<post>
12 Aug. 2016 | Ernest C. Domestic Motorsports News , Motorsport All sights are set on the Sepang International Circuit as the Audi R8 LMS Cup returns to Malaysia’s one and only Formula One track. Qualifying is slated for tomorrow, followed by the two races on Sunday. Audi DTM driver Edoardo Mortara is set to join Reigning Audi R8 LMS Cup Champion Alex Yoong and the rest of the series’ drivers on track, over the weekend. 
Competing on home ground as defending champion,Yoong is set to square off against Mortara and current standings leader Alessio Picariello. Picariello currently leads the standings by a hairline (65 points total) as only four points separate the top three contenders. The MGT Team by Absolute driver has pulled into an overall points lead with three second-place finishes from the first four races of the Cup ’s fifth season. 
Mortara, Audi Hong Kong’s representative, will look for a win in the series at the 5.5 kilometer long Sepang track. In his previous appearance, Mortara won the first race of the triple-header in Taiwan in 2015. The Italian is known in motorsport as “Mr. Macau” for winning the Macau GP Formula 3 race twice, before securing an Audi R8 LMS Cup race win and a hat trick (2011-2013) of GT Cup victories on the demanding street circuit. Mortara is currently third in the DTM drivers’ standings. His main competitor Yoong, the former F1 driver, captured his first win of the year at Round 3 in Thailand, finishing ahead of Picariello. The Malaysian is currently just 3 points behind Picariello, therefore the local round should present a good chance for Yoong to snatch the standings lead from the rookie R8 LMS Cup driver. 
Rounding up the top three, Martin Rump (61 points) of Champion Racing Team travels to Sepang as the only driver to have recorded two wins this year. Hailing from Estonia and having won last year’s Formula Masters China Series (FMCS) championship, this series contender has managed the transition from single-seater racing to GT3 cars in remarkable fashion thus far. Fourth overall is Marchy Lee (49 points) of team Audi Hong Kong. 
After sweeping back-to-back wins in Thailand, Jeffrey Lee of Team Audi Volkswagen leads the Amateur Cup classification ahead of Sun Jingzu and Johnson Huang, both of Absolute Racing. Qualifying starts on Saturday afternoon, then the two rounds on Sunday. 
The R8 LMS Cup one-make series is organized by Audi China and is part of the Audi Sport customer racing Asia program. The championship is run in cooperation with FAW-Volkswagen Audi, Audi Hong Kong, Audi Korea, Audi Taiwan and Audi Malaysia. Link to this post!
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>MY</country>
<main_image>http://www.motorsportchannel.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Pic-5_resize.jpg</main_image>
</document>
