<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://feeds.dailycamera.com/mngi/rss/CustomRssServlet/21/219918.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Recreation Columnists</forum_title>
<discussion_title>August Nature Walk: Wild Basin Horse Trail</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.dailycamera.com/recreation/ci_30235963/august-nature-walk-wild-basin-horse-trail</topic_url>
<topic_text>
August Nature Walk: Wild Basin Horse Trail By Ruth Carol Cushman and Glenn Cushman 
For the Camera Posted: 08/11/2016 10:23:40 PM MDT Updated: 08/11/2016 10:24:19 PM MDT North St. Vrain Creek continues to rumble and tumble below Copeland Falls. ( Glenn Cushman / Courtesy photo ) 
If you go 
Highlights: Waterfalls, wildlife, wildflowers, mountain views 
Distance: 2.3 miles one way from Copeland Lake to Copeland Falls. Or, you can walk shorter segments of the trail; the portion we did was about 1.3 miles. 
Elevation: From 8,300 feet at Copeland Lake to about 8,600 feet at Copeland Falls 
Difficulty: Easy to moderate, depending on how far you go 
Access: Take U.S. 36 north to Lyons. Turn left onto Colo. 7 and continue to the Wild Basin turnoff, about 2 miles northwest of Allenspark. Try to arrive early on a week-day to avoid the crowds, but even later in the day, the park rangers are helpful about directing you to a suitable spot. 
Last year Elizabeth Mekkelsen — then 101 years old — and Ruth Carol stumbled on a shady, un-crowded, creek-side trail in Wild Basin in Rocky Mountain National Park. 
This summer, we returned and re-found the trail, called simply &quot;The Horse Trail&quot; that&apos;s not even on the Rocky Mountain National Park map. For an easy trail in RMNP, it was surprisingly un-crowded. Although the soft dirt trail is designed for horses, it&apos;s one hikers can also enjoy. 
Even at 10 a.m., the Wild Basin parking lot was full. However, you can join the Horse Trail at several points along a route parallelling North St. Vrain Creek from Copeland Lake to Copeland Falls. All the &quot;Copeland&quot; features are named for Don Copeland who homesteaded here in the 19th century. Advertisement 
We joined the trail a short distance before the road to the Wild Basin parking area crosses the creek on a wooden bridge, about a mile in from the fee station. Although it&apos;s hard to find any signs, the trail itself is not hard to find. It runs near the road, on the south side. 
Other good entry points are from the Finch Lake Trailhead, the Wild Basin Ranger Station and at Copeland Lake, where you can park at the second parking area and walk around a wooden fence. Mountain views are especially spectacular as you walk west from Copeland Lake. Copeland Falls tumble over granite boulders in North St. Vrain Creek. ( Glenn Cushman / Courtesy photo ) 
The trail heads up through a forest of aspen and mixed conifer with aspen predominating at lower elevations and spruce and fir as you ascend. Holly grape, kinnikinnik and blueberries make up the understory. We even managed to find a couple of ripe blueberries. 
At the Finch Lake Trailhead, a trail to the left leads to Finch and Pear Lakes. Continue on the Horse Trail for about half a mile to another intersection. 
From this intersection, the Horse Trail heads up to Copeland Falls in about half a mile, a short distance beyond the hitching area for horses. The right-hand trail goes to the Ranger Station and to the Wild Basin Trailhead, where there&apos;s a trail to the north side of Copeland Falls and then on to Calypso Cascades, Ouzel Falls and more lakes. 
We sat on the boulders south of the falls watching the roiling, boiling waters, and as we munched lunch, a dipper flew by. A path continues uphill from the falls but eventually peters out. There&apos;s no way to cross from here to the main trail up to Calypso Cascades and beyond. A ranger we chatted with said Hidden Falls, a favorite ice-climbing route in winter, is the source for two ephemeral streams to the left of this rough trail. 
Elizabeth and Ruth Carol returned on Aug. 8 and found golden and lavender asters in bloom and red &quot;Fairy Bell&quot; berries dangling over the creek. In late May, Wild Basin is lush with orchids, including fairy slippers, brownie lady&apos;s slippers and coralroots. 
We hope to return in autumn when the aspen turn to gold. 
Ruth Carol and Glenn Cushman are the authors of &quot;Boulder Hiking Trails,&quot; published by Graphic Arts Books
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.dailycamera.com/recreation/ci_30235963/august-nature-walk-wild-basin-horse-trail</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0424</post_time>
<username>Ruth Carol Cushman and Glenn Cushman 

For the Camera</username>
<post>
August Nature Walk: Wild Basin Horse Trail By Ruth Carol Cushman and Glenn Cushman 
For the Camera Posted: 08/11/2016 10:23:40 PM MDT Updated: 08/11/2016 10:24:19 PM MDT North St. Vrain Creek continues to rumble and tumble below Copeland Falls. ( Glenn Cushman / Courtesy photo ) 
If you go 
Highlights: Waterfalls, wildlife, wildflowers, mountain views 
Distance: 2.3 miles one way from Copeland Lake to Copeland Falls. Or, you can walk shorter segments of the trail; the portion we did was about 1.3 miles. 
Elevation: From 8,300 feet at Copeland Lake to about 8,600 feet at Copeland Falls 
Difficulty: Easy to moderate, depending on how far you go 
Access: Take U.S. 36 north to Lyons. Turn left onto Colo. 7 and continue to the Wild Basin turnoff, about 2 miles northwest of Allenspark. Try to arrive early on a week-day to avoid the crowds, but even later in the day, the park rangers are helpful about directing you to a suitable spot. 
Last year Elizabeth Mekkelsen — then 101 years old — and Ruth Carol stumbled on a shady, un-crowded, creek-side trail in Wild Basin in Rocky Mountain National Park. 
This summer, we returned and re-found the trail, called simply &quot;The Horse Trail&quot; that&apos;s not even on the Rocky Mountain National Park map. For an easy trail in RMNP, it was surprisingly un-crowded. Although the soft dirt trail is designed for horses, it&apos;s one hikers can also enjoy. 
Even at 10 a.m., the Wild Basin parking lot was full. However, you can join the Horse Trail at several points along a route parallelling North St. Vrain Creek from Copeland Lake to Copeland Falls. All the &quot;Copeland&quot; features are named for Don Copeland who homesteaded here in the 19th century. Advertisement 
We joined the trail a short distance before the road to the Wild Basin parking area crosses the creek on a wooden bridge, about a mile in from the fee station. Although it&apos;s hard to find any signs, the trail itself is not hard to find. It runs near the road, on the south side. 
Other good entry points are from the Finch Lake Trailhead, the Wild Basin Ranger Station and at Copeland Lake, where you can park at the second parking area and walk around a wooden fence. Mountain views are especially spectacular as you walk west from Copeland Lake. Copeland Falls tumble over granite boulders in North St. Vrain Creek. ( Glenn Cushman / Courtesy photo ) 
The trail heads up through a forest of aspen and mixed conifer with aspen predominating at lower elevations and spruce and fir as you ascend. Holly grape, kinnikinnik and blueberries make up the understory. We even managed to find a couple of ripe blueberries. 
At the Finch Lake Trailhead, a trail to the left leads to Finch and Pear Lakes. Continue on the Horse Trail for about half a mile to another intersection. 
From this intersection, the Horse Trail heads up to Copeland Falls in about half a mile, a short distance beyond the hitching area for horses. The right-hand trail goes to the Ranger Station and to the Wild Basin Trailhead, where there&apos;s a trail to the north side of Copeland Falls and then on to Calypso Cascades, Ouzel Falls and more lakes. 
We sat on the boulders south of the falls watching the roiling, boiling waters, and as we munched lunch, a dipper flew by. A path continues uphill from the falls but eventually peters out. There&apos;s no way to cross from here to the main trail up to Calypso Cascades and beyond. A ranger we chatted with said Hidden Falls, a favorite ice-climbing route in winter, is the source for two ephemeral streams to the left of this rough trail. 
Elizabeth and Ruth Carol returned on Aug. 8 and found golden and lavender asters in bloom and red &quot;Fairy Bell&quot; berries dangling over the creek. In late May, Wild Basin is lush with orchids, including fairy slippers, brownie lady&apos;s slippers and coralroots. 
We hope to return in autumn when the aspen turn to gold. 
Ruth Carol and Glenn Cushman are the authors of &quot;Boulder Hiking Trails,&quot; published by Graphic Arts Books
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://extras.mnginteractive.com/live/media/site21/2016/0811/20160811__12DCGCEN~3.jpg</main_image>
</document>
