<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news</forum>
<forum_title>News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Police: 3 victims in serial killer case shot sitting in car</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/crime/police-3-victims-in-serial-killer-case-shot-sitting-in-car/ar-BBvwGKl</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Police: 3 victims in serial killer case shot sitting in car Associated Press 4 hrs ago By JACQUES BILLEAUD, Associated Press © AP Photo/Matt York FILE - In this July 27, 2016 photo, flowers are seen outside the home where a suspected serial killer murdered a man earlier in the year in Phoenix. PHOENIX — Two women and a 12-year-old girl who died in the deadliest attack in Phoenix&apos;s first serial killer case in a decade were sitting in a car talking and listening to music when they were shot, according to police reports released Thursday.
Angela Rochelle Liner, Stefanie R. Ellis and Ellis&apos; daughter Maleah were shot on June 12 while the car was parked in a driveway, authorities said.
The gunman fired as many as eight shots from a handgun while standing on the passenger side of the car then fled in another vehicle, the report states.
Police say the triple killing doesn&apos;t appear to have been the result of a robbery because the attacker didn&apos;t take purses or $2,900 in the possession of one of the adult victims.
Phoenix police spokesman Sgt. Jonathan Howard said the shooting prompted investigators to look at whether it was tied to four earlier attacks.
In all, seven people have been killed and two others wounded in nine attacks in two predominantly Hispanic neighborhoods over a four-month period.
Police say the shootings are being carried out by a man who shoots victims from a car or briefly steps out to attack them at close range before driving away.
The suspect is believed to have used several vehicles, including a late-1990s brown Nissan, a late-1990s black BMW and a white Cadillac or Lincoln.
Investigators have declined to reveal the evidence that led them to conclude the attacks are related and committed by the same killer. No motive has been established.
Ellis, 33, was hospitalized for her injuries and later died. Liner, 31, and Ellis&apos; daughter Maleah died at the scene.
A witness told police that it wasn&apos;t unusual for them to sit in a parked car listening to music.
Authorities also released a police report on a shooting that targeted an unoccupied pickup truck just a half-hour before the triple killing and is believed to have been the work of the serial killer.
Investigators found bullet casings and recovered a bullet from a seat and bullet fragments from the engine compartment.
___
Follow Jacques Billeaud at twitter.com/jacquesbilleaud. His work can be found at http://bigstory.ap.org/content/jacques-billeaud.
Go to MSN Home
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>47</post_num>
<post_id>post-47</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/crime/police-3-victims-in-serial-killer-case-shot-sitting-in-car/ar-BBvwGKl</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0518</post_time>
<username>Manuel Moreno</username>
<post>
Ken Javor, yep Ken, be afraid be very afraid!
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
