<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Special:NewPages&amp;feed=atom</forum>
<forum_title>Wikipedia - New pages [en]</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Nawagamuwa Pattini Devalaya</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nawagamuwa_Pattini_Devalaya</topic_url>
<topic_text>
at 05:38 UTC ( 0 seconds ago ) Nawagamuwa Pattini Devalaya 16th and 19th Century Architecture Number of temples Viharaya (Pilimage), Maha Pattini Devalaya, Dedimunda Devalaya, Kataragama Devalaya, Vishnu Devalaya, Saman Devalaya and Moratu Devalaya History and governance Gajabahu I (A.D. 114 - 136) Built for Perform Rituals for Goddess Pattini Demolished Perform Rituals for Enshrine Gods Type National Historic Site of Sri Lanka Part of Sri Lankan Buddhist and Hindu Culture 
Among the archaeologically significant sites in the Colombo District, Nawagamuwa Pattini Devalaya is important as a historic place of worship [1] . The Devalaya is dedicated to Goddess Pattini . Buddhists as well as non-Buddhists perform puja to the deity with the intention of getting blessings for children and pregnant mothers [2] . The Maha Pattini Devalaya, the main shrine of the area, has been built during the 19th century. A gilded statue of the Goddess Pattini is enshrined in it. There are five other shrines stands in a row in front of the Maha [3] Devalaya. Out of these Dedimunda, Kataragama and Vishnu Devalayas belongs to the 19th century, however others are built recently. During a recent research conducted by the Department of Archaeology, Viharage, Sangavasaya (the Monks abode), Galkanu Devalaya, Maha Pattini Devale, along with these three ancient shrines has declared as archaeologically important sites [2] . Legends [ edit ] 
Legend has it that the origin of this Pattini Devalaya close to the Kelani River goes back to the early Anuradhapura period [1] . As the legend unfolds King Gajabahu I of Anuradhapura (A.D. 114 - 136) came from India with 12,000 men as prisoners, bringing with him a Pattini anklet, he landed at a place close to devalaya. Devalaya was built enshrining the anklet [2] [1] . A different version of this legend is that Goddess Pattini arrived at this place from India with 12,000 devotees belonging to 16 castes. The men and women settled down in adjacent villages to serve the goddess [2] . History [ edit ] 
Archaeological research has revealed several sites in the Nawagamuwa area to confirm that settlements in the area date back to a B.C. era [1] . The first historical mention of the Nawagamuwa Pattini Devale is found during the Kotte period, in the ‘Godagama Sannasa’, it is said that King Buwanekabahu V the Last King of Kingdom of Gampola , a gift of oil is made for the Nawagamuwa Pattini Kovil Perahera [2] . During the period of Kingdom of Sitawaka King Mayadunne of Sitawaka (A.D. 1521 - 1580) had stopped at the Nawagamuwa Pattini Devale to make a vow before he went to war with the Portuguese in the Colombo Fort. According to the reports of the Portuguese, in 1550, the King of Portuguese sent 600 troops to help King Bhuvanaikabahu VII of Kotte . They fought with King Mayadunne at Nawagamuwa. It is also recorded that in 1576, the Portuguese army destroyed Nawagamuwa Devale and established an army camp there [2] . It is also recorded that in 1576, the Portuguese army destroyed Nawagamuwa Devale and established an army camp there. The devalaya was rebuilt by King Mayadunne only to be destroyed again by the Captain of the Colombo fort, leaving a pile of ruins [2] [1] . Mr. A.E.L.Tillekewardene of the Archaeological Department says that according to popular beliefs and historical data, Nawagamuwa devalaya was known as a pilgrim site from the beginning of the 15th century. Excavations around the devalaya from time to time unearthed building materials, wells, Dutch coins and iron implements of the Middle Ages . North of the old devalaya at what was known as the old landing place, coins used during the period of Dutch Ceylon , 1640–1796, have been found [1] . The Latest restoration of the Devalaya was by Katuwawala Sri Sumanatissa Thero, the chief priest of the temple during A.D. 1813 – 1928. Sri Sumanatissa Thero constructed the monks abode or Sanghavasaya and the Vihare or Pilimage in 1894 [1] .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nawagamuwa_Pattini_Devalaya</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0531</post_time>
<username>Sumanabandara</username>
<post>
at 05:38 UTC ( 0 seconds ago ) Nawagamuwa Pattini Devalaya 16th and 19th Century Architecture Number of temples Viharaya (Pilimage), Maha Pattini Devalaya, Dedimunda Devalaya, Kataragama Devalaya, Vishnu Devalaya, Saman Devalaya and Moratu Devalaya History and governance Gajabahu I (A.D. 114 - 136) Built for Perform Rituals for Goddess Pattini Demolished Perform Rituals for Enshrine Gods Type National Historic Site of Sri Lanka Part of Sri Lankan Buddhist and Hindu Culture 
Among the archaeologically significant sites in the Colombo District, Nawagamuwa Pattini Devalaya is important as a historic place of worship [1] . The Devalaya is dedicated to Goddess Pattini . Buddhists as well as non-Buddhists perform puja to the deity with the intention of getting blessings for children and pregnant mothers [2] . The Maha Pattini Devalaya, the main shrine of the area, has been built during the 19th century. A gilded statue of the Goddess Pattini is enshrined in it. There are five other shrines stands in a row in front of the Maha [3] Devalaya. Out of these Dedimunda, Kataragama and Vishnu Devalayas belongs to the 19th century, however others are built recently. During a recent research conducted by the Department of Archaeology, Viharage, Sangavasaya (the Monks abode), Galkanu Devalaya, Maha Pattini Devale, along with these three ancient shrines has declared as archaeologically important sites [2] . Legends [ edit ] 
Legend has it that the origin of this Pattini Devalaya close to the Kelani River goes back to the early Anuradhapura period [1] . As the legend unfolds King Gajabahu I of Anuradhapura (A.D. 114 - 136) came from India with 12,000 men as prisoners, bringing with him a Pattini anklet, he landed at a place close to devalaya. Devalaya was built enshrining the anklet [2] [1] . A different version of this legend is that Goddess Pattini arrived at this place from India with 12,000 devotees belonging to 16 castes. The men and women settled down in adjacent villages to serve the goddess [2] . History [ edit ] 
Archaeological research has revealed several sites in the Nawagamuwa area to confirm that settlements in the area date back to a B.C. era [1] . The first historical mention of the Nawagamuwa Pattini Devale is found during the Kotte period, in the ‘Godagama Sannasa’, it is said that King Buwanekabahu V the Last King of Kingdom of Gampola , a gift of oil is made for the Nawagamuwa Pattini Kovil Perahera [2] . During the period of Kingdom of Sitawaka King Mayadunne of Sitawaka (A.D. 1521 - 1580) had stopped at the Nawagamuwa Pattini Devale to make a vow before he went to war with the Portuguese in the Colombo Fort. According to the reports of the Portuguese, in 1550, the King of Portuguese sent 600 troops to help King Bhuvanaikabahu VII of Kotte . They fought with King Mayadunne at Nawagamuwa. It is also recorded that in 1576, the Portuguese army destroyed Nawagamuwa Devale and established an army camp there [2] . It is also recorded that in 1576, the Portuguese army destroyed Nawagamuwa Devale and established an army camp there. The devalaya was rebuilt by King Mayadunne only to be destroyed again by the Captain of the Colombo fort, leaving a pile of ruins [2] [1] . Mr. A.E.L.Tillekewardene of the Archaeological Department says that according to popular beliefs and historical data, Nawagamuwa devalaya was known as a pilgrim site from the beginning of the 15th century. Excavations around the devalaya from time to time unearthed building materials, wells, Dutch coins and iron implements of the Middle Ages . North of the old devalaya at what was known as the old landing place, coins used during the period of Dutch Ceylon , 1640–1796, have been found [1] . The Latest restoration of the Devalaya was by Katuwawala Sri Sumanatissa Thero, the chief priest of the temple during A.D. 1813 – 1928. Sri Sumanatissa Thero constructed the monks abode or Sanghavasaya and the Vihare or Pilimage in 1894 [1] .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>NL</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
