<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Missy Franklin finishes disappointing Olympics | wltx.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wltx.com/sports/missy-franklin-finishes-disappointing-olympics/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wltx&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;missy-franklin-finishes-disappointing-olympics&amp;#x2f;295470287</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Missy Franklin finishes disappointing Olympics Nicole Auerbach, USA TODAY Sports , KING 9:20 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Missy Franklin (USA) during the women&apos;s 200m backstroke heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. (Photo: Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
RIO DE JANEIRO - Four years is a long time, and no one knows that better than Missy Franklin. 
Back in 2012, the 17-year-old was the darling of the London Games, winning five Olympic medals and winning over the world with her big smile. 
Now, she’s done with what she termed a “disappointing” Olympics that included: Her failing to qualify for both the 200 freestyle and 200 back finals; and her swimming with the 4x200 free relay in its preliminary heat, not the final. Her grand medal total is one, gold from the relay, but she only got it because she swam in prelims. She did not get to stand on the podium, medal on her neck, listening to the national anthem with her teammates. 
Franklin seems legitimately perplexed about her poor performances this week, and why she was not able to swim fast here in Rio. 
“This is a disappointing meet for me,” Franklin, 21, said Thursday afternoon. “But life goes on. This is just one phase of my life that I worked so hard for and made so many sacrifices for. For whatever reason, this meet didn’t go my way. But that doesn’t mean I’m anywhere close to being done with this sport or that I don’t have anything left to give. Because I do. I have so much more left to give to this sport, to my fans, to the people that have been supporting me. It’s a disappointment, but the support that I’ve received has shown me so much more than I could have ever expected about — you’re so much more than just the number of medals, you’re so much more than the time you are in a pool. Your value goes beyond all of that. I don’t think I would have ever come to that realization without something like this.” 
Franklin was asked what she’s learned throughout the week of adversity. She said to ask her again in a few weeks. 
“Right now, it sucks,” Franklin said, laughing. “Right now, it’s my faith in God that’s really getting me through. He’s going to transform me and my life into doing something from all of this. I have no cluse what that is, and I wish I could ask Him what to do, but right now I have to have faith that it’s going to happen.” 
Franklin said her parents have remained positive this week, reminding her that everything will be OK and those around her still love her no matter what. 
“When you put things in perspective, if a disappointing swim meet is the worst thing that happens to me in my life, then I’m having a good life,” Franklin said. Loading... Lilly King (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke semifinals. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Ryan Lochte (USA) react after the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Ryan Lochte (USA) swim during the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Allison Schmitt started off the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay for the United States. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Team USA celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports The U.S. team of Maya Dirado, Allison Schmitt, Leah Smith and Katie Ledecky celebrate after winning the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Yaxin Liu (CHN) during the women&apos;s 200m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Swimmers in the start blocks during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Long Gutierrez Feng (MEX) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Missy Franklin (USA) and Maya Dirado (USA) react after the women&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinal. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinal. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) reacts after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke final. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) swims in the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) races Ryan Lochte (USA) during the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) races Ryan Lochte (USA) during the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) holds up four fingers, for his fourth gold of the Rio Games, after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps and Ryan Lochte react after the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) during the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) celebrates after getting a tie for gold in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) hugs Penny Oleksiak (CAN) after they tied for gold in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) reacts after getting gold in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Hali Flickinger (USA) greets Cammille Adams (USA) after the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly final. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) greets Kyle Chalmers (AUS) after the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Adrian took third. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Kyle Chalmers (AUS) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mireia Belmonte Garcia (ESP) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Mirela Belmonte Garcia (ESP) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Josh Prenot swam to a second-place finish in the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dmitriy Balandin (KAZ) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Guangyuan Li (CHN) reacts after the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Jacob Pebley (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 200m individual medley heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200m freestyle semifinals on Monday. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) competes during the men&apos;s 200m butterfly semifinals. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates on the podium after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) with his bronze medal after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Kathleen Baker (USA) celebrates on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims in the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) and Ryan Murphy (USA) react after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) celebrates with David Plummer (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Murphy won, and Plummer placed second. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) and David Plummer (USA) pose with their medals after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) races during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) and Katie Meili (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) blows a kiss after the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) during the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel (USA) and Nathan Adrian (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m freestyle heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel of the U.S. competes in the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen of China during the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps during the 200-meter butterfly final. He won the race for his 20th career gold medal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) reacts after winning the women&apos;s 200m individual medley final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) , Katie Ledecky (USA) and Emma Mckeon (AUS) with their medals after the women&apos;s 200m freestyle final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) , Masato Sakai (JPN) and Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) with their medals after the men&apos;s 200m butterfly final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Abbey Weitzeil (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Rexford Tullius (ISV) during the men&apos;s 200m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Japan&apos;s Kosuke Hagino (JPN) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) dives in at the start of the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Daynara de Paula (BRA) reacts after winning a women&apos;s 100m butterfly heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Ziao Qiu (CHN) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) reacts after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (Hungary) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Ross Murdoch (GBR) in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Connor Jaeger (USA) and Yang Sun (CHN) after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) stretches before the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) celebrates after the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Australia team members celebrate after winning the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports USA team members Simone Manuel , Abbey Weitzeil , Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky on the podium with their medals after the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) during the women&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Corey Main (NZL) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Jimmy Feigen (USA) greets Anthony Ervin (USA) after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mitchell Larkin (AUS) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) swims during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) reacts after placing third in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) reacts after setting a world record during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) receives her bronze medal on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) and Cody Miller (USA) celebrate after the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Miller came in third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Cody Miller (USA) celebrates on the podium after placing third in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) preps for the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final, breaking her own world record in the process. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates with Leah Smith (USA) after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Leah Smith (USA) and Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Ledecky won, and Smith placed third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) leads his relay teammates to the pool before the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps preps for the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps swam the second leg for the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps helped the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team take gold. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian celebrates after anchoring the USA to victory during the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Caeleb Dressel (USA) celebrate after winning the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Nathan Adrian , Ryan Held , Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel celebrate with their gold medals after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Katie Ledecky and Leah Smith celebrate with their medals after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Camille Cheng (HKG) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen (CHN) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m individual medley heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Missy Franklin (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports of 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wltx.com/sports/missy-franklin-finishes-disappointing-olympics/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wltx&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;missy-franklin-finishes-disappointing-olympics&amp;#x2f;295470287</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Missy Franklin finishes disappointing Olympics Nicole Auerbach, USA TODAY Sports , KING 9:20 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Missy Franklin (USA) during the women&apos;s 200m backstroke heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. (Photo: Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
RIO DE JANEIRO - Four years is a long time, and no one knows that better than Missy Franklin. 
Back in 2012, the 17-year-old was the darling of the London Games, winning five Olympic medals and winning over the world with her big smile. 
Now, she’s done with what she termed a “disappointing” Olympics that included: Her failing to qualify for both the 200 freestyle and 200 back finals; and her swimming with the 4x200 free relay in its preliminary heat, not the final. Her grand medal total is one, gold from the relay, but she only got it because she swam in prelims. She did not get to stand on the podium, medal on her neck, listening to the national anthem with her teammates. 
Franklin seems legitimately perplexed about her poor performances this week, and why she was not able to swim fast here in Rio. 
“This is a disappointing meet for me,” Franklin, 21, said Thursday afternoon. “But life goes on. This is just one phase of my life that I worked so hard for and made so many sacrifices for. For whatever reason, this meet didn’t go my way. But that doesn’t mean I’m anywhere close to being done with this sport or that I don’t have anything left to give. Because I do. I have so much more left to give to this sport, to my fans, to the people that have been supporting me. It’s a disappointment, but the support that I’ve received has shown me so much more than I could have ever expected about — you’re so much more than just the number of medals, you’re so much more than the time you are in a pool. Your value goes beyond all of that. I don’t think I would have ever come to that realization without something like this.” 
Franklin was asked what she’s learned throughout the week of adversity. She said to ask her again in a few weeks. 
“Right now, it sucks,” Franklin said, laughing. “Right now, it’s my faith in God that’s really getting me through. He’s going to transform me and my life into doing something from all of this. I have no cluse what that is, and I wish I could ask Him what to do, but right now I have to have faith that it’s going to happen.” 
Franklin said her parents have remained positive this week, reminding her that everything will be OK and those around her still love her no matter what. 
“When you put things in perspective, if a disappointing swim meet is the worst thing that happens to me in my life, then I’m having a good life,” Franklin said. Loading... Lilly King (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke semifinals. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Ryan Lochte (USA) react after the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Ryan Lochte (USA) swim during the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Allison Schmitt started off the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay for the United States. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Team USA celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports The U.S. team of Maya Dirado, Allison Schmitt, Leah Smith and Katie Ledecky celebrate after winning the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Yaxin Liu (CHN) during the women&apos;s 200m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Swimmers in the start blocks during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Long Gutierrez Feng (MEX) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Missy Franklin (USA) and Maya Dirado (USA) react after the women&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinal. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinal. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) reacts after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke final. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) swims in the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) races Ryan Lochte (USA) during the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) races Ryan Lochte (USA) during the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) holds up four fingers, for his fourth gold of the Rio Games, after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps and Ryan Lochte react after the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) during the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) celebrates after getting a tie for gold in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) hugs Penny Oleksiak (CAN) after they tied for gold in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) reacts after getting gold in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Hali Flickinger (USA) greets Cammille Adams (USA) after the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly final. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) greets Kyle Chalmers (AUS) after the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Adrian took third. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Kyle Chalmers (AUS) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mireia Belmonte Garcia (ESP) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Mirela Belmonte Garcia (ESP) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Josh Prenot swam to a second-place finish in the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dmitriy Balandin (KAZ) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Guangyuan Li (CHN) reacts after the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Jacob Pebley (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 200m individual medley heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200m freestyle semifinals on Monday. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) competes during the men&apos;s 200m butterfly semifinals. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates on the podium after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) with his bronze medal after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Kathleen Baker (USA) celebrates on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims in the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) and Ryan Murphy (USA) react after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) celebrates with David Plummer (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Murphy won, and Plummer placed second. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) and David Plummer (USA) pose with their medals after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) races during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) and Katie Meili (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) blows a kiss after the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) during the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel (USA) and Nathan Adrian (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m freestyle heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel of the U.S. competes in the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen of China during the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps during the 200-meter butterfly final. He won the race for his 20th career gold medal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) reacts after winning the women&apos;s 200m individual medley final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) , Katie Ledecky (USA) and Emma Mckeon (AUS) with their medals after the women&apos;s 200m freestyle final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) , Masato Sakai (JPN) and Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) with their medals after the men&apos;s 200m butterfly final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Abbey Weitzeil (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Rexford Tullius (ISV) during the men&apos;s 200m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Japan&apos;s Kosuke Hagino (JPN) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) dives in at the start of the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Daynara de Paula (BRA) reacts after winning a women&apos;s 100m butterfly heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Ziao Qiu (CHN) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) reacts after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (Hungary) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Ross Murdoch (GBR) in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Connor Jaeger (USA) and Yang Sun (CHN) after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) stretches before the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) celebrates after the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Australia team members celebrate after winning the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports USA team members Simone Manuel , Abbey Weitzeil , Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky on the podium with their medals after the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) during the women&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Corey Main (NZL) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Jimmy Feigen (USA) greets Anthony Ervin (USA) after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mitchell Larkin (AUS) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) swims during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) reacts after placing third in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) reacts after setting a world record during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) receives her bronze medal on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) and Cody Miller (USA) celebrate after the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Miller came in third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Cody Miller (USA) celebrates on the podium after placing third in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) preps for the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final, breaking her own world record in the process. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates with Leah Smith (USA) after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Leah Smith (USA) and Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Ledecky won, and Smith placed third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) leads his relay teammates to the pool before the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps preps for the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps swam the second leg for the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps helped the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team take gold. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian celebrates after anchoring the USA to victory during the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Caeleb Dressel (USA) celebrate after winning the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Nathan Adrian , Ryan Held , Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel celebrate with their gold medals after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Katie Ledecky and Leah Smith celebrate with their medals after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Camille Cheng (HKG) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen (CHN) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m individual medley heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Missy Franklin (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports of 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.king5.com/photo/2016/08/11/636065494617774967-USATSI-9447060_1470968383495_5106618_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
