<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Promising day looms for T&amp;T | The Trinidad Guardian Newspaper</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.guardian.co.tt/sport/2016-08-12/promising-day-looms-tt</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Cleopatra Borel ...will be in action from 9.05am today. 
Rio de Janeiro, Brazil 
Thank God it’s Friday is not only popular in Trinidad and Tobago because it is the end of the working week, but rather it is a day when most will leave their respective offices to go out and relax. 
However, for T&amp;T at the 2016 Rio Olympics, today promises a lot with the start of both the athletics programme as well as action for our lone cyclist Njisane Phillips. Add to that Felice Aisha Chow in the single skulls contest C-semifinals at 12 noon (TT time) and Andrew Lewis returns to the water. 
First up will be the experienced shot putter Cleopatra Borel who will be in action from 9.05 am (TT time) in Group A, which also includes Olympic champion Valerie Adams. In 2012, Borel just missed a place in the final, only to learn after that one of the athletes who qualified ahead of her tested positive for drugs and was disqualified. 
This time, Borel is leaving nothing to chance. She has been training over the last 12 months with Adams who spent some time in Trinidad with her. “So far training has been going well. As is to be expected, there were both good and bad days. I smile after the good ones and cry after the bad. I have done all that I can. My coach Ismael Lopez Mastrapa and physiotherapist Abdel Murguia Miranda have done their best to prepare me for the task ahead, ” said Borel yesterday. 
“The Olympic Committee provided excellent support in the pre - Olympic camp and now that we are in the village, I am going to go out there tomorrow and fight to represent T&amp;T to the best of my ability,” added a resilient Borel. 
The men’s 400 metres runners will also be in action in the heats from 8.05pm (TT time) with Machel Cedenio (Heat 1, Lane 2), La Londe Gordon (Heat 4, Lane 5) and Deon Lendore (Heat 5, Lane 5) in action 
Also in the 400 metres will be defending champion, Grenadian Kirani James in Heat 6 running from Lane 6. At 9.40 pm, the women will be in action in the 100 metres heats where Michele Lee Ahye, Semoy Hackett and Kelly Ann Baptiste will get their first taste of competition. 
Manager of the track and field contingent George Commissiong said yesterday. ”Preparations are going well. The athletes have been training regularly under the supervision of the coaches. Some have personal coaches as well.” 
Commissiong identified some specifics without going into detail. ”There are the usual medical issues resulting from training and competing at this level but where they arise, they are being handled by our medical team.” 
“Also, we had staggered arrivals into the Pre Camp and not all the relay legs were available for the full duration. Nonetheless, we were able to get in two sessions of relay work with each of the relay teams before coming into Rio,” he added. 
Phillips who was fourth in the 2012 London Olympics in the match sprint, appears positive ahead of his first qualifier at 3pm (TT time). 
He remains very focussed and would only say: “Hello Trinidad and Tobago, I just want to say thank you for the prayers and support. I really appreciate it and I look forward to representing with pride. Continue to pray for us as we put everything on the line to represent Trinidad and Tobago.” 
Also returning to action after yesterday’s rest day is sailor Andrew Lewis who will continue in the laser class with Races 7 ( 12.15pm TT time) and Race 8 (1.40pm TT time ). 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.guardian.co.tt/sport/2016-08-12/promising-day-looms-tt</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Cleopatra Borel ...will be in action from 9.05am today. 
Rio de Janeiro, Brazil 
Thank God it’s Friday is not only popular in Trinidad and Tobago because it is the end of the working week, but rather it is a day when most will leave their respective offices to go out and relax. 
However, for T&amp;T at the 2016 Rio Olympics, today promises a lot with the start of both the athletics programme as well as action for our lone cyclist Njisane Phillips. Add to that Felice Aisha Chow in the single skulls contest C-semifinals at 12 noon (TT time) and Andrew Lewis returns to the water. 
First up will be the experienced shot putter Cleopatra Borel who will be in action from 9.05 am (TT time) in Group A, which also includes Olympic champion Valerie Adams. In 2012, Borel just missed a place in the final, only to learn after that one of the athletes who qualified ahead of her tested positive for drugs and was disqualified. 
This time, Borel is leaving nothing to chance. She has been training over the last 12 months with Adams who spent some time in Trinidad with her. “So far training has been going well. As is to be expected, there were both good and bad days. I smile after the good ones and cry after the bad. I have done all that I can. My coach Ismael Lopez Mastrapa and physiotherapist Abdel Murguia Miranda have done their best to prepare me for the task ahead, ” said Borel yesterday. 
“The Olympic Committee provided excellent support in the pre - Olympic camp and now that we are in the village, I am going to go out there tomorrow and fight to represent T&amp;T to the best of my ability,” added a resilient Borel. 
The men’s 400 metres runners will also be in action in the heats from 8.05pm (TT time) with Machel Cedenio (Heat 1, Lane 2), La Londe Gordon (Heat 4, Lane 5) and Deon Lendore (Heat 5, Lane 5) in action 
Also in the 400 metres will be defending champion, Grenadian Kirani James in Heat 6 running from Lane 6. At 9.40 pm, the women will be in action in the 100 metres heats where Michele Lee Ahye, Semoy Hackett and Kelly Ann Baptiste will get their first taste of competition. 
Manager of the track and field contingent George Commissiong said yesterday. ”Preparations are going well. The athletes have been training regularly under the supervision of the coaches. Some have personal coaches as well.” 
Commissiong identified some specifics without going into detail. ”There are the usual medical issues resulting from training and competing at this level but where they arise, they are being handled by our medical team.” 
“Also, we had staggered arrivals into the Pre Camp and not all the relay legs were available for the full duration. Nonetheless, we were able to get in two sessions of relay work with each of the relay teams before coming into Rio,” he added. 
Phillips who was fourth in the 2012 London Olympics in the match sprint, appears positive ahead of his first qualifier at 3pm (TT time). 
He remains very focussed and would only say: “Hello Trinidad and Tobago, I just want to say thank you for the prayers and support. I really appreciate it and I look forward to representing with pride. Continue to pray for us as we put everything on the line to represent Trinidad and Tobago.” 
Also returning to action after yesterday’s rest day is sailor Andrew Lewis who will continue in the laser class with Races 7 ( 12.15pm TT time) and Race 8 (1.40pm TT time ). 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.guardian.co.tt/sites/default/files/styles/thumbnail/public/field/image/cleo_1.png?itok=tO08H2xL</main_image>
</document>
