<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Golf tourney fundraiser moves out of Moorpark</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Community/Golf_tourney_fundraiser_moves_out_of_Moorpark.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Golf tourney fundraiser moves out of Moorpark By Caitlin Trude 
LONG DRIVE FOR CHARITY—The ninth annual Scott Medlock- Robby Krieger Invitational Golf Tournament moved to North Ranch Country Club in Thousand Oaks this year to accommodate more participants. Models, rock stars, a concert and a tequila bar sounds like the recipe for a wild weekend in Las Vegas. 
For Moorpark artist Scott Medlock and his longtime friend, Doors guitarist Robby Krieger, it’s what makes up one of the biggest golf tournaments in Ventura County. 
This year’s Scott Medlock- Robby Krieger Invitational Golf Tournament will be Mon., Aug. 29, but the big-time fundraiser for Memphis-based St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital won’t be swinging and rocking at Moorpark Country Club. 
The annual golf tourney, now in its ninth year, has grown so much it will move to North Ranch Country Club in Thousand Oaks, 4761 Valley Spring Drive, to make room for the big hair on the stage and the big drives on the fairway. 
“Were pretty excited it’s there this year,” said Odette Gutierrez, committee coordinator for the event. “(The fundraiser has) been growing by leaps and bounds every year . . . but obviously that means we’ve outgrown a few places.” 
Gutierrez said nearly 800 guests attended last year, and organizers hope the bigger venue will bring even more guests to the event. 
The all-day affair starts with golfer registration at 8:30 a.m., followed by the golf tournament at 10:30 a.m. Guests will be served a continental breakfast and an on-course lunch and will have the chance to win prizes throughout the tournament. 
Golfers will end the day with hors d’oeuvres and cocktails at the 19th Hole Party at 5 p.m. and live entertainment at the All-Star Concert at 7 p.m. 
The concert will feature Krieger as well as a slew of other big-name rockers. An updated list of this year’s performers will be released a week before the tournament. 
Past performers included Alice Cooper, Richie Sambora (Bon Jovi), Cherie Currie (The Runaways), Tommy Thayer (KISS) and Jack Black. 
The golf tournament fundraiser was founded in 2008 when Medlock and Krieger hosted the event to benefit the Pat Tillman Foundation, an organization that provides academic scholarships for military veterans and their spouses. 
But the pair moved the fundraiser in a different direction in 2011 after Medlock met Richard Shadyac, then-CEO of St. Jude Hospital, at another celebrity golf tournament. At that point, he and Krieger decided to focus on raising money for the children’s hospital. 
Founded in 1962, St. Jude treats about 7,800 children worldwide every year. The nonprofit hospital requires about $2 million in daily operating costs, 75 percent of which is funded by public contributions. 
Medlock said he’s excited to see the event come together. 
“It’s going to be our seventh year for (St. Jude) and our event just keeps growing and growing.” 
Last year’s event raised a total of $500,000. 
“We were pretty thrilled with that,” Medlock said. “Every year, we’ve kind of gotten a little bit better and better and raised more and more . . . so we’re hoping to surpass what we did last year.” 
Gutierrez also looks forward to seeing guests rally for a worthy cause. 
“It’s been growing pretty rapidly and I think it’s a great opportunity for us as well to bring awareness about St. Jude,” she said. “I’m excited for (St. Jude’s) CEO to talk to the guests there about everything that’s going on at St. Jude. . . . Hopefully, we’re going to be raising a lot of money for these kids.” 
Individual golfers can play for $1,500, while a foursome sponsor costs $6,000. For non-golfers, tickets to the 19th Hole Party and All-Star Concert cost $200. 
Guests can purchase tickets at www.medlockkriegerinvitational.com .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Community/Golf_tourney_fundraiser_moves_out_of_Moorpark.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0219</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
Golf tourney fundraiser moves out of Moorpark By Caitlin Trude 
LONG DRIVE FOR CHARITY—The ninth annual Scott Medlock- Robby Krieger Invitational Golf Tournament moved to North Ranch Country Club in Thousand Oaks this year to accommodate more participants. Models, rock stars, a concert and a tequila bar sounds like the recipe for a wild weekend in Las Vegas. 
For Moorpark artist Scott Medlock and his longtime friend, Doors guitarist Robby Krieger, it’s what makes up one of the biggest golf tournaments in Ventura County. 
This year’s Scott Medlock- Robby Krieger Invitational Golf Tournament will be Mon., Aug. 29, but the big-time fundraiser for Memphis-based St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital won’t be swinging and rocking at Moorpark Country Club. 
The annual golf tourney, now in its ninth year, has grown so much it will move to North Ranch Country Club in Thousand Oaks, 4761 Valley Spring Drive, to make room for the big hair on the stage and the big drives on the fairway. 
“Were pretty excited it’s there this year,” said Odette Gutierrez, committee coordinator for the event. “(The fundraiser has) been growing by leaps and bounds every year . . . but obviously that means we’ve outgrown a few places.” 
Gutierrez said nearly 800 guests attended last year, and organizers hope the bigger venue will bring even more guests to the event. 
The all-day affair starts with golfer registration at 8:30 a.m., followed by the golf tournament at 10:30 a.m. Guests will be served a continental breakfast and an on-course lunch and will have the chance to win prizes throughout the tournament. 
Golfers will end the day with hors d’oeuvres and cocktails at the 19th Hole Party at 5 p.m. and live entertainment at the All-Star Concert at 7 p.m. 
The concert will feature Krieger as well as a slew of other big-name rockers. An updated list of this year’s performers will be released a week before the tournament. 
Past performers included Alice Cooper, Richie Sambora (Bon Jovi), Cherie Currie (The Runaways), Tommy Thayer (KISS) and Jack Black. 
The golf tournament fundraiser was founded in 2008 when Medlock and Krieger hosted the event to benefit the Pat Tillman Foundation, an organization that provides academic scholarships for military veterans and their spouses. 
But the pair moved the fundraiser in a different direction in 2011 after Medlock met Richard Shadyac, then-CEO of St. Jude Hospital, at another celebrity golf tournament. At that point, he and Krieger decided to focus on raising money for the children’s hospital. 
Founded in 1962, St. Jude treats about 7,800 children worldwide every year. The nonprofit hospital requires about $2 million in daily operating costs, 75 percent of which is funded by public contributions. 
Medlock said he’s excited to see the event come together. 
“It’s going to be our seventh year for (St. Jude) and our event just keeps growing and growing.” 
Last year’s event raised a total of $500,000. 
“We were pretty thrilled with that,” Medlock said. “Every year, we’ve kind of gotten a little bit better and better and raised more and more . . . so we’re hoping to surpass what we did last year.” 
Gutierrez also looks forward to seeing guests rally for a worthy cause. 
“It’s been growing pretty rapidly and I think it’s a great opportunity for us as well to bring awareness about St. Jude,” she said. “I’m excited for (St. Jude’s) CEO to talk to the guests there about everything that’s going on at St. Jude. . . . Hopefully, we’re going to be raising a lot of money for these kids.” 
Individual golfers can play for $1,500, while a foursome sponsor costs $6,000. For non-golfers, tickets to the 19th Hole Party and All-Star Concert cost $200. 
Guests can purchase tickets at www.medlockkriegerinvitational.com .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/12p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
