<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>HP Elite X3 Pre-Orders Can Now Be Done From The Company’s Official Website</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wccftech.com/hp-elite-x3-pre-order-companys-website/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Mobile 1 hour ago by Omar Sohail Tweet 
Despite the fact that Windows 10 Mobile is an utter disaster, you cannot deny that HP Elite X3 is a terrific phone to purchase for the enterprise user. On this occasion, the company has made it extremely simple for you to pre-order the smartphone because now, the entire process is taking place through the company’s official website. Check out all the details right here. HP Elite X3 Pre-Orders Can Now Be Done Through The Company’s Official Website – Accessories Will Have To Be Purchased Separately 
HP Elite X3 pre-orders are taking place through the company UK-based website. The company is charging a total of £706.80 for the smartphone. Keep in mind that the aforementioned price also includes 20 percent VAT. The VAT-exclusive price of the Windows 10 Mobile powered smartphone is £589. Looking at the sorry state of Microsoft’s mobile OS and the lack of functionality and apps it possesses to really change its overall face, HP Elite X3 is definitely going to be targeted to several business owners and workers. 
In order to be promoted as a smartphone that’s going to cater to the user’s business requirements, the company is also bundling a Lap Dock accessory, which allows you to attach the smartphone to it and extend your workspace further. There is also a Continuum Dock that you can purchase separately, although if HP Elite X3 was advertised as a smartphone made for businesses, the company would have done itself a favor had the Continuum Dock been bundled with the smartphone. You’ll be Paying More For HP Elite X3 Than You’re Paying For An Unlocked iPhone 6s In The US Advertisements 
Regardless, it’s a common tactic that companies use and HP is no exception. Coming to the hardware specifications of the smartphone, HP Elite X3 possesses a massive 5.96-inch screen size with a QHD resolution (2560 x 1440 pixels) and comes with 4GB of RAM. A Snapdragon 820 powers up the smartphone, and the chipset indicates that you’ll have a ton of processing firepower at your disposal. There’s also 64GB of onboard storage, and if you feel that it’s on the low side, you can increase it at will thanks to the presence of a MicroSD card slot that can accommodate a 2TB storage card. 
The smartphone also supports wireless charging, which will deliver a ton of convenience to the user, and thanks to its sheer size, the smartphone packs a 4,150mAh battery underneath it. HP states that shipping of the smartphone will start from August 29, but if you’re going to pre-order it, let us know why in the comments below. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wccftech.com/hp-elite-x3-pre-order-companys-website/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Omar Sohail</username>
<post>
Mobile 1 hour ago by Omar Sohail Tweet 
Despite the fact that Windows 10 Mobile is an utter disaster, you cannot deny that HP Elite X3 is a terrific phone to purchase for the enterprise user. On this occasion, the company has made it extremely simple for you to pre-order the smartphone because now, the entire process is taking place through the company’s official website. Check out all the details right here. HP Elite X3 Pre-Orders Can Now Be Done Through The Company’s Official Website – Accessories Will Have To Be Purchased Separately 
HP Elite X3 pre-orders are taking place through the company UK-based website. The company is charging a total of £706.80 for the smartphone. Keep in mind that the aforementioned price also includes 20 percent VAT. The VAT-exclusive price of the Windows 10 Mobile powered smartphone is £589. Looking at the sorry state of Microsoft’s mobile OS and the lack of functionality and apps it possesses to really change its overall face, HP Elite X3 is definitely going to be targeted to several business owners and workers. 
In order to be promoted as a smartphone that’s going to cater to the user’s business requirements, the company is also bundling a Lap Dock accessory, which allows you to attach the smartphone to it and extend your workspace further. There is also a Continuum Dock that you can purchase separately, although if HP Elite X3 was advertised as a smartphone made for businesses, the company would have done itself a favor had the Continuum Dock been bundled with the smartphone. You’ll be Paying More For HP Elite X3 Than You’re Paying For An Unlocked iPhone 6s In The US Advertisements 
Regardless, it’s a common tactic that companies use and HP is no exception. Coming to the hardware specifications of the smartphone, HP Elite X3 possesses a massive 5.96-inch screen size with a QHD resolution (2560 x 1440 pixels) and comes with 4GB of RAM. A Snapdragon 820 powers up the smartphone, and the chipset indicates that you’ll have a ton of processing firepower at your disposal. There’s also 64GB of onboard storage, and if you feel that it’s on the low side, you can increase it at will thanks to the presence of a MicroSD card slot that can accommodate a 2TB storage card. 
The smartphone also supports wireless charging, which will deliver a ton of convenience to the user, and thanks to its sheer size, the smartphone packs a 4,150mAh battery underneath it. HP states that shipping of the smartphone will start from August 29, but if you’re going to pre-order it, let us know why in the comments below. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>DE</country>
<main_image>http://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/HP-Elite-X3-9.png</main_image>
</document>
