<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news</forum>
<forum_title>News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Political violence is no joke</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/opinion/political-violence-is-no-joke/ar-BBvuwwe</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Political violence is no joke The Washington Post 18 hrs ago William Kennedy Smith, Jean Kennedy Smith © John R. Fulton Jr./Associated Press Then-Sen. Robert F. Kennedy (D- N.Y.) informed people gathered in Indianapolis of the assassination of Martin Luther King Jr. on that day, April 4, 1968. William Kennedy Smith and Jean Kennedy Smith are the nephew and sister of President John. F. Kennedy and Sen. Robert F. Kennedy, who was assassinated on June 6, 1968.
On April 4, 1968, the day the Rev. Martin Luther King Jr. was shot and killed, Robert Kennedy was campaigning for the presidency in Indianapolis. Bobby conveyed the news of King’s death to a shattered, mostly black audience. He took pains to remind those whose first instinct may have been toward violence that President John F. Kennedy had also been shot and killed. Bobby went on , “What we need in the United States is not division; what we need in the United States is not hatred; what we need in the United States is not violence and lawlessness, but is love, and wisdom, and compassion toward one another, and a feeling of justice toward those who still suffer within our country, whether they be white or whether they be black.”
That speech has crystallized into the single most enduring portrait of Bobby’s candidacy. Because it was extemporaneous, it conveyed directly, and with raw emotion, his own vulnerability, his aspirations for his country and a deep compassion for the suffering of others. Bobby concluded his remarks that night by urging those listening to return home and say a prayer for our country and for our people. Those words mattered. While there were riots in cities across the nation that night, Indianapolis did not burn.
Today, almost 50 years later, words still matter. They shape who we are as a people and who we wish to be as a nation. In the white-hot cauldron of a presidential campaign, it is still the words delivered extemporaneously, off the cuff, in the raw pressure of the moment that matter most. They say most directly what is in a candidate’s heart. So it was with a real sense of sadness and revulsion that we listened to Donald Trump, the Republican nominee for president, as he referred to the options available to “ Second Amendment people ,” a remark widely, and we believe correctly, interpreted as a thinly veiled reference or “joke” about the possibility of political assassination.
Political violence is a terrible inherent risk to any free society. Dictators and strongmen like Vladimir Putin have an answer. They are surrounded and shielded by force at all times. They do not brook dissent. In democracies, we expect our leaders to be accessible and, by and large, they want to be. Inevitably, that makes them vulnerable and the loss of a leader at a crucial time impacts family, country and even the world, for generations. Anyone who loves politics, the open competition of ideas and public participation in a free society, knows that political violence is the greatest of all civic sins. It is not to be encouraged. It is not funny. It is not a joke.
By now, we have heard enough dark and offensive rhetoric from Trump to know that it reflects something fundamentally troubled, and troubling, about his candidacy. Trump’s remarks frequently, if not inevitably, spark outrage, which is followed by a clarification that, in lieu of an apology, seeks to attribute the dark undertones of his words to the listener’s twisted psyche. This fools no one. Whether you like what he is saying or, like a growing segment of the electorate, you reject it, it is easy to grasp Trump’s meaning from his words. But what to make of a candidate who directly appeals to violence, smears his opponents and publicly bullies a Gold Star family, a decorated prisoner of war and a reporter with a disability, among others? To borrow the words of Army Counsel Joseph Welch, directed at another dangerous demagogue : “Have you no sense of decency, sir, at long last? Have you left no sense of decency?”
The truth remains that words do matter, especially when it comes to presidential candidates. On that basis alone, Donald Trump is not qualified to be president of the United States.
Read more:
Paul Waldman: Trump’s latest outrageous statement wasn’t a ‘gaffe.’ It was something much worse.
Joe Scarborough: The GOP must dump Trump
The Post’s View: Donald Trump is a unique threat to American democracy
Go to MSN Home
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>5</post_num>
<post_id>post-5</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/opinion/political-violence-is-no-joke/ar-BBvuwwe</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1932</post_time>
<username>Anthony Deangelo</username>
<post>
The crazy train is derailing. His own people are jumping ship. You can say what you want but this has gone far enough. More republicans are leaving the sinking ship because this idiot is not promoting anything but hate and racism. He even advocates violence to anyone who opposes him. This is no longer about crump and Clinton.. This is about who we want running this country. This man is so unfit in too many ways that it is really really scary. As a disabled vet, blue collar working class I will not vote for a bully, sexist. Racist, traitor. Especially one who invokes violence as an end to his means. Say what you want this fool has shown us all what he is made of. To me that is what the crumpster is. How dare he mock America and say that we are not great. How dare he pick a fight with a gold metal family and then not apologize. How dare he incite violence against a soon to be sitting president? This great country allowed him to cheat workers, investors, banks his followers and yet he says we are not great. Think about that. He cheated workers out of money he owed them. He cheated his investors out of their money; He cheated students out of their money at his non accredited university all with lies. He throws out buzz words and you cheer yet he will not be honest with you or anyone else. Where are his taxes? Ah that’s right he is being audited even though the IRS says reveling his taxes has no Bering on his audit I don’t get it. How much more of this insane crap are you going to take. He mocks all of us. This idiot calls people names that he does not agree with and all of you just go along with it. Do you really want your kids to see all this hate? Is this how you were brought up? To respect a bully with no purpose well I am still waiting for all of you to wake up. This fool has insulted everyone and has no feelings for anyone but himself. How do all of you look in a mirror and say yes we back this guy. He is so unpatriotic and un-American that you should really look again at who you are backing. The tide is turning and turning fast. So to all you Elmer J Fudd supporters. Are you ready? Have you had enough of the rhetoric and the bs from the orange guy. Do you still believe he has your best interest at heart? He has sold us out to the Russians. How can you do this to our country? So can you hear it? It&apos;s getting louder, What! you can&apos;t hear it yet? The rest of the world is watching and they hear it. I forgot you have be reading all the crumpsters tweets. You didn&apos;t hear it. Let me tell you what you missed. You missed not only a party that came together but a sound that will resonate within all the borders of this USA. So again I want you crumpsters to explain to all of us why you would stand behind a man who has divided your party and keeps the division in the land growing? Your Elmer J Fudd has over 3500 lawsuits in ongoing cases not yet heard in court.. He throws out sound bites and all of you eat them up like it&apos;s the gospel. He uses debt leverage to make his money which is something you cannot do to our economy. He is a racist and has already caused racial tensions to rise. He promotes fear and loathing about other religions and is backed by most of the major hate groups. Aryan brotherhood, the KKK and Putin. That tells a lot about his character. He blames everyone for his mistakes and does not think before he speaks. He has no real plans for his agenda but sound bites. And best of all without the house and senate he will not be able to do anything he says. He does not care about the working folks as he is promoting longer hours for less pay. Just look at his track record for bankrupting small businesses that have done work for him. He refuses to release his tax returns while the IRS says there is no reason for him not to. There is nothing he says that will benefit you or me. Yes we need change but he is not that change. And best of all 7 out of10voters will not vote for him. So please tell me something good about him for I cannot see anything but a future that is bleak and dark under his control. Little Hitler is not what we need. He talks about bringing jobs back when he is exporting all his lines to other countries to make. He is the apitimy of do as i say and not as i do. Under these terms I cannot support him and in fact I am truly scared of him and what he will do to our country. Now on top of that he is being sued for sexual assault. Read all about it in the link attached. Tell me you can honestly stand behind this man http://www.alternet.org/.../donald-trump-accused-rape... The racketeering case is Cohen v. Trump, 13-cv-02519, U.S. District Court, Southern District of California (San Diego). The consumer fraud case is Low v. Trump University LLC, 10-cv-00940, U.S. District Court, Southern District of California (San Diego).
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
