<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.metrowestdailynews.com/entertainment/arts?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Arts - MetroWest Daily News, Framingham, MA</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Boston Comic Con: Stoughton&apos;s Tom Sniegoski will be holding court along Artists Alley</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.metrowestdailynews.com/entertainment/20160811/boston-comic-con-stoughtons-tom-sniegoski-will-be-holding-court-along-artists-alley</topic_url>
<topic_text>
log in 
Comic book creator and graphic novelist Frank Miller is the big-get for this weekend’s Boston Comic Con. But Miller, who created the noirish “Sin City” and historical graphic novel “300,” isn’t the only draw. Stoughton’s Tom Sniegoski also will be holding court along Artists Alley at the annual convention, which runs Friday through Sunday at the Seaport World Trade Center. 
Sniegoski wrote the best-selling, young-adult-fantasy novel series “The Fallen,” which was turned into an ABC miniseries. “That’s my big crowning achievement,” Sniegoski said. That, and getting to meet geek culture hero Joss Whedon. 
Sniegoski also has written for the comics “Buffy the Vampire Slayer,”“Angel,”“Batman,”“Hellboy” and “Wolverine.” He penned the prequel to Jeff Smith’s award-winning series “Bone,” which was titled “Stupid, Stupid Rat Tails: The Adventures of Big Johnson Bone.” 
Other projects include dark fantasy for grown-ups and a novel called “Legacy,” about a deadbeat father who’s a superhero. His latest project is “Dark Exodus,” the second book in a series called “Demonists.” 
Sniegoski said the majority of his projects are more horror and action. “Angels and devils, heaven and hell, religious mythology, I play in that playground,” he said. But he also has range and does a lot in the young-adult-fantasy genre. 
Last month at the San Diego Comic Con, Sniegoski participated in a panel titled “A World After Harry,” which considered how the genre has changed since JK Rowling introduced us to Hogwarts and her boy magician. The panel, Sniegoski said, “turned into something bigger than that. It was how storytelling has expanded and fantasy narratives have evolved.” 
Sniegoski called the San Diego show a “mecca of geeks,” and while he’s been going there for 20 years, he said the Boston show is one of his favorites. He has seen the Boston Comic Con grow from a small gathering of about 900 fans in a basement at the Back Bay Events Center to New England’s biggest industry convention, where artists, vendors, anime, comic book and gaming aficionados come together to share their interests and passions. 
Other major comic writers and artists scheduled for the Boston event are Brian Azzarello (“100 Bullets, “Wonder Woman”) and the husband-and-wife duo Amanda Conner (“Before Watchmen”) and Jimmy Palmiotti (“Deadpool”). They will be celebrating “Harley Quinn No. 1,” which will be released in a special edition at Boston Comic Con. 
“I’ve watched the show mature over the past years,” Sniegoski said. “Each year they fine tune it a little bit more.” 
Before he became the guy who put the words in the word bubbles, Sniegoski worked in the financial-aid office at Northeastern University. While there, he started part-time in comics writing for “Vampirella,” the raven-haired vampire vixen. Sniegoski wrote her monthly comic and soon became a fan favorite. More job offers followed, and Sniegoski left cubicle life behind. “My wife being the good egg that she was, said to go for it, so I did,” Sniegoski said. 
And he hasn’t looked back, even when deadlines loom, or his “demon” dog needs a walk, or some other obstacle materializes. “I remind myself that I could be back at NU in a cubicle getting yelled at by a student,” he said, laughing. 
At his home office in Stoughton, Sniegoski is surrounded by a motherlode of geek tchotchkes: figurines of Batman, Yoda, Hellboy, Lobster Johnson, Homer Simpson, an Iron Man wall calendar and “inspirational” books such as the “Encyclopedia of Hell, Death and the Afterlife”; “Ghosts”; and “Angels: A to Z.”“It’s goofy stuff that you pick up that somehow triggers inspiration,” he said. “You never know where a good idea is going to come from.” 
His dog, Kirby, named after Marvel co-creator Jack Kirby, also hangs out in the office in a little doggie bed next to Sniegoski’s desk. And although Sniegoski endearingly calls his French bulldog the “anti-Christ,” the animal is a big part of his creative process. “I include him somehow. It’s a common thing in all my work,” he said. “I’m shopping a project that’s all about him. It’s a real hoot.” 
Sniegoski said he also gets a kick out of seeing the convention crowd decked in colorful costumes. Usually there are superheroes of all kinds, including Captain America and Wonder Woman, plus characters from “Game of Thrones” and “Star Wars” and other lesser-known witches, warlocks, pirates and characters from video games and anime. A Cosplay Contest is scheduled for Sunday. 
For an extra cost, fans also can meet and snap photos with Ben McKenzie (“Gotham”), Danielle Panabaker (“Arrow”), Robbie Amell (“The Flash”) and Jenna Coleman (“Dr. Who”). Other celebrity appearances include “Star Trek’s” William Shatner, Gillian Anderson from “The X-Files,” Elizabeth Henstridge from “Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D.” and Karen Gillan from “Guardians of the Galaxy” and “Dr. Who.” 
However, you can hang out with Sniegoski in Artists Alley for just the price of admission. He’ll sign books and chat comics with gusto. “It’s just this big geek love fest,” he said. “You can see the glow coming off them while they are walking around.” 
Dana Barbuto may be reached at dbarbuto@ledger.com or follow her on Twitter @dbarbuto_Ledger. 
IF YOU GO 
WHAT: Boston Comic Con 
WHERE: Seaport World Trade Center, 200 Seaport Blvd., Boston. 
WHEN: Aug. 12-14; Friday noon to 8 p.m.; Saturday 10 a.m. to 7 p.m.; Sunday 10 a.m. to 6 p.m. 
TICKETS: Must be purchased online. Friday single-day admission: $30; Saturday single-day admission: $45; Sunday single-day admission: $40; three-day pass $90; three-day VIP pass: $165. Celebrity photo ops: $45 to $115. 
INFO: www.bostoncomiccon.com
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.metrowestdailynews.com/entertainment/20160811/boston-comic-con-stoughtons-tom-sniegoski-will-be-holding-court-along-artists-alley</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2028</post_time>
<username>Dana Barbuto</username>
<post>
log in 
Comic book creator and graphic novelist Frank Miller is the big-get for this weekend’s Boston Comic Con. But Miller, who created the noirish “Sin City” and historical graphic novel “300,” isn’t the only draw. Stoughton’s Tom Sniegoski also will be holding court along Artists Alley at the annual convention, which runs Friday through Sunday at the Seaport World Trade Center. 
Sniegoski wrote the best-selling, young-adult-fantasy novel series “The Fallen,” which was turned into an ABC miniseries. “That’s my big crowning achievement,” Sniegoski said. That, and getting to meet geek culture hero Joss Whedon. 
Sniegoski also has written for the comics “Buffy the Vampire Slayer,”“Angel,”“Batman,”“Hellboy” and “Wolverine.” He penned the prequel to Jeff Smith’s award-winning series “Bone,” which was titled “Stupid, Stupid Rat Tails: The Adventures of Big Johnson Bone.” 
Other projects include dark fantasy for grown-ups and a novel called “Legacy,” about a deadbeat father who’s a superhero. His latest project is “Dark Exodus,” the second book in a series called “Demonists.” 
Sniegoski said the majority of his projects are more horror and action. “Angels and devils, heaven and hell, religious mythology, I play in that playground,” he said. But he also has range and does a lot in the young-adult-fantasy genre. 
Last month at the San Diego Comic Con, Sniegoski participated in a panel titled “A World After Harry,” which considered how the genre has changed since JK Rowling introduced us to Hogwarts and her boy magician. The panel, Sniegoski said, “turned into something bigger than that. It was how storytelling has expanded and fantasy narratives have evolved.” 
Sniegoski called the San Diego show a “mecca of geeks,” and while he’s been going there for 20 years, he said the Boston show is one of his favorites. He has seen the Boston Comic Con grow from a small gathering of about 900 fans in a basement at the Back Bay Events Center to New England’s biggest industry convention, where artists, vendors, anime, comic book and gaming aficionados come together to share their interests and passions. 
Other major comic writers and artists scheduled for the Boston event are Brian Azzarello (“100 Bullets, “Wonder Woman”) and the husband-and-wife duo Amanda Conner (“Before Watchmen”) and Jimmy Palmiotti (“Deadpool”). They will be celebrating “Harley Quinn No. 1,” which will be released in a special edition at Boston Comic Con. 
“I’ve watched the show mature over the past years,” Sniegoski said. “Each year they fine tune it a little bit more.” 
Before he became the guy who put the words in the word bubbles, Sniegoski worked in the financial-aid office at Northeastern University. While there, he started part-time in comics writing for “Vampirella,” the raven-haired vampire vixen. Sniegoski wrote her monthly comic and soon became a fan favorite. More job offers followed, and Sniegoski left cubicle life behind. “My wife being the good egg that she was, said to go for it, so I did,” Sniegoski said. 
And he hasn’t looked back, even when deadlines loom, or his “demon” dog needs a walk, or some other obstacle materializes. “I remind myself that I could be back at NU in a cubicle getting yelled at by a student,” he said, laughing. 
At his home office in Stoughton, Sniegoski is surrounded by a motherlode of geek tchotchkes: figurines of Batman, Yoda, Hellboy, Lobster Johnson, Homer Simpson, an Iron Man wall calendar and “inspirational” books such as the “Encyclopedia of Hell, Death and the Afterlife”; “Ghosts”; and “Angels: A to Z.”“It’s goofy stuff that you pick up that somehow triggers inspiration,” he said. “You never know where a good idea is going to come from.” 
His dog, Kirby, named after Marvel co-creator Jack Kirby, also hangs out in the office in a little doggie bed next to Sniegoski’s desk. And although Sniegoski endearingly calls his French bulldog the “anti-Christ,” the animal is a big part of his creative process. “I include him somehow. It’s a common thing in all my work,” he said. “I’m shopping a project that’s all about him. It’s a real hoot.” 
Sniegoski said he also gets a kick out of seeing the convention crowd decked in colorful costumes. Usually there are superheroes of all kinds, including Captain America and Wonder Woman, plus characters from “Game of Thrones” and “Star Wars” and other lesser-known witches, warlocks, pirates and characters from video games and anime. A Cosplay Contest is scheduled for Sunday. 
For an extra cost, fans also can meet and snap photos with Ben McKenzie (“Gotham”), Danielle Panabaker (“Arrow”), Robbie Amell (“The Flash”) and Jenna Coleman (“Dr. Who”). Other celebrity appearances include “Star Trek’s” William Shatner, Gillian Anderson from “The X-Files,” Elizabeth Henstridge from “Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D.” and Karen Gillan from “Guardians of the Galaxy” and “Dr. Who.” 
However, you can hang out with Sniegoski in Artists Alley for just the price of admission. He’ll sign books and chat comics with gusto. “It’s just this big geek love fest,” he said. “You can see the glow coming off them while they are walking around.” 
Dana Barbuto may be reached at dbarbuto@ledger.com or follow her on Twitter @dbarbuto_Ledger. 
IF YOU GO 
WHAT: Boston Comic Con 
WHERE: Seaport World Trade Center, 200 Seaport Blvd., Boston. 
WHEN: Aug. 12-14; Friday noon to 8 p.m.; Saturday 10 a.m. to 7 p.m.; Sunday 10 a.m. to 6 p.m. 
TICKETS: Must be purchased online. Friday single-day admission: $30; Saturday single-day admission: $45; Sunday single-day admission: $40; three-day pass $90; three-day VIP pass: $165. Celebrity photo ops: $45 to $115. 
INFO: www.bostoncomiccon.com
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.metrowestdailynews.com/storyimage/WL/20160811/ENTERTAINMENT/160819291/AR/0/AR-160819291.jpg</main_image>
</document>
