<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.stuff.co.nz/rss/waikato-times/news/national-news</forum>
<forum_title>Stuff.co.nz - National News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Hamilton&apos;s mayoral hopefuls named</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/national/politics/83117738/Hamiltons-mayoral-hopefuls-named</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Controversial pocket park sale in Forrest Hill on Auckland&apos;s North Shore rejected by Auckland Council Kids&apos; march remembers Moko Rangitoheriri 
A field of seven hopefuls will vie to be Hamilton&apos;s next mayor. 
The mayoral candidates will line up next to 35 other contenders hoping to win a seat on the city council. 
The field is greatly reduced from three years ago, when 49 candidates battled it out across the city&apos;s two wards. 
Outgoing Hamilton Mayor Julie Hardaker​ secured the city&apos;s top job in 2013 with 15,737 votes, but in her absences, the contest to be the city&apos;s next mayor looks wide open. 
All but one of the mayoral candidates will contest a ward seat as well. 
Current councillors Rob Pascoe and Andrew King are joined in the mayoral race by Chris Simpson, Paula Southgate, James Casson, Arshad Chatha​ and Jack Gielen. 
In the east, a field of 25 candidates will chase three vacancies and the seats of three incumbents who are standing again. 
Deputy Mayor Gordon Chesterman and Crs Margaret Forsyth and Karina Green will not seek re-election in the east ward, while across the river, one-time mayoral hopeful Ewan Wilson is not standing again. 
A much smaller lineup of 16 candidates will vie for six seats in the west ward. 
In 2013, at least 5800 votes was needed to secure a seat in the east ward, while in the west, the threshold for election was about 4800 votes. 
The city council uses a first past the post system, where voters tick the name of candidates they want to vote for. 
Meanwhile, 28 Waikato Regional Council candidates submitted their nomination forms in time for Friday&apos;s midday cut-off. 
As with the city council race, the number of candidates contesting a seat on the regional council is down from three years ago when 38 people stepped forward for election. 
Due to a lack of rivals, incumbent regional councillors Stuart Husband and Hugh Vercoe have been elected unopposed in the Waihou constituency, while Alan Livingston​ and Stuart Kneebone have been elected unopposed in the Waipa-King Country constituency. 
The regional council will use a first-past-the-post system to elect candidates in the Hamilton, Taupo, Thames-Coromandel and Waikato general constituencies, and in the two Maori constituencies. 
The Hamilton constituency, where seven names will contest four vacancies, has attracted the most candidates. 
In the Waikato District, incumbent Mayor Allan Sanson will be challenged for the top job by John Deacon, Brian Cathro, Donna Nichols and current councillor Wally Hayes. 
In Waipa, Vern Wilson will take on incumbent Jim Mylchreest​ in a head-to-head battle for the mayoral chains. 
In Matamata-Piako, Mayor Jan Barnes has been elected unopposed, while the number of councillor candidates did not exceed the number of vacancies in the district&apos;s Morrinsville and Te Aroha wards.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/national/politics/83117738/Hamiltons-mayoral-hopefuls-named</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0537</post_time>
<username>Aaron Leaman</username>
<post>
Controversial pocket park sale in Forrest Hill on Auckland&apos;s North Shore rejected by Auckland Council Kids&apos; march remembers Moko Rangitoheriri 
A field of seven hopefuls will vie to be Hamilton&apos;s next mayor. 
The mayoral candidates will line up next to 35 other contenders hoping to win a seat on the city council. 
The field is greatly reduced from three years ago, when 49 candidates battled it out across the city&apos;s two wards. 
Outgoing Hamilton Mayor Julie Hardaker​ secured the city&apos;s top job in 2013 with 15,737 votes, but in her absences, the contest to be the city&apos;s next mayor looks wide open. 
All but one of the mayoral candidates will contest a ward seat as well. 
Current councillors Rob Pascoe and Andrew King are joined in the mayoral race by Chris Simpson, Paula Southgate, James Casson, Arshad Chatha​ and Jack Gielen. 
In the east, a field of 25 candidates will chase three vacancies and the seats of three incumbents who are standing again. 
Deputy Mayor Gordon Chesterman and Crs Margaret Forsyth and Karina Green will not seek re-election in the east ward, while across the river, one-time mayoral hopeful Ewan Wilson is not standing again. 
A much smaller lineup of 16 candidates will vie for six seats in the west ward. 
In 2013, at least 5800 votes was needed to secure a seat in the east ward, while in the west, the threshold for election was about 4800 votes. 
The city council uses a first past the post system, where voters tick the name of candidates they want to vote for. 
Meanwhile, 28 Waikato Regional Council candidates submitted their nomination forms in time for Friday&apos;s midday cut-off. 
As with the city council race, the number of candidates contesting a seat on the regional council is down from three years ago when 38 people stepped forward for election. 
Due to a lack of rivals, incumbent regional councillors Stuart Husband and Hugh Vercoe have been elected unopposed in the Waihou constituency, while Alan Livingston​ and Stuart Kneebone have been elected unopposed in the Waipa-King Country constituency. 
The regional council will use a first-past-the-post system to elect candidates in the Hamilton, Taupo, Thames-Coromandel and Waikato general constituencies, and in the two Maori constituencies. 
The Hamilton constituency, where seven names will contest four vacancies, has attracted the most candidates. 
In the Waikato District, incumbent Mayor Allan Sanson will be challenged for the top job by John Deacon, Brian Cathro, Donna Nichols and current councillor Wally Hayes. 
In Waipa, Vern Wilson will take on incumbent Jim Mylchreest​ in a head-to-head battle for the mayoral chains. 
In Matamata-Piako, Mayor Jan Barnes has been elected unopposed, while the number of councillor candidates did not exceed the number of vacancies in the district&apos;s Morrinsville and Te Aroha wards.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>NZ</country>
<main_image>https://static2.stuff.co.nz/1470980334/397/15592397.jpg</main_image>
</document>
