<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.sj-r.com/news/local?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Local Government - The State Journal-Register</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Lake residents have doubts about annexation into Springfield</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.sj-r.com/news/20160811/lake-residents-have-doubts-about-annexation-into-springfield</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Lake residents have doubts about annexation into Springfield Comment Posted Aug. 11, 2016 at 6:57 PM Updated at 10:17 PM Posted Aug. 11, 2016 at 6:57 PM Updated at 10:17 PM Some Lake Springfield residents aren&apos;t buying Mayor Jim Langfelder&apos;s proposal to annex 272 lake properties into the city. It may be good for Springfield, as the mayor has argued, but the homeowners don&apos;t think it will be good for them. There are still too many unanswered questions, they say. “I understand, it is city property,” said Ed Holt, who with other affected residents met with Langfelder Wednesday night. “We don’t have a choice, we don’t have a say in it.” The city has 744 leases for land around the lake. Through past annexations, including when residents have renewed expired leases, 472 properties are already in Springfield. Under state law, the city council can vote to absorb the remaining land. Holt said he plans to be at the council meeting on Tuesday, when aldermen will hear public comments about Langfelder&apos;s proposal. “There’s a lot of questions that haven’t been answered yet, even with (Wednesday&apos;s) meeting,” Holt said. Aldermen could vote on the annexations after the public hearing. Residents on Wednesday asked how services might change after annexation, what would happen to their property taxes, and what the city plans to do with the money. Property taxes for annexed houses would likely increase, city officials acknowledged. The bulk of property taxes go to school districts, which would not be affected. Annexed residents would no longer have to pay separate taxing districts for fire protection and access to a library, but would have to pay into the city’s corporate fund. For a $200,000 house on Cottage Grove Lane slated to join the city, for example, the owners paid $304 in 2015 for fire department and library services, which they wouldn’t have to if annexed. But, using those 2015 numbers, they would have to pay $522 to the city. They might also be subject to other taxing bodies, including the Springfield Park District. Township taxes make it more complicated. The owners of the Cottage Grove Lane house paid about $300 for road maintenance and other services to Rochester Township. If the house were annexed and joined Capital Township, the owners would pay only about $50 in township taxes. After the owners of a Hazel Dell Drive house renewed their lease with the city and were annexed into Springfield in 2012, they paid about $388 more in property taxes the next year. In order to make annexation more palatable, Langfelder has proposed allowing residents to stay in their current townships through an intergovernmental agreement. Township officials met with Langfelder on Wednesday, as well, to discuss the agreement. Carroll Sutton, a Woodside Township trustee, said he was unsure if his township would sign on. “I’m not sure what the intergovernmental agreement is about,” Sutton said. “It doesn’t look like something Woodside is going to do.” Page 2 of 2 - For now, he is encouraging residents to go to next week&apos;s public hearing. Langfelder argues that road maintenance would improve, with some responsibilities shifting to public works instead of City Water, Light and Power, which repairs the lake roads now. Ken Foard, a 25-year lake resident, attended Wednesday&apos;s meeting, which drew about 100 people. “My biggest concern was, are services going to go down?” he said. “Once you get lost in a city of 100,000, your voice is a lot weaker.” -- Contact Mary Hansen: 788-1528, , twitter.com/maryfhansen . By
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.sj-r.com/news/20160811/lake-residents-have-doubts-about-annexation-into-springfield</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0317</post_time>
<username>Mary Hansen</username>
<post>
Lake residents have doubts about annexation into Springfield Comment Posted Aug. 11, 2016 at 6:57 PM Updated at 10:17 PM Posted Aug. 11, 2016 at 6:57 PM Updated at 10:17 PM Some Lake Springfield residents aren&apos;t buying Mayor Jim Langfelder&apos;s proposal to annex 272 lake properties into the city. It may be good for Springfield, as the mayor has argued, but the homeowners don&apos;t think it will be good for them. There are still too many unanswered questions, they say. “I understand, it is city property,” said Ed Holt, who with other affected residents met with Langfelder Wednesday night. “We don’t have a choice, we don’t have a say in it.” The city has 744 leases for land around the lake. Through past annexations, including when residents have renewed expired leases, 472 properties are already in Springfield. Under state law, the city council can vote to absorb the remaining land. Holt said he plans to be at the council meeting on Tuesday, when aldermen will hear public comments about Langfelder&apos;s proposal. “There’s a lot of questions that haven’t been answered yet, even with (Wednesday&apos;s) meeting,” Holt said. Aldermen could vote on the annexations after the public hearing. Residents on Wednesday asked how services might change after annexation, what would happen to their property taxes, and what the city plans to do with the money. Property taxes for annexed houses would likely increase, city officials acknowledged. The bulk of property taxes go to school districts, which would not be affected. Annexed residents would no longer have to pay separate taxing districts for fire protection and access to a library, but would have to pay into the city’s corporate fund. For a $200,000 house on Cottage Grove Lane slated to join the city, for example, the owners paid $304 in 2015 for fire department and library services, which they wouldn’t have to if annexed. But, using those 2015 numbers, they would have to pay $522 to the city. They might also be subject to other taxing bodies, including the Springfield Park District. Township taxes make it more complicated. The owners of the Cottage Grove Lane house paid about $300 for road maintenance and other services to Rochester Township. If the house were annexed and joined Capital Township, the owners would pay only about $50 in township taxes. After the owners of a Hazel Dell Drive house renewed their lease with the city and were annexed into Springfield in 2012, they paid about $388 more in property taxes the next year. In order to make annexation more palatable, Langfelder has proposed allowing residents to stay in their current townships through an intergovernmental agreement. Township officials met with Langfelder on Wednesday, as well, to discuss the agreement. Carroll Sutton, a Woodside Township trustee, said he was unsure if his township would sign on. “I’m not sure what the intergovernmental agreement is about,” Sutton said. “It doesn’t look like something Woodside is going to do.” Page 2 of 2 - For now, he is encouraging residents to go to next week&apos;s public hearing. Langfelder argues that road maintenance would improve, with some responsibilities shifting to public works instead of City Water, Light and Power, which repairs the lake roads now. Ken Foard, a 25-year lake resident, attended Wednesday&apos;s meeting, which drew about 100 people. “My biggest concern was, are services going to go down?” he said. “Once you get lost in a city of 100,000, your voice is a lot weaker.” -- Contact Mary Hansen: 788-1528, , twitter.com/maryfhansen . By
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.sj-r.com/storyimage/LS/20160811/NEWS/160819880/AR/0/AR-160819880.jpg</main_image>
</document>
