<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.devilslakejournal.com/obituaries?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Obituaries - Devils Lake Journal - Devils Lake, ND</forum_title>
<discussion_title>OBIT: Dakotah Skye Old Rock</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.devilslakejournal.com/news/20160811/obit-dakotah-skye-old-rock</topic_url>
<topic_text>
OBIT: Dakotah Skye Old Rock Dacotah Skye Old Rock, 21, of Devils Lake ND and the Spirit Lake Nation, began his journey to the Spirit World on Sunday, August 7, 2016.   11, 2016 at 10:04 AM Posted Aug. 11, 2016 at 10:04 AM Dacotah Skye Old Rock, 21, of Devils Lake ND and the Spirit Lake Nation, began his journey to the Spirit World on Sunday, August 7, 2016. The wake for Dacotah will be held on Sunday, August 14 at St. Michael’s Recreation Center beginning at 5 p.m. with a Rosary and prayer service at 7 p.m. The procession to St. Michael will leave at 4 p.m. on Sunday from the City Plaza. Mass of the Resurrection will be held on Monday, August 15 at 10 a.m. at St. Michael’s Catholic Church with Father Paul Schuster celebrating the Mass. Dacotah will be laid to rest in St. Jerome’s Cemetery, rural Fort Totten, ND. Active pallbearers will be Rashawn Thompson, Ryan Robertson, Wayne Littleghost, Angel Najar, Anthony Sam Migual, Darret Mudgett, Markie Littleghost, Colton Littleghost. Honorary pallbearers are Shandie Brown, Jarrett Cook, Chris Cook, Tom Robertson, Drazen White Bull, McKenzie White Bull, Cherylin Bendickson, Amaryllis Eagle, Trista RedFox, Montel Thompson, Latoyah Demarce, Julia Ann Yatskis, Tawny GoodLeft, Kaylee Nadeau, Emjayee Leaf, Autumn Rosebud, Joe Azure, Kesharia Pollins, Emily Ashleen SwiftHawk, Roslyn Thompson, Montana Chaske, Kyle IronHawk, Trista Dauphinais, Kyle Belgarde, the staff at Quentin Burdick Job Corps and the Devils Lake police officers, Cory Gilbertson, Matthew Ertelt, Tyler Czarnowsky and Brandon Potts, Dr. Jackie Downs, EMT Staff, Sean Roed, Issac Bennet, Alissa James family, Myra Pearson family, April Longie family, Wahnita Chaske family, Renita “FeeFee” Shaw family, Tracie Charboneau family, Phyllis DuBois family and Cynthia Lindquist. We are most grateful for your caring hearts. If we forgot to name someone it was not intentional. God Bless all of Dacotah’s loving family and many friends. Dacotah blessed us with his birth on May 21, 1995, in Bismarck ND. He is the son of Jory White Bull and Rani Old Rock. He attended many schools throughout his very short life. He attended school at Riverside Elementary, Bismarck, Minnie H Elementary Devils Lake, Four Winds Elementary Fort Totten, Devils Lake Middle School Devils Lake, Riverside Indian School Anadarko, OK, and Warwick Public School. He later realized his dream to complete school at Quentin Burdick Job Corp in Minot, ND, getting his high school diploma March 11, 2016 and his Carpentry Certificate March 24, 2016. Dacotah enjoyed playing basketball, hanging out with his friends, being helpful and self-motivated. He was always willing to go the extra mile. He held a job in East Grand Forks, MN at McDonalds and then later at McDonalds in Fargo, ND. He was fun loving and loved kids with hopes of having some of his own one day. Dacotah is survived by his parents, Jory White Bull and Rani Old Rock; his sister, Sierra White Bull and five brothers, Trevor Alberts, Kaleb Old Rock, Kobe Old Rock, Austa White Bull, Jory White Bull Jr. He also leaves his paternal great grandma, Belva Eagle of Mobridge, SD; maternal grandpa, Darren Yankton, Grand Forks, ND; adopted grandma, Rita Leaf, St. Michael, ND; aunts and uncles, Pretty Deer and Steve Eagleman of Oregon, Memorie Old Rock, Fargo and Winterhawk and Janet Old Rock, Minnesota; numerous loved other aunts, uncles and cousins. He loved all his family very much. Page 2 of 2 - He is joining his great grandma, Irene Yankton Brown; great grandpa, Leonard Old Rock; grandmas, Patricia White Bull, and Micki Diserly; grandpas, Levi Eagleman and Oliver Eagleman; aun,t Star Martin and grandma, Wilma Martin. Gilbertson Funeral Home, Devils Lake, has been entrusted with his care.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.devilslakejournal.com/news/20160811/obit-dakotah-skye-old-rock</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1504</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
OBIT: Dakotah Skye Old Rock Dacotah Skye Old Rock, 21, of Devils Lake ND and the Spirit Lake Nation, began his journey to the Spirit World on Sunday, August 7, 2016.   11, 2016 at 10:04 AM Posted Aug. 11, 2016 at 10:04 AM Dacotah Skye Old Rock, 21, of Devils Lake ND and the Spirit Lake Nation, began his journey to the Spirit World on Sunday, August 7, 2016. The wake for Dacotah will be held on Sunday, August 14 at St. Michael’s Recreation Center beginning at 5 p.m. with a Rosary and prayer service at 7 p.m. The procession to St. Michael will leave at 4 p.m. on Sunday from the City Plaza. Mass of the Resurrection will be held on Monday, August 15 at 10 a.m. at St. Michael’s Catholic Church with Father Paul Schuster celebrating the Mass. Dacotah will be laid to rest in St. Jerome’s Cemetery, rural Fort Totten, ND. Active pallbearers will be Rashawn Thompson, Ryan Robertson, Wayne Littleghost, Angel Najar, Anthony Sam Migual, Darret Mudgett, Markie Littleghost, Colton Littleghost. Honorary pallbearers are Shandie Brown, Jarrett Cook, Chris Cook, Tom Robertson, Drazen White Bull, McKenzie White Bull, Cherylin Bendickson, Amaryllis Eagle, Trista RedFox, Montel Thompson, Latoyah Demarce, Julia Ann Yatskis, Tawny GoodLeft, Kaylee Nadeau, Emjayee Leaf, Autumn Rosebud, Joe Azure, Kesharia Pollins, Emily Ashleen SwiftHawk, Roslyn Thompson, Montana Chaske, Kyle IronHawk, Trista Dauphinais, Kyle Belgarde, the staff at Quentin Burdick Job Corps and the Devils Lake police officers, Cory Gilbertson, Matthew Ertelt, Tyler Czarnowsky and Brandon Potts, Dr. Jackie Downs, EMT Staff, Sean Roed, Issac Bennet, Alissa James family, Myra Pearson family, April Longie family, Wahnita Chaske family, Renita “FeeFee” Shaw family, Tracie Charboneau family, Phyllis DuBois family and Cynthia Lindquist. We are most grateful for your caring hearts. If we forgot to name someone it was not intentional. God Bless all of Dacotah’s loving family and many friends. Dacotah blessed us with his birth on May 21, 1995, in Bismarck ND. He is the son of Jory White Bull and Rani Old Rock. He attended many schools throughout his very short life. He attended school at Riverside Elementary, Bismarck, Minnie H Elementary Devils Lake, Four Winds Elementary Fort Totten, Devils Lake Middle School Devils Lake, Riverside Indian School Anadarko, OK, and Warwick Public School. He later realized his dream to complete school at Quentin Burdick Job Corp in Minot, ND, getting his high school diploma March 11, 2016 and his Carpentry Certificate March 24, 2016. Dacotah enjoyed playing basketball, hanging out with his friends, being helpful and self-motivated. He was always willing to go the extra mile. He held a job in East Grand Forks, MN at McDonalds and then later at McDonalds in Fargo, ND. He was fun loving and loved kids with hopes of having some of his own one day. Dacotah is survived by his parents, Jory White Bull and Rani Old Rock; his sister, Sierra White Bull and five brothers, Trevor Alberts, Kaleb Old Rock, Kobe Old Rock, Austa White Bull, Jory White Bull Jr. He also leaves his paternal great grandma, Belva Eagle of Mobridge, SD; maternal grandpa, Darren Yankton, Grand Forks, ND; adopted grandma, Rita Leaf, St. Michael, ND; aunts and uncles, Pretty Deer and Steve Eagleman of Oregon, Memorie Old Rock, Fargo and Winterhawk and Janet Old Rock, Minnesota; numerous loved other aunts, uncles and cousins. He loved all his family very much. Page 2 of 2 - He is joining his great grandma, Irene Yankton Brown; great grandpa, Leonard Old Rock; grandmas, Patricia White Bull, and Micki Diserly; grandpas, Levi Eagleman and Oliver Eagleman; aun,t Star Martin and grandma, Wilma Martin. Gilbertson Funeral Home, Devils Lake, has been entrusted with his care.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.devilslakejournal.com/storyimage/MO/20160811/NEWS/160819818/AR/0/AR-160819818.jpg</main_image>
</document>
