<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.stuff.co.nz/rss/manawatu-standard/news</forum>
<forum_title>Stuff.co.nz - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mayoral contest in Palmerston North to cost $30,000</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/manawatu-standard/news/83124328/mayoral-contest-in-palmerston-north-to-cost-30000</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Mayoral contest in Palmerston North to cost $30,000 Last updated 17:21, August 12 2016 Janine Rankin 
Palmerston North electoral officer Dr John Annabell counts down the seconds before the noon deadline for local body election nominations. 
Palmerston North mayor Grant Smith is going to have to defend his position after an eleventh-hour bid for the top job from pig farmer and convicted child assaulter Ross Barber. 
Campaigning under the banner of Team God, Barber also contested the 2013 mayoral election and 2015 by-election, most recently ending at the back of the field with 151 first preference votes. 
Up until an hour before nominations closed on Friday, Smith had been looking likely to be re-elected unopposed, and ratepayers would have saved $30,000 for a simplified election for council only. 
Smith said he had not expected to be the sole nominee, and it was Barber&apos;s democratic right to have another go. 
READ MORE: * Council candidates perform for a small crowd 
He said he had already booked in time for campaigning, and would be getting his 2015 election signs out for another round of duty. 
Barber said he had long intended to stand, and was doing what Team God, the good people of the Dominion, wanted him to do. 
He said he was standing because people were sick of &quot;corruption and lack of honesty&quot; in the council and in the world. 
Massey University local government commentator Christine Cheyne said it was disappointing the incumbent mayor was not facing some strong challenges. 
&quot;My concern is voter turn out, and when people think the incumbent is likely to get a lot of support, they tend to be less interested.&quot; Ad Feedback 
She said the $30,000 cost of the contest was simply the price of democracy, and it ensured Smith would have to engage with voters and respond to any critics. 
Cheyne said it was good to see a healthy, strong field of candidates for the city council, with a good mix of age, gender and ethnicity. 
A total of 28 people are competing for the 15 seats, and at least three new councillors will be elected, with sitting councillors Ross Linklater, Annette Nixon and Chris Teo-Sherrell not seeking re-election. 
In the Manawatu District, incumbent mayor Margaret Kouvelis will go head to head with Helen Worboys in the race for mayoralty. 
Kouvelis has served on the Manawatu District Council since 2010. In 2012 she won the mayoral by-election and in 2013 was elected unopposed 
Kouvelis said &quot;there is more work to be done&quot; and wanted to continue to build a brighter future for Manawatu. 
She noted the importance of lifting the tourism potential of Feilding by supporting local businesses. She also wanted to complete the upgrade of the Feilding waste water treatment plant. 
&quot;We need to grow Feilding and our villages,&quot; she said. 
&quot;We are the heart of central New Zealand. Farming is our key industry. We need to drive the future of the agricultural economy along with its supporting industries.&quot; 
She comes up against former manager of Feilding and District Promotions Helen Worboys who said she was &quot;determined&quot; to &quot;change the culture&quot; and put community voice back into council. 
&quot;I am concerned about the growth of the actual council organisation in recent years as council should be a lean organisation with a can-do attitude.&quot; 
She believed community and volunteer organisations had been treated roughly under Kouvelis with many of them having their funding cut or seriously limited. 
Worboys said it was these organisations that were the backbone of Feilding and made the town stand out among the rest. 
&quot;Feilding and District Promotions, the Coachouse Museum, Manchester House are all community or volunteer groups which have struggled but make Feilding what it is.&quot; 
Over at the Rangitikei District Council, mayor Andy Watson faces opposition from George London and Robert Snijders. 
Watson said there was still a job to be finished. 
He said the council was starting to make headway on major infrastructure upgrades around the region. 
&quot;It&apos;s something that&apos;s close to my heart and I want to see it through. The new proposed centre in Bulls is in the process and there&apos;s similar plans for Marton and Taihape that I want to be there for.&quot; 
He said his highlight was increasing government subsidies for the district&apos;s road network after the Government proposed a nine per cent drop. He said it was a &quot;major win&quot; that saved the district millions of dollars. 
London has been a resident in Marton for 16 years and has chaired the community patrol there. He said the council needed a &quot;stronger&quot; leader. 
&quot;I don&apos;t think there&apos;s a strong enough council there at the moment. 
&quot;They&apos;re a bit shy, a bit quiet and I want to be a bit louder and get out there more.&quot; 
Tararua will be electing a new mayor, with Roly Ellis standing down. Shirley Hull, Allan Benbow, Tracey Collis, Ernie Christison and Kay McKenzie are in the running. 
For Horizons Regional Council, chairman Bruce Gordon and the other sitting councillor for Manawatu-Rangitikei Gordon McKellar have both been re-elected unopposed. 
The remaining constituencies need elections, with all current sitting councillors, bar Murray Guy and Rod Pearce, standing again. A field of 18 are contesting seven seats on the MidCentral District Health Board. All existing members have put their names in for another term. As well as sitting board member and city councillor Adrian Broad, five other city council candidates are also standing — deputy mayor Duncan McCann, sitting councillors Lew Findlay and Vaughan Dennison, candidate Martin Egan and council candidate and sitting board member Karen Naylor.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/manawatu-standard/news/83124328/mayoral-contest-in-palmerston-north-to-cost-30000</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0521</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Mayoral contest in Palmerston North to cost $30,000 Last updated 17:21, August 12 2016 Janine Rankin 
Palmerston North electoral officer Dr John Annabell counts down the seconds before the noon deadline for local body election nominations. 
Palmerston North mayor Grant Smith is going to have to defend his position after an eleventh-hour bid for the top job from pig farmer and convicted child assaulter Ross Barber. 
Campaigning under the banner of Team God, Barber also contested the 2013 mayoral election and 2015 by-election, most recently ending at the back of the field with 151 first preference votes. 
Up until an hour before nominations closed on Friday, Smith had been looking likely to be re-elected unopposed, and ratepayers would have saved $30,000 for a simplified election for council only. 
Smith said he had not expected to be the sole nominee, and it was Barber&apos;s democratic right to have another go. 
READ MORE: * Council candidates perform for a small crowd 
He said he had already booked in time for campaigning, and would be getting his 2015 election signs out for another round of duty. 
Barber said he had long intended to stand, and was doing what Team God, the good people of the Dominion, wanted him to do. 
He said he was standing because people were sick of &quot;corruption and lack of honesty&quot; in the council and in the world. 
Massey University local government commentator Christine Cheyne said it was disappointing the incumbent mayor was not facing some strong challenges. 
&quot;My concern is voter turn out, and when people think the incumbent is likely to get a lot of support, they tend to be less interested.&quot; Ad Feedback 
She said the $30,000 cost of the contest was simply the price of democracy, and it ensured Smith would have to engage with voters and respond to any critics. 
Cheyne said it was good to see a healthy, strong field of candidates for the city council, with a good mix of age, gender and ethnicity. 
A total of 28 people are competing for the 15 seats, and at least three new councillors will be elected, with sitting councillors Ross Linklater, Annette Nixon and Chris Teo-Sherrell not seeking re-election. 
In the Manawatu District, incumbent mayor Margaret Kouvelis will go head to head with Helen Worboys in the race for mayoralty. 
Kouvelis has served on the Manawatu District Council since 2010. In 2012 she won the mayoral by-election and in 2013 was elected unopposed 
Kouvelis said &quot;there is more work to be done&quot; and wanted to continue to build a brighter future for Manawatu. 
She noted the importance of lifting the tourism potential of Feilding by supporting local businesses. She also wanted to complete the upgrade of the Feilding waste water treatment plant. 
&quot;We need to grow Feilding and our villages,&quot; she said. 
&quot;We are the heart of central New Zealand. Farming is our key industry. We need to drive the future of the agricultural economy along with its supporting industries.&quot; 
She comes up against former manager of Feilding and District Promotions Helen Worboys who said she was &quot;determined&quot; to &quot;change the culture&quot; and put community voice back into council. 
&quot;I am concerned about the growth of the actual council organisation in recent years as council should be a lean organisation with a can-do attitude.&quot; 
She believed community and volunteer organisations had been treated roughly under Kouvelis with many of them having their funding cut or seriously limited. 
Worboys said it was these organisations that were the backbone of Feilding and made the town stand out among the rest. 
&quot;Feilding and District Promotions, the Coachouse Museum, Manchester House are all community or volunteer groups which have struggled but make Feilding what it is.&quot; 
Over at the Rangitikei District Council, mayor Andy Watson faces opposition from George London and Robert Snijders. 
Watson said there was still a job to be finished. 
He said the council was starting to make headway on major infrastructure upgrades around the region. 
&quot;It&apos;s something that&apos;s close to my heart and I want to see it through. The new proposed centre in Bulls is in the process and there&apos;s similar plans for Marton and Taihape that I want to be there for.&quot; 
He said his highlight was increasing government subsidies for the district&apos;s road network after the Government proposed a nine per cent drop. He said it was a &quot;major win&quot; that saved the district millions of dollars. 
London has been a resident in Marton for 16 years and has chaired the community patrol there. He said the council needed a &quot;stronger&quot; leader. 
&quot;I don&apos;t think there&apos;s a strong enough council there at the moment. 
&quot;They&apos;re a bit shy, a bit quiet and I want to be a bit louder and get out there more.&quot; 
Tararua will be electing a new mayor, with Roly Ellis standing down. Shirley Hull, Allan Benbow, Tracey Collis, Ernie Christison and Kay McKenzie are in the running. 
For Horizons Regional Council, chairman Bruce Gordon and the other sitting councillor for Manawatu-Rangitikei Gordon McKellar have both been re-elected unopposed. 
The remaining constituencies need elections, with all current sitting councillors, bar Murray Guy and Rod Pearce, standing again. A field of 18 are contesting seven seats on the MidCentral District Health Board. All existing members have put their names in for another term. As well as sitting board member and city councillor Adrian Broad, five other city council candidates are also standing — deputy mayor Duncan McCann, sitting councillors Lew Findlay and Vaughan Dennison, candidate Martin Egan and council candidate and sitting board member Karen Naylor.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>NZ</country>
<main_image>http://www.stuff.co.nz/content/dam/images/1/d/h/q/1/m/image.related.StuffLandscapeSixteenByNine.620x349.1dhn54.png/1470979291532.jpg</main_image>
</document>
