<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Big Kedumba drawing award makes a return | Central Western Daily</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.centralwesterndaily.com.au/story/4092906/big-kedumba-drawing-award-makes-a-return/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Big Kedumba drawing award makes a return 12 Aug 2016, 2:29 p.m. This year’s Kedumba Drawing Award, opens on Saturday, August 20 Wendy Tsai: The gully, winter #1 (detail), 2015, pencil and watercolour. Acquired from the 2015 
This year’s Kedumba Drawing Award, opens next Saturday, August 20 at Orange Regional Gallery. As readers may recall from previous years, the Kedumba Drawing Award is now an annual highlight at Orange Regional Gallery having moved here from the Blue Mountains in 2014. Each year, approximately 20 artists are invited to submit a recent drawing for the exhibition, from which the judge (usually an artist) acquires works for the Kedumba Collection. This means that around five or so new drawings enter the Kedumba Collection of Australian Drawings annually, which is now on long term loan to Orange Regional Gallery. 
The Kedumba Award and Collection have played a vital role in fostering the appreciation of drawing in Australia. Since its inception in 1990, the Kedumba Collection has acquired over 220 drawings. 
These have been mainly sourced from the annual Kedumba Drawing Award, but also via approved gifts from artists and other benefactors, and acquisitions by the artist Trustees and Director on behalf of the collection. As a result of this unique approach, the collection is considered to be of outstanding significance and importance. 
Drawing is the foundation of all visual art and this principle lies at the heart of the Kedumba Collection. The diversity of work highlights just how varied the personal visions of different artists can be within a single discipline. It also demonstrates the varying subjective tastes of the judges of the Kedumba Drawing Award over the years, a list which includes many notable artists. 
This years artists are: Tim Allen, John Bokor, Chris Casali, Maryanne Coutts, Todd Fuller, Gabrielle Jones, Gina Kalabishis, Martin King, Jo Lane, Rowen Matthews, Kevin McKay, Julie Nettleton, Stephen Nova, Edgar Schilter, Heather Vallance, Peter Wegner, Mirra Whale, Tim Winters, Gosia Wlodarczak and Lisa Woolfe. 
While there are periods when the art of drawing is overlooked in teaching institutions and the contemporary art world, it continually re-emerges as an essential practice. This is largely because it is the primary means of visual expression, offering to the artist a direct and immediate way of responding to experiences and expressing ideas. 
The Kedumba Collection embodies and reflects all the elements of outstanding drawing created in Australia over more than 40 years. 
Join us at 2.30pm on Saturday, August 20 for the opening event. The 2016 judge Paul Delprat will discuss his responses to this year’s selection and announce the acquisitions. This is a fundraising event for Kedumba and entry is $25. 
The Kedumba Drawing Award exhibition runs from August 20 to October 16. 
Also on display at the gallery: Country and Western: landscape re-imagined, Murmuration: Jenny Cuthbert; and Ways of Being: Portraits from the Collection. Exhibitions are free. 
The gallery is open 10am to 4pm daily. For more information contact 6393 8136 or visit the gallery’s website: www.org.nsw.gov.au. Latest News 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.centralwesterndaily.com.au/story/4092906/big-kedumba-drawing-award-makes-a-return/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Australian Community Media - Fairfax Media</username>
<post>
Big Kedumba drawing award makes a return 12 Aug 2016, 2:29 p.m. This year’s Kedumba Drawing Award, opens on Saturday, August 20 Wendy Tsai: The gully, winter #1 (detail), 2015, pencil and watercolour. Acquired from the 2015 
This year’s Kedumba Drawing Award, opens next Saturday, August 20 at Orange Regional Gallery. As readers may recall from previous years, the Kedumba Drawing Award is now an annual highlight at Orange Regional Gallery having moved here from the Blue Mountains in 2014. Each year, approximately 20 artists are invited to submit a recent drawing for the exhibition, from which the judge (usually an artist) acquires works for the Kedumba Collection. This means that around five or so new drawings enter the Kedumba Collection of Australian Drawings annually, which is now on long term loan to Orange Regional Gallery. 
The Kedumba Award and Collection have played a vital role in fostering the appreciation of drawing in Australia. Since its inception in 1990, the Kedumba Collection has acquired over 220 drawings. 
These have been mainly sourced from the annual Kedumba Drawing Award, but also via approved gifts from artists and other benefactors, and acquisitions by the artist Trustees and Director on behalf of the collection. As a result of this unique approach, the collection is considered to be of outstanding significance and importance. 
Drawing is the foundation of all visual art and this principle lies at the heart of the Kedumba Collection. The diversity of work highlights just how varied the personal visions of different artists can be within a single discipline. It also demonstrates the varying subjective tastes of the judges of the Kedumba Drawing Award over the years, a list which includes many notable artists. 
This years artists are: Tim Allen, John Bokor, Chris Casali, Maryanne Coutts, Todd Fuller, Gabrielle Jones, Gina Kalabishis, Martin King, Jo Lane, Rowen Matthews, Kevin McKay, Julie Nettleton, Stephen Nova, Edgar Schilter, Heather Vallance, Peter Wegner, Mirra Whale, Tim Winters, Gosia Wlodarczak and Lisa Woolfe. 
While there are periods when the art of drawing is overlooked in teaching institutions and the contemporary art world, it continually re-emerges as an essential practice. This is largely because it is the primary means of visual expression, offering to the artist a direct and immediate way of responding to experiences and expressing ideas. 
The Kedumba Collection embodies and reflects all the elements of outstanding drawing created in Australia over more than 40 years. 
Join us at 2.30pm on Saturday, August 20 for the opening event. The 2016 judge Paul Delprat will discuss his responses to this year’s selection and announce the acquisitions. This is a fundraising event for Kedumba and entry is $25. 
The Kedumba Drawing Award exhibition runs from August 20 to October 16. 
Also on display at the gallery: Country and Western: landscape re-imagined, Murmuration: Jenny Cuthbert; and Ways of Being: Portraits from the Collection. Exhibitions are free. 
The gallery is open 10am to 4pm daily. For more information contact 6393 8136 or visit the gallery’s website: www.org.nsw.gov.au. Latest News 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://nnimgt-a.akamaihd.net/transform/v1/crop/frm/gQFChmftLwURjFztaywNzt/311f3fa3-f37a-4f8f-80c6-b5905cb8b613.jpg/r666_695_1852_1365_w1200_h678_fmax.jpg</main_image>
</document>
