<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Update on the latest news, sports, business and entertainment: - News-Talk 1110 &amp; 99.3 WBT</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wbt.com/update-on-the-latest-news-sports-business-and-entertainment-225/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Update on the latest news, sports, business and entertainment: 
CAMPAIGN 2016-TRUMP 
NEW: Trump reconsidering US immigration policy for Cubans 
WASHINGTON (AP) -- Donald Trump says he wants to know what Cuban-Americans think about continuing with the &quot;wet foot, dry foot&quot; immigration policy. 
Under the policy, Cubans intercepted at sea usually are sent back to the island. 
Those who step foot on U.S. soil are usually allowed to stay. 
Trump says he plans to meet with Cuban-Americans to help determine whether he&apos;ll support continuing the policy. 
RIO OLYMPICS 
UPDATE: More US gold 
RIO DE JANEIRO (AP) -- U.S. swimmer Michael Phelps and gymnast Simone Biles have powered their way to more gold medals at the Rio Games. 
Biles moved to the sounds of Latin music as she soared to the women&apos;s all-around gymnastics title. 
Hours later, Phelps blew away rival Ryan Lochte and everyone else to win his fourth gold medal at the Rio Games, and his 22nd overall with a victory in the 200-meter individual medley. 
American swimmer Simone Manuel tied with Canadian Penny Oleksiak for the gold medal in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. 
OLY-POLICE ATTACKED 
Olympic officer who was shot after wrong turn into slum dies 
RIO DE JANEIRO (AP) -- A police officer has died after being shot in the head when he and two others working security at the Rio Olympics got lost near a slum and encountered gunfire. 
The officers from Brazil&apos;s national security force were using a GPS device to navigate unfamiliar streets Wednesday afternoon when they took a wrong turn off a highway leading to Rio&apos;s international airport. Their truck was sprayed with bullets, and officer Helio Vieira (EH&apos;-lee-oh vee-AYR&apos;-uh) was shot. He died late Thursday. 
The other officers suffered minor injuries when the windows of their vehicle shattered. 
More than 85,000 security forces have been deployed in Rio for the Olympics, which is double the number of London in 2012. 
OLY-TAXI STRIKE 
Rio taxi drivers plan strike over Uber during Olympics 
RIO DE JANEIRO (AP) -- Taxi drivers in Rio de Janeiro are planning a demonstration on Friday morning in the immediate vicinity of the Olympic Park to protest the use of ride-sharing program Uber. 
The U.S. Consulate General&apos;s office sent a message to U.S. citizens in Brazil on Thursday, based on information they received from organizers of the planned strike. Those organizers say they&apos;re planning to close avenues around the Olympic Park, and doing so at rush hour could snarl traffic. 
The message says &quot;such an event would affect transport for visitors to venues in the Olympic Park.&quot; 
There was no immediate comment from local organizers about whether they were concerned about the planned strike. 
Uber has been the target of scorn from taxi drivers around the world, including demonstrations in Paris, New York, Chicago and Mexico City. 
THAILAND-BOMBING 
UPDATE: Deadly bombings in Thailand 
BANGKOK (AP) -- Police in Thailand say a wave of deadly bomb blasts in the central and southern parts of the country is not linked to Islamic terrorism. 
Multiple explosions hit at least four Thai cities overnight and on Friday, killing several people and wounding dozens more. 
About 10 foreigners were wounded in the seaside town of Hua Hin. 
CHANCE AT FREEDOM 
Judge orders man free after 28 years, cites unfair trial 
WILMINGTON, N.C. (AP) -- A judge on Thursday ruled that a North Carolina man who was convicted of murder as a teenager and was imprisoned 28 years ago did not get a fair trial and allowed him to go free. 
North Carolina Superior Court Judge W. Douglas Parsons ruled Thursday that there was not enough evidence to justify 43-year-old Johnny Small&apos;s conviction for a 1988 murder. 
The judge said he didn&apos;t see proof of Small&apos;s innocence, but was persuaded that prosecutors must decide if there was enough evidence to put him on trial again. 
Small was released from a Wilmington prison and arrived at his cousin&apos;s manufactured home just before nightfall Thursday. There he&apos;ll spend his first night of freedom on the living room sofa rather than in a bed in a room cleared for him. 
&quot;I don&apos;t want to sleep in no room. I want to be in a big space,&quot; Small said. 
MISSING BOY-SEARCH 
Still no sign of missing Arizona boy after latest search 
BUCKEYE, Ariz. (AP) -- Federal and local authorities in Arizona unsuccessfully searched a field for a 10-year-old boy who has been missing for nearly a month. 
Buckeye Police Sgt. Jason Weeks says officers walked Thursday through an undeveloped lot covered with brush and trees as part of what he called a secondary search. 
He says authorities have been actively searching for Jesse Wilson since he went missing from his home and want to double check areas that had been searched previously. 
Weeks says authorities will not stop looking for the boy. 
The case still is being investigated as a runaway and no foul play has been identified. 
The FBI, Buckeye police and the Maricopa County Sheriff&apos;s Office participated in Thursday&apos;s search. 
Previous searches have involved drones, U.S. Border Patrol tracking dogs and citizen volunteers. 
CHICAGO POLICE 
Muslim woman sues Chicago, 6 officers for false terrorist ID 
CHICAGO (AP) -- A Muslim woman is suing the city of Chicago and six officers who falsely singled her out as a potential terrorist on July 4, 2015, as she left a subway station wearing a headscarf, face veil and carrying a backpack. 
Itemid Al-Matar&apos;s federal lawsuit filed Thursday says officers pulled off her religious garb, arrested her and later strip-searched her. The 32-year-old was acquitted of obstructing justice. 
The Council on American-Islamic Relations says &quot;blatant xenophobia, Islamophobia and racial profiling&quot; motivated the arrest. 
A public police report says officers &quot;were on high alert of terrorist activity&quot; on the national holiday and that Al-Matar was exhibiting &quot;suspicious behavior.&quot; 
The CPD declined to comment but said in a statement that police &quot;strive to treat all individuals with the highest levels of dignity of respect.&quot; 
PENN STATE-ABUSE 
NEW: Sandusky prepares to testify in bid to overturn conviction 
HARRISBURG, Pa. (AP) -- Former Penn State assistant football coach Jerry Sandusky is expected to take the stand Friday to try to prove his claim that he was wrongly convicted four years ago of sexually abusing 10 boys. 
Sandusky plans to appear in a Pennsylvania courthouse for a Post-Conviction Relief Act hearing. 
The 72-year-old was convicted of 45 counts and is serving a 30- to 60-year sentence. 
CALIFORNIA WATER TUNNELS-FUNDING 
NEW: New questions over California water project 
SAN FRANCISCO (AP) -- Critics and a California lawmaker want more answers from Gov. Jerry Brown&apos;s administration on who&apos;s paying for a proposed giant water project. 
That&apos;s after a Southern California water district said Thursday that Brown&apos;s administration is now stating that state or federal funds will be used to finish planning for two $16 billion water tunnels. The 35-mile-long tunnels would carry water from Northern California south, mainly for Central and Southern California. Brown&apos;s administration is pushing to get regulatory approval for the tunnels before he leaves office in two years. 
Tunnel opponents say Thursday&apos;s statement from the Metropolitan Water District in Los Angeles could go against longstanding assurances that local water agencies would pay for the tunnels, not the state. Aides to California Assemblywoman Susan Eggman say she has asked officials for an explanation of the water district&apos;s statement Thursday. Eggman was part of a legislative committee that already had ordered a state audit of the tunnels project earlier this week. 
State spokeswoman Nancy Vogel says funding to finish the planning of the tunnels will come from user payments for an existing state water project, and not from the state&apos;s general fund. 
HOSTESS-WAL-MART 
NEW: Hostess launches &quot;Deep Fried Twinkies&quot; as first frozen treat 
NEW YORK (AP) -- The deep-fried Twinkie is jumping from the state fair to the home freezer. 
Hostess Brands is launching packaged &quot;Deep Fried Twinkies&quot; starting Friday that mark its first foray into frozen foods. 
The cream-filled snack in vanilla or chocolate is the result of a yearlong collaboration between Hostess and Wal-Mart, as both companies look to spark food sales with innovative products. Hostess says the Twinkie is a bigger business now than even right before the company filed for bankruptcy in 2012. 
For Wal-Mart, it&apos;s part of a strategy of working with suppliers to come up with twists on existing foods or developing new ones. The company, which gets more than half its sales from food, opened a food lab in June as it aims to get products to the shelves faster. Category 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wbt.com/update-on-the-latest-news-sports-business-and-entertainment-225/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Update on the latest news, sports, business and entertainment: 
CAMPAIGN 2016-TRUMP 
NEW: Trump reconsidering US immigration policy for Cubans 
WASHINGTON (AP) -- Donald Trump says he wants to know what Cuban-Americans think about continuing with the &quot;wet foot, dry foot&quot; immigration policy. 
Under the policy, Cubans intercepted at sea usually are sent back to the island. 
Those who step foot on U.S. soil are usually allowed to stay. 
Trump says he plans to meet with Cuban-Americans to help determine whether he&apos;ll support continuing the policy. 
RIO OLYMPICS 
UPDATE: More US gold 
RIO DE JANEIRO (AP) -- U.S. swimmer Michael Phelps and gymnast Simone Biles have powered their way to more gold medals at the Rio Games. 
Biles moved to the sounds of Latin music as she soared to the women&apos;s all-around gymnastics title. 
Hours later, Phelps blew away rival Ryan Lochte and everyone else to win his fourth gold medal at the Rio Games, and his 22nd overall with a victory in the 200-meter individual medley. 
American swimmer Simone Manuel tied with Canadian Penny Oleksiak for the gold medal in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. 
OLY-POLICE ATTACKED 
Olympic officer who was shot after wrong turn into slum dies 
RIO DE JANEIRO (AP) -- A police officer has died after being shot in the head when he and two others working security at the Rio Olympics got lost near a slum and encountered gunfire. 
The officers from Brazil&apos;s national security force were using a GPS device to navigate unfamiliar streets Wednesday afternoon when they took a wrong turn off a highway leading to Rio&apos;s international airport. Their truck was sprayed with bullets, and officer Helio Vieira (EH&apos;-lee-oh vee-AYR&apos;-uh) was shot. He died late Thursday. 
The other officers suffered minor injuries when the windows of their vehicle shattered. 
More than 85,000 security forces have been deployed in Rio for the Olympics, which is double the number of London in 2012. 
OLY-TAXI STRIKE 
Rio taxi drivers plan strike over Uber during Olympics 
RIO DE JANEIRO (AP) -- Taxi drivers in Rio de Janeiro are planning a demonstration on Friday morning in the immediate vicinity of the Olympic Park to protest the use of ride-sharing program Uber. 
The U.S. Consulate General&apos;s office sent a message to U.S. citizens in Brazil on Thursday, based on information they received from organizers of the planned strike. Those organizers say they&apos;re planning to close avenues around the Olympic Park, and doing so at rush hour could snarl traffic. 
The message says &quot;such an event would affect transport for visitors to venues in the Olympic Park.&quot; 
There was no immediate comment from local organizers about whether they were concerned about the planned strike. 
Uber has been the target of scorn from taxi drivers around the world, including demonstrations in Paris, New York, Chicago and Mexico City. 
THAILAND-BOMBING 
UPDATE: Deadly bombings in Thailand 
BANGKOK (AP) -- Police in Thailand say a wave of deadly bomb blasts in the central and southern parts of the country is not linked to Islamic terrorism. 
Multiple explosions hit at least four Thai cities overnight and on Friday, killing several people and wounding dozens more. 
About 10 foreigners were wounded in the seaside town of Hua Hin. 
CHANCE AT FREEDOM 
Judge orders man free after 28 years, cites unfair trial 
WILMINGTON, N.C. (AP) -- A judge on Thursday ruled that a North Carolina man who was convicted of murder as a teenager and was imprisoned 28 years ago did not get a fair trial and allowed him to go free. 
North Carolina Superior Court Judge W. Douglas Parsons ruled Thursday that there was not enough evidence to justify 43-year-old Johnny Small&apos;s conviction for a 1988 murder. 
The judge said he didn&apos;t see proof of Small&apos;s innocence, but was persuaded that prosecutors must decide if there was enough evidence to put him on trial again. 
Small was released from a Wilmington prison and arrived at his cousin&apos;s manufactured home just before nightfall Thursday. There he&apos;ll spend his first night of freedom on the living room sofa rather than in a bed in a room cleared for him. 
&quot;I don&apos;t want to sleep in no room. I want to be in a big space,&quot; Small said. 
MISSING BOY-SEARCH 
Still no sign of missing Arizona boy after latest search 
BUCKEYE, Ariz. (AP) -- Federal and local authorities in Arizona unsuccessfully searched a field for a 10-year-old boy who has been missing for nearly a month. 
Buckeye Police Sgt. Jason Weeks says officers walked Thursday through an undeveloped lot covered with brush and trees as part of what he called a secondary search. 
He says authorities have been actively searching for Jesse Wilson since he went missing from his home and want to double check areas that had been searched previously. 
Weeks says authorities will not stop looking for the boy. 
The case still is being investigated as a runaway and no foul play has been identified. 
The FBI, Buckeye police and the Maricopa County Sheriff&apos;s Office participated in Thursday&apos;s search. 
Previous searches have involved drones, U.S. Border Patrol tracking dogs and citizen volunteers. 
CHICAGO POLICE 
Muslim woman sues Chicago, 6 officers for false terrorist ID 
CHICAGO (AP) -- A Muslim woman is suing the city of Chicago and six officers who falsely singled her out as a potential terrorist on July 4, 2015, as she left a subway station wearing a headscarf, face veil and carrying a backpack. 
Itemid Al-Matar&apos;s federal lawsuit filed Thursday says officers pulled off her religious garb, arrested her and later strip-searched her. The 32-year-old was acquitted of obstructing justice. 
The Council on American-Islamic Relations says &quot;blatant xenophobia, Islamophobia and racial profiling&quot; motivated the arrest. 
A public police report says officers &quot;were on high alert of terrorist activity&quot; on the national holiday and that Al-Matar was exhibiting &quot;suspicious behavior.&quot; 
The CPD declined to comment but said in a statement that police &quot;strive to treat all individuals with the highest levels of dignity of respect.&quot; 
PENN STATE-ABUSE 
NEW: Sandusky prepares to testify in bid to overturn conviction 
HARRISBURG, Pa. (AP) -- Former Penn State assistant football coach Jerry Sandusky is expected to take the stand Friday to try to prove his claim that he was wrongly convicted four years ago of sexually abusing 10 boys. 
Sandusky plans to appear in a Pennsylvania courthouse for a Post-Conviction Relief Act hearing. 
The 72-year-old was convicted of 45 counts and is serving a 30- to 60-year sentence. 
CALIFORNIA WATER TUNNELS-FUNDING 
NEW: New questions over California water project 
SAN FRANCISCO (AP) -- Critics and a California lawmaker want more answers from Gov. Jerry Brown&apos;s administration on who&apos;s paying for a proposed giant water project. 
That&apos;s after a Southern California water district said Thursday that Brown&apos;s administration is now stating that state or federal funds will be used to finish planning for two $16 billion water tunnels. The 35-mile-long tunnels would carry water from Northern California south, mainly for Central and Southern California. Brown&apos;s administration is pushing to get regulatory approval for the tunnels before he leaves office in two years. 
Tunnel opponents say Thursday&apos;s statement from the Metropolitan Water District in Los Angeles could go against longstanding assurances that local water agencies would pay for the tunnels, not the state. Aides to California Assemblywoman Susan Eggman say she has asked officials for an explanation of the water district&apos;s statement Thursday. Eggman was part of a legislative committee that already had ordered a state audit of the tunnels project earlier this week. 
State spokeswoman Nancy Vogel says funding to finish the planning of the tunnels will come from user payments for an existing state water project, and not from the state&apos;s general fund. 
HOSTESS-WAL-MART 
NEW: Hostess launches &quot;Deep Fried Twinkies&quot; as first frozen treat 
NEW YORK (AP) -- The deep-fried Twinkie is jumping from the state fair to the home freezer. 
Hostess Brands is launching packaged &quot;Deep Fried Twinkies&quot; starting Friday that mark its first foray into frozen foods. 
The cream-filled snack in vanilla or chocolate is the result of a yearlong collaboration between Hostess and Wal-Mart, as both companies look to spark food sales with innovative products. Hostess says the Twinkie is a bigger business now than even right before the company filed for bankruptcy in 2012. 
For Wal-Mart, it&apos;s part of a strategy of working with suppliers to come up with twists on existing foods or developing new ones. The company, which gets more than half its sales from food, opened a food lab in June as it aims to get products to the shelves faster. Category 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://wbt.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/22/2015/09/defaultnewsimage.jpg</main_image>
</document>
