<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>https://www.chautauquastar.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>chautauquastar.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Chamber Corner 8/11</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.chautauquastar.com/chamber-corner-811/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Chautauqua County Chamber of Commerce Sign Up for the Chautauqua Gran Fondo Written by Todd J. Tranum, President and CEO of the Chautauqua County Chamber of Commerce &amp; Executive Director of the Manufacturers Association of the Southern Tier The Grand Fondo is back after a successful inaugural year in 2015. The second annual Chautauqua Gran Fondo, scheduled for August 27, is a community event designed to promote health and well-being for bicyclists of all skill levels while raising funds for local non-profit organizations. Participants will have the opportunity to enjoy the beauty of Chautauqua Lake and its surrounding historic destinations on one of four scenic routes. There will plenty of rest stops, photo ops and full support on the road. Both teams and individuals are welcome to sign up and ride. Social riders can enjoy a peaceful ride around the lake on our 20 Mile Route, complete with a trip across the lake on the nostalgic Bemus Point–Stow Ferry. Fitness enthusiasts can challenge themselves or compete with friends on a 40.7 Mile Route around Chautauqua Lake. There are also two Challenge Routes this year: a 37-Mile Challenge or a 58-Mile Challenge, which will let riders climb the Chautauqua Ridge with an elevation change of over 1,500 feet and then relax on the Bemus Point-Stow Ferry. All routes feature support and refreshment stops along the way. The event developed, produced and marketed by the Chautauqua Region Economic Development Corporation, will raise funds for local charities including the Southwestern Schools Education Foundation, the Mental Health Association in Chautauqua County, and the Chautauqua County Veterans Endowment Fund. The Gran Fondo will conclude with an after-party at Webb’s Captains Table including a live band and a for-kids-only free ice cream sundae station. For more information or to register visit chautauquagranfondo.com . Mini Maker Faire Planned at Fredonia Sign up now to participate in or to sponsor the inaugural Mini Maker Faire to be held in Chautauqua County on Saturday, October 22. Billed as a “circus of creativity,” a Maker Faire is also known as the Greatest Show (and Tell) on Earth, where participants are encouraged to make, create, craft, build, and play in a fun, engaging, and exciting way. The event will be open to the entire region and attendees will hear from experts, get hands-on experience, and learn from each other in the spirit of creativity and collaboration. This family-friendly showcase of invention is designed to unite and inspire resourceful people who undertake projects in their backyards, basements, and garages. Makers will discuss their process, creations, and vision. The Mini Maker Faire will be held at the State University of Fredonia from 10am-4pm, Saturday, October 22, and is a collaboration of Fredonia, Erie 2-Chautauqua-Cattaruagus BOCES, and Make Magazine. Regional businesses can help sponsor this extraordinary event by contacting BOCES at (716) 672-4371. Sponsorships are requested by August 26. Makers can sign up online at Facebook.com/fredoniaminimakerfaire and anyone who is interested can attend the next Maker Meet Up at 6pm, Wednesday, August 17 in the atrium of the Science Center on the Fredonia State campus. Bill Ward and Amanda Barton to Perform in Mayville August 18 The shores of Chautauqua Lake will be the backdrop for the Thursday, August 18 Entertainment in the Park summer concert, featuring Bill Ward and Amanda Barton. The concert will run from 6:30 – 8:30 pm at the gazebo at Lakeside Park, Mayville. Bill Ward is a long-time local favorite performer at this summertime concert series. He has been a musician and entertainer for many years, performing and recording with The Bill Ward Band as well as being a solo performer and is currently performing with the musical duo Bill Ward and Amanda Barton. Amanda Barton has performed with David Grisman, Peter Rowan, The Blue Grasshoppers, the Steve Johnson Band, and Big Leg Emma. The combination of these two talented and well known Chautauqua County musicians and performers promises to make for an enjoyable concert experience for the entire family. Entertainment in the Park is provided free through the support of the Village of Mayville and Town of Chautauqua and is organized by the Mayville-Chautauqua Community Chamber of Commerce. Remember to bring your own seating for this event. First Friday is September 2 The Westfield-Barcelona Community Chamber of Commerce will wrap up its First Friday events for the season on September 2. First Friday is a community street fair in the village of Westfield, featuring businesses, street vendors, food and wine tasting, arts and crafts, live music, and fun for all ages! The event begins at 5pm along both sides of Main Street and in Moore Park. Everyone is welcome to attend First Friday in Westfield! WNY Food Bank Motorcycle Rally September 17 The Food Bank of Western New York Motorcycle Run and Rally is once again headed for Chautauqua County on Saturday, September 17. The event will begin in Eden, and will include stops in Gowanda, Kennedy, Cassadaga, and Merritt Estate Winery in Forestville, before ending at Sunset Bay Beach Club in Irving. Even those who aren’t riding are welcome to attend the rally at the Beach Club, which starts at 2pm, to help welcome back the motorcyclists. Proceeds from this event, co-sponsored by the Hanover Community Chamber of Commerce, go to the Food Bank of Western New York, which provides nutritious food and resources to hungry Western New Yorkers through its 329 member agencies, including soup kitchens, food pantries, and shelters, throughout Cattaraugus, Chautauqua, Erie and Niagara counties. Through these agencies, the Food Bank can assist as many as 129,000 individuals, including more than 44,000 families, more than 45,000 children and nearly 17,000 seniors, in any given month. For more information or to register, visit www.wnyfoodbankrun.com .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.chautauquastar.com/chamber-corner-811/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1447</post_time>
<username>chautadmin</username>
<post>
Chautauqua County Chamber of Commerce Sign Up for the Chautauqua Gran Fondo Written by Todd J. Tranum, President and CEO of the Chautauqua County Chamber of Commerce &amp; Executive Director of the Manufacturers Association of the Southern Tier The Grand Fondo is back after a successful inaugural year in 2015. The second annual Chautauqua Gran Fondo, scheduled for August 27, is a community event designed to promote health and well-being for bicyclists of all skill levels while raising funds for local non-profit organizations. Participants will have the opportunity to enjoy the beauty of Chautauqua Lake and its surrounding historic destinations on one of four scenic routes. There will plenty of rest stops, photo ops and full support on the road. Both teams and individuals are welcome to sign up and ride. Social riders can enjoy a peaceful ride around the lake on our 20 Mile Route, complete with a trip across the lake on the nostalgic Bemus Point–Stow Ferry. Fitness enthusiasts can challenge themselves or compete with friends on a 40.7 Mile Route around Chautauqua Lake. There are also two Challenge Routes this year: a 37-Mile Challenge or a 58-Mile Challenge, which will let riders climb the Chautauqua Ridge with an elevation change of over 1,500 feet and then relax on the Bemus Point-Stow Ferry. All routes feature support and refreshment stops along the way. The event developed, produced and marketed by the Chautauqua Region Economic Development Corporation, will raise funds for local charities including the Southwestern Schools Education Foundation, the Mental Health Association in Chautauqua County, and the Chautauqua County Veterans Endowment Fund. The Gran Fondo will conclude with an after-party at Webb’s Captains Table including a live band and a for-kids-only free ice cream sundae station. For more information or to register visit chautauquagranfondo.com . Mini Maker Faire Planned at Fredonia Sign up now to participate in or to sponsor the inaugural Mini Maker Faire to be held in Chautauqua County on Saturday, October 22. Billed as a “circus of creativity,” a Maker Faire is also known as the Greatest Show (and Tell) on Earth, where participants are encouraged to make, create, craft, build, and play in a fun, engaging, and exciting way. The event will be open to the entire region and attendees will hear from experts, get hands-on experience, and learn from each other in the spirit of creativity and collaboration. This family-friendly showcase of invention is designed to unite and inspire resourceful people who undertake projects in their backyards, basements, and garages. Makers will discuss their process, creations, and vision. The Mini Maker Faire will be held at the State University of Fredonia from 10am-4pm, Saturday, October 22, and is a collaboration of Fredonia, Erie 2-Chautauqua-Cattaruagus BOCES, and Make Magazine. Regional businesses can help sponsor this extraordinary event by contacting BOCES at (716) 672-4371. Sponsorships are requested by August 26. Makers can sign up online at Facebook.com/fredoniaminimakerfaire and anyone who is interested can attend the next Maker Meet Up at 6pm, Wednesday, August 17 in the atrium of the Science Center on the Fredonia State campus. Bill Ward and Amanda Barton to Perform in Mayville August 18 The shores of Chautauqua Lake will be the backdrop for the Thursday, August 18 Entertainment in the Park summer concert, featuring Bill Ward and Amanda Barton. The concert will run from 6:30 – 8:30 pm at the gazebo at Lakeside Park, Mayville. Bill Ward is a long-time local favorite performer at this summertime concert series. He has been a musician and entertainer for many years, performing and recording with The Bill Ward Band as well as being a solo performer and is currently performing with the musical duo Bill Ward and Amanda Barton. Amanda Barton has performed with David Grisman, Peter Rowan, The Blue Grasshoppers, the Steve Johnson Band, and Big Leg Emma. The combination of these two talented and well known Chautauqua County musicians and performers promises to make for an enjoyable concert experience for the entire family. Entertainment in the Park is provided free through the support of the Village of Mayville and Town of Chautauqua and is organized by the Mayville-Chautauqua Community Chamber of Commerce. Remember to bring your own seating for this event. First Friday is September 2 The Westfield-Barcelona Community Chamber of Commerce will wrap up its First Friday events for the season on September 2. First Friday is a community street fair in the village of Westfield, featuring businesses, street vendors, food and wine tasting, arts and crafts, live music, and fun for all ages! The event begins at 5pm along both sides of Main Street and in Moore Park. Everyone is welcome to attend First Friday in Westfield! WNY Food Bank Motorcycle Rally September 17 The Food Bank of Western New York Motorcycle Run and Rally is once again headed for Chautauqua County on Saturday, September 17. The event will begin in Eden, and will include stops in Gowanda, Kennedy, Cassadaga, and Merritt Estate Winery in Forestville, before ending at Sunset Bay Beach Club in Irving. Even those who aren’t riding are welcome to attend the rally at the Beach Club, which starts at 2pm, to help welcome back the motorcyclists. Proceeds from this event, co-sponsored by the Hanover Community Chamber of Commerce, go to the Food Bank of Western New York, which provides nutritious food and resources to hungry Western New Yorkers through its 329 member agencies, including soup kitchens, food pantries, and shelters, throughout Cattaraugus, Chautauqua, Erie and Niagara counties. Through these agencies, the Food Bank can assist as many as 129,000 individuals, including more than 44,000 families, more than 45,000 children and nearly 17,000 seniors, in any given month. For more information or to register, visit www.wnyfoodbankrun.com .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
