<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Fiji wins rugby sevens for nation&apos;s first Olympic gold | wltx.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wltx.com/sports/olympics/fiji-wins-rugby-sevens-for-nations-first-olympic-gold/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wltx&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;fiji-wins-rugby-sevens-for-nations-first-olympic-gold&amp;#x2f;295418007</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Fiji wins rugby sevens for nation&apos;s first Olympic gold Here are the rules of rugby for the 2016 Olympics Nate Scott, USA TODAY Sports , KING 8:10 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Figi celebrates a win against Great Britain. (Photo: Matt Kryger, USA TODAY Sports) 
After 16 appearances in the Olympics, the tiny nation of Fiji has its first medal. 
And it is gold. 
The Fiji rugby sevens squad routed Great Britain in the gold medal game on Thursday night, winning 43-7 in a game that was never in doubt. Team GB seemed overwhelmed by Fiji&apos;s size and speed and couldn’t seem to bring down anyone with a clean tackle. 
For Fiji, a small Oceanic nation that is comprised of over 300 islands in the South Pacific and boasts a population of just 800,000, it was nothing less than what was expected. The team entered the Olympics as the heavy favorites, led by Leone Nakarawa, who is listed at 6-6 and 240 pounds, and Semi Kunatani, who is 6-3, 240. 
Seven different Fiji players scored tries in the match. Dan Norton scored the lone try for Great Britain. 
“The team, they are our heroes,” said Vaseva Varea, a Fiji native who lives in Australia and traveled to Brazil for the Games. “They are our warriors. They are everything to us.” 
In the bronze medal game, South Africa routed Japan. Japan should be proud of its performance at this Olympics, though — its upset against New Zealand in group play was considered by many to be the match of the tournament. Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Simone Manuel (L) and Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak react after they equally won the Women&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / GABRIEL BOUYS (Photo credit should read GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images) GABRIEL BOUYS, This content is subject to copyright. Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Competitors sail during the men’s Finn opening series race at Marina da Gloria during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Mandatory Credit: Eric Seals-USA TODAY Sports Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; United States defender Katelyn Falgowski (23) and midfield Melissa Gonzalez (5) battle for the ball with India defender Namita Toppo (19) during women&apos;s field hockey pool play in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Hockey Centre. Mandatory Credit: John David Mercer-USA TODAY Sports John David Mercer, John David Mercer Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Nathan Adrian (USA) during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wltx.com/sports/olympics/fiji-wins-rugby-sevens-for-nations-first-olympic-gold/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wltx&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;fiji-wins-rugby-sevens-for-nations-first-olympic-gold&amp;#x2f;295418007</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Fiji wins rugby sevens for nation&apos;s first Olympic gold Here are the rules of rugby for the 2016 Olympics Nate Scott, USA TODAY Sports , KING 8:10 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Figi celebrates a win against Great Britain. (Photo: Matt Kryger, USA TODAY Sports) 
After 16 appearances in the Olympics, the tiny nation of Fiji has its first medal. 
And it is gold. 
The Fiji rugby sevens squad routed Great Britain in the gold medal game on Thursday night, winning 43-7 in a game that was never in doubt. Team GB seemed overwhelmed by Fiji&apos;s size and speed and couldn’t seem to bring down anyone with a clean tackle. 
For Fiji, a small Oceanic nation that is comprised of over 300 islands in the South Pacific and boasts a population of just 800,000, it was nothing less than what was expected. The team entered the Olympics as the heavy favorites, led by Leone Nakarawa, who is listed at 6-6 and 240 pounds, and Semi Kunatani, who is 6-3, 240. 
Seven different Fiji players scored tries in the match. Dan Norton scored the lone try for Great Britain. 
“The team, they are our heroes,” said Vaseva Varea, a Fiji native who lives in Australia and traveled to Brazil for the Games. “They are our warriors. They are everything to us.” 
In the bronze medal game, South Africa routed Japan. Japan should be proud of its performance at this Olympics, though — its upset against New Zealand in group play was considered by many to be the match of the tournament. Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Simone Manuel (L) and Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak react after they equally won the Women&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / GABRIEL BOUYS (Photo credit should read GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images) GABRIEL BOUYS, This content is subject to copyright. Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Competitors sail during the men’s Finn opening series race at Marina da Gloria during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Mandatory Credit: Eric Seals-USA TODAY Sports Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; United States defender Katelyn Falgowski (23) and midfield Melissa Gonzalez (5) battle for the ball with India defender Namita Toppo (19) during women&apos;s field hockey pool play in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Hockey Centre. Mandatory Credit: John David Mercer-USA TODAY Sports John David Mercer, John David Mercer Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Nathan Adrian (USA) during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.king5.com/photo/2016/08/11/636065384069831883-USP-OLYMPICS-RUGBY-SEVENS-84123610_1470964136708_5101408_ver1.0_640_360.JPG</main_image>
</document>
