<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.wfaa.com/_/20/110040338/wfaa/home</forum>
<forum_title>WFAA - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>DA Hawk returns to work after 12 weeks</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.wfaa.com/_/20/110040338/wfaa/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wfaa&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;health&amp;#x2f;da-hawk-returns-to-work-after-12-weeks-of-treatment&amp;#x2f;295031108</topic_url>
<topic_text>
DA Hawk returns to work after 12 weeks of treatment Hawk return after 12 weeks of treatment WFAA 9:00 PM. CDT August 11, 2016 Dallas County DA Susan Hawk (Photo: WFAA) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
DALLAS -- Dallas County District Attorney Susan Hawk maintained a low profile Thursday on her first day back at the Dallas County Courthouse. 
Hawk, the county&apos;s top law enforcement official, was away from work for exactly 12 weeks. She declined interview requests. 
She spent almost three months in inpatient treatment for mood disorders and major depression in facilities in Houston and Arizona. 
Hawk’s return to work came as a bit of a surprise, because her office had previously said that a return date would be announced. 
In a statement, she said her “mental health team and I felt it was important to minimize my exposure to the media” while she was undergoing treatment. The statement said Hawk was “completely transparent” about her illness. It said she had been in “constant contact” with her office and that they had decided she was “physically” ready to return to work. 
“I look forward to once again working with my staff to make Dallas County safe and thriving,” the statement said. 
In Hawk’s absence, her second-in-command, First Assistant District Attorney Messina Madson, has been running the office. 
This marks the second time that Hawk has been away from the office for an extended period of time seeking psychiatric treatment since taking office in January 2015. 
Last summer, Hawk was away for about nine weeks. She returned to work Oct. 1, 2015. 
“I&apos;m happy to hear that Susan&apos;s back,” said Danny Clancy, a Hawk backer and a former Republican DA candidate. “It was getting to the point where, &apos;OK, enough is enough.&apos; Everyone is pulling for you. We hope that you&apos;re getting the treatment that you need to get heathy.” 
Clancy, a longtime friend of the district attorney, doesn&apos;t think people would be calling on Hawk to resign if she had cancer. 
“She has to make that decision, and only she can make that decision,” Clancy said. 
County access card records show in the months prior to going out on leave, she was only reporting to work to her $218,000-a-year job on a sporadic basis. Prior to Thursday, Hawk has reported to work at the courthouse just 66 days this year. 
Hawk used her access card 14 days in January, 18 days in February, 17 days in March, 15 days in April, and just two days in May, the records show. 
The last day Hawk used her access card was May 19. The DA’s office has previously said that she checked herself into a Houston psychiatric facility the next day. 
The records are not a perfect accounting of Hawk’s work schedule, in that they do not account for situations when she may have worked away from the office, such as attending a conference or doing a speaking engagement. But they do provide a pretty good reflection of how often she was on the job. 
“It’s amazing,” said attorney Deandra Grant, a Republican and former Hawk supporter. “I think she should pay the taxpayers back for all of the money she’s been paid while she’s been gone.” 
Grant wants Hawk to resign. 
She says Hawk has been repeatedly dishonest, from secretly going into drug rehab during the campaign, to having friends claim she was on summer break when she sought psychiatric treatment last summer. 
“I don’t know that she has depression,” Grant said. &quot;That’s what she says, but she said lots of things that turned out to not be true. I’d like to see some documentation of what her diagnosis actually is.” 
SMU political science professor Cal Jillson said Hawk’s performance over the last year has shown that she’s not been up to the task for running the DA’s office. He and others are concerned that she may end up having to take another extended leave from her job to seek psychiatric treatment. 
“Even those who wish her well -- unless they are partisans -- worry about the pressure of that job on her,” he said. “Susan Hawk was elected to lead that office, and the people who elected her who put her in that position expect her to be there.” 
He offered a way that Hawk could find out the level of public support there is for her to remain in office. He suggested that she resign before the Aug. 26 deadline. If she resigns before that deadline, then it would the post would be put on the ballot. 
“If she wanted to do that and then immediately declare for election to the post, that would clear the air,” Jillson said. “If she got re-elected, it would be because the voters of Dallas County wanted her as DA.” 
Copyright 2016 WFAA
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.wfaa.com/_/20/110040338/wfaa/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wfaa&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;health&amp;#x2f;da-hawk-returns-to-work-after-12-weeks-of-treatment&amp;#x2f;295031108</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0200</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
DA Hawk returns to work after 12 weeks of treatment Hawk return after 12 weeks of treatment WFAA 9:00 PM. CDT August 11, 2016 Dallas County DA Susan Hawk (Photo: WFAA) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
DALLAS -- Dallas County District Attorney Susan Hawk maintained a low profile Thursday on her first day back at the Dallas County Courthouse. 
Hawk, the county&apos;s top law enforcement official, was away from work for exactly 12 weeks. She declined interview requests. 
She spent almost three months in inpatient treatment for mood disorders and major depression in facilities in Houston and Arizona. 
Hawk’s return to work came as a bit of a surprise, because her office had previously said that a return date would be announced. 
In a statement, she said her “mental health team and I felt it was important to minimize my exposure to the media” while she was undergoing treatment. The statement said Hawk was “completely transparent” about her illness. It said she had been in “constant contact” with her office and that they had decided she was “physically” ready to return to work. 
“I look forward to once again working with my staff to make Dallas County safe and thriving,” the statement said. 
In Hawk’s absence, her second-in-command, First Assistant District Attorney Messina Madson, has been running the office. 
This marks the second time that Hawk has been away from the office for an extended period of time seeking psychiatric treatment since taking office in January 2015. 
Last summer, Hawk was away for about nine weeks. She returned to work Oct. 1, 2015. 
“I&apos;m happy to hear that Susan&apos;s back,” said Danny Clancy, a Hawk backer and a former Republican DA candidate. “It was getting to the point where, &apos;OK, enough is enough.&apos; Everyone is pulling for you. We hope that you&apos;re getting the treatment that you need to get heathy.” 
Clancy, a longtime friend of the district attorney, doesn&apos;t think people would be calling on Hawk to resign if she had cancer. 
“She has to make that decision, and only she can make that decision,” Clancy said. 
County access card records show in the months prior to going out on leave, she was only reporting to work to her $218,000-a-year job on a sporadic basis. Prior to Thursday, Hawk has reported to work at the courthouse just 66 days this year. 
Hawk used her access card 14 days in January, 18 days in February, 17 days in March, 15 days in April, and just two days in May, the records show. 
The last day Hawk used her access card was May 19. The DA’s office has previously said that she checked herself into a Houston psychiatric facility the next day. 
The records are not a perfect accounting of Hawk’s work schedule, in that they do not account for situations when she may have worked away from the office, such as attending a conference or doing a speaking engagement. But they do provide a pretty good reflection of how often she was on the job. 
“It’s amazing,” said attorney Deandra Grant, a Republican and former Hawk supporter. “I think she should pay the taxpayers back for all of the money she’s been paid while she’s been gone.” 
Grant wants Hawk to resign. 
She says Hawk has been repeatedly dishonest, from secretly going into drug rehab during the campaign, to having friends claim she was on summer break when she sought psychiatric treatment last summer. 
“I don’t know that she has depression,” Grant said. &quot;That’s what she says, but she said lots of things that turned out to not be true. I’d like to see some documentation of what her diagnosis actually is.” 
SMU political science professor Cal Jillson said Hawk’s performance over the last year has shown that she’s not been up to the task for running the DA’s office. He and others are concerned that she may end up having to take another extended leave from her job to seek psychiatric treatment. 
“Even those who wish her well -- unless they are partisans -- worry about the pressure of that job on her,” he said. “Susan Hawk was elected to lead that office, and the people who elected her who put her in that position expect her to be there.” 
He offered a way that Hawk could find out the level of public support there is for her to remain in office. He suggested that she resign before the Aug. 26 deadline. If she resigns before that deadline, then it would the post would be put on the ballot. 
“If she wanted to do that and then immediately declare for election to the post, that would clear the air,” Jillson said. “If she got re-elected, it would be because the voters of Dallas County wanted her as DA.” 
Copyright 2016 WFAA
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.wfaa.com/photo/2016/07/21/0721%20susan%20hawk%202_1469144194465_4251945_ver1.0_640_360.JPG</main_image>
</document>
