<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Lewis McPherson inquest: Police had no grounds to arrest killer Liam Humbles on drug offences - ABC News (Australian Broadcasting Corporation)</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2016-08-12/police-had-no-evidence-to-arrest-killer-liam-humbles/7729130</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Map: Warradale 5046 
Police had no grounds to arrest Liam Humbles on drug offences five months before he shot dead teenager Lewis McPherson in Adelaide, a coronial inquest has heard. 
Humbles, who was 17 years old at the time, was drunk and on drugs on New Years Eve 2012 when he shot Mr McPherson, 18, who was walking to a party at Warradale in the city&apos;s south . 
Several SA Police officers today gave evidence to an inquest examining how the convicted killer came into possession of a gun. 
The inquest previously heard police had contact with Humbles at least four times before the fatal shooting. 
The Coroners Court heard that anonymous reports had been made to police that a teen with drugs was approaching cars displaying P-plates along Railway Terrace in Warradale in July 2012. 
Deputy Coroner Anthony Schapel asked Senior Constable Brent Anderson, who was charged with investigating the reports, why he did not arrest Humbles when he located him. 
&quot;He only had one bag of cannabis on him, which he said was for personal use,&quot; Senior Constable Anderson said. 
&quot;The only option I had on that day was to issue a drug diversion.&quot; 
Counsel Assisting the Coroner Amy Cacas was astounded that Humbles was not arrested on the suspicion that he was dealing cannabis. 
But Mr Anderson said there was a lack of evidence. 
&quot;If I had found Humbles with 10 bags of marijuana it would have been a different story,&quot; he said. Police questioned over their lack of follow-up work 
Mr Schapel asked whether a notification should have been made to the Child Abuse Report Line about Humbles. 
&quot;He&apos;s 17. He&apos;s not living at his parents&apos; address. He&apos;s couch surfing and he couldn&apos;t tell you where he spent the previous night,&quot; he said. 
But Mr Anderson told the court there was &quot;absolutely not&quot; any reason at the time to think Humbles was in danger. 
The court heard police had further contact with Humbles in August 2012 after a patrol stopped him for riding his bicycle at night without lights. 
Senior Constable Christopher Paul Holmes said he did not see any need to search Humbles for drugs or weapons at the time. 
The inquest yesterday heard that SA Police failed to follow-up a call from Brighton Secondary School , which had been told Humbles was selling drugs and in possession of a gun. 
The court heard the school was never contacted again by police about the matter. 
Humbles is serving a minimum 18-year jail sentence for murdering Mr McPherson and attempting to murder two other teenagers who were with the victim at the time. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2016-08-12/police-had-no-evidence-to-arrest-killer-liam-humbles/7729130</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Court Reporter Rebecca Opie</username>
<post>
Map: Warradale 5046 
Police had no grounds to arrest Liam Humbles on drug offences five months before he shot dead teenager Lewis McPherson in Adelaide, a coronial inquest has heard. 
Humbles, who was 17 years old at the time, was drunk and on drugs on New Years Eve 2012 when he shot Mr McPherson, 18, who was walking to a party at Warradale in the city&apos;s south . 
Several SA Police officers today gave evidence to an inquest examining how the convicted killer came into possession of a gun. 
The inquest previously heard police had contact with Humbles at least four times before the fatal shooting. 
The Coroners Court heard that anonymous reports had been made to police that a teen with drugs was approaching cars displaying P-plates along Railway Terrace in Warradale in July 2012. 
Deputy Coroner Anthony Schapel asked Senior Constable Brent Anderson, who was charged with investigating the reports, why he did not arrest Humbles when he located him. 
&quot;He only had one bag of cannabis on him, which he said was for personal use,&quot; Senior Constable Anderson said. 
&quot;The only option I had on that day was to issue a drug diversion.&quot; 
Counsel Assisting the Coroner Amy Cacas was astounded that Humbles was not arrested on the suspicion that he was dealing cannabis. 
But Mr Anderson said there was a lack of evidence. 
&quot;If I had found Humbles with 10 bags of marijuana it would have been a different story,&quot; he said. Police questioned over their lack of follow-up work 
Mr Schapel asked whether a notification should have been made to the Child Abuse Report Line about Humbles. 
&quot;He&apos;s 17. He&apos;s not living at his parents&apos; address. He&apos;s couch surfing and he couldn&apos;t tell you where he spent the previous night,&quot; he said. 
But Mr Anderson told the court there was &quot;absolutely not&quot; any reason at the time to think Humbles was in danger. 
The court heard police had further contact with Humbles in August 2012 after a patrol stopped him for riding his bicycle at night without lights. 
Senior Constable Christopher Paul Holmes said he did not see any need to search Humbles for drugs or weapons at the time. 
The inquest yesterday heard that SA Police failed to follow-up a call from Brighton Secondary School , which had been told Humbles was selling drugs and in possession of a gun. 
The court heard the school was never contacted again by police about the matter. 
Humbles is serving a minimum 18-year jail sentence for murdering Mr McPherson and attempting to murder two other teenagers who were with the victim at the time. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>AU</country>
<main_image>http://www.abc.net.au/news/image/5302106-1x1-700x700.jpg</main_image>
</document>
