<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news</forum>
<forum_title>News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Donald Trump suggests trying Americans at Guantanamo Bay</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/donald-trump-suggests-trying-americans-at-guantanamo-bay/ar-BBvwT6A</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Donald Trump suggests trying Americans at Guantanamo Bay CBS News 1 hr ago Emily Schultheis © REUTERS/Eric Thayer 2016-08-09t234527z481093163s1betunnkxaartrmadp3usa-election-trump.jpg Donald Trump suggested in an interview Thursday that he might allow Americans accused of terrorism to be tried at the Guantanamo Bay detention center in Cuba.
&quot;Well, I know that they want to try them in our regular court systems, and I don&apos;t like that at all, I don&apos;t like that at all,&quot; he told the Miami Herald. &quot;I would say they could be tried there, that&apos;ll be fine.&quot;
Current federal law prohibits U.S. citizens from being tried in military tribunals. Of Guantanamo, Trump has previously suggested he would &quot;load it up with bad dudes.&quot;
&quot;I want to make sure that if we have radical Islamic terrorists, we have a very safe place to keep &apos;em and we have a word, those are words our president won&apos;t even issue,&quot; he said. &quot;He&apos;s allowing people to get out that are terrible people. He&apos;s allowing a lot of people out of Guantanamo that should not be released.&quot;
Trump has come under fire for other comments he&apos;s made recently on the topic of terrorism -- namely his suggestion Wednesday night that President Obama is &quot;the founder of ISIS.&quot;
&quot;I will tell you that as far as Guantanamo is concerned I want to make sure, 100 percent sure, that if we&apos;re going to release people, number one they&apos;re going to be people that can be released and it&apos;s going to be safe to release them and there are plenty of bad ones out there and I&apos;d use it for that,&quot; Trump continued.
Go to MSN Home
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>9</post_num>
<post_id>post-9</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/donald-trump-suggests-trying-americans-at-guantanamo-bay/ar-BBvwT6A</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0530</post_time>
<username>Bob Jones</username>
<post>
Jon, federal law be damned what Trump wants to do is a violation of due process. He is a constitutional nightmare. Having just gone through eight years with a president who knows the constitution but refuses to follow it I dread to think what an ignorant buffoon like Trump is capable of doing.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
