<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://lufkindailynews.com/search/?q=&amp;t=article&amp;l=25&amp;d=&amp;d1=&amp;d2=&amp;s=start_time&amp;sd=desc&amp;c[]=news/sports*&amp;f=rss</forum>
<forum_title>The Lufkin News - news/sports</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Who&apos;s more excited: Michael Phelps or Rowdy Gaines?</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://lufkindailynews.com/news/sports/article_ebe02b6d-1320-5c2f-a76a-94c2b974934f.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Lee Jin-man Who&apos;s more excited: Michael Phelps or Rowdy Gaines? 
United States&apos; Michael Phelps celebrates winning the gold medal in the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley during the swimming competitions at the 2016 Summer Olympics, Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016, in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (AP Photo/Lee Jin-man) Posted: Thursday, August 11, 2016 11:38 pm | Updated: 12:06 am, Fri Aug 12, 2016. Who&apos;s more excited: Michael Phelps or Rowdy Gaines? Associated Press | 
NEW YORK (AP) — Rowdy Gaines clearly had much to say as Michael Phelps turned the race for his 22nd Olympic gold medal into a rout on Thursday. We&apos;re just not sure what it was. 
The NBC swimming analyst&apos;s voice turned into a high-pitched shout that became lost in the roar of the crowd. There&apos;s nothing wrong with an announcer reflecting an event&apos;s excitement, but not to the point of losing control. Better to take a breath. 
Only hours earlier, the knowledgeable Gaines showed what he had to offer. In the relative calm of an 800-meter freestyle preliminary race in the afternoon, Gaines neatly broke down gold medalist Katie Ledecky&apos;s swimming style in illuminating fashion, explaining to non-experts what put her ahead of her rivals. 
&quot;This is the only time I get to talk about her stroke,&quot; Gaines said. &quot;She&apos;s so fast in the 400.&quot; 
Swimming analyst Michele Tafoya was impressive in leading Simone Manuel into speaking with emotion and a sense of history after becoming the first African-American woman to win a gold medal in swimming. 
The best part of NBC&apos;s swimming coverage — no, not the silly count-up clock marking the minutes between Phelps&apos; race time — was the decision to televise the ceremony after Phelps won the 200-meter individual medley for the fourth consecutive Olympics. His eyes glistening, Phelps struggled to control his emotions as the national anthem played. 
&quot;Even for the 22nd time, it never gets old,&quot; NBC&apos;s Dan Hicks said. 
FIJI GOLD: It was a joy to watch the Pacific Island nation of Fiji win its first Olympic medal, striking gold by routing Britain in the rugby sevens final, and a great example of the benefits to searching beyond NBC&apos;s prime-time coverage to see all that is being offered. &quot;It&apos;s hard to put into words how big icons these players will be,&quot; NBC announcer Bill Seward said. &quot;Being gold medalists, they will be heroes in their country forevermore.&quot; 
The win produced an outpouring of celebrations in the stands and by players after the match. The sport is huge in Fiji, and the nation&apos;s prime minister traveled to Brazil for the games. 
SIMONE&apos;S GOLD: &quot;That is dominance,&quot; said NBC&apos;s Al Trautwig, explaining that gymnast Simone Biles&apos; margin of victory was larger than the last nine all-around women gold medalists combined. 
DVR ALERT: Let&apos;s hope mom and dad pressed the &quot;record&quot; button for any young aspiring gymnasts who wanted to see Biles&apos; win. After starting its broadcast showing half the competition, it was a long wait until the second half. 
RATINGS: NBC reached 26.4 million people with its Wednesday prime-time telecast, dominated by swimming and beach volleyball. Add in streaming and the 1.9 million people who watched the U.S.-Australia basketball game on NBCSN, and there was a total of 28.6 million consuming Olympic content. During the corresponding night in London, NBC had 30.8 million viewers. 
FORE: NBC has clearly not been happy with the golfers who chose to stay away from Rio de Janeiro, making the Olympics&apos; first golf competition a little less star-studded than expected. Jordan Spieth, Jason Day, Rory McIlroy and Dustin Johnson cited concerns about the Zika virus; some critics have suggested concerns about a lack of prize money were in the mix, too. NBC host Mike Tirico said Thursday they were missing the chance to increase their sport&apos;s popularity worldwide. &quot;I&apos;m a believer that golf needs the Olympics more than the Olympics need golf,&quot; he said.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://lufkindailynews.com/news/sports/article_ebe02b6d-1320-5c2f-a76a-94c2b974934f.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0438</post_time>
<username>DAVID BAUDER</username>
<post>
Lee Jin-man Who&apos;s more excited: Michael Phelps or Rowdy Gaines? 
United States&apos; Michael Phelps celebrates winning the gold medal in the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley during the swimming competitions at the 2016 Summer Olympics, Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016, in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (AP Photo/Lee Jin-man) Posted: Thursday, August 11, 2016 11:38 pm | Updated: 12:06 am, Fri Aug 12, 2016. Who&apos;s more excited: Michael Phelps or Rowdy Gaines? Associated Press | 
NEW YORK (AP) — Rowdy Gaines clearly had much to say as Michael Phelps turned the race for his 22nd Olympic gold medal into a rout on Thursday. We&apos;re just not sure what it was. 
The NBC swimming analyst&apos;s voice turned into a high-pitched shout that became lost in the roar of the crowd. There&apos;s nothing wrong with an announcer reflecting an event&apos;s excitement, but not to the point of losing control. Better to take a breath. 
Only hours earlier, the knowledgeable Gaines showed what he had to offer. In the relative calm of an 800-meter freestyle preliminary race in the afternoon, Gaines neatly broke down gold medalist Katie Ledecky&apos;s swimming style in illuminating fashion, explaining to non-experts what put her ahead of her rivals. 
&quot;This is the only time I get to talk about her stroke,&quot; Gaines said. &quot;She&apos;s so fast in the 400.&quot; 
Swimming analyst Michele Tafoya was impressive in leading Simone Manuel into speaking with emotion and a sense of history after becoming the first African-American woman to win a gold medal in swimming. 
The best part of NBC&apos;s swimming coverage — no, not the silly count-up clock marking the minutes between Phelps&apos; race time — was the decision to televise the ceremony after Phelps won the 200-meter individual medley for the fourth consecutive Olympics. His eyes glistening, Phelps struggled to control his emotions as the national anthem played. 
&quot;Even for the 22nd time, it never gets old,&quot; NBC&apos;s Dan Hicks said. 
FIJI GOLD: It was a joy to watch the Pacific Island nation of Fiji win its first Olympic medal, striking gold by routing Britain in the rugby sevens final, and a great example of the benefits to searching beyond NBC&apos;s prime-time coverage to see all that is being offered. &quot;It&apos;s hard to put into words how big icons these players will be,&quot; NBC announcer Bill Seward said. &quot;Being gold medalists, they will be heroes in their country forevermore.&quot; 
The win produced an outpouring of celebrations in the stands and by players after the match. The sport is huge in Fiji, and the nation&apos;s prime minister traveled to Brazil for the games. 
SIMONE&apos;S GOLD: &quot;That is dominance,&quot; said NBC&apos;s Al Trautwig, explaining that gymnast Simone Biles&apos; margin of victory was larger than the last nine all-around women gold medalists combined. 
DVR ALERT: Let&apos;s hope mom and dad pressed the &quot;record&quot; button for any young aspiring gymnasts who wanted to see Biles&apos; win. After starting its broadcast showing half the competition, it was a long wait until the second half. 
RATINGS: NBC reached 26.4 million people with its Wednesday prime-time telecast, dominated by swimming and beach volleyball. Add in streaming and the 1.9 million people who watched the U.S.-Australia basketball game on NBCSN, and there was a total of 28.6 million consuming Olympic content. During the corresponding night in London, NBC had 30.8 million viewers. 
FORE: NBC has clearly not been happy with the golfers who chose to stay away from Rio de Janeiro, making the Olympics&apos; first golf competition a little less star-studded than expected. Jordan Spieth, Jason Day, Rory McIlroy and Dustin Johnson cited concerns about the Zika virus; some critics have suggested concerns about a lack of prize money were in the mix, too. NBC host Mike Tirico said Thursday they were missing the chance to increase their sport&apos;s popularity worldwide. &quot;I&apos;m a believer that golf needs the Olympics more than the Olympics need golf,&quot; he said.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://bloximages.chicago2.vip.townnews.com/lufkindailynews.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/0/c0/0c006a55-1cdc-51f9-9486-8b708e693433/57ad5964e7555.image.jpg?resize=512%2C351</main_image>
</document>
