<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news</forum>
<forum_title>News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>HP&apos;s low-cost Stream laptops now include a 14-inch model</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/technology/hps-low-cost-stream-laptops-now-include-a-14-inch-model/ar-BBvw1J4</topic_url>
<topic_text>
HP&apos;s low-cost Stream laptops now include a 14-inch model Engadget 12 hrs ago Jon Fingas © Provided by Engadget HP is clearly having some success with its cheap-and-cheerful Stream laptops , as it&apos;s expanding them in a big, big way. It&apos;s refreshing the range with not only some under-the-hood upgrades, but a new model.
The Stream 14 (above) effectively replaces the 13-inch version, delivering better performance and a more portable design despite the larger screen. It has faster 2x2 802.11ac WiFi, a 2016-era Celeron processor and a longer 10 hours, 45 minutes of battery life, but weighs less than the old Stream 13 at 3.17 pounds. You won&apos;t be blown away by its 4GB of RAM, 32GB of flash storage or 1,366 x 768 resolution, but the Stream 14 will also start at $219 when it arrives on September 7th. Not bad for a mid-size Windows 10 portable, we&apos;d say.
Other machines are getting a tune-up as well, as you&apos;d expect. The $199 Stream 11 update coming on August 24th will pack the faster WiFi, upgraded processor and slimmer design of its bigger sibling. Meanwhile, the 11-inch Stream x360 (aka HP x360) laptop/tablet hybrid gets similar guts while starting at $249, or $50 less than its ancestor. It arrives in &quot;select regions&quot; sometime in September. And if you&apos;re running a school rather than attending it, there&apos;s a more secure Stream 11 Pro coming in late September with an optional 64GB of storage.
Go to MSN Home
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/technology/hps-low-cost-stream-laptops-now-include-a-14-inch-model/ar-BBvw1J4</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2341</post_time>
<username>Richard Cornell</username>
<post>
Nice bells and whistles, but what your looking at might be the last of the thin laptops. It is almost cheaper to make a tablet with a keyboard as a option. Conside that your cell phones have just about what any computer has. Maybe HP will sell a cell phone that is tune to a tablet screen with a wireless keyboard and a wireless mouse. With the option of a wireless solid state hard drive. If you go into the cloud as storage the sky is not the limit.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
