<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Challenges for the secret service | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/challenges-for-the-secret-service/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Challenges for the secret service This year, the challenge of protecting candidates has reached new heights Brian Todd, CNN Published: August 11, 2016, 8:30 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
(CNN) – The secret service has its hands full trying to protect this election’s crop of presidential candidates. 
In the middle of Hillary Clinton’s rally, a protester rushed the stage. The secret service quickly responded. The woman was subdued and hustled out. 
In March, a man rushed Donald Trump’s podium in Dayton, Ohio. Trump was startled, and the agents quickly handled the situation. 
This year, the challenge of protecting candidates has reached new heights. 
From a man using suction-cups to climb trump tower, to two party conventions with fence-jumpers and other security headaches. There are a multitude of candidates who attract passionate crowds. 
At a Bernie Sanders event in California, he was rushed by several people. 
What’s that moment like for a secret service agent? 
Larry Johnson, Fmr. Secret Service Special Agent in Charge, said, “You want to get between them and the protectee and hold and cover their hands and make sure that you’ve got an area to touch and reach and feel for anything inside a coat or a jacket.” 
Former secret service agents tell us that at that moment, one or two agents have to go to the threat and take down that person. Another agent secures the candidate, while other agents immediately check for other threats. 
Former Secret Service Assistant Director Anthony Chapa, said, “Others are running to other areas, so you have 360-degree coverage at all times, in an instant.” 
The secret service is constantly training for these scenarios, sometimes role-playing with a fake candidate. This year, however, they face another challenge: a candidate whose rallies are often marked by fights in the audience. A candidate who sometimes incites violence himself. 
Republican Presidential Candidate Donald Trump, said, “I’d like to punch him in the face, I’ll tell ya.” 
Trump has also told his supporters that, “If you see anyone getting ready to throw a tomato, knock the crap out of em, would you? I will pay for the legal fees, I promise.” 
Brian Todd, reporting from CNN, asks, “Is Trump himself frustrating the Secret Service by inciting some of these people and saying the things that he says?” 
Larry Johnson, Fmr. Secret Service Special Agent in Charge, recognized the difficulty of protecting Trump, saying, “A-hundred percent that protecting Donald Trump is a challenge, but so was President Obama as the first African American, 8-years ago.” 
Former Secret Service Assistant Director Anthony Chapa agreed, saying, “It creates a unique challenge for sure. Look what happens to presidents when they’re in a war footing and start talking about the enemy.” 
Former agents say that each one of these events is a Super Bowl for the secret service, and losing that Super Bowl isn’t an option. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/challenges-for-the-secret-service/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Brian Todd</username>
<post>
Challenges for the secret service This year, the challenge of protecting candidates has reached new heights Brian Todd, CNN Published: August 11, 2016, 8:30 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
(CNN) – The secret service has its hands full trying to protect this election’s crop of presidential candidates. 
In the middle of Hillary Clinton’s rally, a protester rushed the stage. The secret service quickly responded. The woman was subdued and hustled out. 
In March, a man rushed Donald Trump’s podium in Dayton, Ohio. Trump was startled, and the agents quickly handled the situation. 
This year, the challenge of protecting candidates has reached new heights. 
From a man using suction-cups to climb trump tower, to two party conventions with fence-jumpers and other security headaches. There are a multitude of candidates who attract passionate crowds. 
At a Bernie Sanders event in California, he was rushed by several people. 
What’s that moment like for a secret service agent? 
Larry Johnson, Fmr. Secret Service Special Agent in Charge, said, “You want to get between them and the protectee and hold and cover their hands and make sure that you’ve got an area to touch and reach and feel for anything inside a coat or a jacket.” 
Former secret service agents tell us that at that moment, one or two agents have to go to the threat and take down that person. Another agent secures the candidate, while other agents immediately check for other threats. 
Former Secret Service Assistant Director Anthony Chapa, said, “Others are running to other areas, so you have 360-degree coverage at all times, in an instant.” 
The secret service is constantly training for these scenarios, sometimes role-playing with a fake candidate. This year, however, they face another challenge: a candidate whose rallies are often marked by fights in the audience. A candidate who sometimes incites violence himself. 
Republican Presidential Candidate Donald Trump, said, “I’d like to punch him in the face, I’ll tell ya.” 
Trump has also told his supporters that, “If you see anyone getting ready to throw a tomato, knock the crap out of em, would you? I will pay for the legal fees, I promise.” 
Brian Todd, reporting from CNN, asks, “Is Trump himself frustrating the Secret Service by inciting some of these people and saying the things that he says?” 
Larry Johnson, Fmr. Secret Service Special Agent in Charge, recognized the difficulty of protecting Trump, saying, “A-hundred percent that protecting Donald Trump is a challenge, but so was President Obama as the first African American, 8-years ago.” 
Former Secret Service Assistant Director Anthony Chapa agreed, saying, “It creates a unique challenge for sure. Look what happens to presidents when they’re in a war footing and start talking about the enemy.” 
Former agents say that each one of these events is a Super Bowl for the secret service, and losing that Super Bowl isn’t an option. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/clinton-rally.jpg?w=1200</main_image>
</document>
