<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.gackhollywood.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Gack Hollywood</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Review: Pete’s Dragon Opening Day Box Office Collection David Lowery’s Film</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.gackhollywood.com/2016/08/review-petes-dragon-opening-day-box-office-collection-david-lowerys-film/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
0 
Pete’s dragon, the upcoming Hollywood movie is an adventure fantasy film which is directed by David lowery ie. taken from a screenplay which is written by Lowery and Toby Hal brooks. It is a remake of a 1977 movie having the same title. The film is starring Dallas Howard, Wes Bentley, Oakes Fegley, Karl Urban, Oona laurence and also Robert Redford. The Release date of the movie is August 12, 2016. It is releasing in Disney digital 3D and RealD formats. 
Grace Meacham (Bryce Dallace Hollywood) is the daughter of a wood carver (Robert Redford) who meets a young guy Pete (Oakes Fegley) who used to live in a forest for 6 years with a dragon Elliot whose existence was kept a mystery. Grace Meacham looks out for help from Natalie (Oona Laurence) who is a daughter of a lumber mill owner Jack (Wes Bentley) to find out about Pete and the truth about Elliot. Whereas Gavin (Karl Urban) who is the uncle of Natalie and also the brother of Jack is planning to capture Elliot. John Kassir is the voice behind Elliot the dragon. 
The movie is produced by James Whitaker under the production company Walt Disney Pictures Whitaker entertainment. The movie has a runtime of 102 minutes. The cinematography is done by Bojan Bazelli and has a budget of US$ 65 million. 
The movie will be released in about 3702 venues out of which 2884 theatres will be in 3D, will have 150 plus premium large format screens, 57 D box and 16 Dolby Cinemas sites. 
The Review aggregator Rotten tomatoes is said to have given an approval rating of 86% based on 58 reviews and has given an average rating of 7.2 out of 10. The film has a score of 73 out of 100 on Metacritic which is based on 23 critics and indicated “generally favourable reviews”. 
The first-day collection of the movie is said to be US$ 20 – 25 million. It is expected to gain very much popularity among the people. The boy Pete is an orphan and has Elliot as his best friend. The movie is full of action, adventure, and magic. 
As far the technical specifications are concerned, the sound mix is in Datasat and Dolby digital.The director David Lowery has also explained that why Elliot is a furry dragon, “It’s is a kind of dragon you want to give a hug to”. 
The movie is an action adventure movie but does not have a typical storyline. The pace of the movie is slow and has less suspense but has a very good direction by David Lowery. The plot of the movie is very predictable but has really good twists and turns. So far the trailer has gained 3543196 views and is giving a very good response and has already started to gain fans. The huge dragon Elliot loves his best friend as can be seen in the trailer. And the title says, “Some secrets are too big to keep”.We recommend to watch the adventures of Pete and his dragon on August 12, 2016. For more updates, stay tuned with us.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.gackhollywood.com/2016/08/review-petes-dragon-opening-day-box-office-collection-david-lowerys-film/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0545</post_time>
<username>Aryan Arora</username>
<post>
0 
Pete’s dragon, the upcoming Hollywood movie is an adventure fantasy film which is directed by David lowery ie. taken from a screenplay which is written by Lowery and Toby Hal brooks. It is a remake of a 1977 movie having the same title. The film is starring Dallas Howard, Wes Bentley, Oakes Fegley, Karl Urban, Oona laurence and also Robert Redford. The Release date of the movie is August 12, 2016. It is releasing in Disney digital 3D and RealD formats. 
Grace Meacham (Bryce Dallace Hollywood) is the daughter of a wood carver (Robert Redford) who meets a young guy Pete (Oakes Fegley) who used to live in a forest for 6 years with a dragon Elliot whose existence was kept a mystery. Grace Meacham looks out for help from Natalie (Oona Laurence) who is a daughter of a lumber mill owner Jack (Wes Bentley) to find out about Pete and the truth about Elliot. Whereas Gavin (Karl Urban) who is the uncle of Natalie and also the brother of Jack is planning to capture Elliot. John Kassir is the voice behind Elliot the dragon. 
The movie is produced by James Whitaker under the production company Walt Disney Pictures Whitaker entertainment. The movie has a runtime of 102 minutes. The cinematography is done by Bojan Bazelli and has a budget of US$ 65 million. 
The movie will be released in about 3702 venues out of which 2884 theatres will be in 3D, will have 150 plus premium large format screens, 57 D box and 16 Dolby Cinemas sites. 
The Review aggregator Rotten tomatoes is said to have given an approval rating of 86% based on 58 reviews and has given an average rating of 7.2 out of 10. The film has a score of 73 out of 100 on Metacritic which is based on 23 critics and indicated “generally favourable reviews”. 
The first-day collection of the movie is said to be US$ 20 – 25 million. It is expected to gain very much popularity among the people. The boy Pete is an orphan and has Elliot as his best friend. The movie is full of action, adventure, and magic. 
As far the technical specifications are concerned, the sound mix is in Datasat and Dolby digital.The director David Lowery has also explained that why Elliot is a furry dragon, “It’s is a kind of dragon you want to give a hug to”. 
The movie is an action adventure movie but does not have a typical storyline. The pace of the movie is slow and has less suspense but has a very good direction by David Lowery. The plot of the movie is very predictable but has really good twists and turns. So far the trailer has gained 3543196 views and is giving a very good response and has already started to gain fans. The huge dragon Elliot loves his best friend as can be seen in the trailer. And the title says, “Some secrets are too big to keep”.We recommend to watch the adventures of Pete and his dragon on August 12, 2016. For more updates, stay tuned with us.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
