<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Upcoming Meizu Smartphone Will Feature Samsung’s Exynos 8890 SoC – Can You Guess Which One</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wccftech.com/meizu-coming-with-exynos-8890-soc/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Leak Mobile 7 mins ago by Omar Sohail Tweet 
As we’ve seen in the past, Meizu is no stranger to using Samsung’s mobile chipsets and it looks like we might have a flagship smartphone inbound that will be using none other than the South Korean’s Exynos 8890 . Leaked Specifications Sheet For A Meizu Smartphone Points To The Presence Of An Exynos 8890 
The last Meizu phone to possess a Samsung SoC was the PRO 5 and it came with an Exynos 7420, along with other hardware upgrades that would allow it to take on a Galaxy Note 5. Fast forward to 2016, we have another smartphone inbound that could be using superior hardware, but will be sold for a far more affordable price to attract a larger consumer base. On this occasion, the unnamed Meizu phone is also going to be running a QHD display, but it’s not confirmed if that display will be an OLED one, or belong to a different origin. 
The GPU has been listed as ARM’s Mali-T880, but it hasn’t been specified how many cores the processor will feature. Keep in mind that the GPU present in all Galaxy models feature 12 clusters and even then, it’s not sufficient enough to gain an upper hand against the Adreno 530 present in a Snapdragon 820. The camera has been listed as a 12MP shooter at the backside, and we reckon that the smartphone will have enough firepower to record 4K videos at 30FPS. Once again, details are extremely scarce at this point, so we don’t know if the 12MP sensor will be the same one present in the Galaxy Note 7 lineup, or will it be a different one. Samsung Galaxy S7&apos;s Exynos 8890 To Enter Mass Production In December Claim Sources Advertisements 
There is 4GB of RAM present, and it’s going to be supplemented by 32GB on onboard storage. To save costs, Chinese manufacturers normally incorporate internal memory based on the eMMC standard rather than the UFS 2.0 standard, but once again, we’re in limbo regarding this information. We will be updating this information in the future, but we can safely say that we should prep ourselves for a Meizu flagship smartphone that’s going to take on Galaxy Note 7 (at least from the specifications bit) and be affordable to the masses as well. 

</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wccftech.com/meizu-coming-with-exynos-8890-soc/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Omar Sohail</username>
<post>
Leak Mobile 7 mins ago by Omar Sohail Tweet 
As we’ve seen in the past, Meizu is no stranger to using Samsung’s mobile chipsets and it looks like we might have a flagship smartphone inbound that will be using none other than the South Korean’s Exynos 8890 . Leaked Specifications Sheet For A Meizu Smartphone Points To The Presence Of An Exynos 8890 
The last Meizu phone to possess a Samsung SoC was the PRO 5 and it came with an Exynos 7420, along with other hardware upgrades that would allow it to take on a Galaxy Note 5. Fast forward to 2016, we have another smartphone inbound that could be using superior hardware, but will be sold for a far more affordable price to attract a larger consumer base. On this occasion, the unnamed Meizu phone is also going to be running a QHD display, but it’s not confirmed if that display will be an OLED one, or belong to a different origin. 
The GPU has been listed as ARM’s Mali-T880, but it hasn’t been specified how many cores the processor will feature. Keep in mind that the GPU present in all Galaxy models feature 12 clusters and even then, it’s not sufficient enough to gain an upper hand against the Adreno 530 present in a Snapdragon 820. The camera has been listed as a 12MP shooter at the backside, and we reckon that the smartphone will have enough firepower to record 4K videos at 30FPS. Once again, details are extremely scarce at this point, so we don’t know if the 12MP sensor will be the same one present in the Galaxy Note 7 lineup, or will it be a different one. Samsung Galaxy S7&apos;s Exynos 8890 To Enter Mass Production In December Claim Sources Advertisements 
There is 4GB of RAM present, and it’s going to be supplemented by 32GB on onboard storage. To save costs, Chinese manufacturers normally incorporate internal memory based on the eMMC standard rather than the UFS 2.0 standard, but once again, we’re in limbo regarding this information. We will be updating this information in the future, but we can safely say that we should prep ourselves for a Meizu flagship smartphone that’s going to take on Galaxy Note 7 (at least from the specifications bit) and be affordable to the masses as well. 

</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>DE</country>
<main_image>http://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Meizu-2.jpg</main_image>
</document>
