<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.afr.com/news</forum>
<forum_title>Finance &amp;amp; Political Breaking News Australia &amp;amp; Worldwide | afr.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Majority of Senate crossbench to be given three-year terms</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/majority-of-senate-crossbench-to-be-given-threeyear-terms-20160812-gqqxd1</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Derryn Hinch would receive a three-year term. Daniel Pockett Share on twitter by Phillip Coorey Seven of the 11 new Senate crossbenchers will have just over two years in Parliament before they must again face the voters in an election at which it will be much more difficult to hold their spot.
Because the July 2 poll was a double dissolution election, it was a full Senate election, meaning all 12 senators in each state were elected.
To rebalance the Senate, only half of those elected will receive a full, six-year term and the other half will receive a three-year half term.
Labor and the Coalition, who have a combined majority in the Senate, have agreed that the Senators who won the most votes in the July 2 double dissolution will receive six-year terms. Those who came in the bottom six in each state would receive three years.
This precedent, which has been used in all previous double dissolution elections, means of the 11 member crossbench, just Nick Xenophon, his colleague Stirling Griff, Pauline Hanson and Tasmania&apos;s Jacqui Lambie, would receive six-year terms.
 The other seven would receive three-year terms. If the next election is a normal half-Senate election, the quota of votes needed to win a spot will be twice as high as it was on July 2, making it much more difficult to hold on.
These seven are Derryn Hinch, David Leyonhjelm, Bob Day, One Nation&apos;s Malcolm Roberts, Brian Burston and Rod Culleton, and the NXTs Skye Kakoschke-Moore.
As well, six of the nine Greens senators would be relegated to bottom six.
The next election must be held by May 2019 at the very latest because the three-year Senate terms began on July 1, this year and will expire on June 30, 2019. It is likely the next election will be held between August 2018 and March 2019.
Last month, The Australian Financial Review reported that the major parties were considering invoking a never-before used countback provision to determine who served six-year terms and three-year terms.
Under this mechanism, each elected senator would be ranked as if it was a half-Senate election, and their vote matched against the much higher quota for a seat of 14.28 per cent.
But the method is complicated and prone to claims that it was undemocratic and was being used by the major parties to target the crossbench.
Deputy government Senate leader Mathias Cormann and Labor Senate leader Penny Wong said on Friday they would stick with the previous system of ranking senators in the order in which they were elected, saying this also reflected the will of voters.
&quot;The important point is obviously this is a function of how many votes and how many preferences you are able to attract. If you are elected in the first six out of 12 then it stands to reason that you were elected earlier and as such you qualify for the longer period,&quot; Senator Cormann said.
AFR Magazine
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/majority-of-senate-crossbench-to-be-given-threeyear-terms-20160812-gqqxd1</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0552</post_time>
<username>Phillip Coorey</username>
<post>
Derryn Hinch would receive a three-year term. Daniel Pockett Share on twitter by Phillip Coorey Seven of the 11 new Senate crossbenchers will have just over two years in Parliament before they must again face the voters in an election at which it will be much more difficult to hold their spot.
Because the July 2 poll was a double dissolution election, it was a full Senate election, meaning all 12 senators in each state were elected.
To rebalance the Senate, only half of those elected will receive a full, six-year term and the other half will receive a three-year half term.
Labor and the Coalition, who have a combined majority in the Senate, have agreed that the Senators who won the most votes in the July 2 double dissolution will receive six-year terms. Those who came in the bottom six in each state would receive three years.
This precedent, which has been used in all previous double dissolution elections, means of the 11 member crossbench, just Nick Xenophon, his colleague Stirling Griff, Pauline Hanson and Tasmania&apos;s Jacqui Lambie, would receive six-year terms.
 The other seven would receive three-year terms. If the next election is a normal half-Senate election, the quota of votes needed to win a spot will be twice as high as it was on July 2, making it much more difficult to hold on.
These seven are Derryn Hinch, David Leyonhjelm, Bob Day, One Nation&apos;s Malcolm Roberts, Brian Burston and Rod Culleton, and the NXTs Skye Kakoschke-Moore.
As well, six of the nine Greens senators would be relegated to bottom six.
The next election must be held by May 2019 at the very latest because the three-year Senate terms began on July 1, this year and will expire on June 30, 2019. It is likely the next election will be held between August 2018 and March 2019.
Last month, The Australian Financial Review reported that the major parties were considering invoking a never-before used countback provision to determine who served six-year terms and three-year terms.
Under this mechanism, each elected senator would be ranked as if it was a half-Senate election, and their vote matched against the much higher quota for a seat of 14.28 per cent.
But the method is complicated and prone to claims that it was undemocratic and was being used by the major parties to target the crossbench.
Deputy government Senate leader Mathias Cormann and Labor Senate leader Penny Wong said on Friday they would stick with the previous system of ranking senators in the order in which they were elected, saying this also reflected the will of voters.
&quot;The important point is obviously this is a function of how many votes and how many preferences you are able to attract. If you are elected in the first six out of 12 then it stands to reason that you were elected earlier and as such you qualify for the longer period,&quot; Senator Cormann said.
AFR Magazine
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>
<external_link>https://twitter.com/PhillipCoorey</external_link>
</external_links>
<country>AU</country>
<main_image>http://www.afr.com/content/dam/images/g/q/l/z/5/l/image.related.afrArticleLead.620x365.gqqxd1.png/1470981144090.jpg</main_image>
</document>
