<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.king5.com/_/20/103632866/king5/food</forum>
<forum_title>KING - Food</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Woman led a coffee creamer crusade</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.king5.com/_/20/103632866/king5/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;king5&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;local&amp;#x2f;michigan-woman-led-a-coffee-creamer-crusade&amp;#x2f;295367725</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Michigan woman led a coffee creamer crusade Vickki Dozier, Lansing State Journal , WZZM 7:03 AM. PDT August 10, 2016 Williamston resident Judy Riedel Tugen holds a bottle of Amaretto Coffee-mate at a surprise gathering at Harrison Roadhouse in East Lansing. The company is bringing Tugen&apos;s favorite flavor back through the end of the year. (Photo: Courtesy photo) 
This is the story of a woman&apos;s love for her morning coffee creamer. 
It&apos;s a story of painful separation and unflinching devotion. 
And it has a happy ending. 
Judy Riedel Tugen began drinking Coffee-mate Amaretto two decades ago. Once she found it, she never wavered, never flirted with other flavors of the nondairy liquid creamer, with Hazelnut or Italian sweet creme. 
&quot;I loved amaretto Coffee-mate, and I’m not alone,&quot; said Tugen, who lives in Williamston. &quot;It has a very comforting, soothing, almond and cherry flavor that&apos;s just so great to wake up to. There&apos;s nothing like it. 
Then, in January of last year, she went shopping at the Okemos Meijer and found that they were out of Coffee-mate Amaretto. The store gave her a rain check. When she went back a week or so later, she was told the amaretto flavor was being discontinued. 
Tugen was shocked. She was heartbroken. 
&quot;There are a lot of fans that drank it for many, many years...&quot; she said. &quot;I very much wanted amaretto to come back.&quot; 
And she didn&apos;t give up. 
She contacted Coffee-mate, she said, and they told her the decision to discontinue the amaretto flavor had not been made lightly. 
&quot;They said sales had been down across the country, so sadly, they had to make that decision,&quot; Tugen said. &quot;My hope was to keep amaretto flavor in front of them, keep it on their minds, to let them know there were a lot of us that were going to miss it.&quot; 
The 73-year-old retiree petitioned Coffee-mate via social media. She made phone calls. She wrote emails and letters. 
Tugen found the Bring Back Amaretto Coffee-mate Creamer Facebook page, which launched on Valentines Day 2015. She followed it. She began posting information on how to contact Coffee-mate. She encouraged others. She did such a good job that she was asked to take over as page administrator. 
&quot;When my mom took over as administrator of the Facebook page, it was at around 300 followers,&quot; said Melanie Zaremba, Tugen&apos;s daughter, &quot;Over the course of her engaging with the page, it’s now over 1,300.&quot; 
Tugen contacted Coffee-mate every week. She invited others to join her. She rallied the group with posts instructing them to call Coffee-mate’s 800 number, post on their Facebook page, and recruit more fans. She checked the page every day, read the comments, added them up. 
&quot;Coffee-mate has wonderful people that answer their phones,&quot; Tugen said. &quot;At one time their office was small enough that the second I called in they knew who I was. They’d say, &apos;Hi Judy.&apos;&quot; 
In the meantime, Tugen tried, in vain, to replace her amaretto creamer. 
&quot;I tried being very creative, and I did buy other brands, but nothing compared to Coffee-mate Amaretto,&quot; she said. &quot;No one could find anything else to substitute for it. I’ve gotten comment after comment on that Facebook page on how unique and wonderful it was. At least one person said &apos;I can’t even drink coffee anymore because I miss my amaretto.&apos;&quot; 
Tugen still drank coffee, but resorted to adding milk and sugar. 
After &quot;1,519 phone calls, 2,337 FB posts, 1,868 emails, 17 passionate letters,&quot; Coffee-mate heard Tugen loud and clear, according to a video on the Bring Back Amaretto Coffee-mate Creamer Facebook page. 
“We made the tough decision to discontinue Coffee-mate Amaretto in January 2015,&quot; said Daniel Jhung, Director of Marketing at Coffee-mate. &quot;Almost immediately, we received thousands of consumer requests across social media, phone and email asking us to bring back the flavor – but none were as passionate as Judy. We wanted to thank Judy for her tireless effort and passion for Coffee-mate. Inspired by her passion, we are bringing back Coffee-mate Amaretto at select retailers in the U.S. through the end of the year.” 
The company contacted Zaremba, a communications director at Michigan State University, and worked with her to coordinate a surprise gathering for Tugen and her friends at the Harrison Roadhouse, where she would learn that her favorite flavor would be coming back for a limited time because of her efforts. 
They wanted Tugen to have the first taste. 
Zaremba had to cook up a ruse to get her mother to attend, saying that she and her team at MSU were being honored. Zaremba&apos;s director and coworkers attended to help her pull it off, along with a few friends. 
&quot;She came in thinking she was celebrating me,&quot; Zaremba said. 
As they sat around a table, a waiter, who was actually an actor, poured coffee. After pouring Tugen&apos;s coffee last, he apologized, saying he had forgotten something and retreated to the kitchen. 
He returned with a bottle of Coffee-mate Amaretto creamer on a silver platter. 
&quot;Mom was engaging and talking with the folks at the table and I said, &apos;Mom, what&apos;s that?&apos;&quot; Zaremba said. &quot;She looked up, and her jaw just dropped open.&quot; 
The first sip was every bit as wonderful as she had remembered. &quot;It was, as one person put it, dreamy and heavenly,&quot; she laughed. &quot;I loved it.&quot; 
&quot;The day was kind of a blur. I think my jaw started hurting from smiling so much. Everybody that came, all of the folks from Coffee-mate marketing and other departments, from different states, I wish I could name all of them, and they give good hugs too.&quot; 
Tugen is quick to give credit where credit is due. 
&quot;I had a large group backing me, and they went step by step with me,&quot; she said. I’m just a little person in this whole thing. I just kept track of it all, but people kept joining and joining and joining.&quot; 
And what is it about the amaretto flavor that made Tugren and others put in so much effort to get it back? 
&quot;I started drinking it when I worked for AT&amp;T in the 1990s and just got hooked,&quot; Tugren said. &quot;I&apos;ve had people tell me they drove 45 miles to find it. But I sympathize because it&apos;s such a unique and different and special flavor. There just isn&apos;t anything else that can compare to it. No one makes it as good as Coffee-mate.&quot; 
(2016 © Lansing State Journal)
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.king5.com/_/20/103632866/king5/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;king5&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;local&amp;#x2f;michigan-woman-led-a-coffee-creamer-crusade&amp;#x2f;295367725</post_url>
<post_date>20160810</post_date>
<post_time>1403</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Michigan woman led a coffee creamer crusade Vickki Dozier, Lansing State Journal , WZZM 7:03 AM. PDT August 10, 2016 Williamston resident Judy Riedel Tugen holds a bottle of Amaretto Coffee-mate at a surprise gathering at Harrison Roadhouse in East Lansing. The company is bringing Tugen&apos;s favorite flavor back through the end of the year. (Photo: Courtesy photo) 
This is the story of a woman&apos;s love for her morning coffee creamer. 
It&apos;s a story of painful separation and unflinching devotion. 
And it has a happy ending. 
Judy Riedel Tugen began drinking Coffee-mate Amaretto two decades ago. Once she found it, she never wavered, never flirted with other flavors of the nondairy liquid creamer, with Hazelnut or Italian sweet creme. 
&quot;I loved amaretto Coffee-mate, and I’m not alone,&quot; said Tugen, who lives in Williamston. &quot;It has a very comforting, soothing, almond and cherry flavor that&apos;s just so great to wake up to. There&apos;s nothing like it. 
Then, in January of last year, she went shopping at the Okemos Meijer and found that they were out of Coffee-mate Amaretto. The store gave her a rain check. When she went back a week or so later, she was told the amaretto flavor was being discontinued. 
Tugen was shocked. She was heartbroken. 
&quot;There are a lot of fans that drank it for many, many years...&quot; she said. &quot;I very much wanted amaretto to come back.&quot; 
And she didn&apos;t give up. 
She contacted Coffee-mate, she said, and they told her the decision to discontinue the amaretto flavor had not been made lightly. 
&quot;They said sales had been down across the country, so sadly, they had to make that decision,&quot; Tugen said. &quot;My hope was to keep amaretto flavor in front of them, keep it on their minds, to let them know there were a lot of us that were going to miss it.&quot; 
The 73-year-old retiree petitioned Coffee-mate via social media. She made phone calls. She wrote emails and letters. 
Tugen found the Bring Back Amaretto Coffee-mate Creamer Facebook page, which launched on Valentines Day 2015. She followed it. She began posting information on how to contact Coffee-mate. She encouraged others. She did such a good job that she was asked to take over as page administrator. 
&quot;When my mom took over as administrator of the Facebook page, it was at around 300 followers,&quot; said Melanie Zaremba, Tugen&apos;s daughter, &quot;Over the course of her engaging with the page, it’s now over 1,300.&quot; 
Tugen contacted Coffee-mate every week. She invited others to join her. She rallied the group with posts instructing them to call Coffee-mate’s 800 number, post on their Facebook page, and recruit more fans. She checked the page every day, read the comments, added them up. 
&quot;Coffee-mate has wonderful people that answer their phones,&quot; Tugen said. &quot;At one time their office was small enough that the second I called in they knew who I was. They’d say, &apos;Hi Judy.&apos;&quot; 
In the meantime, Tugen tried, in vain, to replace her amaretto creamer. 
&quot;I tried being very creative, and I did buy other brands, but nothing compared to Coffee-mate Amaretto,&quot; she said. &quot;No one could find anything else to substitute for it. I’ve gotten comment after comment on that Facebook page on how unique and wonderful it was. At least one person said &apos;I can’t even drink coffee anymore because I miss my amaretto.&apos;&quot; 
Tugen still drank coffee, but resorted to adding milk and sugar. 
After &quot;1,519 phone calls, 2,337 FB posts, 1,868 emails, 17 passionate letters,&quot; Coffee-mate heard Tugen loud and clear, according to a video on the Bring Back Amaretto Coffee-mate Creamer Facebook page. 
“We made the tough decision to discontinue Coffee-mate Amaretto in January 2015,&quot; said Daniel Jhung, Director of Marketing at Coffee-mate. &quot;Almost immediately, we received thousands of consumer requests across social media, phone and email asking us to bring back the flavor – but none were as passionate as Judy. We wanted to thank Judy for her tireless effort and passion for Coffee-mate. Inspired by her passion, we are bringing back Coffee-mate Amaretto at select retailers in the U.S. through the end of the year.” 
The company contacted Zaremba, a communications director at Michigan State University, and worked with her to coordinate a surprise gathering for Tugen and her friends at the Harrison Roadhouse, where she would learn that her favorite flavor would be coming back for a limited time because of her efforts. 
They wanted Tugen to have the first taste. 
Zaremba had to cook up a ruse to get her mother to attend, saying that she and her team at MSU were being honored. Zaremba&apos;s director and coworkers attended to help her pull it off, along with a few friends. 
&quot;She came in thinking she was celebrating me,&quot; Zaremba said. 
As they sat around a table, a waiter, who was actually an actor, poured coffee. After pouring Tugen&apos;s coffee last, he apologized, saying he had forgotten something and retreated to the kitchen. 
He returned with a bottle of Coffee-mate Amaretto creamer on a silver platter. 
&quot;Mom was engaging and talking with the folks at the table and I said, &apos;Mom, what&apos;s that?&apos;&quot; Zaremba said. &quot;She looked up, and her jaw just dropped open.&quot; 
The first sip was every bit as wonderful as she had remembered. &quot;It was, as one person put it, dreamy and heavenly,&quot; she laughed. &quot;I loved it.&quot; 
&quot;The day was kind of a blur. I think my jaw started hurting from smiling so much. Everybody that came, all of the folks from Coffee-mate marketing and other departments, from different states, I wish I could name all of them, and they give good hugs too.&quot; 
Tugen is quick to give credit where credit is due. 
&quot;I had a large group backing me, and they went step by step with me,&quot; she said. I’m just a little person in this whole thing. I just kept track of it all, but people kept joining and joining and joining.&quot; 
And what is it about the amaretto flavor that made Tugren and others put in so much effort to get it back? 
&quot;I started drinking it when I worked for AT&amp;T in the 1990s and just got hooked,&quot; Tugren said. &quot;I&apos;ve had people tell me they drove 45 miles to find it. But I sympathize because it&apos;s such a unique and different and special flavor. There just isn&apos;t anything else that can compare to it. No one makes it as good as Coffee-mate.&quot; 
(2016 © Lansing State Journal)
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.wzzm13.com/photo/2016/08/10/download%20_OP_1_CP__1470837715123_4944890_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
