<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Battle lines drawn over transit tax</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Business/Battle_lines_drawn_over_transit_tax.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Battle lines drawn over transit tax MEASURE AA Notable names emerge on both sides of the debate By Becca Whitnall 
NEW MEASURE—Transportation is the focus of a half-cent county sales tax that will be on the November ballot. Arguments for and against the measure have been filed with the county. If it passes, the tax would be in effect for 30 years and provide money for various transportation projects. ACORN FILE PHOTO Nobody says Ventura County’s freeways aren’t crowded or that roads don’t need to be maintained, but now that a countywide sales tax that includes provisions to help with these issues is on the ballot, sides are forming about whether the measure is the right fix. 
Dubbed Measure AA, the half-cent tax, brought to the ballot by the Ventura County Transportation Commission, would raise about $70 million per year for 30 years. The transportation commission expects a total of about $3.3 billion to be raised when accounting for interest. 
The money will go toward improving local and regional streets and roads, freeways, bus and rail enhancements, bicycle and pedestrian improvements, environmental mitigation, oversight administration and board of equalization fees. 
In their supporting argument filed with the county, U.S. Rep. Julia Brownley, Sheriff Geoff Dean and Los Angeles Deputy Mayor Jeff Gorell said the county’s transportation system is under serious strain. 
“There is too much traffic congestion on our freeways, too many potholes in our streets, and transit services are struggling to maintain service,” they wrote. 
A campaign committee formed to support Measure AA, Ventura County Citizens for Traffic Relief, also took part in filing the argument in favor. 
Proponents of the measure say the tax is needed because the only counties receiving federal and state money to improve transportation nowadays are those that have matching funds to give toward projects. Ventura County doesn’t have those funds to offer. 
“We’re the only county in Southern California without its own transportation revenue source,” Brownley wrote in a statement to the Acorn. “That means our federal tax dollars, which require a local matching grant, are going to other counties.” 
“We’re basically paying for streets and roads in other regions,” said VCTC Chair Keith Millhouse. 
Meanwhile, opponents Supervisor Peter Foy, former U.S. Rep. Elton Gallegly, Thousand Oaks City Councilmember Rob Mc- Coy and Pleasant Valley School District trustee Kelly Long say the plan is “full of generalities and short on specifics” and a 30-year tax is too long. 
The primary objection Foy has with the tax is he thinks money the government already collects could be better used, which would negate the need for the tax. 
“I think there are a lot of things we’re spending money on that are not cost-effective,” he said. “The money is there, it’s just how we’re spending the money.” 
Gallegly and McCoy both take issue with the almost $383 million that would be used on public transportation enhancements should the measure pass. 
“My concern for it is it doesn’t meet the need for the county,” Mc- Coy said. “If we’re going to put another tax on the backs of taxpayers, it needs to go to infrastructure.” 
Ventura County commuters just don’t take public transportation much, Gallegly said. 
“This measure is advocating $191 million for buses— buses that we don’t need,” the former Simi Valley mayor said. 
“Clearly, we know this solution (mass transit) isn’t working,” he said, citing low ridership throughout Southern California. 
But VCTC Director Darren Kettle said that while other regions are experiencing declines, this county is maintaining its bus and train ridership with about 6 million rides per year. 
The transit enhancement goals for program funds are twofold, he said. 
“One is to keep fares affordable for riders,” Kettle said. “If we want public transportation available as an option, we need to be sensitive that some of these riders, like seniors and students, are on limited or fixed incomes.” 
The other goal would be extending hours for existing services, like offering nighttime bus rides and weekend Metrolink services, he said. 
A second argument against the measure, filed by Janis Mc- Cormick, president of the Ventura County Environmental Coalition, says Measure AA would not help ease freeway congestion long term because new developments bring additional traffic. 
“Measure AA would help open up areas for new development,” she writes. “Before voting, ask yourself, ‘Do I want to pay taxes on everything I buy for 30 years to help build up and pave over Ventura County, just like what happened in the San Fernando Valley and Orange County?’” 
While two opposing arguments were filed, state elections code mandates only one may appear in voter information guides. In selecting the argument to include, county elections officials must give preference and priority to any submitted by a county supervisor. 
The latest effort to institute a transportation tax follows failed attempts to pass a similar tax in 1990 and 2004. 
In order to pass, the measure needs the approval of two-thirds of the voters. 
Should it pass, it would become effective April 1, with funds expected to be returned to the county from the California Board of Equalization six months later.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Business/Battle_lines_drawn_over_transit_tax.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
Battle lines drawn over transit tax MEASURE AA Notable names emerge on both sides of the debate By Becca Whitnall 
NEW MEASURE—Transportation is the focus of a half-cent county sales tax that will be on the November ballot. Arguments for and against the measure have been filed with the county. If it passes, the tax would be in effect for 30 years and provide money for various transportation projects. ACORN FILE PHOTO Nobody says Ventura County’s freeways aren’t crowded or that roads don’t need to be maintained, but now that a countywide sales tax that includes provisions to help with these issues is on the ballot, sides are forming about whether the measure is the right fix. 
Dubbed Measure AA, the half-cent tax, brought to the ballot by the Ventura County Transportation Commission, would raise about $70 million per year for 30 years. The transportation commission expects a total of about $3.3 billion to be raised when accounting for interest. 
The money will go toward improving local and regional streets and roads, freeways, bus and rail enhancements, bicycle and pedestrian improvements, environmental mitigation, oversight administration and board of equalization fees. 
In their supporting argument filed with the county, U.S. Rep. Julia Brownley, Sheriff Geoff Dean and Los Angeles Deputy Mayor Jeff Gorell said the county’s transportation system is under serious strain. 
“There is too much traffic congestion on our freeways, too many potholes in our streets, and transit services are struggling to maintain service,” they wrote. 
A campaign committee formed to support Measure AA, Ventura County Citizens for Traffic Relief, also took part in filing the argument in favor. 
Proponents of the measure say the tax is needed because the only counties receiving federal and state money to improve transportation nowadays are those that have matching funds to give toward projects. Ventura County doesn’t have those funds to offer. 
“We’re the only county in Southern California without its own transportation revenue source,” Brownley wrote in a statement to the Acorn. “That means our federal tax dollars, which require a local matching grant, are going to other counties.” 
“We’re basically paying for streets and roads in other regions,” said VCTC Chair Keith Millhouse. 
Meanwhile, opponents Supervisor Peter Foy, former U.S. Rep. Elton Gallegly, Thousand Oaks City Councilmember Rob Mc- Coy and Pleasant Valley School District trustee Kelly Long say the plan is “full of generalities and short on specifics” and a 30-year tax is too long. 
The primary objection Foy has with the tax is he thinks money the government already collects could be better used, which would negate the need for the tax. 
“I think there are a lot of things we’re spending money on that are not cost-effective,” he said. “The money is there, it’s just how we’re spending the money.” 
Gallegly and McCoy both take issue with the almost $383 million that would be used on public transportation enhancements should the measure pass. 
“My concern for it is it doesn’t meet the need for the county,” Mc- Coy said. “If we’re going to put another tax on the backs of taxpayers, it needs to go to infrastructure.” 
Ventura County commuters just don’t take public transportation much, Gallegly said. 
“This measure is advocating $191 million for buses— buses that we don’t need,” the former Simi Valley mayor said. 
“Clearly, we know this solution (mass transit) isn’t working,” he said, citing low ridership throughout Southern California. 
But VCTC Director Darren Kettle said that while other regions are experiencing declines, this county is maintaining its bus and train ridership with about 6 million rides per year. 
The transit enhancement goals for program funds are twofold, he said. 
“One is to keep fares affordable for riders,” Kettle said. “If we want public transportation available as an option, we need to be sensitive that some of these riders, like seniors and students, are on limited or fixed incomes.” 
The other goal would be extending hours for existing services, like offering nighttime bus rides and weekend Metrolink services, he said. 
A second argument against the measure, filed by Janis Mc- Cormick, president of the Ventura County Environmental Coalition, says Measure AA would not help ease freeway congestion long term because new developments bring additional traffic. 
“Measure AA would help open up areas for new development,” she writes. “Before voting, ask yourself, ‘Do I want to pay taxes on everything I buy for 30 years to help build up and pave over Ventura County, just like what happened in the San Fernando Valley and Orange County?’” 
While two opposing arguments were filed, state elections code mandates only one may appear in voter information guides. In selecting the argument to include, county elections officials must give preference and priority to any submitted by a county supervisor. 
The latest effort to institute a transportation tax follows failed attempts to pass a similar tax in 1990 and 2004. 
In order to pass, the measure needs the approval of two-thirds of the voters. 
Should it pass, it would become effective April 1, with funds expected to be returned to the county from the California Board of Equalization six months later.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/19p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
