<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Wade Barrett Says His KOTR Win Was “Thrown Together” : SquaredCircle</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.reddit.com/r/SquaredCircle/comments/4xbslr/wade_barrett_says_his_kotr_win_was_thrown_together/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Description Our Mission Statement Clear rules that help give the subreddit a balance of content. -- In addition please follow redditquette and reddit&apos;s site-wide rules . Spoiler Policy No spoilers in titles for 24 hours after a show has aired. -- If your post contains spoilers put the tag [SPOILERS] at the START of your title and the show title. Posts must be about wrestling &quot;All link posts must be directly related to wrestling. Any link post not featuring wrestling itself, or in relation to a wrestling show or the wrestling industry, is subject to removal. No image posts that are: memes/image macros i.e. an image with text on it done for comedic effect or with slight variation for the sake of a cheap laugh (if it can be found on /r/AdviceAnimals it doesn&apos;t belong here) or observations better suited to a text post. Don&apos;t reply as a new post If you want to fix someone&apos;s post, or have a better example of what&apos;s been posted, tell us so in the comments, not by making a new post! No spam or re-hosted content Always link to the original source and don&apos;t post re-hosted content. Only link to your own content if you contribute to the community. Reposts and vague titles Obvious reposts and titles that are overly ambiguous will be deleted at the moderators&apos; discretion. (e.g. &quot;This Guy&quot;) No Low-Effort Content Low-effort, single image link posts , including but not limited to, screenshots, crude photoshops, and MS paint-style artwork, are subject to removal. However, these may be posted as a self post with a description of the content. No &quot;Plot&quot;/Sexual Content Posts focused on sexual content will be removed. /r/WrestleWithThePlot and /r/WrestleWithThePackage are better places for this content. [Meta] posts Posts or submissions about the community itself are allowed as long as they follow the general rules of Squared Circle. Text posts A text post should have sufficient text in its body to either strengthen the title, create discussion or add more information. Moderator Discretion At any time the moderators will use discretion on any given rule. If they feel it&apos;s significant or unique to be up despite the rules. On the other hand, they also reserve the right to remove any post they feel breaks the rules. All of this can of course be appealed by messaging us. Event Threads 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.reddit.com/r/SquaredCircle/comments/4xbslr/wade_barrett_says_his_kotr_win_was_thrown_together/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Description Our Mission Statement Clear rules that help give the subreddit a balance of content. -- In addition please follow redditquette and reddit&apos;s site-wide rules . Spoiler Policy No spoilers in titles for 24 hours after a show has aired. -- If your post contains spoilers put the tag [SPOILERS] at the START of your title and the show title. Posts must be about wrestling &quot;All link posts must be directly related to wrestling. Any link post not featuring wrestling itself, or in relation to a wrestling show or the wrestling industry, is subject to removal. No image posts that are: memes/image macros i.e. an image with text on it done for comedic effect or with slight variation for the sake of a cheap laugh (if it can be found on /r/AdviceAnimals it doesn&apos;t belong here) or observations better suited to a text post. Don&apos;t reply as a new post If you want to fix someone&apos;s post, or have a better example of what&apos;s been posted, tell us so in the comments, not by making a new post! No spam or re-hosted content Always link to the original source and don&apos;t post re-hosted content. Only link to your own content if you contribute to the community. Reposts and vague titles Obvious reposts and titles that are overly ambiguous will be deleted at the moderators&apos; discretion. (e.g. &quot;This Guy&quot;) No Low-Effort Content Low-effort, single image link posts , including but not limited to, screenshots, crude photoshops, and MS paint-style artwork, are subject to removal. However, these may be posted as a self post with a description of the content. No &quot;Plot&quot;/Sexual Content Posts focused on sexual content will be removed. /r/WrestleWithThePlot and /r/WrestleWithThePackage are better places for this content. [Meta] posts Posts or submissions about the community itself are allowed as long as they follow the general rules of Squared Circle. Text posts A text post should have sufficient text in its body to either strengthen the title, create discussion or add more information. Moderator Discretion At any time the moderators will use discretion on any given rule. If they feel it&apos;s significant or unique to be up despite the rules. On the other hand, they also reserve the right to remove any post they feel breaks the rules. All of this can of course be appealed by messaging us. Event Threads 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://www.redditstatic.com/icon.png</main_image>
</document>
