<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.wsj.com/public/page/news-career-jobs.html</forum>
<forum_title>Career Advice, Find a Job &amp;amp; Salary Trends - Wall Street Journal - Wsj.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Saatchi &amp; Saatchi Executive Kevin Roberts Resigns After Gender Diversity Comments</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wsj.com/articles/publicis-executive-kevin-roberts-resigns-after-gender-diversity-comments-1470221483</topic_url>
<topic_text>
28 COMMENTS PARIS— Kevin Roberts, the executive chairman of ad agency Saatchi &amp; Saatchi, plans to leave following comments he made that were dismissive of the raging debate over gender diversity on Madison Avenue.
Mr. Roberts, who is also “head coach” at parent group Publicis Groupe SA, PUBGY 0.05 % said he would bring forward his retirement date to Sept. 1 following the furor caused by remarks he made in an interview last week. He had been due to retire in May 2017.
In the interview with Business Insider published Friday, Mr. Roberts said with regard to gender equality in the ad industry “the f—ing debate is all over” and he doesn’t spend “any time” on the issue at his company.
He also said agencies are misunderstanding how women view success.
“Their ambition is not a vertical ambition; it’s this intrinsic, circular ambition to be happy,” he is Quote: d as saying in the article. “So they say: ‘We are not judging ourselves by those standards that you idiotic dinosaurlike men judge yourself by.’ I don’t think [the lack of women in leadership roles] is a problem. I’m just not worried about it because they are very happy, they’re very successful, and doing great work.”
In a statement, Mr. Roberts, 66, apologized to colleagues, staff, clients and his company for the comments. “My miscommunication on a number of points has caused upset and offense, and for this I am sorry,” he said.
“’Fail fast, fix fast, learn fast’ is a leadership maxim I advocate,” he added. “When discussing with Business Insider evolving career priorities and new ways of work/life integration, I failed exceptionally fast.”
Publicis Chief Executive Maurice Lévy condemned Mr. Roberts’s comments shortly after they were published, saying the company would “not tolerate anyone speaking for our organization who does not value the importance of inclusion.”
Arthur Sadoun, who heads Publicis’s creative agencies, said in a memo to staff over the weekend that he found the way Mr. Roberts’s remarks were expressed “offensive in terms of language and tonality.”
The lack of diversity and attitudes toward women in the ad industry has attracted international attention this year following a string of scandals. In March, J. Walter Thompson’s chief communications officer filed a harassment lawsuit against former CEO Gustavo Martinez alleging that Mr. Martinez had a pattern of racist and sexist behavior. Mr. Martinez has denied the allegations.
Women make up half of the advertising industry but only 11% of its creative directors, according to the 3% Conference, a movement dedicated to building a business case for more female creative directors in advertising.
In a memo to employees in March, Mr. Lévy stated that diversity remains a key focus for Publicis and highlighted initiatives in place to promote those efforts. Thirty-eight percent of the company’s executive positions are held by women and the supervisory board is equally divided among men and women, he said.
A Publicis spokesman declined to comment when asked whether Mr. Roberts would be getting the same retirement package as the one planned for May next year.
In its 2015 annual report, Publicis said that in the event of a forced departure “other than in the case of serious or gross misconduct,” Mr. Roberts would be entitled to a termination benefit equal to 120% of his annual fixed salary, the maximum annual amount of his target bonus and the annual cost of various benefits he receives.
Mr. Roberts, was paid €3,055,854 ($3,420,660) in total compensation for 2015, down 21.5% on the previous year.
A longtime Publicis executive, Mr. Roberts is a well-known ad executive whose career has also included stints at Procter &amp; Gamble Co. PG 0.49 % and PepsiCo Inc. PEP -0.31 %
Publicis late Saturday said that it had placed Mr. Roberts on leave following the comments, adding that its supervisory board would evaluate Mr. Roberts’s standing.
Write to Nick Kostov at Nick.Kostov@wsj.com
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>9</post_num>
<post_id>post-9</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wsj.com/articles/publicis-executive-kevin-roberts-resigns-after-gender-diversity-comments-1470221483</post_url>
<post_date>20160803</post_date>
<post_time>1841</post_time>
<username>august rossy</username>
<post>
I guess he was tired of hearing it like many others are. This is a tricky debate because numbers don&apos;t always tell the whole story. It&apos;s like disparate impact. There are cause and effect arguments that people fail to take into account. However, if 50 percent of the industry are women the industry should be prepared to present a quantified argument with good reasoning on executive hiring.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-PF655_public_G_20160803063957.jpg</main_image>
</document>
