<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>High A a chance of claiming first victory | Central Western Daily</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.centralwesterndaily.com.au/story/4093016/high-a-a-chance-of-claiming-first-victory/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
12 Aug 2016, 2:28 p.m. High A takes on Robin Hood Craig Harvey Mechanical on Saturday. TIME FOR A WIN: Cheynoah Merchant and her High A side have a good chance at trumping Robin Hood CHM on Saturday. Photo: PHIL BLATCH 0521pbhigh6 
WHILE the top-of-the-table clash between Robin Hood and Royal Hawks is undeniably the biggest game of Saturday’s 12 th round of Orange Netball Association’s Toyota Cup, one other game will feature two sides just as desperate to claim victory. 
Robin Hood Craig Harvey Mechanical (CHM) sits sixth with two wins on the board while OHS High A remains in last place, and hasn’t tasted victory so far in 2016. 
High A mentor Tegan Dray, who also plays centre for Robin Hood and has a heavy involvement in the coaching of the CHM side, said both sides will view the game as a good chance to claim a win. 
Both are hell-bent on doing so too, considering the only time they’ve met this season they drew 34-34. 
“It’s a pretty even match-up too,” Dray said. 
“[CHM] have been improving all the time and High A, while we haven’t had a win, have been doing some really good things each week. 
“I think, this applies to both sides, they just haven’t been able to put those consistent performances together for all four quarters.” 
For CHM a win would keep the side in contention to finish fifth, which coach Cindy Gilchrist said had become the main goal for the year while for High A, a victory could lift them off the bottom of the table if other results fall their way. 
Dray said for her side – the first-placed Robin Hood unit, that is – a complete performance will be necessary to take down Hawks. 
Although the eight-time consecutive champions are still winning the competition Dray admitted the side has been uncharacteristically inconsistent through the opening 11 rounds of the competition. 
“I just don’t think we’ve quite been there mentally at the start of games,” Dray said. 
“We’ve been starting slowly, the last time we played Hawks we started slowly although we did end up winning that game. 
“We’ve been a bit inconsistent, so I’d hope we can produce a four-quarter performance on Saturday. 
“We’ve played together quite a bit now so we’re quite confident in the way we play, we just need to try and get it right for the entire game.” 
Robin Hood is two points clear of Hawks at the moment although the latter side would take top spot with a win thanks to their superior percentage, which would only improve should they triumph. 
“We’ve always viewed Hawks as a danger side, they’ve always been a good, determined team who are willing to put it all in week-in-week-out,” Dray said. 
“Maybe they’re a bit more dangerous this year but we never take them lightly. ALWAYS A DANGER: Robin Hood centre Tegan Dray said her side never takes Royal Hawks lightly. Photo: JUDE KEOGH 0730jknetball3 
“Kristin Zinga’s height in the attacking end is definitely a big advantage for them and Kellie (Watson) knows what she’s doing up there as well, they’ve formed a pretty good little combination. 
“But for them to do well they need the players in the middle feeding them and the defensive players doing their job too. 
“They’re pretty strong up and down the court.” 
Robin Hood and Hawks kick-off Saturday’s action at 1.10pm at Sir Neville Howse Stadium before Vipers take on Life Studio Mid West Eyes and CHM plays High A (both at 2.30pm). Life Studio’s clash with Kinross 1sts is the last game of the day, at 3.50pm. 
Game start at Sir Neville Howse Stadium form 1.10pm. Latest News 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.centralwesterndaily.com.au/story/4093016/high-a-a-chance-of-claiming-first-victory/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Matthew Findlay</username>
<post>
12 Aug 2016, 2:28 p.m. High A takes on Robin Hood Craig Harvey Mechanical on Saturday. TIME FOR A WIN: Cheynoah Merchant and her High A side have a good chance at trumping Robin Hood CHM on Saturday. Photo: PHIL BLATCH 0521pbhigh6 
WHILE the top-of-the-table clash between Robin Hood and Royal Hawks is undeniably the biggest game of Saturday’s 12 th round of Orange Netball Association’s Toyota Cup, one other game will feature two sides just as desperate to claim victory. 
Robin Hood Craig Harvey Mechanical (CHM) sits sixth with two wins on the board while OHS High A remains in last place, and hasn’t tasted victory so far in 2016. 
High A mentor Tegan Dray, who also plays centre for Robin Hood and has a heavy involvement in the coaching of the CHM side, said both sides will view the game as a good chance to claim a win. 
Both are hell-bent on doing so too, considering the only time they’ve met this season they drew 34-34. 
“It’s a pretty even match-up too,” Dray said. 
“[CHM] have been improving all the time and High A, while we haven’t had a win, have been doing some really good things each week. 
“I think, this applies to both sides, they just haven’t been able to put those consistent performances together for all four quarters.” 
For CHM a win would keep the side in contention to finish fifth, which coach Cindy Gilchrist said had become the main goal for the year while for High A, a victory could lift them off the bottom of the table if other results fall their way. 
Dray said for her side – the first-placed Robin Hood unit, that is – a complete performance will be necessary to take down Hawks. 
Although the eight-time consecutive champions are still winning the competition Dray admitted the side has been uncharacteristically inconsistent through the opening 11 rounds of the competition. 
“I just don’t think we’ve quite been there mentally at the start of games,” Dray said. 
“We’ve been starting slowly, the last time we played Hawks we started slowly although we did end up winning that game. 
“We’ve been a bit inconsistent, so I’d hope we can produce a four-quarter performance on Saturday. 
“We’ve played together quite a bit now so we’re quite confident in the way we play, we just need to try and get it right for the entire game.” 
Robin Hood is two points clear of Hawks at the moment although the latter side would take top spot with a win thanks to their superior percentage, which would only improve should they triumph. 
“We’ve always viewed Hawks as a danger side, they’ve always been a good, determined team who are willing to put it all in week-in-week-out,” Dray said. 
“Maybe they’re a bit more dangerous this year but we never take them lightly. ALWAYS A DANGER: Robin Hood centre Tegan Dray said her side never takes Royal Hawks lightly. Photo: JUDE KEOGH 0730jknetball3 
“Kristin Zinga’s height in the attacking end is definitely a big advantage for them and Kellie (Watson) knows what she’s doing up there as well, they’ve formed a pretty good little combination. 
“But for them to do well they need the players in the middle feeding them and the defensive players doing their job too. 
“They’re pretty strong up and down the court.” 
Robin Hood and Hawks kick-off Saturday’s action at 1.10pm at Sir Neville Howse Stadium before Vipers take on Life Studio Mid West Eyes and CHM plays High A (both at 2.30pm). Life Studio’s clash with Kinross 1sts is the last game of the day, at 3.50pm. 
Game start at Sir Neville Howse Stadium form 1.10pm. Latest News 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://nnimgt-a.akamaihd.net/transform/v1/crop/frm/Qrs2cpbWHRW8qVd3GhSkX2/630c8cf0-fe58-46ac-b8d9-162de5229e63.JPG/r1382_918_3982_2387_w1200_h678_fmax.jpg</main_image>
</document>
