<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Toast the Oaks</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Sports/Toast_the_Oaks.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
College wood-bat team savors one of its best summers By Jonathan Andrade 
WHAT’S THE CALL?—Conejo Oaks outfielder Cody Farhat, left, looks for the umpire to make the call after a close play at second base against the So Cal Catch at Cal Lutheran earlier this season. Photos by MICHAEL COONS/Acorn Newspapers It wasn’t a long, hot summer for the Conejo Oaks. They enjoyed their day in the sun. 
The Oaks, a collegiate wood-bat team, enjoyed one of their best seasons, reaching the California Collegiate League championship game on July 31 at the MLB Urban Youth Academy in Compton. 
The Oaks dropped the title bout 5-2 against league powerhouse Santa Barbara Foresters, but head coach David Soliz said the players improved their craft over the course of the season. 
“I was very pleased with how we started and how we finished,” said Soliz, Rio Mesa High’s skipper who wrapped up his sixth year as head coach of the Oaks. “We had two goals. One was to improve, and I think we accomplished that. We also played until the last day, which was goal No. 2.” 
ENTER SANDMAN— So Cal Catch base runner Evan Sandman, left, slides safely to first base, beating the tag from Conejo Oaks’ Codi Santana. The Oaks (28-20 overall) reached the playoffs for the second straight summer after missing the postseason in 2014. 
Soliz said the squad improved this year thanks to another strong crop of talented athletes. 
“They’re quality players,” Soliz said. “They come out and work hard. We just continue to try to provide an opportunity and an atmosphere for the guys to improve their skills.” 
Chad Spanberger, a junior at Arkansas, had a memorable summer. The outfielder hammered a league-high 11 home runs, drove in 43 RBI and notched a .316 batting average in his second stint with the Oaks. 
“We had a lineup of quality players, but he was the one guy who I’m sure brought a lot of attention,” Soliz said of Spanberger. “When he walked to the plate, everyone knew it because he was having a great summer. 
DROP ZONE—Cody Thompson delivers a pitch for the Conejo Oaks earlier this summer. “He was a good player for us last year. This year he came out with a specific intention of driving the ball to the opposite field a little more, which would free up the pull side, and he did that.” 
Spanberger launched a monster grand slam that cleared the right-center field wall during the league’s all-star game on July 13. 
Cal Lutheran senior outfielder Gabriel Gunter, a Hawaii native, found his groove at the dish. 
The 6-foot-2, 200 pound lefty was second on the team in homers (four) and RBI (26). He hit .250 in 90 at bats with the Oaks. 
“I thought it was a great experience playing with high-level competition,” Gunter said. “It really forced me to play up to my competition.” 
Gunter said he will take what he learned and apply it with the Kingsmen. 
“I really honed in on my skills at the plate,” he said. “I stuck with the same mindset coming into the Cal Lu season. It really worked out for me seeing faster pitching, better pitching from what I see in D-III.” 
Oaks pitchers, including locals Jackson Simonsgaard (Thousand Oaks grad), Casey Ryan (Westlake), Tyson Quolas (Oaks Christian) and Ryan Bill (Moorpark), notched ample innings to fine-tune their technique. 
Bill, a Cal Lutheran sophomore, said the summer allowed him to face quality hitters without the stress that comes along with the regular spring season. 
“It was a great environment to play in,” he said. “We were all trying to get better playing against good competition while remaining relaxed. It made it fun while we were getting better. I’m looking forward to our (Cal Lutheran) spring season starting.” 
For players who missed time during the spring with injuries, the summer was a chance to find a groove. 
Simi Valley native Dallas Tessar, a University of Washington middle infielder who played high school ball at Chaminade, missed most of the regular season with a back injury. 
“It took him a little while to get his feet on the ground playing regularly, six days a week,” Soliz said of Tessar. “He ended up with a lot of at-bats, which is really beneficial to him going back for his season.” 
Cal Lutheran redshirt junior infielder Max Weinstein, a Canyon Country native, also missed time last spring. 
He nursed a partial ulnar collateral ligament tear in his right elbow before returning to the field this summer. 
“After being hurt this past year, it was kind of hard to get back into the swing of things playing every day and seeing live pitching,” Weinstein said. “It was good to have some success for my confidence going into this upcoming season. 
Weinstein hit .294 in 136 at bats. He knocked in 17 RBI while coming around to score 22 runs. 
“I’m trying to do what I did over summer and translate that into helping Cal Lutheran,” he said. “Hopefully I have the same sort of success.” 
Weinstein said the summer was a big hit. 
“I loved the team,” he said. “I had one of the best baseball summers I’ve had in a while. The team was great and the coaches were great. 
“It was a lot of fun.” 
Conejo Oaks’ local roots
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Sports/Toast_the_Oaks.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
College wood-bat team savors one of its best summers By Jonathan Andrade 
WHAT’S THE CALL?—Conejo Oaks outfielder Cody Farhat, left, looks for the umpire to make the call after a close play at second base against the So Cal Catch at Cal Lutheran earlier this season. Photos by MICHAEL COONS/Acorn Newspapers It wasn’t a long, hot summer for the Conejo Oaks. They enjoyed their day in the sun. 
The Oaks, a collegiate wood-bat team, enjoyed one of their best seasons, reaching the California Collegiate League championship game on July 31 at the MLB Urban Youth Academy in Compton. 
The Oaks dropped the title bout 5-2 against league powerhouse Santa Barbara Foresters, but head coach David Soliz said the players improved their craft over the course of the season. 
“I was very pleased with how we started and how we finished,” said Soliz, Rio Mesa High’s skipper who wrapped up his sixth year as head coach of the Oaks. “We had two goals. One was to improve, and I think we accomplished that. We also played until the last day, which was goal No. 2.” 
ENTER SANDMAN— So Cal Catch base runner Evan Sandman, left, slides safely to first base, beating the tag from Conejo Oaks’ Codi Santana. The Oaks (28-20 overall) reached the playoffs for the second straight summer after missing the postseason in 2014. 
Soliz said the squad improved this year thanks to another strong crop of talented athletes. 
“They’re quality players,” Soliz said. “They come out and work hard. We just continue to try to provide an opportunity and an atmosphere for the guys to improve their skills.” 
Chad Spanberger, a junior at Arkansas, had a memorable summer. The outfielder hammered a league-high 11 home runs, drove in 43 RBI and notched a .316 batting average in his second stint with the Oaks. 
“We had a lineup of quality players, but he was the one guy who I’m sure brought a lot of attention,” Soliz said of Spanberger. “When he walked to the plate, everyone knew it because he was having a great summer. 
DROP ZONE—Cody Thompson delivers a pitch for the Conejo Oaks earlier this summer. “He was a good player for us last year. This year he came out with a specific intention of driving the ball to the opposite field a little more, which would free up the pull side, and he did that.” 
Spanberger launched a monster grand slam that cleared the right-center field wall during the league’s all-star game on July 13. 
Cal Lutheran senior outfielder Gabriel Gunter, a Hawaii native, found his groove at the dish. 
The 6-foot-2, 200 pound lefty was second on the team in homers (four) and RBI (26). He hit .250 in 90 at bats with the Oaks. 
“I thought it was a great experience playing with high-level competition,” Gunter said. “It really forced me to play up to my competition.” 
Gunter said he will take what he learned and apply it with the Kingsmen. 
“I really honed in on my skills at the plate,” he said. “I stuck with the same mindset coming into the Cal Lu season. It really worked out for me seeing faster pitching, better pitching from what I see in D-III.” 
Oaks pitchers, including locals Jackson Simonsgaard (Thousand Oaks grad), Casey Ryan (Westlake), Tyson Quolas (Oaks Christian) and Ryan Bill (Moorpark), notched ample innings to fine-tune their technique. 
Bill, a Cal Lutheran sophomore, said the summer allowed him to face quality hitters without the stress that comes along with the regular spring season. 
“It was a great environment to play in,” he said. “We were all trying to get better playing against good competition while remaining relaxed. It made it fun while we were getting better. I’m looking forward to our (Cal Lutheran) spring season starting.” 
For players who missed time during the spring with injuries, the summer was a chance to find a groove. 
Simi Valley native Dallas Tessar, a University of Washington middle infielder who played high school ball at Chaminade, missed most of the regular season with a back injury. 
“It took him a little while to get his feet on the ground playing regularly, six days a week,” Soliz said of Tessar. “He ended up with a lot of at-bats, which is really beneficial to him going back for his season.” 
Cal Lutheran redshirt junior infielder Max Weinstein, a Canyon Country native, also missed time last spring. 
He nursed a partial ulnar collateral ligament tear in his right elbow before returning to the field this summer. 
“After being hurt this past year, it was kind of hard to get back into the swing of things playing every day and seeing live pitching,” Weinstein said. “It was good to have some success for my confidence going into this upcoming season. 
Weinstein hit .294 in 136 at bats. He knocked in 17 RBI while coming around to score 22 runs. 
“I’m trying to do what I did over summer and translate that into helping Cal Lutheran,” he said. “Hopefully I have the same sort of success.” 
Weinstein said the summer was a big hit. 
“I loved the team,” he said. “I had one of the best baseball summers I’ve had in a while. The team was great and the coaches were great. 
“It was a lot of fun.” 
Conejo Oaks’ local roots
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/37p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
