<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/110043338/wxia-sports</forum>
<forum_title>WXIA - Sports</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Nearly 20 local athletes compete on Day</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/110043338/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;11alive&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;georgia-athletes&amp;#x2f;nearly-20-local-athletes-compete-on-day-7-in-rio&amp;#x2f;295698613</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nearly 20 local athletes compete on Day 7 in Rio USA Today gives you 5 things to watch Alec McQuade, WXIA 1:30 AM. EDT August 12, 2016 RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 10: A general view of the warm up track at Olympic Stadium on August 10, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Shaun Botterill/Getty Images) (Photo: Shaun Botterill, 2016 Getty Images) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
It&apos;s hard to believe the games opened just one week ago. 
Already so much has happened, but no time to dwell on the past because it is a full Day 7 for Georgia Athletes. There are just under 20 athletes competing today! Plus, track and field gets underway. 
Here&apos;s what you have to look forward to: 
Golf 
GOLF Channel 6:30 a.m.-3 p.m. 
Matt Kuchar has himself in a good position going into the second round. He is tied for 11th after shooting a 69 in the first 18 holes. The same can&apos;t be said for Patrick Reed, who sits at 32nd place, or Bubba Watson, who is in 43rd. But that doesn&apos;t mean they aren&apos;t having fun representing the U.S. and seeing those Capybaras. Those are the real story! 
PHOTOS | Animals of the Rio Olympic golf course Loading... A Brazilian burrowing owl is seen on the course during a practice round on Day 4 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Olympic Golf Course on August 9, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Scott Halleran/Getty Images, 2016 Getty Images A capybara crosses a fairway during a practice round during Day 3 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Olympic Golf Course on August 8, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Scott Halleran/Getty Images, 2016 Getty Images A caiman waits in pond during a practice round during Day 3 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Olympic Golf Course on August 8, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Scott Halleran/Getty Images, 2016 Getty Images A burrowing owl sits in its underground nest in a bunker on the 18th green during a morning training session at the Rio Olympic golf course ahead of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games on August 5, 2016. JIM WATSON/AFP/Getty Images, This content is subject to copyright. A capybara on the course in preparation for the golf competition in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Gold Course on August 9, 2016. Christopher Hanewinckel/USA TODAY Sports, Christopher Hanewinckel Birds are seen on the course in preparation for the golf competition in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Gold Course on August 9, 2016. Christopher Hanewinckel/USA TODAY Sports, Christopher Hanewinckel Burrowing owls on the course in preparation for the golf competition in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Gold Course on August 9, 2016. Christopher Hanewinckel/USA TODAY Sports, Christopher Hanewinckel of 
Shooting 
Live Stream 8:30 a.m. 
Vincent Hancock will try to qualify for the Men&apos;s skeet. Hancock won the Gold medal in 2008 and 2012 becoming the first skeet shooter to repeat as an Olympic champion. Friday, he has a chance to add to his own record. If he qualifies, the Gold medal round will be streamed at 10 a.m. To watch live: Click Here. 
Track &amp; Field 
NBCSN 8 a.m.- Noon &amp; NBC 10 a.m.-2 p.m. 
Kendell Williams will kick off track &amp; field for all our local athletes. Williams, from UGA, is competing in the heptathlon, so she will be competing for the next couple days in several events. Meanwhile, Charles Grethen, also from UGA, will represent Luxembourg in the 800-meter race. 
In NBC Primetime, Willliams will continue to compete. Her fellow Bulldog Jenny Dahlgreen will represent Argentina in the Hammer throw. 
Weightlifting 
Jenny Arthur is competing in the 75kg weightlifting competition. The time is to be determined. Arthur was the first athlete named to the U.S. weightlifting team. Arthur graduated from Gainesville High School. Read more of her story: Road to Rio: The weight of Gold. 
Swimming 
NBC Noon-2:30 p.m. 
Swimming is nearly complete at the Olympics. Two local swimmers will compete in the women&apos;s 50-meter freestyle sprint. UGA&apos;s Chantal Van Landeghem will swim in her final race for Canada. Van Landeghem has already won a Bronze medal in Rio. 
Atlanta&apos;s Naomy Grand Pierre is also in the sprint and will represent Haiti. She is the first female swimmer to represent Haiti in the Olympics. Read more of her story: Atlanta resident is first female swimmer to represent Haiti in Olympics 
If they qualify, they will swim in a semifinal race in primetime. 
Women&apos;s soccer 
NBCSN Noon-2:30 p.m. 
Our three local soccer players, Kelley O&apos;Hara, Morgan Brian and Emily Sonnett, will help the U.S. women&apos;s team in the Round of 16 elimination game. The U.S. won their group going 2-0-1. Hope Solo struggled in her last game. Luckily for her, the U.S. is going up against Sweden. Their offense has struggled in Rio. 
Women&apos;s basketball 
NBCSN 2:30-4:15 p.m. 
So far, so good for the women&apos;s basketball team. Atlanta Dream&apos;s Angel McCoughtry is third on the team&apos;s scoring list in Rio. She has scored 34 points while averaging 13.7 points per game. Collins Hill grad Maya Moore is averaging just under 10 points per game. The U.S. team faces Canada in its last game before the elimination rounds begin. 
Volleyball 
Live Stream 4:05 p.m. 
UGA volleyball player Alexandra Oquendo will play in a final game with Puerto Rico. To watch the game live: Click Here. 
Table Tennis Doubles 
Live Stream 6:30 p.m. 
Atlanta&apos;s Yijun Feng will compete in doubles with partners Kanak Jha and Timothy Wang. Wang also trains in Norcross with Feng. The U.S. has never medaled in table tennis, and our local boys are looking to change that. Click here to watch their competition live. 
Outside of the many local athletes we have competing Friday, the U.S. men&apos;s basketball team will play Serbia on NBCSN at 6 p.m. Finally, Michael Phelps will swim in his last individual Gold medal final in the 100-meter butterfly. 
PHOTOS | Day 6 at Rio Olympics Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Simone Manuel (L) and Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak react after they equally won the Women&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / GABRIEL BOUYS (Photo credit should read GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images) GABRIEL BOUYS, This content is subject to copyright. Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Competitors sail during the men’s Finn opening series race at Marina da Gloria during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Mandatory Credit: Eric Seals-USA TODAY Sports Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; United States defender Katelyn Falgowski (23) and midfield Melissa Gonzalez (5) battle for the ball with India defender Namita Toppo (19) during women&apos;s field hockey pool play in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Hockey Centre. Mandatory Credit: John David Mercer-USA TODAY Sports John David Mercer, John David Mercer Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Nathan Adrian (USA) during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of 
PHOTOS | Every medal captured by Team USA Loading... Simone Biles captured gold and Aly Raisman claimed silver in women&apos;s individual all-around gymnastics. Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy won gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps won gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel captured a gold medal in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports The team of Allison Schmitt, Leah Smith, Maya DiRado and Katie Ledecky won gold in the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Kayla Harrison took gold in the women&apos;s 78kg judo. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Simone Biles captured gold and Aly Raisman claimed silver in women&apos;s individual all-around gymnastics. Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports (FromL) Allison Schmitt, USA&apos;s Leah Smith, USA&apos;s Madeline &quot;Maya&quot; Dirado and USA&apos;s Katie Ledecky listen to their national anthem on the podium after they won the Women&apos;s 4x200m Freestyle Relay. / AFP / Martin BUREAU. MARTIN BUREAU, Custom Bronze medalist USA&apos;s Nathan Adrian on the podium of the Men&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 10, 2016. / AFP / Martin BUREAU MARTIN BUREAU, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 10: Silver medalist Josh Prenot of the United States poses on the podium during the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 200m Breaststroke Final on Day 5 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 10: Silver medalist Daryl Homer of the United States poses on the podium during the medal ceremony for the men&apos;s individual sabre on Day 5 of the Rio 2016. (Photo by Dean Mouhtaropoulos/Getty Images) Dean Mouhtaropoulos, Custom The U.S. women&apos;s gymnastics team (Aly Raisman, Madison Kocian, Laurie Hernandez, Gabby Douglas and Simone Biles) captured gold. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Travis Stevens claimed the silver medal in men&apos;s 81kg judo. John David Mercer, USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz claimed silver in the men&apos;s 400-meter IM. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King, right, won gold and Katie Meili took bronze in the women&apos;s 100-meter breaststroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky won the gold medal in the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Phillip Dutton, aboard Mighty Nice, took bronze in open&apos;s individual eventing. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Ginny Thrasher captured gold in the women&apos;s 10-meter air rifle. Geoff Burke, USA TODAY Sports The team of Conor Dwyer, Townley Haas, Ryan Lochte and Michael Phelps won the 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer took bronze in the men&apos;s 200-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya DiRado claimed the bronze medal in the women&apos;s 200-meter IM. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports The team of Nathan Adrian, Ryan Held, Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel won gold in the men&apos;s 4x100-meter freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps won the gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Boudia and Steele Johnson brought home silver in 10-meter platform synchronized diving. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Cody Miller claimed bronze in the men&apos;s 100-meter breaststroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya DiRado claimed silver in the women&apos;s 400-meter IM. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Corey Cogdell took bronze in women&apos;s trap. Matt Kryger, USA TODAY Sports The team of Brady Ellison, and Zach Garrett and Jake Kaminski won silver in archery. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer took the bronze medal in the women&apos;s 100-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports The team of Simone Manuel, Abbey Weitzeil, Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky captured silver in the women&apos;s 4x100-meter freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Kristin Armstrong won gold in the women&apos;s road cycling time trial, her third consecutive gold in the event. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky captured gold and Leah Smith took bronze in the women&apos;s 400-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy, right, took the gold medal while David Plummer brought home a bronze in the men&apos;s 100-meter backstroke. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Kathleen Baker captured silver in the women&apos;s 100-meter backstroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports of
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/110043338/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;11alive&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;georgia-athletes&amp;#x2f;nearly-20-local-athletes-compete-on-day-7-in-rio&amp;#x2f;295698613</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0530</post_time>
<username>Alec McQuade</username>
<post>
Nearly 20 local athletes compete on Day 7 in Rio USA Today gives you 5 things to watch Alec McQuade, WXIA 1:30 AM. EDT August 12, 2016 RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 10: A general view of the warm up track at Olympic Stadium on August 10, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Shaun Botterill/Getty Images) (Photo: Shaun Botterill, 2016 Getty Images) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
It&apos;s hard to believe the games opened just one week ago. 
Already so much has happened, but no time to dwell on the past because it is a full Day 7 for Georgia Athletes. There are just under 20 athletes competing today! Plus, track and field gets underway. 
Here&apos;s what you have to look forward to: 
Golf 
GOLF Channel 6:30 a.m.-3 p.m. 
Matt Kuchar has himself in a good position going into the second round. He is tied for 11th after shooting a 69 in the first 18 holes. The same can&apos;t be said for Patrick Reed, who sits at 32nd place, or Bubba Watson, who is in 43rd. But that doesn&apos;t mean they aren&apos;t having fun representing the U.S. and seeing those Capybaras. Those are the real story! 
PHOTOS | Animals of the Rio Olympic golf course Loading... A Brazilian burrowing owl is seen on the course during a practice round on Day 4 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Olympic Golf Course on August 9, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Scott Halleran/Getty Images, 2016 Getty Images A capybara crosses a fairway during a practice round during Day 3 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Olympic Golf Course on August 8, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Scott Halleran/Getty Images, 2016 Getty Images A caiman waits in pond during a practice round during Day 3 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Olympic Golf Course on August 8, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Scott Halleran/Getty Images, 2016 Getty Images A burrowing owl sits in its underground nest in a bunker on the 18th green during a morning training session at the Rio Olympic golf course ahead of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games on August 5, 2016. JIM WATSON/AFP/Getty Images, This content is subject to copyright. A capybara on the course in preparation for the golf competition in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Gold Course on August 9, 2016. Christopher Hanewinckel/USA TODAY Sports, Christopher Hanewinckel Birds are seen on the course in preparation for the golf competition in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Gold Course on August 9, 2016. Christopher Hanewinckel/USA TODAY Sports, Christopher Hanewinckel Burrowing owls on the course in preparation for the golf competition in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Gold Course on August 9, 2016. Christopher Hanewinckel/USA TODAY Sports, Christopher Hanewinckel of 
Shooting 
Live Stream 8:30 a.m. 
Vincent Hancock will try to qualify for the Men&apos;s skeet. Hancock won the Gold medal in 2008 and 2012 becoming the first skeet shooter to repeat as an Olympic champion. Friday, he has a chance to add to his own record. If he qualifies, the Gold medal round will be streamed at 10 a.m. To watch live: Click Here. 
Track &amp; Field 
NBCSN 8 a.m.- Noon &amp; NBC 10 a.m.-2 p.m. 
Kendell Williams will kick off track &amp; field for all our local athletes. Williams, from UGA, is competing in the heptathlon, so she will be competing for the next couple days in several events. Meanwhile, Charles Grethen, also from UGA, will represent Luxembourg in the 800-meter race. 
In NBC Primetime, Willliams will continue to compete. Her fellow Bulldog Jenny Dahlgreen will represent Argentina in the Hammer throw. 
Weightlifting 
Jenny Arthur is competing in the 75kg weightlifting competition. The time is to be determined. Arthur was the first athlete named to the U.S. weightlifting team. Arthur graduated from Gainesville High School. Read more of her story: Road to Rio: The weight of Gold. 
Swimming 
NBC Noon-2:30 p.m. 
Swimming is nearly complete at the Olympics. Two local swimmers will compete in the women&apos;s 50-meter freestyle sprint. UGA&apos;s Chantal Van Landeghem will swim in her final race for Canada. Van Landeghem has already won a Bronze medal in Rio. 
Atlanta&apos;s Naomy Grand Pierre is also in the sprint and will represent Haiti. She is the first female swimmer to represent Haiti in the Olympics. Read more of her story: Atlanta resident is first female swimmer to represent Haiti in Olympics 
If they qualify, they will swim in a semifinal race in primetime. 
Women&apos;s soccer 
NBCSN Noon-2:30 p.m. 
Our three local soccer players, Kelley O&apos;Hara, Morgan Brian and Emily Sonnett, will help the U.S. women&apos;s team in the Round of 16 elimination game. The U.S. won their group going 2-0-1. Hope Solo struggled in her last game. Luckily for her, the U.S. is going up against Sweden. Their offense has struggled in Rio. 
Women&apos;s basketball 
NBCSN 2:30-4:15 p.m. 
So far, so good for the women&apos;s basketball team. Atlanta Dream&apos;s Angel McCoughtry is third on the team&apos;s scoring list in Rio. She has scored 34 points while averaging 13.7 points per game. Collins Hill grad Maya Moore is averaging just under 10 points per game. The U.S. team faces Canada in its last game before the elimination rounds begin. 
Volleyball 
Live Stream 4:05 p.m. 
UGA volleyball player Alexandra Oquendo will play in a final game with Puerto Rico. To watch the game live: Click Here. 
Table Tennis Doubles 
Live Stream 6:30 p.m. 
Atlanta&apos;s Yijun Feng will compete in doubles with partners Kanak Jha and Timothy Wang. Wang also trains in Norcross with Feng. The U.S. has never medaled in table tennis, and our local boys are looking to change that. Click here to watch their competition live. 
Outside of the many local athletes we have competing Friday, the U.S. men&apos;s basketball team will play Serbia on NBCSN at 6 p.m. Finally, Michael Phelps will swim in his last individual Gold medal final in the 100-meter butterfly. 
PHOTOS | Day 6 at Rio Olympics Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Simone Manuel (L) and Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak react after they equally won the Women&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / GABRIEL BOUYS (Photo credit should read GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images) GABRIEL BOUYS, This content is subject to copyright. Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Competitors sail during the men’s Finn opening series race at Marina da Gloria during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Mandatory Credit: Eric Seals-USA TODAY Sports Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; United States defender Katelyn Falgowski (23) and midfield Melissa Gonzalez (5) battle for the ball with India defender Namita Toppo (19) during women&apos;s field hockey pool play in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Hockey Centre. Mandatory Credit: John David Mercer-USA TODAY Sports John David Mercer, John David Mercer Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Nathan Adrian (USA) during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of 
PHOTOS | Every medal captured by Team USA Loading... Simone Biles captured gold and Aly Raisman claimed silver in women&apos;s individual all-around gymnastics. Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy won gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps won gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel captured a gold medal in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports The team of Allison Schmitt, Leah Smith, Maya DiRado and Katie Ledecky won gold in the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Kayla Harrison took gold in the women&apos;s 78kg judo. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Simone Biles captured gold and Aly Raisman claimed silver in women&apos;s individual all-around gymnastics. Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports (FromL) Allison Schmitt, USA&apos;s Leah Smith, USA&apos;s Madeline &quot;Maya&quot; Dirado and USA&apos;s Katie Ledecky listen to their national anthem on the podium after they won the Women&apos;s 4x200m Freestyle Relay. / AFP / Martin BUREAU. MARTIN BUREAU, Custom Bronze medalist USA&apos;s Nathan Adrian on the podium of the Men&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 10, 2016. / AFP / Martin BUREAU MARTIN BUREAU, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 10: Silver medalist Josh Prenot of the United States poses on the podium during the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 200m Breaststroke Final on Day 5 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 10: Silver medalist Daryl Homer of the United States poses on the podium during the medal ceremony for the men&apos;s individual sabre on Day 5 of the Rio 2016. (Photo by Dean Mouhtaropoulos/Getty Images) Dean Mouhtaropoulos, Custom The U.S. women&apos;s gymnastics team (Aly Raisman, Madison Kocian, Laurie Hernandez, Gabby Douglas and Simone Biles) captured gold. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Travis Stevens claimed the silver medal in men&apos;s 81kg judo. John David Mercer, USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz claimed silver in the men&apos;s 400-meter IM. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King, right, won gold and Katie Meili took bronze in the women&apos;s 100-meter breaststroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky won the gold medal in the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Phillip Dutton, aboard Mighty Nice, took bronze in open&apos;s individual eventing. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Ginny Thrasher captured gold in the women&apos;s 10-meter air rifle. Geoff Burke, USA TODAY Sports The team of Conor Dwyer, Townley Haas, Ryan Lochte and Michael Phelps won the 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer took bronze in the men&apos;s 200-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya DiRado claimed the bronze medal in the women&apos;s 200-meter IM. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports The team of Nathan Adrian, Ryan Held, Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel won gold in the men&apos;s 4x100-meter freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps won the gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Boudia and Steele Johnson brought home silver in 10-meter platform synchronized diving. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Cody Miller claimed bronze in the men&apos;s 100-meter breaststroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya DiRado claimed silver in the women&apos;s 400-meter IM. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Corey Cogdell took bronze in women&apos;s trap. Matt Kryger, USA TODAY Sports The team of Brady Ellison, and Zach Garrett and Jake Kaminski won silver in archery. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer took the bronze medal in the women&apos;s 100-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports The team of Simone Manuel, Abbey Weitzeil, Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky captured silver in the women&apos;s 4x100-meter freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Kristin Armstrong won gold in the women&apos;s road cycling time trial, her third consecutive gold in the event. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky captured gold and Leah Smith took bronze in the women&apos;s 400-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy, right, took the gold medal while David Plummer brought home a bronze in the men&apos;s 100-meter backstroke. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Kathleen Baker captured silver in the women&apos;s 100-meter backstroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports of
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.11alive.com/photo/2016/08/12/GettyImages-588148692_1470979380084_5121735_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
