<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.thenorthernecho.co.uk/sport/cricket/rss/</forum>
<forum_title>The Northern Echo | Cricket</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Durham hope Ben Stokes will return next week</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.thenorthernecho.co.uk/sport/cricket/14678419.Durham_hope_Ben_Stokes_will_return_next_week/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Have you got a local story, picture or video you would like to send to us? Send it to us now for a chance to get published. Services Durham hope Ben Stokes will return next week INJURED: Ben Stokes of Durham and England. Picture: SIMON COOPER/PA 0 comments 
DURHAM hope to have Ben Stokes available for the NatWest T20 Blast finals at Edgbaston next Saturday. 
The England all-rounder has stepped up his training this week as he recovers from the calf injury which has ruled him out of the last two Tests. 
England want him fully fit for the one-day internationals, which start four days after T20 finals day, and there is an outside chance he could play as a batsman in the championship match against Middlesex, starting at Lord&apos;s tomorrow. 
  
“It&apos;s not inconceivable,” said coach Jon Lewis. “He played a few one-day games for us just as a batsman when he was recovering from his knee operation. But a calf is a bit different. 
“He could stand at slip, but he&apos;s not the type to chase a ball to the boundary half-heartedly and England know that. They might want him fit to bowl as well before they let him play.” 
While any changes to the T20 side which beat Gloucestershire by 19 runs at Bristol on Wednesday would be made reluctantly, Jack Burnham could make way. 
The highly-rated youngster failed to score in his only appearance in the group matches and came into the quarter-final because Calum MacLeod chose to play for Scotland in a four-day Intercontinental Cup match against the UAE at Ayr. Unfortunately for him, only 66 overs have been bowled over the first three days because of rain. 
MacLeod has been told his contract will not be renewed as Durham continue to cut costs and he is unlikely to feature on finals day. 
If Stokes were able to bowl it would reduce the need for skipper Paul Collingwood to risk a repeat of his nightmare five balls on Wednesday. 
He conceded 22 with two deliveries being no-balls above waist height, which meant he was not allowed to continue. 
He said afterwards: “Who knows what this team is capable of – as long as I don&apos;t bowl.” 
Michael Richardson was named Man of the Match for his 37 off 21 balls and the outstanding catch, standing up to Chris Rushworth, which got rid of dangerman Michael Klinger. 
Richardson, who has taken over the one-day gloves only since Phil Mustard went on loan to Gloucestershire, had hit only one six in T20 cricket until he cleared the leg-side rope three times on Wednesday. 
Warwickshire have announced that tickets for finals day, other than the 800 allocated to each semi-finalist, have sold out. 
Durham&apos;s T20 season ticket holders and Friday night season ticket holders can apply at Emirates Riverside from 9am today. 
Any unsold tickets will go on general sale at Edgbaston from 10am on Tuesday (tel 0844 847 1902). 
Westoe Travel are organising coach transport for those wishing to go there and back in the day, or a train journey with an overnight stay (tel 0191 455 2292).
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.thenorthernecho.co.uk/sport/cricket/14678419.Durham_hope_Ben_Stokes_will_return_next_week/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0452</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Have you got a local story, picture or video you would like to send to us? Send it to us now for a chance to get published. Services Durham hope Ben Stokes will return next week INJURED: Ben Stokes of Durham and England. Picture: SIMON COOPER/PA 0 comments 
DURHAM hope to have Ben Stokes available for the NatWest T20 Blast finals at Edgbaston next Saturday. 
The England all-rounder has stepped up his training this week as he recovers from the calf injury which has ruled him out of the last two Tests. 
England want him fully fit for the one-day internationals, which start four days after T20 finals day, and there is an outside chance he could play as a batsman in the championship match against Middlesex, starting at Lord&apos;s tomorrow. 
  
“It&apos;s not inconceivable,” said coach Jon Lewis. “He played a few one-day games for us just as a batsman when he was recovering from his knee operation. But a calf is a bit different. 
“He could stand at slip, but he&apos;s not the type to chase a ball to the boundary half-heartedly and England know that. They might want him fit to bowl as well before they let him play.” 
While any changes to the T20 side which beat Gloucestershire by 19 runs at Bristol on Wednesday would be made reluctantly, Jack Burnham could make way. 
The highly-rated youngster failed to score in his only appearance in the group matches and came into the quarter-final because Calum MacLeod chose to play for Scotland in a four-day Intercontinental Cup match against the UAE at Ayr. Unfortunately for him, only 66 overs have been bowled over the first three days because of rain. 
MacLeod has been told his contract will not be renewed as Durham continue to cut costs and he is unlikely to feature on finals day. 
If Stokes were able to bowl it would reduce the need for skipper Paul Collingwood to risk a repeat of his nightmare five balls on Wednesday. 
He conceded 22 with two deliveries being no-balls above waist height, which meant he was not allowed to continue. 
He said afterwards: “Who knows what this team is capable of – as long as I don&apos;t bowl.” 
Michael Richardson was named Man of the Match for his 37 off 21 balls and the outstanding catch, standing up to Chris Rushworth, which got rid of dangerman Michael Klinger. 
Richardson, who has taken over the one-day gloves only since Phil Mustard went on loan to Gloucestershire, had hit only one six in T20 cricket until he cleared the leg-side rope three times on Wednesday. 
Warwickshire have announced that tickets for finals day, other than the 800 allocated to each semi-finalist, have sold out. 
Durham&apos;s T20 season ticket holders and Friday night season ticket holders can apply at Emirates Riverside from 9am today. 
Any unsold tickets will go on general sale at Edgbaston from 10am on Tuesday (tel 0844 847 1902). 
Westoe Travel are organising coach transport for those wishing to go there and back in the day, or a train journey with an overnight stay (tel 0191 455 2292).
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://www.thenorthernecho.co.uk/resources/images/5367333/</main_image>
</document>
