<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Nancy Dell: Agave as a sugar alternative; benefits of tomatoes + | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/nancy-dell-agave-as-a-sugar-alternative-benefits-of-tomatoes/</topic_url>
<topic_text>

1. Is agave a good alternative to sugar? I hear it is healthful. Bev, Monson 
In a word, no, agave is not a good alternative. Agave syrup comes from the same cactus plant from which we get tequila. The ads say agave has a lower glycemic index which means it does not raise blood sugar as much as granulated sugar. 
However, this claim is misleading. Agave is high in fructose which does raise blood sugar less than granulated sugar but it has some harmful qualities. Fructose raises your bad cholesterol, triglycerides, uric acid and the fat in your liver. All these factors increase your risk of diabetes and heart disease. 
So, no sugar including agave is healthful and all sugars should be use in small p+-ortions. How much sugar is a “small portion”? It varies person to person but on average, it’s seven level teaspoons a day, including the sugar already added to the foods you buy. 
2. My garden is loaded with tomatoes. What are the health benefits? Bob, Hadley 
In the Middle Ages, tomatoes were thought to be poisonous. Fortunately, we eventually learned that they are not only delicious this time of year but have many health benefits. 
According to a study in the journal Medicine , eating tomatoes can reduce a man’s risk of developing prostate cancer. In addition, tomatoes can prevent and treat some diseases of the mouth including periodontal disease, and oral cancer. A study in the journal Nutrition reports that drinking tomato juice everyday for 2 months significantly reduce the size of participants waistlines, their cholesterol and overall risk of heart disease, stroke and diabetes. 
Ripe tomatoes can keep for up to 1 week at room temperature. If you have so many that you can’t eat them all in 1 week, you can refrigerate or can them Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/nancy-dell-agave-as-a-sugar-alternative-benefits-of-tomatoes/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Nancy Dell</username>
<post>

1. Is agave a good alternative to sugar? I hear it is healthful. Bev, Monson 
In a word, no, agave is not a good alternative. Agave syrup comes from the same cactus plant from which we get tequila. The ads say agave has a lower glycemic index which means it does not raise blood sugar as much as granulated sugar. 
However, this claim is misleading. Agave is high in fructose which does raise blood sugar less than granulated sugar but it has some harmful qualities. Fructose raises your bad cholesterol, triglycerides, uric acid and the fat in your liver. All these factors increase your risk of diabetes and heart disease. 
So, no sugar including agave is healthful and all sugars should be use in small p+-ortions. How much sugar is a “small portion”? It varies person to person but on average, it’s seven level teaspoons a day, including the sugar already added to the foods you buy. 
2. My garden is loaded with tomatoes. What are the health benefits? Bob, Hadley 
In the Middle Ages, tomatoes were thought to be poisonous. Fortunately, we eventually learned that they are not only delicious this time of year but have many health benefits. 
According to a study in the journal Medicine , eating tomatoes can reduce a man’s risk of developing prostate cancer. In addition, tomatoes can prevent and treat some diseases of the mouth including periodontal disease, and oral cancer. A study in the journal Nutrition reports that drinking tomato juice everyday for 2 months significantly reduce the size of participants waistlines, their cholesterol and overall risk of heart disease, stroke and diabetes. 
Ripe tomatoes can keep for up to 1 week at room temperature. If you have so many that you can’t eat them all in 1 week, you can refrigerate or can them Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/640x480-nancydell.jpg</main_image>
</document>
