<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Poland volleyball reportedly facing fine after skirmish with Iran | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/poland-volleyball-reportedly-facing-fine-after-skirmish-with-iran/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Poland volleyball reportedly facing fine after skirmish with Iran Poland volleyball reportedly facing fine after skirmish with Iran NBC Olympics.com Published: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
The Iranian men’s volleyball team is certainly making its presence known in its first Olympics ever. 
After a hard-fought fifth set on Day 2 of the preliminary round Tuesday, Iran and Poland nearly came to blows at the net in a benches-clearing incident: 
It’s unclear exactly what started the issue, but if the official Twitter account for Iran volleyball is to be believed, Poland may be facing a fine from the Federation Internationale de Volleyball (FIVB): Also according to the Iranian volleyball Twitter account, Iranian setter Saeid Marouf said he doesn’t know what’s wrong with the Polish players: 
And in the postgame press conference Tuesday according to the clip posted by VarzeshVideo.com , Marouf said, “I don’t know why they hate us.” 
Polish outside hitter Michal Kubiak responded to the incident and Marouf in that same press conference, saying ( h/t VarzeshVideo.com ): 
“We like them. It’s just emotion that we give off during the game. They laugh inside the court in our face. I don’t care. For me, it’s just a part of the sport. We stare at them, they stare at us. They smile at us, we smile at them. It’s just a sport. But in the end, for me, the most important thing is just the result. 
“It’s not about beating anybody or going to a fight with anybody. I just want to win and I will do everything in my power to win the games against any kind of team. Not against them, personally. I have nothing to do with them, personally. For me, it’s just a normal game. I want to win. This is the Olympics. For me, this is the story of my life. I want to be here; I want to win here. So I will do everything to win. That’s it.” 
Both teams currently qualify for the quarterfinals round, so this may not be the last of this matchup in Rio. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/poland-volleyball-reportedly-facing-fine-after-skirmish-with-iran/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Nbc Olympics.Com</username>
<post>
Poland volleyball reportedly facing fine after skirmish with Iran Poland volleyball reportedly facing fine after skirmish with Iran NBC Olympics.com Published: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
The Iranian men’s volleyball team is certainly making its presence known in its first Olympics ever. 
After a hard-fought fifth set on Day 2 of the preliminary round Tuesday, Iran and Poland nearly came to blows at the net in a benches-clearing incident: 
It’s unclear exactly what started the issue, but if the official Twitter account for Iran volleyball is to be believed, Poland may be facing a fine from the Federation Internationale de Volleyball (FIVB): Also according to the Iranian volleyball Twitter account, Iranian setter Saeid Marouf said he doesn’t know what’s wrong with the Polish players: 
And in the postgame press conference Tuesday according to the clip posted by VarzeshVideo.com , Marouf said, “I don’t know why they hate us.” 
Polish outside hitter Michal Kubiak responded to the incident and Marouf in that same press conference, saying ( h/t VarzeshVideo.com ): 
“We like them. It’s just emotion that we give off during the game. They laugh inside the court in our face. I don’t care. For me, it’s just a part of the sport. We stare at them, they stare at us. They smile at us, we smile at them. It’s just a sport. But in the end, for me, the most important thing is just the result. 
“It’s not about beating anybody or going to a fight with anybody. I just want to win and I will do everything in my power to win the games against any kind of team. Not against them, personally. I have nothing to do with them, personally. For me, it’s just a normal game. I want to win. This is the Olympics. For me, this is the story of my life. I want to be here; I want to win here. So I will do everything to win. That’s it.” 
Both teams currently qualify for the quarterfinals round, so this may not be the last of this matchup in Rio. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/poland-iran-volleyball-skirmish-photo.png</main_image>
</document>
