<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>County’s foster kids get back-to-school boost</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Community/Countys_foster_kids_get_backtoschool_boost.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
County’s foster kids get back-to-school boost By Hector Gonzalez 
CLOTHING AND MORE—Volunteers Marie Dayal, left, of Thousand Oaks and Jade Chu of Monrovia help out during the annual school supplies giveaway Saturday at Casa Pacifica in Camarillo. BOBBY CURTIS/Acorn Newspapers In a single shopping trip, Austin, a 16-year-old from a foster group home in Oxnard, found everything he needed for school “and more,” he said. 
“I got a couple of shirts, two pants, a jacket, a hat and a backpack,” he said. “I think I’m set for school.” 
Like Austin, children from dozens of foster homes in Ventura County pored through aisles and racks of new and gently worn clothing, tried on new shoes, snatched up backpacks and books, and loaded up on school supplies during a special event Aug. 6 at Casa Pacifica Centers for Children and Families in Camarillo. 
“This really helps them out,” said Justin Haulcy-Bateman, who brought six children from the Trinity Group Home in Oxnard. “They’re able to get items like backpacks and supplies for free, so they don’t have to spend their money on them and they can use their money for other things they might need.” 
More than 250 foster children ages 10 to 18, as well as former foster wards up to age 25, were helped at the second-annual giveaway— and not just materially, said Stacey DeWitt, executive director of James Storehouse, a Newbury Park-based nonprofit that provides for the needs of children in foster care. The nonprofit hosted the back-to-school event at Casa Pacifica. 
“When they go to school, we want them to feel good about themselves,” she said. “We want them to feel successful. And we want to show them that we love them, we care for them and that they matter.” 
Casa Pacifica provides emergency shelter placement and residential care for children referred to the nonprofit by the county’s Human Services Agency, particularly difficult-to-place children ages 13 to 18. 
The agency also provides educational and support services for foster children and parents. It runs a school on its 24-acre campus. 
In Ventura County, nearly 1,000 young people were in foster care in 2014, and each month 40 new children need to be placed in temporary homes for their safety and well-being, according to Child Protective Services. 
Statistics are stacked against the youngsters. Only 54 percent of children in foster care finish high school and less than 3 percent earn four-year college degrees, according to a 2012 study by California Lutheran University in Thousand Oaks. 
Among California’s approximately 60,000 foster children, many are among the 15 percent of the state’s children who live in poverty. About 9 percent of foster children live in group homes. 
“When children come into foster care, they usually don’t have much, just the clothes on their back,” DeWitt said. 
That’s where James Storehouse and other nonprofits come in, helping to provide free clothing and school supplies year-round to children in foster care. 
For the back- to- school giveaway last weekend, the nonprofit started collecting donations three months ago to make sure there would be enough items to meet the need. 
“We just put a shout out on social media and word of mouth through friends,” DeWitt said. 
Helping out this year was Claudia Cortez, 18, a former foster care ward who founded her own nonprofit, Claudia’s Closet, to raise donations for older foster youths. She stored donated items at James Storehouse and brought books, backpacks and clothing to the event. 
“It’s my vision of how to help the teens. I want to help ages 11 to 25,” the Newbury Park High graduate said. “There’s a lot of help for the little kids, but not enough help for teens.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Community/Countys_foster_kids_get_backtoschool_boost.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0219</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
County’s foster kids get back-to-school boost By Hector Gonzalez 
CLOTHING AND MORE—Volunteers Marie Dayal, left, of Thousand Oaks and Jade Chu of Monrovia help out during the annual school supplies giveaway Saturday at Casa Pacifica in Camarillo. BOBBY CURTIS/Acorn Newspapers In a single shopping trip, Austin, a 16-year-old from a foster group home in Oxnard, found everything he needed for school “and more,” he said. 
“I got a couple of shirts, two pants, a jacket, a hat and a backpack,” he said. “I think I’m set for school.” 
Like Austin, children from dozens of foster homes in Ventura County pored through aisles and racks of new and gently worn clothing, tried on new shoes, snatched up backpacks and books, and loaded up on school supplies during a special event Aug. 6 at Casa Pacifica Centers for Children and Families in Camarillo. 
“This really helps them out,” said Justin Haulcy-Bateman, who brought six children from the Trinity Group Home in Oxnard. “They’re able to get items like backpacks and supplies for free, so they don’t have to spend their money on them and they can use their money for other things they might need.” 
More than 250 foster children ages 10 to 18, as well as former foster wards up to age 25, were helped at the second-annual giveaway— and not just materially, said Stacey DeWitt, executive director of James Storehouse, a Newbury Park-based nonprofit that provides for the needs of children in foster care. The nonprofit hosted the back-to-school event at Casa Pacifica. 
“When they go to school, we want them to feel good about themselves,” she said. “We want them to feel successful. And we want to show them that we love them, we care for them and that they matter.” 
Casa Pacifica provides emergency shelter placement and residential care for children referred to the nonprofit by the county’s Human Services Agency, particularly difficult-to-place children ages 13 to 18. 
The agency also provides educational and support services for foster children and parents. It runs a school on its 24-acre campus. 
In Ventura County, nearly 1,000 young people were in foster care in 2014, and each month 40 new children need to be placed in temporary homes for their safety and well-being, according to Child Protective Services. 
Statistics are stacked against the youngsters. Only 54 percent of children in foster care finish high school and less than 3 percent earn four-year college degrees, according to a 2012 study by California Lutheran University in Thousand Oaks. 
Among California’s approximately 60,000 foster children, many are among the 15 percent of the state’s children who live in poverty. About 9 percent of foster children live in group homes. 
“When children come into foster care, they usually don’t have much, just the clothes on their back,” DeWitt said. 
That’s where James Storehouse and other nonprofits come in, helping to provide free clothing and school supplies year-round to children in foster care. 
For the back- to- school giveaway last weekend, the nonprofit started collecting donations three months ago to make sure there would be enough items to meet the need. 
“We just put a shout out on social media and word of mouth through friends,” DeWitt said. 
Helping out this year was Claudia Cortez, 18, a former foster care ward who founded her own nonprofit, Claudia’s Closet, to raise donations for older foster youths. She stored donated items at James Storehouse and brought books, backpacks and clothing to the event. 
“It’s my vision of how to help the teens. I want to help ages 11 to 25,” the Newbury Park High graduate said. “There’s a lot of help for the little kids, but not enough help for teens.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/15p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
