<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>A tale of two priests at Holy Cross</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Faith/A_tale_of_two_priests_at_Holy_Cross.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
A tale of two priests at Holy Cross By Stephanie Bertholdo 
Monsignor Albee A changing of the guard is underway at two Catholic churches. 
Monsignor Paul Albee was welcomed as the new pastor of St. Maximilian Kolbe Catholic Church in Westlake on July 1, and Monsignor Joseph Hernandez took Albee’s place at Holy Cross Catholic Church in Moorpark. 
Here’s a look at both men: 
Monsignor Paul Albee 
Albee, the pastor at Holy Cross for 11 years, joined St. Max after the Rev. Jarlath Dolan retired. 
Albee has worked in numerous California parishes since he became a priest over 32 years ago. In his first year as a priest in 1984, he served at St. Bruno Catholic Church in Whittier, followed by three years as associate pastor at San Pancratius Catholic Church in Lakewood. 
The rotation of priests in California’s Catholic churches makes for a small world at times. Albee said the priest who replaced him at St. Bruno, the Rev. Patrick O’Dwyer, later became pastor at St. Maximilian Kolbe. Dolan joined the St. Max parish in July 2009 after O’Dwyer died. 
Monsignor Hernandez After his time at San Pancratius ended in 1988, Albee worked at the Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Los Angeles for a year. He headed a matrimonial tribunal that investigated requests for marriage annulments. 
“What I did there was review the cases write and helped the judge write his decision,” Albee said. “It was a very hot topic, and I had very limited experience.” 
In 1989, he was happy to return to a parish job as associate pastor of St. Rose of Lima in Simi Valley for seven years. 
After several short assignments in various parishes, he worked as secretary to Cardinal Roger Mahony at the Archdiocese of Los Angeles for five and half years. 
After leaving the archdiocese, Albee worked as a temporary pastor at St. Joseph the Worker in Winnetka. In 2005, he became pastor at Holy Cross in Moorpark. 
He said his experience handling a range of general church matters, coupled with some of the specialized duties he’s had over the years, prepared him for the challenge of running a community church. 
He talked briefly about Pope Francis, who by many accounts has captured the hearts of Catholics and the faithful from other denominations around the world for his generosity of spirit. 
“I think that people are very excited about the Holy Father’s ministry in the Catholic Church,” he said. “It seems to be a different approach than others, but (actually) it’s all based in Catholic traditions for centuries.” 
The tenets promoted by the pope, he said, are based on “treating people with honor and dignity.” 
“That’s always been part of Catholic theology and tradition,” Albee said. “I think it’s exciting and refreshing to hear it being reiterated in the Catholic Church.” 
He said his philosophy jibes with the pope’s in that he would never deny Eucharist to anyone, including members of the gay community. 
“To quote Pope Francis, ‘Who are we to judge?’” Albee said. 
For now, he is focused on getting to know the St. Max community. He is particularly pleased with the congregational outreach done at the church, including participation in Habitat for Humanity. 
Ordinarily, priests are moved from parish to parish every six years. But Albee, who is just shy of 60, said he expects to be the pastor at St. Max for far longer. 
“Given my age, this is the last stop of the journey,” he said. 
Monsignor Joseph Hernandez 
Hernandez, ordained as a priest in 1981, served as pastor of St. Teresa of Avila in Los Angeles and vice chancellor of the archdiocese prior to his appointment at Holy Cross in Moorpark. 
He’s not a stranger to the area. 
“My time at St. John’s Seminary (in Camarillo) was my introduction to the particular beauty of Ventura County,” he said. “I have been fortunate to have been assigned to a number of parishes in the county.” 
As a deacon, Hernandez served at Santa Clara Church &amp; Chapel in Oxnard, followed by a term there as an associate pastor. He’s also worked at Our Lady of the Assumption Catholic Church in Ventura and was pastor of St. Francis of Assisi Roman Catholic Church in Fillmore. 
Hernandez is pleased with his latest local assignment and said he’s delighted by the Holy Cross congregation’s level of service to the community and the poor. 
“I do know that they have a very involved outreach program for the poor and the elderly,” he said, adding that the church also supports programs for youths, including a Boy Scout troop. 
The congregation offers a variety of adult programs, including a Knights of Columbus group. 
“My first role is to look and see,” Hernandez said when asked if he would like to launch any new programs at Holy Cross. “We have very involved and caring parishioners.” 
He added that Albee left him a “very good church.” 
When asked about the public’s view of the Catholic Church in the Pope Francis era, Hernandez echoed Albee’s contention that the pope is a modern example of the original Catholic creed. 
“What Pope Francis is stating is really an echo of what people are trying to live as Catholics,” he said. 
“There’s a real care for others and the responsibility to help others, with what little they have they share,” he said of Catholics and his congregation in particular. 
“Moorpark is not the most humble of the humble, but these people are so generous with their time, and that’s impressed me,” he said. “They care about the youth, they care about the elderly and they care about the poor.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Faith/A_tale_of_two_priests_at_Holy_Cross.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
A tale of two priests at Holy Cross By Stephanie Bertholdo 
Monsignor Albee A changing of the guard is underway at two Catholic churches. 
Monsignor Paul Albee was welcomed as the new pastor of St. Maximilian Kolbe Catholic Church in Westlake on July 1, and Monsignor Joseph Hernandez took Albee’s place at Holy Cross Catholic Church in Moorpark. 
Here’s a look at both men: 
Monsignor Paul Albee 
Albee, the pastor at Holy Cross for 11 years, joined St. Max after the Rev. Jarlath Dolan retired. 
Albee has worked in numerous California parishes since he became a priest over 32 years ago. In his first year as a priest in 1984, he served at St. Bruno Catholic Church in Whittier, followed by three years as associate pastor at San Pancratius Catholic Church in Lakewood. 
The rotation of priests in California’s Catholic churches makes for a small world at times. Albee said the priest who replaced him at St. Bruno, the Rev. Patrick O’Dwyer, later became pastor at St. Maximilian Kolbe. Dolan joined the St. Max parish in July 2009 after O’Dwyer died. 
Monsignor Hernandez After his time at San Pancratius ended in 1988, Albee worked at the Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Los Angeles for a year. He headed a matrimonial tribunal that investigated requests for marriage annulments. 
“What I did there was review the cases write and helped the judge write his decision,” Albee said. “It was a very hot topic, and I had very limited experience.” 
In 1989, he was happy to return to a parish job as associate pastor of St. Rose of Lima in Simi Valley for seven years. 
After several short assignments in various parishes, he worked as secretary to Cardinal Roger Mahony at the Archdiocese of Los Angeles for five and half years. 
After leaving the archdiocese, Albee worked as a temporary pastor at St. Joseph the Worker in Winnetka. In 2005, he became pastor at Holy Cross in Moorpark. 
He said his experience handling a range of general church matters, coupled with some of the specialized duties he’s had over the years, prepared him for the challenge of running a community church. 
He talked briefly about Pope Francis, who by many accounts has captured the hearts of Catholics and the faithful from other denominations around the world for his generosity of spirit. 
“I think that people are very excited about the Holy Father’s ministry in the Catholic Church,” he said. “It seems to be a different approach than others, but (actually) it’s all based in Catholic traditions for centuries.” 
The tenets promoted by the pope, he said, are based on “treating people with honor and dignity.” 
“That’s always been part of Catholic theology and tradition,” Albee said. “I think it’s exciting and refreshing to hear it being reiterated in the Catholic Church.” 
He said his philosophy jibes with the pope’s in that he would never deny Eucharist to anyone, including members of the gay community. 
“To quote Pope Francis, ‘Who are we to judge?’” Albee said. 
For now, he is focused on getting to know the St. Max community. He is particularly pleased with the congregational outreach done at the church, including participation in Habitat for Humanity. 
Ordinarily, priests are moved from parish to parish every six years. But Albee, who is just shy of 60, said he expects to be the pastor at St. Max for far longer. 
“Given my age, this is the last stop of the journey,” he said. 
Monsignor Joseph Hernandez 
Hernandez, ordained as a priest in 1981, served as pastor of St. Teresa of Avila in Los Angeles and vice chancellor of the archdiocese prior to his appointment at Holy Cross in Moorpark. 
He’s not a stranger to the area. 
“My time at St. John’s Seminary (in Camarillo) was my introduction to the particular beauty of Ventura County,” he said. “I have been fortunate to have been assigned to a number of parishes in the county.” 
As a deacon, Hernandez served at Santa Clara Church &amp; Chapel in Oxnard, followed by a term there as an associate pastor. He’s also worked at Our Lady of the Assumption Catholic Church in Ventura and was pastor of St. Francis of Assisi Roman Catholic Church in Fillmore. 
Hernandez is pleased with his latest local assignment and said he’s delighted by the Holy Cross congregation’s level of service to the community and the poor. 
“I do know that they have a very involved outreach program for the poor and the elderly,” he said, adding that the church also supports programs for youths, including a Boy Scout troop. 
The congregation offers a variety of adult programs, including a Knights of Columbus group. 
“My first role is to look and see,” Hernandez said when asked if he would like to launch any new programs at Holy Cross. “We have very involved and caring parishioners.” 
He added that Albee left him a “very good church.” 
When asked about the public’s view of the Catholic Church in the Pope Francis era, Hernandez echoed Albee’s contention that the pope is a modern example of the original Catholic creed. 
“What Pope Francis is stating is really an echo of what people are trying to live as Catholics,” he said. 
“There’s a real care for others and the responsibility to help others, with what little they have they share,” he said of Catholics and his congregation in particular. 
“Moorpark is not the most humble of the humble, but these people are so generous with their time, and that’s impressed me,” he said. “They care about the youth, they care about the elderly and they care about the poor.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/38p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
