<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/109575288/wxia-sports</forum>
<forum_title>WXIA - Sports</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Gold medal winner Gunnar Bentz</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/109575288/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;11alive&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;georgia-athletes&amp;#x2f;gunnar-bentz-amazed-at-attention-gold-medal-has-brought&amp;#x2f;295122197</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Gunnar Bentz amazed at attention Gold medal has brought 11Alive interviews UGA gold medalist Gunnar Bentz Alec McQuade, WXIA 3:16 PM. EDT August 11, 2016 Jul 11, 2016; Chamblee, GA, USA; Gunnar Bentz during practice at Dynamo Swim Club. Mandatory Credit: Kevin D. Liles-USA TODAY Sports (Photo: Kevin D. Liles, Kevin D. Liles) 
RIO DE JANEIRO -- Gunnar Bentz is a Gold medal winner. 
&quot;I haven&apos;t heard that yet, but that sounds cool,&quot; he said. 
Bentz won his first Olympic Gold medal as a member of the men&apos;s 4x100-meter freestyle relay team. He did not swim in the final, but he did swam in the preliminary qualifying heat putting the U.S. in a prime position to win the Gold. Thus, he gets a medal, too. 
&quot;I haven&apos;t even seen it. But I&apos;ve touched others and they&apos;re pretty cool. They&apos;re actually pretty heavy,&quot; he said. 
&quot;Just seeing all the work pay off is really great. Being there to cheer on the finals relay to the Gold medal was incredible,&quot; he said. 
Bentz, 20, trained and swam with American stars Ryan Lochte and Michael Phelps who were both part of the relay team. He said spending so much time with them has made him close with the sport&apos;s biggest stars. It has also given him a glimpse of the spotlight they are constantly in. 
&quot;That&apos;s a little different than at a swim meet at UGA,&quot; he said. 
&quot;This is beyond anything I&apos;ve ever seen. We&apos;re not in the limelight that often, but to be (in it) here is amazing.&quot; 
Better get used to it, Bentz. Billboards around Atlanta with Bentz and his teammates who have won medals in Rio have surfaced around Atlanta congratulating the Bulldogs. 
All that attention amazes Bentz, but now that his run at the 2016 Olympics is over, he&apos;s has his sights on the next Olympics: 
The 2020 games in Tokyo. He&apos;s already getting to work. 
PHOTOS | Swimming at the Rio Olympics Loading... Hali Flickinger (USA) greets Cammille Adams (USA) after the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly final. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) greets Kyle Chalmers (AUS) after the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Adrian took third. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Kyle Chalmers (AUS) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mireia Belmonte Garcia (ESP) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Mirela Belmonte Garcia (ESP) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Josh Prenot swam to a second-place finish in the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dmitriy Balandin (KAZ) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Guangyuan Li (CHN) reacts after the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Jacob Pebley (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 200m individual medley heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200m freestyle semifinals on Monday. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) competes during the men&apos;s 200m butterfly semifinals. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates on the podium after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) with his bronze medal after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Kathleen Baker (USA) celebrates on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims in the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) and Ryan Murphy (USA) react after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) celebrates with David Plummer (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Murphy won, and Plummer placed second. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) and David Plummer (USA) pose with their medals after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) races during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) and Katie Meili (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) blows a kiss after the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) during the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel (USA) and Nathan Adrian (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m freestyle heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel of the U.S. competes in the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen of China during the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps during the 200-meter butterfly final. He won the race for his 20th career gold medal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) reacts after winning the women&apos;s 200m individual medley final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) , Katie Ledecky (USA) and Emma Mckeon (AUS) with their medals after the women&apos;s 200m freestyle final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) , Masato Sakai (JPN) and Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) with their medals after the men&apos;s 200m butterfly final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Abbey Weitzeil (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Rexford Tullius (ISV) during the men&apos;s 200m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Japan&apos;s Kosuke Hagino (JPN) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) dives in at the start of the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Daynara de Paula (BRA) reacts after winning a women&apos;s 100m butterfly heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Ziao Qiu (CHN) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) reacts after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (Hungary) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Ross Murdoch (GBR) in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Connor Jaeger (USA) and Yang Sun (CHN) after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) stretches before the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) celebrates after the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Australia team members celebrate after winning the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports USA team members Simone Manuel , Abbey Weitzeil , Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky on the podium with their medals after the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) during the women&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Corey Main (NZL) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Jimmy Feigen (USA) greets Anthony Ervin (USA) after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mitchell Larkin (AUS) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) swims during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) reacts after placing third in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) reacts after setting a world record during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) receives her bronze medal on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) and Cody Miller (USA) celebrate after the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Miller came in third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Cody Miller (USA) celebrates on the podium after placing third in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) preps for the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final, breaking her own world record in the process. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates with Leah Smith (USA) after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Leah Smith (USA) and Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Ledecky won, and Smith placed third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) leads his relay teammates to the pool before the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps preps for the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps swam the second leg for the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps helped the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team take gold. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian celebrates after anchoring the USA to victory during the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Caeleb Dressel (USA) celebrate after winning the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Nathan Adrian , Ryan Held , Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel celebrate with their gold medals after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Katie Ledecky and Leah Smith celebrate with their medals after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Camille Cheng (HKG) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen (CHN) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m individual medley heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Missy Franklin (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports of 
PHOTOS | Day 6 at Rio Olympics Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/109575288/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;11alive&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;georgia-athletes&amp;#x2f;gunnar-bentz-amazed-at-attention-gold-medal-has-brought&amp;#x2f;295122197</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1916</post_time>
<username>Alec McQuade</username>
<post>
Gunnar Bentz amazed at attention Gold medal has brought 11Alive interviews UGA gold medalist Gunnar Bentz Alec McQuade, WXIA 3:16 PM. EDT August 11, 2016 Jul 11, 2016; Chamblee, GA, USA; Gunnar Bentz during practice at Dynamo Swim Club. Mandatory Credit: Kevin D. Liles-USA TODAY Sports (Photo: Kevin D. Liles, Kevin D. Liles) 
RIO DE JANEIRO -- Gunnar Bentz is a Gold medal winner. 
&quot;I haven&apos;t heard that yet, but that sounds cool,&quot; he said. 
Bentz won his first Olympic Gold medal as a member of the men&apos;s 4x100-meter freestyle relay team. He did not swim in the final, but he did swam in the preliminary qualifying heat putting the U.S. in a prime position to win the Gold. Thus, he gets a medal, too. 
&quot;I haven&apos;t even seen it. But I&apos;ve touched others and they&apos;re pretty cool. They&apos;re actually pretty heavy,&quot; he said. 
&quot;Just seeing all the work pay off is really great. Being there to cheer on the finals relay to the Gold medal was incredible,&quot; he said. 
Bentz, 20, trained and swam with American stars Ryan Lochte and Michael Phelps who were both part of the relay team. He said spending so much time with them has made him close with the sport&apos;s biggest stars. It has also given him a glimpse of the spotlight they are constantly in. 
&quot;That&apos;s a little different than at a swim meet at UGA,&quot; he said. 
&quot;This is beyond anything I&apos;ve ever seen. We&apos;re not in the limelight that often, but to be (in it) here is amazing.&quot; 
Better get used to it, Bentz. Billboards around Atlanta with Bentz and his teammates who have won medals in Rio have surfaced around Atlanta congratulating the Bulldogs. 
All that attention amazes Bentz, but now that his run at the 2016 Olympics is over, he&apos;s has his sights on the next Olympics: 
The 2020 games in Tokyo. He&apos;s already getting to work. 
PHOTOS | Swimming at the Rio Olympics Loading... Hali Flickinger (USA) greets Cammille Adams (USA) after the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly final. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) greets Kyle Chalmers (AUS) after the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Adrian took third. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Kyle Chalmers (AUS) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mireia Belmonte Garcia (ESP) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Mirela Belmonte Garcia (ESP) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Josh Prenot swam to a second-place finish in the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dmitriy Balandin (KAZ) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Guangyuan Li (CHN) reacts after the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Jacob Pebley (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 200m individual medley heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200m freestyle semifinals on Monday. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) competes during the men&apos;s 200m butterfly semifinals. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates on the podium after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) with his bronze medal after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Kathleen Baker (USA) celebrates on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims in the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) and Ryan Murphy (USA) react after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) celebrates with David Plummer (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Murphy won, and Plummer placed second. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) and David Plummer (USA) pose with their medals after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) races during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) and Katie Meili (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) blows a kiss after the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) during the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel (USA) and Nathan Adrian (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m freestyle heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel of the U.S. competes in the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen of China during the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps during the 200-meter butterfly final. He won the race for his 20th career gold medal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) reacts after winning the women&apos;s 200m individual medley final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) , Katie Ledecky (USA) and Emma Mckeon (AUS) with their medals after the women&apos;s 200m freestyle final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) , Masato Sakai (JPN) and Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) with their medals after the men&apos;s 200m butterfly final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Abbey Weitzeil (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Rexford Tullius (ISV) during the men&apos;s 200m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Japan&apos;s Kosuke Hagino (JPN) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) dives in at the start of the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Daynara de Paula (BRA) reacts after winning a women&apos;s 100m butterfly heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Ziao Qiu (CHN) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) reacts after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (Hungary) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Ross Murdoch (GBR) in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Connor Jaeger (USA) and Yang Sun (CHN) after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) stretches before the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) celebrates after the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Australia team members celebrate after winning the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports USA team members Simone Manuel , Abbey Weitzeil , Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky on the podium with their medals after the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) during the women&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Corey Main (NZL) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Jimmy Feigen (USA) greets Anthony Ervin (USA) after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mitchell Larkin (AUS) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) swims during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) reacts after placing third in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) reacts after setting a world record during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) receives her bronze medal on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) and Cody Miller (USA) celebrate after the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Miller came in third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Cody Miller (USA) celebrates on the podium after placing third in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) preps for the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final, breaking her own world record in the process. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates with Leah Smith (USA) after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Leah Smith (USA) and Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Ledecky won, and Smith placed third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) leads his relay teammates to the pool before the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps preps for the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps swam the second leg for the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps helped the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team take gold. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian celebrates after anchoring the USA to victory during the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Caeleb Dressel (USA) celebrate after winning the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Nathan Adrian , Ryan Held , Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel celebrate with their gold medals after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Katie Ledecky and Leah Smith celebrate with their medals after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Camille Cheng (HKG) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen (CHN) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m individual medley heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Missy Franklin (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports of 
PHOTOS | Day 6 at Rio Olympics Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.11alive.com/photo/2016/08/11/USATSI_9381543_1470941948367_5083017_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
