<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.redwoodfallsgazette.com/lifestyle/family?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Family - Redwood Falls Gazette</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Missionaries see new attitude toward Christianity in Europe, Middle East</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.redwoodfallsgazette.com/news/20160812/missionaries-see-new-attitude-toward-christianity-in-europe-middle-east</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Missionaries see new attitude toward Christianity in Europe, Middle East Europe has become an increasingly more open-minded environment when it comes to faith matters, and for Jerry and Shelly Kragt that is a good thing. Comment Posted Aug. 12, 2016 at 12:01 AM By Troy KrauseRedwood Gazette Posted Aug. 12, 2016 at 12:01 AM Changes are taking place in Europe, and, for some, those changes have provided an opportunity to share what they believe. Europe has become an increasingly more open-minded environment when it comes to faith matters, and for Jerry and Shelly Kragt that is a good thing. The couple, whose roots are in Minnesota, are currently serving as the regional directors for the missionary work of the Christian and Missionary Alliance in Europe and the Middle East. While the initial thought may be that those two global regions have little to do with each other, especially when it comes to religious matters, the Kragts and the missionaries they are serving with are seeing the influx of Middle Eastern culture into Europe due to the mass exodus of people from that region – especially from nations like Syria. Those who come from the Middle East bring with them their culture, including their belief system, which means an increased influence from the Islamic faith. What the Kragts are seeing as that influence becomes more pervasive is a younger generation who are much more open minded and who are searching for answers. Many of them, when asked by those of Middle Eastern descent, what they believe to be true are studying the Bible, and more of them are opening their minds to the truths of the good news Christian missionaries are sharing. Jerry and Shelly Kragt help coordinate the ministry work of 120 workers in Europe and the Middle East, with varied efforts from working with established churches to those who are serving in areas where just being a Christian and proclaiming it can be dangerous. Threats of terrorism compounded by actual acts of violence that have been perpetrated in Europe have created an environment of fear among some Europeans, and that fear is pushing them away from atheism and back to the roots of the Christian faith that run deep in Europe. Jerry and Shelly Kragt learned firsthand about the atheism of Europe when they first started serving as missionaries. What began in West Germany at an international church soon led them east into a nation that had almost completely done away with God. The Kragts worked in East Germany for more than a decade helping to open doors and minds in a nation that was decimated in many ways by the tenets of communism. “We saw a huge need there and began trying to meet it,” said Jerry, adding offering hope in a nation that had lost so much of it slowly began to result in change. The Kragts surmised that part of the reason for a move away from the faith in Europe had to do with the fact that so many faithful Europeans left for the United States and took that faith with them. Page 2 of 2 - People in Europe, especially Germany, became very disillusioned after two world wars were fought on their land. “Younger people are looking for something different, and as a result are rediscovering faith,” said Shelly, adding it is exciting to see some of the changes that have taken place. The Syrian refugee influx has created lots of concern in Europe, said Jerry, but he said what people are discovering is that, for the most part, these are just people like them looking for a better life for them and their families. Living in Kandern, Germany, the Kragts oversee the efforts of the church in the two regions and are enjoying the opportunity to answer the call God placed on their hearts to go and tell others about the faith they hold profess. The Kragts said short-term missions opportunities exist in Europe and the Middle East. Changes are happening in areas where some believed there never would, and the Kragts know that is all because God is still at work. By Troy Krause
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.redwoodfallsgazette.com/news/20160812/missionaries-see-new-attitude-toward-christianity-in-europe-middle-east</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0501</post_time>
<username>Troy Krause Redwood Gazette</username>
<post>
Missionaries see new attitude toward Christianity in Europe, Middle East Europe has become an increasingly more open-minded environment when it comes to faith matters, and for Jerry and Shelly Kragt that is a good thing. Comment Posted Aug. 12, 2016 at 12:01 AM By Troy KrauseRedwood Gazette Posted Aug. 12, 2016 at 12:01 AM Changes are taking place in Europe, and, for some, those changes have provided an opportunity to share what they believe. Europe has become an increasingly more open-minded environment when it comes to faith matters, and for Jerry and Shelly Kragt that is a good thing. The couple, whose roots are in Minnesota, are currently serving as the regional directors for the missionary work of the Christian and Missionary Alliance in Europe and the Middle East. While the initial thought may be that those two global regions have little to do with each other, especially when it comes to religious matters, the Kragts and the missionaries they are serving with are seeing the influx of Middle Eastern culture into Europe due to the mass exodus of people from that region – especially from nations like Syria. Those who come from the Middle East bring with them their culture, including their belief system, which means an increased influence from the Islamic faith. What the Kragts are seeing as that influence becomes more pervasive is a younger generation who are much more open minded and who are searching for answers. Many of them, when asked by those of Middle Eastern descent, what they believe to be true are studying the Bible, and more of them are opening their minds to the truths of the good news Christian missionaries are sharing. Jerry and Shelly Kragt help coordinate the ministry work of 120 workers in Europe and the Middle East, with varied efforts from working with established churches to those who are serving in areas where just being a Christian and proclaiming it can be dangerous. Threats of terrorism compounded by actual acts of violence that have been perpetrated in Europe have created an environment of fear among some Europeans, and that fear is pushing them away from atheism and back to the roots of the Christian faith that run deep in Europe. Jerry and Shelly Kragt learned firsthand about the atheism of Europe when they first started serving as missionaries. What began in West Germany at an international church soon led them east into a nation that had almost completely done away with God. The Kragts worked in East Germany for more than a decade helping to open doors and minds in a nation that was decimated in many ways by the tenets of communism. “We saw a huge need there and began trying to meet it,” said Jerry, adding offering hope in a nation that had lost so much of it slowly began to result in change. The Kragts surmised that part of the reason for a move away from the faith in Europe had to do with the fact that so many faithful Europeans left for the United States and took that faith with them. Page 2 of 2 - People in Europe, especially Germany, became very disillusioned after two world wars were fought on their land. “Younger people are looking for something different, and as a result are rediscovering faith,” said Shelly, adding it is exciting to see some of the changes that have taken place. The Syrian refugee influx has created lots of concern in Europe, said Jerry, but he said what people are discovering is that, for the most part, these are just people like them looking for a better life for them and their families. Living in Kandern, Germany, the Kragts oversee the efforts of the church in the two regions and are enjoying the opportunity to answer the call God placed on their hearts to go and tell others about the faith they hold profess. The Kragts said short-term missions opportunities exist in Europe and the Middle East. Changes are happening in areas where some believed there never would, and the Kragts know that is all because God is still at work. By Troy Krause
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.redwoodfallsgazette.com/storyimage/MN/20160812/NEWS/160819841/AR/0/AR-160819841.jpg</main_image>
</document>
