<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://feeds.feedburner.com/HawaiiWarriorWorldVolleyshots#</forum>
<forum_title>Hawaii Warrior World » Volleyshots</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Thursday check-in, US men over Brazil in 4</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://hawaiiwarriorworld.com/volleyshots/thursday-check-in-4/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Thursday check-in, US men over Brazil in 4 by Cindy Luis on August 11, 2016 
Forgot to mention that former all-MPSF libero Vernon Podlewski was at yesterday’s afternoon session. Gave a very inspirational talk on the importance of defense and communication. Nice guy. Real job is as a longshoreman. still plays volleyball 
A couple of points of emphasis this week have been covering tip shots and serving areas. Players are tracking how accurate their serves are when told to serve certain areas. 
One difference this year is it is a lot louder. Players seem to be more vocal when calling for the balls or helping setters know exactly where they are. Something that Berg has pushed. 
Discussion on previous thread was about Burns. She hasn’t been feeling well and believe she’s been to the doctor. She’s also missed due to summer school. Koelsch missed most of Wednesday afternoon because of class. Showed up for maybe the last 20 minutes. 
They’ve already put in a wrinkle in the offense with inside slides. 
Been very impressed with Iosia. she is connecting well with Taylor, very accurate on the back sets As I mentioned on the Sports Animals Wednesday, her hands are very similar to Kamana’o’s. And Ah Mow-Santos. And Ka’apuni. Hall called Iosia’s hands world class. 
Back after afternoon practice. 
{ 9 comments… read them below or add one } 1 Maverick August 11, 2016 at 10:20 am 
Cindy, I agree with your post on the previous thread about the 2011 squad. I forgot how good they were because of the season-ending loss to Alex Jupiter-led USC. Had UH gotten a more favorable bracket, they could have gone to the final four. Was Danielson’s senior year and Croson impressed as a freshman. 
On another note, hawaiiathletics.com has been redesigned. Cleaner look IMO. 
Finally, Cindy do you have any comments on Sibley or Smith, the other two freshmen? Just wondering how they are looking. Can’t expect too much, but an inquiring mind would like to know. 2 blunite August 11, 2016 at 12:05 pm 
Cindy, 
Curious about their serving. Besides Nikki and Tayler has anyone else developed an “awesome” serve? Having several “wicked” serves in the lineup bodes well for quick points and disrupting the other team’s offense. 3 Cindy Luis August 11, 2016 at 3:45 pm 
saw the redesign this morning. Thought it looked clean as well. They’re primarily doing reps so hard to gauge. but I did think Sibley looked good on blocking drills and has a hard snap from behind 3-meters Smith has a solid platform. Quite the crowd at DS 4 Cindy Luis August 11, 2016 at 3:51 pm 
4. the serving reps aren’t meant to showcase ‘wicked’ serves. The goal is to serve consistently in target areas. It’s only Day 3 so pretty basic stuff. 
And to update Burns. she is not cleared to practice but is shagging balls and stuff. 5 Warriorfan August 11, 2016 at 5:41 pm 
US men just beat Brazil , Erik had some amazing saves,good thing Coach shoji stayed and watched , it aint over till hossana sings!!! 6 Cindy Luis August 11, 2016 at 5:42 pm 
Great win by U.S. 3-1 over Brazil. Had the match on my laptop, coaches watched the final points while team stretched out. 7 Cindy Luis August 11, 2016 at 5:44 pm 
agree about Shoji’s match. Was there a question that Dave would not stay? practice finished with a mini scrimmage. Koelsch played both OH and S in a modified 6-2 with Higgins on one side. Castillo played middle on the other side. Ross used as an OH and DS. Sibley looked pretty good hitting on left and right. Taylor also hit right and left as per usual rotation. 8 mauna August 11, 2016 at 7:24 pm 
The last day of Summer 2 is tomorrow. 
Wondering why they waited until tomorrow for the doc to evaluate Annie’s status. That’s 2 days past after getting injured. 9 mauna August 11, 2016 at 7:29 pm 
Great to hear about Sibley doing so well. Competition for the second LS spot should fare better than everyone thought. 
Leave a Comment By participating in online discussions you acknowledge that you have agreed to the Star-Advertiser&apos;s TERMS OF SERVICE . An insightful discussion of ideas and viewpoints is encouraged, but comments must be civil and in good taste, with no personal attacks. If your comments are inappropriate, you may be banned from posting. To report comments that you believe do not follow our guidelines, email hawaiiwarriorworld@staradvertiser.com. 
Name *
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://hawaiiwarriorworld.com/volleyshots/thursday-check-in-4/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1955</post_time>
<username>Cindy Luis</username>
<post>
Thursday check-in, US men over Brazil in 4 by Cindy Luis on August 11, 2016 
Forgot to mention that former all-MPSF libero Vernon Podlewski was at yesterday’s afternoon session. Gave a very inspirational talk on the importance of defense and communication. Nice guy. Real job is as a longshoreman. still plays volleyball 
A couple of points of emphasis this week have been covering tip shots and serving areas. Players are tracking how accurate their serves are when told to serve certain areas. 
One difference this year is it is a lot louder. Players seem to be more vocal when calling for the balls or helping setters know exactly where they are. Something that Berg has pushed. 
Discussion on previous thread was about Burns. She hasn’t been feeling well and believe she’s been to the doctor. She’s also missed due to summer school. Koelsch missed most of Wednesday afternoon because of class. Showed up for maybe the last 20 minutes. 
They’ve already put in a wrinkle in the offense with inside slides. 
Been very impressed with Iosia. she is connecting well with Taylor, very accurate on the back sets As I mentioned on the Sports Animals Wednesday, her hands are very similar to Kamana’o’s. And Ah Mow-Santos. And Ka’apuni. Hall called Iosia’s hands world class. 
Back after afternoon practice. 
{ 9 comments… read them below or add one } 1 Maverick August 11, 2016 at 10:20 am 
Cindy, I agree with your post on the previous thread about the 2011 squad. I forgot how good they were because of the season-ending loss to Alex Jupiter-led USC. Had UH gotten a more favorable bracket, they could have gone to the final four. Was Danielson’s senior year and Croson impressed as a freshman. 
On another note, hawaiiathletics.com has been redesigned. Cleaner look IMO. 
Finally, Cindy do you have any comments on Sibley or Smith, the other two freshmen? Just wondering how they are looking. Can’t expect too much, but an inquiring mind would like to know. 2 blunite August 11, 2016 at 12:05 pm 
Cindy, 
Curious about their serving. Besides Nikki and Tayler has anyone else developed an “awesome” serve? Having several “wicked” serves in the lineup bodes well for quick points and disrupting the other team’s offense. 3 Cindy Luis August 11, 2016 at 3:45 pm 
saw the redesign this morning. Thought it looked clean as well. They’re primarily doing reps so hard to gauge. but I did think Sibley looked good on blocking drills and has a hard snap from behind 3-meters Smith has a solid platform. Quite the crowd at DS 4 Cindy Luis August 11, 2016 at 3:51 pm 
4. the serving reps aren’t meant to showcase ‘wicked’ serves. The goal is to serve consistently in target areas. It’s only Day 3 so pretty basic stuff. 
And to update Burns. she is not cleared to practice but is shagging balls and stuff. 5 Warriorfan August 11, 2016 at 5:41 pm 
US men just beat Brazil , Erik had some amazing saves,good thing Coach shoji stayed and watched , it aint over till hossana sings!!! 6 Cindy Luis August 11, 2016 at 5:42 pm 
Great win by U.S. 3-1 over Brazil. Had the match on my laptop, coaches watched the final points while team stretched out. 7 Cindy Luis August 11, 2016 at 5:44 pm 
agree about Shoji’s match. Was there a question that Dave would not stay? practice finished with a mini scrimmage. Koelsch played both OH and S in a modified 6-2 with Higgins on one side. Castillo played middle on the other side. Ross used as an OH and DS. Sibley looked pretty good hitting on left and right. Taylor also hit right and left as per usual rotation. 8 mauna August 11, 2016 at 7:24 pm 
The last day of Summer 2 is tomorrow. 
Wondering why they waited until tomorrow for the doc to evaluate Annie’s status. That’s 2 days past after getting injured. 9 mauna August 11, 2016 at 7:29 pm 
Great to hear about Sibley doing so well. Competition for the second LS spot should fare better than everyone thought. 
Leave a Comment By participating in online discussions you acknowledge that you have agreed to the Star-Advertiser&apos;s TERMS OF SERVICE . An insightful discussion of ideas and viewpoints is encouraged, but comments must be civil and in good taste, with no personal attacks. If your comments are inappropriate, you may be banned from posting. To report comments that you believe do not follow our guidelines, email hawaiiwarriorworld@staradvertiser.com. 
Name *
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
