<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://cybergrass.com/rss.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Cybergrass Bluegrass Music News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Flatt Lonesome Receives Dove Award Nomination, Multiple IBMA Nominations</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://cybergrass.com/node/5479</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Flatt Lonesome Receives Dove Award Nomination, Multiple IBMA Nominations   Fri, 08/12/2016 - 00:36   Nashville, TN -- Flatt Lonesome has been overwhelmed from wide-spread industry recognition with the announcement of several awards nominations recently, including FIVE International Bluegrass Music Association (IBMA) nominations and their FIRST EVER Dove Award nomination. 
The IBMA Award nominees were announced last month during a press conference in Nashville, Tennessee and the band was nominated for Entertainer of the Year, Vocal Group of the Year, Album of the Year for Runaway Train (Mountain Home Music), Song of the Year for &quot;You&apos;re The One&quot; and Gospel Recorded Performance for &quot;In The Heat Of The Fire.&quot; The Gospel Music Association announced their Dove Award nominees earlier today and included &quot;In The Heat Of The Fire&quot; in the Bluegrass Recorded Song of the Year category. 
News of the Dove Award nomination was a welcome surprise for the band and especially for Kelsi Harrigill, who wrote &quot;In The Heat Of The Fire&quot; and performs with the band. &quot;I am so thankful for this nomination alongside such great people whom I love and respect. God gave me this song during the most difficult time in my life and I owe all I have to Him. Thank you all!&quot; 
Watch Flatt Lonesome perform &quot;In The Heat Of The Fire&quot; 
The IBMA Awards will take place on September 29th in Raleigh, North Carolina and the Dove Awards will take place on October 11th in Nashville, Tennessee. For more information, please visit www.IBMA.org and www.DoveAwards.com . 
Since their debut in 2011, Flatt Lonesome has enjoyed a nearly unprecedented journey that has placed them among bluegrass music&apos;s elite. Bluegrass Today calls Flatt Lonesome &quot;the sort of band bluegrass needs right now&quot; and says their brand of original bluegrass is &quot;some of the freshest our genre has been offered in a while.&quot; Stellar picking and heartfelt songs centered around beautiful sibling harmony have made Flatt Lonesome a hit among bluegrass fans both young and old and their vibrant, youthful spirit, with careful respect toward tradition, has earned the praise of peers twice their age. Flatt Lonesome&apos;s whirlwind ride has included being awarded Emerging Artists of the Year by the International Bluegrass Music Association (IBMA) in 2014, a trio of successful albums producing chart topping songs, airplay on radio stations around the world, performances at some of the largest bluegrass events on the continent, and regular guest appearances on the hallowed stage of the Grand Ole Opry. Tags:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://cybergrass.com/node/5479</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0436</post_time>
<username>BMNN</username>
<post>
Flatt Lonesome Receives Dove Award Nomination, Multiple IBMA Nominations   Fri, 08/12/2016 - 00:36   Nashville, TN -- Flatt Lonesome has been overwhelmed from wide-spread industry recognition with the announcement of several awards nominations recently, including FIVE International Bluegrass Music Association (IBMA) nominations and their FIRST EVER Dove Award nomination. 
The IBMA Award nominees were announced last month during a press conference in Nashville, Tennessee and the band was nominated for Entertainer of the Year, Vocal Group of the Year, Album of the Year for Runaway Train (Mountain Home Music), Song of the Year for &quot;You&apos;re The One&quot; and Gospel Recorded Performance for &quot;In The Heat Of The Fire.&quot; The Gospel Music Association announced their Dove Award nominees earlier today and included &quot;In The Heat Of The Fire&quot; in the Bluegrass Recorded Song of the Year category. 
News of the Dove Award nomination was a welcome surprise for the band and especially for Kelsi Harrigill, who wrote &quot;In The Heat Of The Fire&quot; and performs with the band. &quot;I am so thankful for this nomination alongside such great people whom I love and respect. God gave me this song during the most difficult time in my life and I owe all I have to Him. Thank you all!&quot; 
Watch Flatt Lonesome perform &quot;In The Heat Of The Fire&quot; 
The IBMA Awards will take place on September 29th in Raleigh, North Carolina and the Dove Awards will take place on October 11th in Nashville, Tennessee. For more information, please visit www.IBMA.org and www.DoveAwards.com . 
Since their debut in 2011, Flatt Lonesome has enjoyed a nearly unprecedented journey that has placed them among bluegrass music&apos;s elite. Bluegrass Today calls Flatt Lonesome &quot;the sort of band bluegrass needs right now&quot; and says their brand of original bluegrass is &quot;some of the freshest our genre has been offered in a while.&quot; Stellar picking and heartfelt songs centered around beautiful sibling harmony have made Flatt Lonesome a hit among bluegrass fans both young and old and their vibrant, youthful spirit, with careful respect toward tradition, has earned the praise of peers twice their age. Flatt Lonesome&apos;s whirlwind ride has included being awarded Emerging Artists of the Year by the International Bluegrass Music Association (IBMA) in 2014, a trio of successful albums producing chart topping songs, airplay on radio stations around the world, performances at some of the largest bluegrass events on the continent, and regular guest appearances on the hallowed stage of the Grand Ole Opry. Tags:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
