<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Art’s playing a part in supporting program | Central Western Daily</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.centralwesterndaily.com.au/story/4093070/arts-playing-a-part-in-supporting-program/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Cancer Care West: Art’s playing a part in supporting program JAN SAVAGE 12 Aug 2016, 3:09 p.m. Cancer Care NSW commenced their collection five years ago WORTH HANGING ON TO: Lita Mathews and Jan Savage with yet another donated piece for the Western Care Lodge&apos;s already impressive collection of artworks. Photo: JUDE KEOGH 0810jklodge3 
Cancer Care Western NSW have again been donated another large artwork to add to their large display and collection of original art works. 
The Rosebank Gallery in Millthorpe which is operated by well-known artist Jenny Beach has provided the painting which is a large work of art, which will contribute an additional work of value to the existing art collection. 
The works are displayed at Western Care Lodge and are curated by Jan Parsons and Catherine Cheney as part of the boards’ enterprising action in supporting arts within a health program – which addresses the positive effect of large well executed art works, that provide a visual display of colour and imagination. 
Art works are used to support ill people in many facilities that include Orange Health Service, Westmead Hospital, The McCallum Centre in Melbourne as well as many other hospitals nationally and world wide. 
Cancer Care NSW commenced their collection five years ago and have displayed the works in all corridors, rooms and community rooms. 
Each piece is professionally displayed on tracking and is hung to a standard that reflects the work of the participating artists. 
Many of the works featured are from Ted Lewis, Loretta Blake, Rhonda Campbell, Sita Cooray and Jan Parsons along with many well known artists, including those from Mudgee. 
The works are collated and displayed on a continual basis, and reflect the high standard set by the art team. 
With so much variety, the guests and staff have enjoyed and continue to enjoy the many aspects of the variety of works, and are amazed at the broad based and dynamic art collection that has been amassed. 
The latest addition is from the collection by artist Jenny Beach, and features an amazing style of work, from the gallery in Millthorpe at Rosebank guest house which features ongoing displays of both photography and art works, including a weekend exhibition. 
The art collection at Western Care Lodge also consists of sculptural items that compliment and add interest for the guests. 
Guests will welcome this valuable piece of art. 
Cancer Care Western NSW registered as a charity in 2007 when fundraising for the construction of Western Care Lodge started. The Lodge was completed in June 2011 at a cost of $4 million. The government provided $1.3 million, the generous support of the communities of the central west raised the rest of the funds. Latest News 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.centralwesterndaily.com.au/story/4093070/arts-playing-a-part-in-supporting-program/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Jan Savage</username>
<post>
Cancer Care West: Art’s playing a part in supporting program JAN SAVAGE 12 Aug 2016, 3:09 p.m. Cancer Care NSW commenced their collection five years ago WORTH HANGING ON TO: Lita Mathews and Jan Savage with yet another donated piece for the Western Care Lodge&apos;s already impressive collection of artworks. Photo: JUDE KEOGH 0810jklodge3 
Cancer Care Western NSW have again been donated another large artwork to add to their large display and collection of original art works. 
The Rosebank Gallery in Millthorpe which is operated by well-known artist Jenny Beach has provided the painting which is a large work of art, which will contribute an additional work of value to the existing art collection. 
The works are displayed at Western Care Lodge and are curated by Jan Parsons and Catherine Cheney as part of the boards’ enterprising action in supporting arts within a health program – which addresses the positive effect of large well executed art works, that provide a visual display of colour and imagination. 
Art works are used to support ill people in many facilities that include Orange Health Service, Westmead Hospital, The McCallum Centre in Melbourne as well as many other hospitals nationally and world wide. 
Cancer Care NSW commenced their collection five years ago and have displayed the works in all corridors, rooms and community rooms. 
Each piece is professionally displayed on tracking and is hung to a standard that reflects the work of the participating artists. 
Many of the works featured are from Ted Lewis, Loretta Blake, Rhonda Campbell, Sita Cooray and Jan Parsons along with many well known artists, including those from Mudgee. 
The works are collated and displayed on a continual basis, and reflect the high standard set by the art team. 
With so much variety, the guests and staff have enjoyed and continue to enjoy the many aspects of the variety of works, and are amazed at the broad based and dynamic art collection that has been amassed. 
The latest addition is from the collection by artist Jenny Beach, and features an amazing style of work, from the gallery in Millthorpe at Rosebank guest house which features ongoing displays of both photography and art works, including a weekend exhibition. 
The art collection at Western Care Lodge also consists of sculptural items that compliment and add interest for the guests. 
Guests will welcome this valuable piece of art. 
Cancer Care Western NSW registered as a charity in 2007 when fundraising for the construction of Western Care Lodge started. The Lodge was completed in June 2011 at a cost of $4 million. The government provided $1.3 million, the generous support of the communities of the central west raised the rest of the funds. Latest News 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://nnimgt-a.akamaihd.net/transform/v1/crop/frm/35WVUfxfAJ5ewz9B7wdJW9B/705c4873-f031-4625-b91d-3294a85b1356.JPG/r199_285_4077_2476_w1200_h678_fmax.jpg</main_image>
</document>
