<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Cast of ‘Peter Pan’ prequel shines on Simi Valley stage</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/On_The_Town/Cast_of__Peter_Pan_prequel_shines_on_Simi_Valley_s.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Cast of ‘Peter Pan’ prequel shines on Simi Valley stage PLAY REVIEW /// ‘Peter and the Starcatcher’ By Cary Ginell 
AHOY, MATEYS— The cast of “Peter and the Starchaser” includes, from left, Jared Price, Ryan Lefton, John Dantona, Katherine Bottoms, Kyle Harrington, Austin Miller and John Manahan. Courtesy of Mario Stephen Acosta Ever wonder how Peter Pan got to Neverland? James W. Barrie’s beloved 1904 novel, “Peter and Wendy,” immortalized the ageless Pan, who famously battled pirates, befriended Wendy, and refused to grow up. In 2012, playwright Rick Elice (“Jersey Boys,” “The Addams Family”) wrote the Tony Award-winning “Peter and the Starcatcher,” adapted from humorist Dave Barry and Ridley Pearson’s prequel to the Peter Pan stories. 
The play, on stage at the Simi Valley Cultural Arts Center, is a Mark Twain-like tale of adventure that explains the origins of each of the “Peter Pan” characters. 
Actors’ Repertory Theatre of Simi has assembled a first-rate cast in what is simply the funniest and most inventive stage play we’ve seen this year. Director Sean Harrington crafted Elice’s book into what can only be described as “scripted improv,” utilizing an ensemble of 12 uber-talented actors who employ ingenious props, pantomime and “special” effects to tell the story. 
The play opens as two ships, the Wasp and the Neverland, leave England for the remote kingdom of Rundoon to deliver a steamer trunk of magical “star stuff.” Aboard the Wasp are “star-catcher” Lord Aster, his precocious daughter, Molly, and her governess, Mrs. Brumbake. To protect the star stuff, a decoy trunk is loaded onto the Neverland, but its corrupt captain, Bill Slank, swaps the trunks. When pirates, led by the evil Black Stache, take over the Wasp, they realize the ship’s trunk is filled with sand and give chase to the Neverland. 
The cast also serves as its own supporting cast, each in a variety of ensemble roles. Ryan Lefton plays a grown-up-hating orphan with no name who ultimately becomes Peter Pan after being enslaved by Slank. Peter develops a friendship with Molly, an independent, high-spirited 13-year-old played by Katherine Bottoms. 
Lefton and Bottoms are marvelous together, bringing to mind Twain’s Tom Sawyer and Becky Thatcher; both play their parts with youthful exuberance and charm. Bottoms is brilliant when she communicates with her father in the “Dodo” and “Norse Code” nonsense languages. 
Austin Robert Miller plays famed British explorer Robert Falcon Scott, friend of the stalwart, up-standing Lord Aster, played with steely grace by William Carmichael. Will Shupe is terrific as Black Stache, the malaprop spouting pirate who will become Captain Hook. Stache and his adjutant, Smee, played by Nick Ferguson, are like the Two Stooges, and are riotously funny physical opposites, bellowing spoonerisms as they connive to retrieve the trunk. 
Evan Smith, in minimal drag consisting of lipstick and a foppish hat, plays Mrs. Brumbake, a character in the British tradition known as the “pantomime dame” (exemplified by the ever-popular Dame Edna Everage). 
Andy Mattick is the boorish, flatulent sailor Alf, who takes a shine to her. John Manahan turns in an outrageously comical performance as Slank, while Jared Price (Prentiss) and Kyle Harrington (Ted) play Peter’s fellow orphans, destined to become Neverland’s Lost Boys. 
The versatile John Dantona plays a variety of character roles, from a sadistic British schoolmaster to Fighting Prawn, the chief of the island-bound Mollusks, who speaks in Italian cooking terms. 
The dialogue is sprinkled with uproarious verbal anachronisms that invoke Ayn Rand, Michael Jackson and, of course, Donald Trump. Inventive pantomime and props are used to simulate everything from ocean waves to a vicious crocodile. 
Matthew Park plays keyboard and percussion on Wayne Barker’s wonderful songs, highlighted by “Star Stuff,” performed by the cast, garishly outfitted by costumer Cyndi Caldwell as motley mermaids. Becky Castells created the ingenious choreography and fight sequences. 
“Peter and the Starcatcher” runs through Aug. 28 at 3050 Los Angeles Ave., Simi Valley. For tickets, call (805) 583-7900 or visit www.simi-arts.org .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/On_The_Town/Cast_of__Peter_Pan_prequel_shines_on_Simi_Valley_s.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
Cast of ‘Peter Pan’ prequel shines on Simi Valley stage PLAY REVIEW /// ‘Peter and the Starcatcher’ By Cary Ginell 
AHOY, MATEYS— The cast of “Peter and the Starchaser” includes, from left, Jared Price, Ryan Lefton, John Dantona, Katherine Bottoms, Kyle Harrington, Austin Miller and John Manahan. Courtesy of Mario Stephen Acosta Ever wonder how Peter Pan got to Neverland? James W. Barrie’s beloved 1904 novel, “Peter and Wendy,” immortalized the ageless Pan, who famously battled pirates, befriended Wendy, and refused to grow up. In 2012, playwright Rick Elice (“Jersey Boys,” “The Addams Family”) wrote the Tony Award-winning “Peter and the Starcatcher,” adapted from humorist Dave Barry and Ridley Pearson’s prequel to the Peter Pan stories. 
The play, on stage at the Simi Valley Cultural Arts Center, is a Mark Twain-like tale of adventure that explains the origins of each of the “Peter Pan” characters. 
Actors’ Repertory Theatre of Simi has assembled a first-rate cast in what is simply the funniest and most inventive stage play we’ve seen this year. Director Sean Harrington crafted Elice’s book into what can only be described as “scripted improv,” utilizing an ensemble of 12 uber-talented actors who employ ingenious props, pantomime and “special” effects to tell the story. 
The play opens as two ships, the Wasp and the Neverland, leave England for the remote kingdom of Rundoon to deliver a steamer trunk of magical “star stuff.” Aboard the Wasp are “star-catcher” Lord Aster, his precocious daughter, Molly, and her governess, Mrs. Brumbake. To protect the star stuff, a decoy trunk is loaded onto the Neverland, but its corrupt captain, Bill Slank, swaps the trunks. When pirates, led by the evil Black Stache, take over the Wasp, they realize the ship’s trunk is filled with sand and give chase to the Neverland. 
The cast also serves as its own supporting cast, each in a variety of ensemble roles. Ryan Lefton plays a grown-up-hating orphan with no name who ultimately becomes Peter Pan after being enslaved by Slank. Peter develops a friendship with Molly, an independent, high-spirited 13-year-old played by Katherine Bottoms. 
Lefton and Bottoms are marvelous together, bringing to mind Twain’s Tom Sawyer and Becky Thatcher; both play their parts with youthful exuberance and charm. Bottoms is brilliant when she communicates with her father in the “Dodo” and “Norse Code” nonsense languages. 
Austin Robert Miller plays famed British explorer Robert Falcon Scott, friend of the stalwart, up-standing Lord Aster, played with steely grace by William Carmichael. Will Shupe is terrific as Black Stache, the malaprop spouting pirate who will become Captain Hook. Stache and his adjutant, Smee, played by Nick Ferguson, are like the Two Stooges, and are riotously funny physical opposites, bellowing spoonerisms as they connive to retrieve the trunk. 
Evan Smith, in minimal drag consisting of lipstick and a foppish hat, plays Mrs. Brumbake, a character in the British tradition known as the “pantomime dame” (exemplified by the ever-popular Dame Edna Everage). 
Andy Mattick is the boorish, flatulent sailor Alf, who takes a shine to her. John Manahan turns in an outrageously comical performance as Slank, while Jared Price (Prentiss) and Kyle Harrington (Ted) play Peter’s fellow orphans, destined to become Neverland’s Lost Boys. 
The versatile John Dantona plays a variety of character roles, from a sadistic British schoolmaster to Fighting Prawn, the chief of the island-bound Mollusks, who speaks in Italian cooking terms. 
The dialogue is sprinkled with uproarious verbal anachronisms that invoke Ayn Rand, Michael Jackson and, of course, Donald Trump. Inventive pantomime and props are used to simulate everything from ocean waves to a vicious crocodile. 
Matthew Park plays keyboard and percussion on Wayne Barker’s wonderful songs, highlighted by “Star Stuff,” performed by the cast, garishly outfitted by costumer Cyndi Caldwell as motley mermaids. Becky Castells created the ingenious choreography and fight sequences. 
“Peter and the Starcatcher” runs through Aug. 28 at 3050 Los Angeles Ave., Simi Valley. For tickets, call (805) 583-7900 or visit www.simi-arts.org .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/31p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
