<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.postandcourier.com/apps/pbcs.dll/section?Category=PC1608&amp;template=rss&amp;mime=XML</forum>
<forum_title>Obituaries</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Deaths Summary for Friday, August 12, 2016</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.postandcourier.com/20160812/160819854/deaths-summary-for-friday-august-12-2016&amp;ampsource=RSS</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Charleston County BROWN, Octavia W., 71, of Charleston, widow of Earl Brown, died Thursday. Arrangements by Pasley’s Mortuary.
BUTLER, Herbert, of Charleston died July 13. Arrangements by Smith-McNeal’s Downtown Chapel.
HOLMES, Bessie Allen, 59, of Mount Pleasant, a teacher with Burke High School, died Thursday. Arrangements by Steven Funeral Home of St. George.
WHITE, Moses, 89, of Charleston, husband of Thelma H. White, died Wednesday. Arrangements by Fielding Home for Funerals.
Berkeley County BROWN, Esther Lewis Cumbee, 90, of Shulerville, a retired postmaster, former owner and operator of Brown’s Grocery, first married to the late Junior Cumbee and widow of Stansell V. Brown, died Thursday. Arrangements by Dial-Murray Funeral Home of Moncks Corner.
CAMPBELL, Walter Thomas, 73, of Goose Creek, an Air Force veteran and retired MARTA transit operator, died Monday. Arrangements by Palmetto Cremation Society of Charleston.
EADE, Leroy, of Summerville, husband of Joyce Eade died Thursday. Arrangements by Carolina Memorial Funeral Home of North Charleston.
LEGREE, Maurice, 60, of Pineville, a Navy veteran, died Wednesday. Arrangements by Gethers Funeral Home of Moncks Corner.
McDONELL, Patricia A., 78, of Summerville, wife of Dennis McDonell, died Thursday. Arrangements by Parks Funeral Home.
Colleton County BROCK, Janie Diane, 64, of Cottageville died Tuesday. Arrangements by Koger’s Mortuary Service of Walterboro.
COLLINGTON, Ella, 113, of Green Pond died Wednesday. Arrangements by Koger’s Mortuary Service of Walterboro.
SHRAUDER, Willis Raymond, 81, of Walterboro, a retired heating air-conditioning technician and husband of Marlene Turner Shrauder, died Wednesday. Arrangements by Brice Herndon’s Walterboro Chapel.
Dorchester County HASH, Edgel Cletis, 71, of Summerville, widower of Lynda M. Hash, died Thursday. Arrangements by James A. Dyal Funeral Home of Summerville.
Georgetown County BOYD, Hogan James, 52, of Andrews, husband of Freda Boyd, died Thursday. Arrangements by Henryhand’s Andrews Chapel.
Elsewhere BENSON, Janice, of Surprise, Ariz., formerly of Folly Beach, S.C., died April 9. Arrangements by Regency Mortuary of Sun City, Ariz.
GILLIARD, Louis, 68, of New York, formerly of James Island, S.C., husband of Inice Gilliard, died Tuesday. Arrangements by Owens Funeral Home of New York.
MILLER, Charles Jr., 36, of New Zion died Thursday. Arrangements by Henryhand’s Kingstree Chapel.
ROGERS, Rosemary Law, 77, of Kingstree, a teacher with Williamsburg Academy and wife of James L. Rogers Jr., died Thursday. Arrangements by Williamsburg Funeral Home.
ROHR, Brienne Irene, of Naperville, Ill., wife of Aaron Rohr, died July 27. Arrangements by DuPage Cremations.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.postandcourier.com/20160812/160819854/deaths-summary-for-friday-august-12-2016&amp;ampsource=RSS</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>postandcourier.com</username>
<post>
Charleston County BROWN, Octavia W., 71, of Charleston, widow of Earl Brown, died Thursday. Arrangements by Pasley’s Mortuary.
BUTLER, Herbert, of Charleston died July 13. Arrangements by Smith-McNeal’s Downtown Chapel.
HOLMES, Bessie Allen, 59, of Mount Pleasant, a teacher with Burke High School, died Thursday. Arrangements by Steven Funeral Home of St. George.
WHITE, Moses, 89, of Charleston, husband of Thelma H. White, died Wednesday. Arrangements by Fielding Home for Funerals.
Berkeley County BROWN, Esther Lewis Cumbee, 90, of Shulerville, a retired postmaster, former owner and operator of Brown’s Grocery, first married to the late Junior Cumbee and widow of Stansell V. Brown, died Thursday. Arrangements by Dial-Murray Funeral Home of Moncks Corner.
CAMPBELL, Walter Thomas, 73, of Goose Creek, an Air Force veteran and retired MARTA transit operator, died Monday. Arrangements by Palmetto Cremation Society of Charleston.
EADE, Leroy, of Summerville, husband of Joyce Eade died Thursday. Arrangements by Carolina Memorial Funeral Home of North Charleston.
LEGREE, Maurice, 60, of Pineville, a Navy veteran, died Wednesday. Arrangements by Gethers Funeral Home of Moncks Corner.
McDONELL, Patricia A., 78, of Summerville, wife of Dennis McDonell, died Thursday. Arrangements by Parks Funeral Home.
Colleton County BROCK, Janie Diane, 64, of Cottageville died Tuesday. Arrangements by Koger’s Mortuary Service of Walterboro.
COLLINGTON, Ella, 113, of Green Pond died Wednesday. Arrangements by Koger’s Mortuary Service of Walterboro.
SHRAUDER, Willis Raymond, 81, of Walterboro, a retired heating air-conditioning technician and husband of Marlene Turner Shrauder, died Wednesday. Arrangements by Brice Herndon’s Walterboro Chapel.
Dorchester County HASH, Edgel Cletis, 71, of Summerville, widower of Lynda M. Hash, died Thursday. Arrangements by James A. Dyal Funeral Home of Summerville.
Georgetown County BOYD, Hogan James, 52, of Andrews, husband of Freda Boyd, died Thursday. Arrangements by Henryhand’s Andrews Chapel.
Elsewhere BENSON, Janice, of Surprise, Ariz., formerly of Folly Beach, S.C., died April 9. Arrangements by Regency Mortuary of Sun City, Ariz.
GILLIARD, Louis, 68, of New York, formerly of James Island, S.C., husband of Inice Gilliard, died Tuesday. Arrangements by Owens Funeral Home of New York.
MILLER, Charles Jr., 36, of New Zion died Thursday. Arrangements by Henryhand’s Kingstree Chapel.
ROGERS, Rosemary Law, 77, of Kingstree, a teacher with Williamsburg Academy and wife of James L. Rogers Jr., died Thursday. Arrangements by Williamsburg Funeral Home.
ROHR, Brienne Irene, of Naperville, Ill., wife of Aaron Rohr, died July 27. Arrangements by DuPage Cremations.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.postandcourier.com/carbon/carbon-generic.png</main_image>
</document>
