<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news</forum>
<forum_title>News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>EPA’s science advisers challenge agency report on the safety of fracking</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/us/epa%e2%80%99s-science-advisers-challenge-agency-report-on-the-safety-of-fracking/ar-BBvww8n</topic_url>
<topic_text>
EPA’s science advisers challenge agency report on the safety of fracking The Washington Post 5 hrs ago Chris Mooney, Steven Mufson, Brady Dennis In this March 29, 2013, file photo, workers tend to a well head during a hydraulic fracturing operation outside Rifle, in western Colorado. (AP Photo/Brennan Linsley, File) Science advisers to the Environmental Protection Agency Thursday challenged an already controversial government repor t on whether thousands of oil and gas wells that rely on hydraulic fracturing, or “fracking,” systemically pollute drinking water across the nation.
That EPA report, many years in the making and still not finalized, had concluded, “We did not find evidence that these mechanisms have led to widespread, systemic impacts on drinking water resources in the United States,” adding that while there had been isolated problems, those were “small compared to the number of hydraulically fractured wells.”
The conclusion was widely cited and interpreted to mean that while there may have been occasional contamination of water supplies, it was not a nationwide problem. Many environmental groups faulted the study , even as industry groups hailed it.
But the 30-member advisory panel on Thursday concluded the agency’s report was “comprehensive but lacking in several critical areas.”
It recommended that the report be revised to include “quantitative analysis that supports its conclusion” — if, indeed, the conclusion can be defended.
The panel said its critique was backed by 26 of its members, but four dissented. The advisory group is comprised of academic, government, and industry scientists.
The EPA report in question was originally requested by Congress in 2010, when one of the principal environmental concerns centered on whether fracking could contaminate drinking supplies. Since then, other environmental questions — including concerns over methane emissions from drilling operations — have also gained prominence.
The report, published in June of last year in draft form, represents a nearly five-year effort by the EPA to analyze technical data from thousands from fracking operations and nearby aquifers in states around the country.
The study has been dogged by controversy over the scope and scale of the research. The draft study linked fracking to a few cases of water pollution but said the problems appeared so far to be isolated. It cautioned that a number of fracking-related activities carry a future risk of polluting wells and aquifers used for drinking and farming.
The EPA acknowledged last year that it was hampered in its assessment by inadequate data, preventing experts from reaching firm conclusions about whether contaminants in an individual well came from fracking or another source. Some critics of the report said poor data skewed the agency’s conclusions.
The Sierra Club hailed the Science Advisory Board critique, saying it “called out” the agency. “Instead of blindly allowing destructive fracking to continue in our communities, we should extend statewide fracking bans and moratoriums that will keep dirty, climate-polluting fossil fuels like fracked gas in the ground.”
Hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, refers to oil and gas wells that are drilled deep in the ground and then horizontally. After that, water containing some chemicals is blasted at high pressure into the well to fracture the rock, unlocking previously trapped natural gas or oil that then flows back up the well.
This technology has driven a major domestic U.S. oil and gas boom that has contributed to the recent plunge in oil prices and triggered the collapse of the coal industry. But there have also been widespread claims that major fracking operations in some communities have contaminated drinking water with methane gas or other substances.
“EPA will use the [science advisory board’s] final comments and suggestions, along with relevant literature published since the release of the draft assessment, and public comments received by the agency, to revise and finalize the assessment,” agency spokeswoman Melissa Harrison said in a statement. “EPA appreciates the work done by the SAB and hopes to finalize the assessment in 2016.”
Go to MSN Home
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>42</post_num>
<post_id>post-42</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/us/epa%e2%80%99s-science-advisers-challenge-agency-report-on-the-safety-of-fracking/ar-BBvww8n</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0244</post_time>
<username>Jeff Johnson</username>
<post>
Hydraulic fracturing does not cause groundwater contamination. Anyone who understands the basic premise of how a hydraulic system works (the brake system on a car for example) knows that if pressure escapes the system at any point the entire system is useless. Prior to any frac job a pressure test is conducted on the well to ensure the casing will hold. In North Dakota this test consists of plugging the wellbore at the liner top (+/- 10,000 feet vertical depth), bringing it up to 5,000 psi and shutting in the wellhead for half an hour. Wellbore pressure cannot drop more than 5% during this time or the well fails and has to be repaired, usually by a cement &quot;squeeze&quot; job. The purpose of this test is to ensure that groundwater supplies (which only go down 2,000 feet by the way, 8,000 feet above the lateral leg of a typical Bakken well) are not being being contaminated, and that the fracture application is actually cracking rock in the pay zone, not useless rock somewhere along the 10,000 feet of vertical wellbore between the surface and the targeted formation. Producers are not going to sink $7 million into a well to get water, which is what happens if you frac out of formation. Furthermore, no one wants to deal with the bullshit involved in an environmental incident or the negative PR it brings. The idiots looking to the EPA to change their report to better suit their &quot;needs&quot; disregard fact, science, and common sense in an effort to become dependent on the same the people who attacked us on 9-11 and eventually pay whatever price they feel is appropriate for an infidel nation stupid enough to put them in that position for a barrel of oil.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
