<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.redbull.com/my/en/rss/index.rss</forum>
<forum_title>Red Bull Malaysia - most recent stories - http://www.redbull.com/my/en</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Beatmaking Wunderkind Santaroena Takes Off!</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.redbull.com/my/en/music/stories/1331811707960/soundseekers-beatmaking-wunderkind-santaroena-takes-off</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Beatmaking Wunderkind Santaroena Takes Off! Let’s discover the dancing notions in the mind of beatmaker Santaroena. Master of sound © Kadir Chan By Cindy Low on 12 August 2016 
The idea to pursue a career in music is something that’s usually abandoned once one reaches adulthood, but for Indonesian Malaysia-based producer Fazry Santaroena , he seized his desire to entertain people at an age where his friends and peers were toiling away at university. 
At the age of 19, Santaroena dropped out of a theatre programme in order to take his music seriously. Though there were definite difficulties in dealing with the transition from teen to young adult, almost 3 years later he released an impressive EP titled Dancing Notions/Nightcrawler , which brings to mind the distinctive sounds of Low End Theory luminaries. 
We speak to the beatmaker about his early experience of venturing into electronic music, getting acquainted with the local music scene he’s now a part of, his upcoming album Rogue , and more. © Sound Seekers: Santaroena - Rogue You dropped out of university to pursue music seriously. What made you so determined to pursue music here, especially when the local scene isn’t known to be the most viable choice? 
I know it’s tough to break a niche genre of music into the local market, but I think it’s still a very early stage for us, especially with different and new sounds. What made me so determined? It sounds cliché but it’s because of passion – it’s something I have wanted to do all my life. I’ve always wanted to perform in any sort of art form and music, I guess it was just something I was good at and that roped me in for the long run. What did your parents say when you told them about dropping out? 
They were asking me questions, like, “Why can’t I finish [school] first?” But I think in time, I proved to them that I wasn’t dropping out to waste my life away. I’m just doing things my way. So far, I think I’m doing fine. It’s all about climbing the ladder now. Having drawn from a difficult experience for your EP, how much of the material you made was actually usable? 
When I want to make something or when I have a goal in mind, it’s easy for me to get a writer’s block. But, when it’s more natural and I feel like I have to release it and when I’m just playing around, then it’ll come out. It’s a good and bad thing, it’s definitely honest and more myself because from there, I don’t have an aim like I’m trying to make a hip hop song. I believe what comes out naturally in that moment, it’s you, you know? Related Stories
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.redbull.com/my/en/music/stories/1331811707960/soundseekers-beatmaking-wunderkind-santaroena-takes-off</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0327</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Beatmaking Wunderkind Santaroena Takes Off! Let’s discover the dancing notions in the mind of beatmaker Santaroena. Master of sound © Kadir Chan By Cindy Low on 12 August 2016 
The idea to pursue a career in music is something that’s usually abandoned once one reaches adulthood, but for Indonesian Malaysia-based producer Fazry Santaroena , he seized his desire to entertain people at an age where his friends and peers were toiling away at university. 
At the age of 19, Santaroena dropped out of a theatre programme in order to take his music seriously. Though there were definite difficulties in dealing with the transition from teen to young adult, almost 3 years later he released an impressive EP titled Dancing Notions/Nightcrawler , which brings to mind the distinctive sounds of Low End Theory luminaries. 
We speak to the beatmaker about his early experience of venturing into electronic music, getting acquainted with the local music scene he’s now a part of, his upcoming album Rogue , and more. © Sound Seekers: Santaroena - Rogue You dropped out of university to pursue music seriously. What made you so determined to pursue music here, especially when the local scene isn’t known to be the most viable choice? 
I know it’s tough to break a niche genre of music into the local market, but I think it’s still a very early stage for us, especially with different and new sounds. What made me so determined? It sounds cliché but it’s because of passion – it’s something I have wanted to do all my life. I’ve always wanted to perform in any sort of art form and music, I guess it was just something I was good at and that roped me in for the long run. What did your parents say when you told them about dropping out? 
They were asking me questions, like, “Why can’t I finish [school] first?” But I think in time, I proved to them that I wasn’t dropping out to waste my life away. I’m just doing things my way. So far, I think I’m doing fine. It’s all about climbing the ladder now. Having drawn from a difficult experience for your EP, how much of the material you made was actually usable? 
When I want to make something or when I have a goal in mind, it’s easy for me to get a writer’s block. But, when it’s more natural and I feel like I have to release it and when I’m just playing around, then it’ll come out. It’s a good and bad thing, it’s definitely honest and more myself because from there, I don’t have an aim like I’m trying to make a hip hop song. I believe what comes out naturally in that moment, it’s you, you know? Related Stories
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>AT</country>
<main_image>http://image2.redbull.com/rbcom/010/2016-08-12/1331811707597_1/0010/1/1500/1000/1/master-of-sound.jpg</main_image>
</document>
