<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news</forum>
<forum_title>News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Merchant Marine Academy under fire for sexual assault allegations</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/us/merchant-marine-academy-under-fire-for-sexual-assault-allegations/ar-BBvwzcL</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Merchant Marine Academy under fire for sexual assault allegations The Washington Post 2 hrs ago Lisa Rein © Mary Altaffer/AP Photo Midshipmen begin to assemble for lunch muster in Barney Square on the campus of the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy in Kings Point, N.Y., Wednesday, June 14, 2006. With an enrollment of approximately 950, the academy prepares its graduates for careers either in the military or private maritime industry. On Monday, June 19, George W. Bush will become the first U.S. president in the academy&apos;s history to address its graduating class. KINGS POINT, N.Y. — They call it the “safe word.”
It’s the secret code that cadets at the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy are advised to use if things get really rough during their year-long shipboard training on merchant vessels thousands of miles from shore, or at ports far from home. It’s supposed to act as a fail-safe for women — and men, in some cases — if the lewd comments and unwanted advances from fellow sailors escalate to something worse. The government will bring them ashore .
But like most efforts by this federal service academy to confront inappropriate behavior, the safe word has not worked.
The word was “Goldfish” in 2012, the year Erika Lawson, an engine cadet on a commercial ship for what is known as “sea year,” was pushed against the back seat of a taxi and groped by the chief mate to force her to kiss him. She tried to push him away.
Lawson was 19 and didn’t use the safe word, provided by school administrators. She was 7,810 miles from school, in port in Saipan in the North Pacific.
Back on campus in New York, it took her more than a year to file a “restricted report,” which informed the school that she had a bad experience. There were no names and no investigation.
“I feel like you’re taught there to keep your head down and just get through it,” said Lawson, 24 and working as a third assistant engineer on a cruise ship out of New York Harbor. “The sexual assault policies are a total joke. Everybody would just snicker and laugh during the training.”
Right after the assault, Larson wrote the chief mate a note telling him she felt violated. He then slipped $200 in cash under her door — and kept working, she said.
Lawson’s tentative response was more than most victims can muster. The smallest and least known of the five national service schools, the Merchant Marine Academy at Kings Point — which trains graduates to become officers in the Navy, Coast Guard and the U.S. commercial shipping industry — has by far the highest rates of sexual assault and harassment, federal surveys show. About 15 percent of Kings Point students are women.
Few of these cases are reported. But government surveys and focus groups show a long-standing problem ignored for years by the federal government. It has finally led to a reckoning at this forgotten outpost on Long Island Sound about 20 miles east of New York City, the first of the service academies to admit women 42 years ago but which today trains the fewest.
The Merchant Marine Academy is a military and civilian hybrid whose glory days came during World War II. Its heavily unionized fleet is dwindling amid growing automation and competition from foreign ships, which transport goods for less than American vessels.
The school trains about 1,000 students tuition free for up to 330 days at sea. Students are nominated by their member of Congress. Graduates are licensed by the Coast Guard and must work five years in the maritime industry or eight in the Navy Reserves, unless they go on active duty.
The academy’s accreditation is now at risk — a first for a federal service school — and is under growing scrutiny from Congress, its advisory board and the inspector general’s office at the Department of Transportation, which oversees it.
In response, Transportation Secretary Anthony Foxx in June canceled Kings Point’s most prestigious feature, a grueling year at sea where midshipmen apprentice on deep-sea ships. Citing rising sexual misconduct both at sea and on campus, school leaders say they won’t reinstate sea year until midshipmen are safe.
“In our judgment, we could no longer continue to send them to sea with the status quo,” Rear Adm. James A. Helis, the school superintendent, said in an interview in his office with a sweeping view of Manhattan and the Throgs Neck and Whitestone bridges.
After announcing the stand-down in June, the school brought ashore 116 cadets who were at sea. “This wasn’t a problem we could fix as we go,” said Helis, a retired Army colonel hired in 2012 as the academy’s fourth superintendent in seven years.
It’s also a black mark on the increasing efforts of the Obama administration to curtail sexual misconduct on college campuses and in the military. Vice President Biden, who is leading that effort, has said that top-ranking government officials won’t visit institutions that don’t take the issue seriously, and even suggested that federal money could be jeopardized by schools that don’t comply.
Yet the problem has been pervasive in some corners of the government itself.
The National Park Service inspector general’s office uncovered years of harassment of employees at the Grand Canyon and other parks. The problem of sexual assault is well known in the military, which has developed new policies to encourage victims to file formal complaints.
Under pressure from Congress, Kings Point hired its first sexual assault coordinator four years ago and beefed up online and face-to-face prevention training. But officials were shocked to find so few victims reporting when surveys told them that sexual misconduct was continuing.
Helis said the prevention training and reporting systems are not effective enough. Furthermore, lawmakers on the congressional Board of Visitors are so concerned that they pushed legislation sponsored by Sens. Deb Fischer (R-Neb.) and Cory Booker (D-N.J.) through the Senate in July requiring more rigorous reporting and training policies. The legislation also urges the academy to consider alternatives to sea year.
Kings Point has been troubled by years of mismanagement, high staff turnover and leadership turmoil and is effectively in receivership, with Washington controlling its budget, hiring and other operations. Some graduates accuse the Obama administration of coddling students and inflating the extent of sexual misconduct.
But the Middle States Commission on Higher Education — which does 10-year accreditation reviews for the U.S. Education Department — placed the Merchant Marine Academy on warning in June, citing failures of leadership and governance, administration and student services . The commission described a “campus climate and incidence of sexual harassment and sexual assault that have been a serious and recognized problem for over 10 years.
“The pervasiveness of the incidents is perceived as undeniable and disturbing,” the report said, criticizing the academy’s efforts to prevent misconduct as “insufficient and ineffective.”
Cadets describe abuse as part of the culture at sea, where women were once said to bring bad luck because they were distracting to sailors.
In interviews, 11 recent Kings Point graduates and current midshipmen, including two men, said they or someone they knew experienced bullying and inappropriate sexual behavior both at sea and on campus. They dealt with it differently. Some shrugged it off and told the offenders to get lost. Others were devastated.
Maritime has always been a man’s industry of oil tankers and container ships, where recent graduates and Kings Point leaders describe how crews at sea for months at a time still frequent brothels when they’re in port, “porn night” below deck is a common fixture and women cadets have to sit on the chief engineer’s lap before he will sign off on their apprenticeship.
“I’ve had crew members come to my door at night to try to kiss me,” recalled Meghan Sadowski, who graduated in 2012.
Sadowski described a system where cadets are sent from the classroom onto ships with older men who often do not treat them as co-workers. The students “feel they’re not empowered to speak up,” she said.
Back on campus during her senior year, she led a successful effort to get locks put on the barrack doors because she felt students were not safe at night.
Some of the behavior at sea carries over to the New York campus, said Maritime Administrator Paul Jaenichen, whose small agency at the Transportation Department oversees the academy. Midshipmen return from sea year with “a new bias that shifted their thought process to sexist behavior.”
Until last year, for instance, the Merchant Marine Academy employed a former Marine on the faculty who called female midshipmen “cookies in my cookie jar” and knocked on their dorm room doors at night, four recent graduates said.
Helis and Jaenichen described a “steady accumulation of evidence” that led to the drastic decision to cancel sea year, setting off a civil war with parents and a vocal group of older graduates who say that the school is overreacting.
“The Merchant Marines are 20 years behind what we experience as gender equality,” said Ali Denning, a 2012 graduate who is a Marine inspector for the U.S. Coast Guard.
Denning said that she tried to “educate” sailors who would comment on her appearance or question whether she was up to the job.
“They told us, ‘Try your best to get through it, so you can pave the way for women behind you,&apos;” she recalled of her instructors and fellow midshipmen.
The school received one report of assault in the 2014-2015 academic year. One case has been adjudicated, with the offender expelled, officials said, but not criminally prosecuted.
Yet student surveys and focus groups during that period showed that 63 percent of women and 11 percent of men experienced unwanted advances or other sexual harassment, and 17.2 percent of women and 2 percent of men experienced some kind of sexual assault, defined as unwanted contact, from groping to rape.
Those numbers exceed the combined rates at West Point and the Naval, Air Force and Coast Guard academies, where 48 percent of women and 10 percent of men described sexual harassment in similar surveys. For both genders, sexual assault rates were half that of Kings Point’s.
Some, including members of Congress, have questioned the need for a costly federal school when there are six state academies.
The shipping industry — which hosts hundreds of Kings Point cadets for sea year on its vessels — and the Merchant Marine union are working with the school to strengthen its training to prevent sexual offenses.
“The notion that it is hard to change the maritime culture — we don’t accept that,” said Michael Roberts, general counsel for Jacksonville, Fla.-based Crowley Maritime Corporation, which is leading the effort.
Although most companies “have mechanisms in place to deal with this,” some are better than others, he said. “We recognize that the goal is zero tolerance and we’re prepared to step up.”
Rebecca Nardi, a 2014 Kings Point graduate, said that it will not be easy for victims to maintain their privacy in a culture that retaliates against them when they come forward.
As a freshman, she was assaulted by a popular midshipman assigned as her mentor. On a boat owned by the school, students were celebrating a sailing race and drinking. Nardi went below deck to lie down. The student pinned her to the bed and started to undress her. Another student stopped the assault.
Nardi went to the campus police, but her report was not kept confidential. After being told she asked for it because she was drinking, she says she was grounded for six weeks.
Nardi eventually withdrew her complaint. Now 25 and working on oil barges and frigates out of Houston, she says, “In hindsight, I was bullied into that decision and I wish I had had the courage to follow it through.”
Some angry parents and graduates are pushing back on the cancellation of sea year, even though the academy has found other training for students on Navy transport ships and ships used by state schools. They have launched a public-relations campaign on Facebook and in the trade press to stop the stand-down.
“It is not the same when a dozen or two cadets stand around on the bridge and watch the mate go about his duties,” said Terry Gray, who is on the parents association’s executive board. “All our midshipmen need to sail on commercial ships.”
The resistance is also coming from older female graduates, who were filmed in an online video clip saying they did not experience sexual misconduct during sea year.
Gray and others say that no one “is so foolish as to think that sexual harassment is nonexistent at sea.”
“The sexual harassment issue has been around for years,” said Charles Hill a former head of the school’s national alumni foundation. “Why cancel the sea year now?”
Said Hill: “I have never talked to anybody who told me they were sexually assaulted at Kings Point.”
Go to MSN Home
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/us/merchant-marine-academy-under-fire-for-sexual-assault-allegations/ar-BBvwzcL</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0531</post_time>
<username>Jerry Dunn</username>
<post>
Yawn! Whatever.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
