<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Team USA enters Grand Prix Special in bronze position | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/team-usa-enters-grand-prix-special-in-bronze-position/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Team USA enters Grand Prix Special in bronze position Team USA has impressive second of Grand Prix NBC Olympics.com Published: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
Team USA solidifies the Bronze position entering into Friday’s Grand Prix Special after stellar performances from Steffen Peters and Laura Graves on day two of the Grand Prix. 
Allison Brock and Kasey Perry-Glass’s performances during Wednesday’s Grand Prix round left the team on the brink bronze positioning. Perry-Glass delivered a top five performance in her Olympic debut after making her first Grand Prix appearance earlier this year. Brock held down the No. 7 spot at the end of day one with a 72.686% dressage test score. In order to remain competitive with Germany, Great Britain, and the Dutch, Team USA had to rely on Peters and Graves to deliver four star performances. 
Peters and Graves came in clutch for Team USA this afternoon in the Deodoro Equestrian Centre, earning the No. 4 and No. 5 spots on the individual leaderboard and increasing the team average to 76.971%. The team falls short behind Germany, the dressage legends and Great Britain, the reigning gold medalists. 
Graves, Peters, and Perry-Glass must deliver phenomenal performances in the Grand Prix Special in order to compete with Great Britain and Germany for a shot at bringing home the gold. 
Germany continues to dominate the dressage competition in the final Grand Prix round with star performances from Kristina Broring-Sprehe and the “Dressage Queen” Isabel Werth take the No. 2 and No. 3 spots on the individual leaderboard. The team is determined to bring home their 12th golden title and at this point in the competition is unstoppable. The team currently holds an 81.295% average score. Only four individuals have scored an 80% or above on their dressage test, three are German. 
Charlotte Dujardin, world-record holder and reigning individual gold medalist impressed the judges with her Grand Prix performance and landed the No.1 spot on the leaderboard. Her 85.071% score helped Great Britain secure the Silver position entering Friday’s Grand Prix Special. The reigning team gold medalists fall short behind Germany with an average of 79.252%. The team must take their performances to the next level in the Grand Prix Special if they want a chance at defeating the ever so dominant Germans. 
The Dutch, Sweeden, and Denmark all remain in the running for a title as they advance to the Grand Prix Special. The Dutch trail Team USA by 0.928%, while Sweden and Denmark fall behind by less than 2%. 
The Grand Prix Special will begin at 9:00 am EST. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/team-usa-enters-grand-prix-special-in-bronze-position/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Nbc Olympics.Com</username>
<post>
Team USA enters Grand Prix Special in bronze position Team USA has impressive second of Grand Prix NBC Olympics.com Published: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
Team USA solidifies the Bronze position entering into Friday’s Grand Prix Special after stellar performances from Steffen Peters and Laura Graves on day two of the Grand Prix. 
Allison Brock and Kasey Perry-Glass’s performances during Wednesday’s Grand Prix round left the team on the brink bronze positioning. Perry-Glass delivered a top five performance in her Olympic debut after making her first Grand Prix appearance earlier this year. Brock held down the No. 7 spot at the end of day one with a 72.686% dressage test score. In order to remain competitive with Germany, Great Britain, and the Dutch, Team USA had to rely on Peters and Graves to deliver four star performances. 
Peters and Graves came in clutch for Team USA this afternoon in the Deodoro Equestrian Centre, earning the No. 4 and No. 5 spots on the individual leaderboard and increasing the team average to 76.971%. The team falls short behind Germany, the dressage legends and Great Britain, the reigning gold medalists. 
Graves, Peters, and Perry-Glass must deliver phenomenal performances in the Grand Prix Special in order to compete with Great Britain and Germany for a shot at bringing home the gold. 
Germany continues to dominate the dressage competition in the final Grand Prix round with star performances from Kristina Broring-Sprehe and the “Dressage Queen” Isabel Werth take the No. 2 and No. 3 spots on the individual leaderboard. The team is determined to bring home their 12th golden title and at this point in the competition is unstoppable. The team currently holds an 81.295% average score. Only four individuals have scored an 80% or above on their dressage test, three are German. 
Charlotte Dujardin, world-record holder and reigning individual gold medalist impressed the judges with her Grand Prix performance and landed the No.1 spot on the leaderboard. Her 85.071% score helped Great Britain secure the Silver position entering Friday’s Grand Prix Special. The reigning team gold medalists fall short behind Germany with an average of 79.252%. The team must take their performances to the next level in the Grand Prix Special if they want a chance at defeating the ever so dominant Germans. 
The Dutch, Sweeden, and Denmark all remain in the running for a title as they advance to the Grand Prix Special. The Dutch trail Team USA by 0.928%, while Sweden and Denmark fall behind by less than 2%. 
The Grand Prix Special will begin at 9:00 am EST. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/rio-olympics-equestri_webf-11.jpg</main_image>
</document>
