<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://seekingalpha.com/atom.xml</forum>
<forum_title>All Articles on Seeking Alpha</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Macy&apos;s Shows Promise, But Be Careful</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://seekingalpha.com/article/3999064-macys-shows-promise-careful</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Summary 
M shot higher after a better-than-expected quarter and the company announced plans to close 100 stores. 
Investors view the store closings as evidence that the company is taking steps toward unlocking value tied up in real estate. 
There is some potential here, but investors should remember that the value of this real estate is tied to the performance of Macy&apos;s. 
We think Macy&apos;s will continue to struggle in its underlying business. Despite continuing to report weak performance, investors have become more optimistic about the outlook for Macy&apos;s (NYSE: M ). Shares popped more than 11% after the company reported better-than-expected results for the second quarter and management announced plans to close more stores. Q2 revenues fell 3.8% year over year, beating estimates by $130 million, while non-GAAP EPS of $0.54 beat by $0.09. Like most investors, we view management&apos;s plans to close underperforming stores and better monetize the firm&apos;s valuable real estate positively, but while some think the company will be able to unlock value by selling off certain assets, we take a cautious approach and think investors should be cognizant of the fact that the value of those assets is still tied to the underlying performance of the company - the outlook for which doesn&apos;t look much better. Macy&apos;s has been plagued by a weakening US economy and increased competition from Amazon (NASDAQ: AMZN ), whose relatively low cost base and massive scale advantages allow the e-commerce giant to outcompete brick-and-mortar businesses such as Macy&apos;s on price. M&apos;s same-store sales in the second quarter fell 2%, and are down 3.8% year to date. Operating margins are lower as well. Q2 operating margin, adjusted for non-cash and nonrecurring items fell to 6.2% in the quarter and 5.7% for the first half of the year, compared to 7.1% and 6.8% respectively. The combination of lower sales and lower margins drove down earnings significantly over last year, and we don&apos;t think they will recover meaningfully anytime soon. Management tried to put positive things by sequential improvements (comps declined by a lower amount compared to the first quarter), but investors shouldn&apos;t interpret this as a sign that M is turning things around. The weaker US economy has made customers more sensitive to price, and while Macy&apos;s is investing in its e-commerce platform, the company will continue to have trouble matching AMZN&apos;s combination of value and convenience. But Macy&apos;s is interesting because it may not have to totally turn things around in its core business in order to unlock value for shareholders. According to Starboard Value, the company has the most valuable real estate in the retail space. Approximately 35% of this real estate comes from top-performing malls in high-traffic locations, and an additional 35% comes from 8 potentially lucrative &quot;downtown&quot; locations in densely populated cities such as New York and Chicago. Starboard Value estimates that the value of this real estate alone is more than Macy&apos;s enterprise value (Figure 1), and many investors are optimistic that the company can create value by selling off pieces of the portfolio. Management has demonstrated a willingness to do such a thing, and many view the company&apos;s decision to close 100 out of its 675 company-owned stores as further evidence that management is taking the steps necessary to better monetize its real estate assets. Figure 1: Sum of Parts Valuation Click to enlarge Source: Starboard Value The proceeds Macy&apos;s might generate by selling parts of its portfolio would allow the company to return more cash to shareholders, pay down debt, and expand the e-commerce platform, putting the company in a better position to compete long term. However, we think investors are overestimating the value of M&apos;s real estate assets for two reasons. First, overcapacity is a big problem in the US department store space. There are 5.5x more retail locations per capita in the US than anywhere else in the world, and the supply glut will put a ceiling on valuations until retailers adjust, which will take some time. Second, the value of an owner&apos;s real estate is based on the cash flows it can generate from the property. In Macy&apos;s case, this means the profits the company can produce by selling clothing. The retail climate in the US is very challenging, and until the company can show progress at its department stores, it will have trouble offloading its properties at the valuations implied by Starboard Value&apos;s model. Conclusion: Investors are optimistic that Macy&apos;s can unlock value by better monetizing its real estate portfolio, and while we think there&apos;s some potential here, investors should remember that the value of this real estate is tied to the company&apos;s performance. M&apos;s Q1 results were so poor that it forced the company to suspend its buyback program, and the company won&apos;t resume share repurchases until it sees &quot;more positive sales trends.&quot; We think Macy&apos;s will continue to struggle with weak comps, which will limit the value M can extract from its real estate. Disclosure: I/we have no positions in any stocks mentioned, and no plans to initiate any positions within the next 72 hours. I wrote this article myself, and it expresses my own opinions. I am not receiving compensation for it (other than from Seeking Alpha). I have no business relationship with any company whose stock is mentioned in this article. About this article: Expand Author payment: $35 + $0.01/page view. Authors of PRO articles receive a minimum guaranteed payment of $150-500. Become a contributor » Tagged: Services , Department Stores , Earnings
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://seekingalpha.com/article/3999064-macys-shows-promise-careful</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0544</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Summary 
M shot higher after a better-than-expected quarter and the company announced plans to close 100 stores. 
Investors view the store closings as evidence that the company is taking steps toward unlocking value tied up in real estate. 
There is some potential here, but investors should remember that the value of this real estate is tied to the performance of Macy&apos;s. 
We think Macy&apos;s will continue to struggle in its underlying business. Despite continuing to report weak performance, investors have become more optimistic about the outlook for Macy&apos;s (NYSE: M ). Shares popped more than 11% after the company reported better-than-expected results for the second quarter and management announced plans to close more stores. Q2 revenues fell 3.8% year over year, beating estimates by $130 million, while non-GAAP EPS of $0.54 beat by $0.09. Like most investors, we view management&apos;s plans to close underperforming stores and better monetize the firm&apos;s valuable real estate positively, but while some think the company will be able to unlock value by selling off certain assets, we take a cautious approach and think investors should be cognizant of the fact that the value of those assets is still tied to the underlying performance of the company - the outlook for which doesn&apos;t look much better. Macy&apos;s has been plagued by a weakening US economy and increased competition from Amazon (NASDAQ: AMZN ), whose relatively low cost base and massive scale advantages allow the e-commerce giant to outcompete brick-and-mortar businesses such as Macy&apos;s on price. M&apos;s same-store sales in the second quarter fell 2%, and are down 3.8% year to date. Operating margins are lower as well. Q2 operating margin, adjusted for non-cash and nonrecurring items fell to 6.2% in the quarter and 5.7% for the first half of the year, compared to 7.1% and 6.8% respectively. The combination of lower sales and lower margins drove down earnings significantly over last year, and we don&apos;t think they will recover meaningfully anytime soon. Management tried to put positive things by sequential improvements (comps declined by a lower amount compared to the first quarter), but investors shouldn&apos;t interpret this as a sign that M is turning things around. The weaker US economy has made customers more sensitive to price, and while Macy&apos;s is investing in its e-commerce platform, the company will continue to have trouble matching AMZN&apos;s combination of value and convenience. But Macy&apos;s is interesting because it may not have to totally turn things around in its core business in order to unlock value for shareholders. According to Starboard Value, the company has the most valuable real estate in the retail space. Approximately 35% of this real estate comes from top-performing malls in high-traffic locations, and an additional 35% comes from 8 potentially lucrative &quot;downtown&quot; locations in densely populated cities such as New York and Chicago. Starboard Value estimates that the value of this real estate alone is more than Macy&apos;s enterprise value (Figure 1), and many investors are optimistic that the company can create value by selling off pieces of the portfolio. Management has demonstrated a willingness to do such a thing, and many view the company&apos;s decision to close 100 out of its 675 company-owned stores as further evidence that management is taking the steps necessary to better monetize its real estate assets. Figure 1: Sum of Parts Valuation Click to enlarge Source: Starboard Value The proceeds Macy&apos;s might generate by selling parts of its portfolio would allow the company to return more cash to shareholders, pay down debt, and expand the e-commerce platform, putting the company in a better position to compete long term. However, we think investors are overestimating the value of M&apos;s real estate assets for two reasons. First, overcapacity is a big problem in the US department store space. There are 5.5x more retail locations per capita in the US than anywhere else in the world, and the supply glut will put a ceiling on valuations until retailers adjust, which will take some time. Second, the value of an owner&apos;s real estate is based on the cash flows it can generate from the property. In Macy&apos;s case, this means the profits the company can produce by selling clothing. The retail climate in the US is very challenging, and until the company can show progress at its department stores, it will have trouble offloading its properties at the valuations implied by Starboard Value&apos;s model. Conclusion: Investors are optimistic that Macy&apos;s can unlock value by better monetizing its real estate portfolio, and while we think there&apos;s some potential here, investors should remember that the value of this real estate is tied to the company&apos;s performance. M&apos;s Q1 results were so poor that it forced the company to suspend its buyback program, and the company won&apos;t resume share repurchases until it sees &quot;more positive sales trends.&quot; We think Macy&apos;s will continue to struggle with weak comps, which will limit the value M can extract from its real estate. Disclosure: I/we have no positions in any stocks mentioned, and no plans to initiate any positions within the next 72 hours. I wrote this article myself, and it expresses my own opinions. I am not receiving compensation for it (other than from Seeking Alpha). I have no business relationship with any company whose stock is mentioned in this article. About this article: Expand Author payment: $35 + $0.01/page view. Authors of PRO articles receive a minimum guaranteed payment of $150-500. Become a contributor » Tagged: Services , Department Stores , Earnings
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://staticseekingalpha3.a.ssl.fastly.net/images/marketing_images/aircraft/space_shuttle_endeavour_and_carrier_plane_passing_directly_overhead_in_marin_headlands.jpeg</main_image>
</document>
