<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Consider putting that vacation on layaway</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Family/Consider_putting_that_vacation_on_layaway.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Consider putting that vacation on layaway Flying Squirrel 
Where are you traveling next summer? Yes, summer 2017. As in a year from now. 
Most people don’t make plans that far in advance. 
They may have just finished this year’s big trip and don’t want to think about another so soon. Or they may not know what they want to do a year from now. Or they’re last-minute planners and would never commit this far ahead. 
But if you book early, you’ll get the best pricing, and by making small, regular payments along the way, you avoid having to come up with a stress-inducing sum of money all at once. 
I used to think this approach would be obvious to vacationers. 
But recently a client was surprised when I told them, yes, you can make payments on a trip, kind of like a vacation layaway. Even if you change your mind, you can get a full refund as long as you cancel before your final payment date. 
Let me give you a couple of examples of how that might work. 
Perhaps you want to visit the Caribbean or Mexico in 2017, staying at an all-inclusive resort. 
Let’s say your vacation cost is $4,000. You make a down payment of $500, with a balance due of $3,500. 
Typically you’d pay this 45 to 90 days before travel. With a departure in mid-July and a 45- day final payment deadline, your balance would be due around June 1. That would mean you’d have 10 payments of about $350 a month. 
Contrast that with the more typical approach: You make the down payment of $500 and wait until June 2017 and then pay $3,500 all at once. Some people might be OK with that. But for others, such a huge lump sum might be an uncomfortable deterrent to traveling. 
And what happens if you change your mind? 
For instance, maybe in January you decide, rather than going to Cancun, you’re going to attend the family reunion in Minnesota everyone’s now excited about. 
You could convince the family to travel south to Mexico, but if not, no worries. Whatever payments you made in advance are usually 100 percent refundable. 
Not every vacation tour operator may offer this option. But the companies I work with, including FunJet Vacations, United Vacations and Delta Vacations, can make it possible. 
Cruise lines also offer this layaway benefit, and in some instances you benefit even more from the long lead time. Many cruise lines already have some itineraries published through 2018. With more time to save, your monthly layaway amount will be even lower. 
Let’s say you want to visit Hawaii on a seven-night cruise from Honolulu in May 2018. (I’m there now and can highly recommend it!) 
The price for a balcony guarantee stateroom is $4,278 for two. With a $250 deposit now and 18 payments through March 1, 2018, your layaway amount would be $223 a month. 
Now it’s true you may miss some payments and not prepay the full amount. But even if you make just half the payments, you’ve put a huge dent in your vacation cost by the time your departure nears. And you’ve taken what may have seemed like an enormous sum and made it much more manageable. 
I want to underline with these examples that you haven’t compromised your ability to ask for a full refund. As long as you cancel your tour or cruise booking before the penalty date, all the money you paid will be refunded. Check with the tour operator, cruise line or your travel consultant to be sure you know the dates. 
Yes, you’ve lost the use of the money during this time or the interest you could have earned on it. (Ha! Interest!) Only you know if this factor is significant enough to forgo the layaway advantages. 
But if the sting of a big vacation payment is the reason you don’t take that trip you’ve dreamed of, consider if paying the expenses over time makes getting to your own paradise easier. 
Thor Challgren is a travel consultant who lives in Thousand Oaks. For info and resources on this story, visit www.facebook.com/loveyourvacation . Email questions to .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Family/Consider_putting_that_vacation_on_layaway.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
Consider putting that vacation on layaway Flying Squirrel 
Where are you traveling next summer? Yes, summer 2017. As in a year from now. 
Most people don’t make plans that far in advance. 
They may have just finished this year’s big trip and don’t want to think about another so soon. Or they may not know what they want to do a year from now. Or they’re last-minute planners and would never commit this far ahead. 
But if you book early, you’ll get the best pricing, and by making small, regular payments along the way, you avoid having to come up with a stress-inducing sum of money all at once. 
I used to think this approach would be obvious to vacationers. 
But recently a client was surprised when I told them, yes, you can make payments on a trip, kind of like a vacation layaway. Even if you change your mind, you can get a full refund as long as you cancel before your final payment date. 
Let me give you a couple of examples of how that might work. 
Perhaps you want to visit the Caribbean or Mexico in 2017, staying at an all-inclusive resort. 
Let’s say your vacation cost is $4,000. You make a down payment of $500, with a balance due of $3,500. 
Typically you’d pay this 45 to 90 days before travel. With a departure in mid-July and a 45- day final payment deadline, your balance would be due around June 1. That would mean you’d have 10 payments of about $350 a month. 
Contrast that with the more typical approach: You make the down payment of $500 and wait until June 2017 and then pay $3,500 all at once. Some people might be OK with that. But for others, such a huge lump sum might be an uncomfortable deterrent to traveling. 
And what happens if you change your mind? 
For instance, maybe in January you decide, rather than going to Cancun, you’re going to attend the family reunion in Minnesota everyone’s now excited about. 
You could convince the family to travel south to Mexico, but if not, no worries. Whatever payments you made in advance are usually 100 percent refundable. 
Not every vacation tour operator may offer this option. But the companies I work with, including FunJet Vacations, United Vacations and Delta Vacations, can make it possible. 
Cruise lines also offer this layaway benefit, and in some instances you benefit even more from the long lead time. Many cruise lines already have some itineraries published through 2018. With more time to save, your monthly layaway amount will be even lower. 
Let’s say you want to visit Hawaii on a seven-night cruise from Honolulu in May 2018. (I’m there now and can highly recommend it!) 
The price for a balcony guarantee stateroom is $4,278 for two. With a $250 deposit now and 18 payments through March 1, 2018, your layaway amount would be $223 a month. 
Now it’s true you may miss some payments and not prepay the full amount. But even if you make just half the payments, you’ve put a huge dent in your vacation cost by the time your departure nears. And you’ve taken what may have seemed like an enormous sum and made it much more manageable. 
I want to underline with these examples that you haven’t compromised your ability to ask for a full refund. As long as you cancel your tour or cruise booking before the penalty date, all the money you paid will be refunded. Check with the tour operator, cruise line or your travel consultant to be sure you know the dates. 
Yes, you’ve lost the use of the money during this time or the interest you could have earned on it. (Ha! Interest!) Only you know if this factor is significant enough to forgo the layaway advantages. 
But if the sting of a big vacation payment is the reason you don’t take that trip you’ve dreamed of, consider if paying the expenses over time makes getting to your own paradise easier. 
Thor Challgren is a travel consultant who lives in Thousand Oaks. For info and resources on this story, visit www.facebook.com/loveyourvacation . Email questions to .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/20p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
