<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Clinton aide at the State Department also worked for the Clinton Foundation</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://news10.com/2016/08/11/clinton-aide-at-the-state-department-also-worked-for-the-clinton-foundation/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Clinton aide at the State Department also worked for the Clinton Foundation CNN Published: Credit: CNN 
WASHINGTON (CNN) – More questions are being raised about Hillary Clinton’s term as Secretary of State. 
Specifically, a top State Department aide during Clinton’s tenure traveled to New York to interview candidates for a top job at the Clinton Foundation. 
On June 19, 2012, Cheryl Mills, then the Chief of Staff for Secretary of State Hillary Clinton, boarded an Amtrak Acela train in Washington’s Union Station, bound for New York. 
For the last seven months, Senate investigators have been trying to find out what Mills was up to, and for seven months, the U.S. Department of State has refused to answer. 
Now CNN has learned on a potential reason why. 
Mills was in New York working on behalf of the Clinton Foundation. 
A source close to the situation confirmed to CNN that Mills was interviewing two potential candidates to lead the foundation. 
Mills would interview top-level executives at Walmart and the drug company Pfizer. 
Both companies are huge donors to the Clinton Foundation and have worked with the Clinton Global Initiative. 
The U.S. State Department released this response: 
“Federal employees are permitted to engage in outside personal activities, within the scope of the federal ethics rules. All federal employees are subject to federal ethics laws and regulations, including rules pertaining to conflicts of interest.” 
The vague response raises more questions that are just not being answered. 
Not to CNN, but worse says one watchdog group, not to the Republican-led Senate Judiciary Committee which has a right to know. 
“Congress has a rightful right to ask for any information that it wants to from the executive branch of government to keep track of them. And the government should be turning that information over. When you have a breakdown in that system, we have a breakdown in our democracy,” Scott Arney, Project on Government Oversight, said. 
It’s easy to understand why Mills was trusted with helping find the next director of the Clinton Foundation. 
Her relationship with the Clintons goes back decades. 
As Bill Clinton’s Deputy White House Counsel, she defended the then president during impeachment proceedings. 
In 2008, when Hillary Clinton was running for president, Mills was her senior legal campaign adviser. 
When Hillary Clinton became Secretary of State, Mills left the Board of the Clinton Foundation and became Clinton’s Chief of Staff. 
The secrecy about the New York trip, the dual roles played by trusted assistants, the mixing of business between State, Clinton Foundation and its donors, all play a central theme of Donald Trump’s campaign – that politicians like the Clintons use the government to benefit themselves. 
“These are crooked people. They’ve been crooked from the beginning. You look at that foundation. It’s pure theft and pure crookedness,” Republican Presidential Nominee Donald Trump said. 
Mills’ attorney says her client was simply doing “volunteer work for a charitable foundation. She was not paid.” 
The Clinton Foundation also says Mills was not a paid employee. 
On Thursday, Clinton Spokesman Brian Fallon issued this statement: 
“Cheryl volunteered her personal time to a charitable organization, as she has to other charities. Cheryl paid for her travel to New York City personally, and it was crystal clear to all involved that this had nothing to do with her official duties. The idea that this poses a conflict of interest is absurd.” Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://news10.com/2016/08/11/clinton-aide-at-the-state-department-also-worked-for-the-clinton-foundation/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Clinton aide at the State Department also worked for the Clinton Foundation CNN Published: Credit: CNN 
WASHINGTON (CNN) – More questions are being raised about Hillary Clinton’s term as Secretary of State. 
Specifically, a top State Department aide during Clinton’s tenure traveled to New York to interview candidates for a top job at the Clinton Foundation. 
On June 19, 2012, Cheryl Mills, then the Chief of Staff for Secretary of State Hillary Clinton, boarded an Amtrak Acela train in Washington’s Union Station, bound for New York. 
For the last seven months, Senate investigators have been trying to find out what Mills was up to, and for seven months, the U.S. Department of State has refused to answer. 
Now CNN has learned on a potential reason why. 
Mills was in New York working on behalf of the Clinton Foundation. 
A source close to the situation confirmed to CNN that Mills was interviewing two potential candidates to lead the foundation. 
Mills would interview top-level executives at Walmart and the drug company Pfizer. 
Both companies are huge donors to the Clinton Foundation and have worked with the Clinton Global Initiative. 
The U.S. State Department released this response: 
“Federal employees are permitted to engage in outside personal activities, within the scope of the federal ethics rules. All federal employees are subject to federal ethics laws and regulations, including rules pertaining to conflicts of interest.” 
The vague response raises more questions that are just not being answered. 
Not to CNN, but worse says one watchdog group, not to the Republican-led Senate Judiciary Committee which has a right to know. 
“Congress has a rightful right to ask for any information that it wants to from the executive branch of government to keep track of them. And the government should be turning that information over. When you have a breakdown in that system, we have a breakdown in our democracy,” Scott Arney, Project on Government Oversight, said. 
It’s easy to understand why Mills was trusted with helping find the next director of the Clinton Foundation. 
Her relationship with the Clintons goes back decades. 
As Bill Clinton’s Deputy White House Counsel, she defended the then president during impeachment proceedings. 
In 2008, when Hillary Clinton was running for president, Mills was her senior legal campaign adviser. 
When Hillary Clinton became Secretary of State, Mills left the Board of the Clinton Foundation and became Clinton’s Chief of Staff. 
The secrecy about the New York trip, the dual roles played by trusted assistants, the mixing of business between State, Clinton Foundation and its donors, all play a central theme of Donald Trump’s campaign – that politicians like the Clintons use the government to benefit themselves. 
“These are crooked people. They’ve been crooked from the beginning. You look at that foundation. It’s pure theft and pure crookedness,” Republican Presidential Nominee Donald Trump said. 
Mills’ attorney says her client was simply doing “volunteer work for a charitable foundation. She was not paid.” 
The Clinton Foundation also says Mills was not a paid employee. 
On Thursday, Clinton Spokesman Brian Fallon issued this statement: 
“Cheryl volunteered her personal time to a charitable organization, as she has to other charities. Cheryl paid for her travel to New York City personally, and it was crystal clear to all involved that this had nothing to do with her official duties. The idea that this poses a conflict of interest is absurd.” Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://mgtvwten.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/cherylmills.png</main_image>
</document>
