<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://seekingalpha.com/atom.xml</forum>
<forum_title>All Articles on Seeking Alpha</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Finjan Holdings&apos; (FNJN) CEO Phil Hartstein on Q2 2016 Results - Earnings Call Transcript</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://seekingalpha.com/article/3999067-finjan-holdings-fnjn-ceo-phil-hartstein-q2-2016-results-earnings-call-transcript</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Finjan Holdings, Inc. (NASDAQ: FNJN ) Q2 2016 Earnings Conference Call August 11, 2016 4:30 PM ET Executives Vanessa Winter - Director of Investor Relations &amp; Corporate Communications Phil Hartstein - President and Chief Executive Officer Michael Noonan - Chief Financial Officer and Treasurer Analysts Mike Crawford - B. Riley &amp; Co. LLC Lisa Thomson - Zacks Investment Research Operator Thank you for standing by. This is the conference operator. Welcome to the Finjan Second Quarter Earnings Update Call. As a reminder, all participants are in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions. [Operator Instructions] I would now like to turn the conference over to Vanessa Winter, Investor Relations. Please go ahead. Vanessa Winter Hello, everyone, and thank you for joining us this afternoon for a review of our second quarter 2016 results. Joining me on today’s call is Phil Hartstein, Finjan’s President and CEO; and Michael Noonan, CFO. As a reminder, this call is being webcast and a replay of the webcast will be available on our website. Before I begin, I would like to quickly make note of our Safe Harbor. During the course of this call, we may make statements related to the overall business outlook, future financial operating results, timing of redemption of shares of Series A preferred stock, outcomes of our pending and future litigation, accounting matters and future prospects. These are forward-looking statements based on certain assumptions and are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties that could cause future results to differ materially from our expectations. You can learn more about these risks in our most recent Form 10-K filed with the SEC on March 25, 2016 as well as our subsequent filings. These documents are available on the Investor Relations page of our website at www.finjan.com. We assume no obligation to update any forward-looking statements. I’d also like to mention, Finjan management will be presenting at a number of upcoming conferences, so we hope to get the opportunity to touch face with many of you in person. We will present at the [indiscernible] Investor Conference on September 7 at 2:30 PM in San Francisco; the Rodman Investor Conference at 3:30 PM Eastern Time on September 13, in New York; and the Aegis Capital Conference on September 21, at 10:00 AM in Las Vegas. We will also be presenting at the Microchip Conferences in Philadelphia on October 17, and the Drexel Hamilton Conference in New York on November 10. Please contact me vanessa@finjan.com to schedule a meeting. With that, I would like to turn the call over to Phil Hartstein, Finjan’s President and CEO. Phil? Phil Hartstein Thank you, Vanessa, and thank you all for joining today’s call. After what was probably one of the busiest quarters we’ve had in our licensing and enforcement program, I’m looking forward to sharing an update on our progress on all fronts. I will begin today’s call discussing our success in defending Finjan’s patent at the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office or USPTO, and The Patent Trial and Appeal Board or PTAB against administrative challenges, provide an update on our litigation schedule and offer some color on our continued licensing efforts before turning the call over to Michael, who will address the financial and operational sides of our business. If you spend anytime following the world of cybersecurity technology, you will likely run across Finjan’s name. This was the reason we were recently approached by Bloomberg at the subject matter of an in-depth article titled Cybersecurity’s Top Patent Litigator. In November, Finjan celebrates its 20th anniversary and it’s satisfying to see this both media and the overall investment community are calling out the fundamental distinctions of Finjan as an operating company against a narrower set of patent licensing company. Finjan spent over a decade developing and selling cybersecurity hardware and software technologies into the market. And today, that innovation sits at the core of modern security architectures. While we may have spun out this portion of our business in 2009, the underlying patents covering those very same technology are owned and enforced by our wholly-owned subsidiary Finjan, Inc. It’s noteworthy that these patents were not acquired from third parties, but the result of Finjan’s own R&amp;D investment now spend in two decades. More recently, our patents have proven to be durable, following numerous validity challenges by accused infringers or defendant and findings by the court the USPTO and the PTAB. While defendants have tried to invalidate 16 different Finjan patents, the PTAB has denied petitions to review 12 and has instituted a review on four. Looking ahead, while we remain committed to vigorously protecting our IP, one of our key objectives as a public company is to grow beyond licensing our patent, by continuing to invest in product development through Finjan mobile, advisory services through our CybeRisk division, and managing our investment in early-stage cybersecurity firms. As a public company, we understand the unpredictability of licensing events, and as we look to deliver the highest return to shareholders developing and fostering more predictable revenue streams is imperative, as we continue to build out our cybersecurity businesses. Returning to the USPTO and PTAB, there are a couple of different administrative pathways to challenge the validity of a patent. Today, Finjan is currently enforcing 22 U.S. patents across our litigation, with a total of 45 administrative challenges having been filed. Of those 45, 15 are Joinders, which means that it’s an attempt of one company to use another’s petition for an administrative challenge to which they can join. Of the 32 decisions received, 28 have been denied or rescinded by the petitioner leading to a strong 88% kill rate. Compare that to the USPTO statistics, which comparatively show the opposite that nearly 80% of challenge patents in an Inter Partes Review or IPR fail to survive. A fact that we think is significant and supports our claim to the quality and durability of our patent portfolio. The 12% institution rate applies to review of 4 Finjan patents, which now entered the standard process for administrative review. While challenges to patents can often lead to the diminishment of value of such assets forcing some companies out of business completely, Finjan has had the inversed experience. Although this barrage of challenges to our patents has been formidable, the silver lining is that the validity of nearly all of our patents challenged thus far has been confirmed either by the court, the USPTO or the PTAB. This leads us to a fast-approaching turning point, where the pool of prior art will be exhausted and the chances of invalidating Finjan’s patents becomes implausible. Turning to a review of our enforcement calendar, Finjan’s code of conduct is well-established through our licensing best practices, in which we clearly lay out our preference for a licensing pathway. Despite our preference to license, the need to enforce our patent through litigation to preserve the value and legitimacy of our innovations has become an unfortunate necessity. Unfortunate, because it burdens the court. It induces significant expense to be incurred by both sides, extends timeline and most significantly leads down an unpredictable path for both parties. With respect to our initial dispute with Blue Coat Systems, the $39.5 million jury award from the District Court is now final. In addition, the District Court granted Finjan pre and post judgment interest on the jury’s award. Blue Coat has the option to appeal to the Federal Circuit, which we would expect to run no less than one year from an anticipated Blue Coat notice of intent to appeal the decision. As many are aware, we have filed a second separate suit against Blue Coat, again, before judge Beth Labson Freeman, the same judge as in Blue Coat one. The second case was initiated, because Blue Coat continues to acquire new company wants new technology offering, and Finjan continues to be issued new patent. Judge Freeman recently denied Blue Coat’s motion to stay this second case, while we await final resolution of pending administrative challenges to certain claims of Finjan’s patents. Today, the remaining seven patents asserted in that second case against Blue Coat are not subject to any administrative challenges at the USPTO or PTAB. Separately, given Blue Coat’s continued and now willful infringement of Finjan’s patent, we filed a motion for preliminary injunction on July 29, to stop Blue Coat from selling or offering for sale its infringing WebPulse product. Hearing on this motion is scheduled to go before Judge Freeman on November 10, 2016. All of this aside, we remain committed to finding a mutually beneficial resolution with Blue Coat through a licensing and settlement agreement to resolve both cases. On a related note, Symantec’s recent acquisition of Blue Coat for more than $4.5 billion was completed earlier this month, just a week or so ago. We have a separate case against Symantec in which our stay was lifted on August 1, and order from the court on our Markman hearing is imminent and we expect to have a trial date for this case set for the first-half of 2018. I’d like to make some quick comments on our recent license and settled agreement with Proofpoint. This is the way results the both party. As Finjan is always there, we prefer to enter into licensing agreement for fair value rather than seek full value in front of the judge and jury. From a peer business perspective, disputes results through meaningful discussions between the parties and ending with a handshake is always our preference as it removes the uncertainties to both parties that you often encounter in courtroom. Next a brief update on our litigation with Sophos. This case is scheduled to go to trial beginning on September 6, 2016, letting infringement of six Finjan patents, which as expected was decreased from original eight patents in an effort to streamline the issues for jury. Despite the streamline and the case is expected to last at least until September 20, given the allocation of time to each side and the court available schedule. Finjan is confident of the merit of this case, comfortable with the various rulings by the court today and working to further streamline the case for trial. Turning to our recent lawsuit against ESET, after a year-and-a-half of meeting, the parties came to impasse in their licensing negotiation, as such we have sued ESET and its affiliate in the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California for infringement of, at least, six Finjan patent and in Germany for infringement of one of Finjan’s European patent. In the Northern California case Finjan is speaking among other things, a jury trial, damages of not less than $44 million, injunctive relief, enhanced damages and reasonable attorney fees and costs, a Case Management Conference or CMC is scheduled to take place on September 29, 2016. In Germany, the CMC has already been held and a trial date is set for July 6, 2017. ESET filed a contemporaneous territory relief action of non-infringement of Finjan asserted patent in the Southern District to California. Lastly, while the Palo Alto Networks and FireEye cases remains stayed pending administrative proceeding before the USPTO and PTAB. We will seek to lift the stay in our FireEye case over the next month or two as the USPTO finalizes its re-examination and review of two Finjan’s patent in that case. Again in Finjan’s favor with the claims being confirmed not changed in both patent. I would now like to turn the call over to Michael to run through our second-quarter results and our recently announced financing in more detail. Michael? Michael Noonan Thanks, Phil and I’d like to begin with an update of our second quarter results. Please note that unless otherwise stated, all comparisons are on a year-over-year basis. We had $6.5 million in revenues, primarily due to the initial payment from our license and settlement at Proofpoint, and two other licensing agreements in the quarter ended June 30, 2016. The other two licenses were $1.65 million from a December 2015 license agreement, contracted revenue and $565,000 from a license that we settled in that quarter. This compared to revenue $700,000 a year ago. Please note that we have already surpassed revenue for the full-year of 2015 and we expect additional revenue in both the third quarter and fourth quarter of this current fiscal year. Operating expenses was primarily consists of SG&amp;A, decreased 28% or $1.2 million to $3.3 million. Expenses for emerging businesses CybeRisk contingent on mobile increased by about $300,000 to $1 million. Despite our two emerging businesses increased revenue and coupled with prudent expense controls led to a nearly threefold improvement in our net income, which excluding the accretion for our Series A preferred financing with all most $900,000 or $0.04 a share. We ended the quarter with $17.2 million in cash and cash equivalents and $13.2 million in working capital. The $11.1 million cash increase from December 2015 is primarily due to our recent $10 million financing, which is the preferred Series A offering that I noted earlier and approximately $9 million received from licensing agreements in the first six months ending June 30, 2016. Again, we have worked diligently to manage expenses and costs across the organizations, helping us to achieve a flat to declining operating expense on a quarterly basis. Our agreement with our outside counsel as given us the opportunity to proactively manage our cash through e-payments, so in periods of trials, we’re not left with a one-time nasal [ph] payment and we are able to maintain our industry-leading gross margins. Now I’d like to offer an update on our emerging businesses. Turning to CybeRisk, we successfully amended our first client while we only recognized $50,000 in revenue in the second quarter. We succeeded in $150,000 in bookings for the total quarter. We will recognize revenue as work is completed with this client and other clients. We have proactively increased our social media efforts in offering weekly bought into share our cybersecurity advisory expertise with the industry and to help build the CybeRisk brand. Our increased outreach has certainly driven traffic to our site and we expect over time will help resource both customers and partners. Gary Moore, one of our Board Members continues to be an asset to Finjan and CybeRisk executive team as we grow this business. Turning to Finjan Mobile, we are working towards our third version of our mobile secure browser build-off Finjan patent technology. We expect this version to be available to the consumer by the end of September of this year. It will feature, among other things new branding, passcode access, menu bar, settings, browsing history and detailed virus information, projecting mobile devices in the workplace and securing data, so it doesn’t leave the network is next on our radar. We have conducted an initial research to find 88% of individuals share file through email and nearly 64% of those individuals are concerned about security and sending attachments, which shows that offering an application to protect both the center of the file in the be well received. Let’s move on nearly 50% of those respondents reported the share file through the mobile phone, showing once again mobile devices in the security and protection of them are essential. Now I’d like to turn to our investment in the cybersecurity of the future through Jerusalem Venture Partners or JVP. We made a $3,000 contribution to the fund in May of this year, bringing our total investment to $2 million. We have an additional $3 million outstanding capital commitment to JVP or Jerusalem Venture Partners fund. I’d like to now give an update on our Series A preferred financing, following the close of the quarter, be redeemed $2.6 million or 17,000 shares of the Series A preferred stock. As a reminder, these shares to be redeemed a liquidation price of 1.5 times the original purchase price within 90 days, 1.65 times the purchase price before 360 days and 1.75 times the purchase price before 720 days. Our momentum in the quarter has led to early redemption of the shares will continue to redeem shares as opportunities arise. We believe we are on track to redeem and retire all of those shares by the middle of 2017. We continue to believe the structure of this financing is ideal, so we’re not facing massive payment in the future as we had hire waterfall revenue events. Please recall, there were no warrants or revenue details with the preferred shares, once they are redeem, they are gone. Now with that, I’d like to turn the call back over to Vanessa to coordinate the Q&amp;A period. Vanessa Winter Thank you, Michael. Operator, can you please take our first question? Question-and-Answer Session Operator We will now begin the question-and-answer session. [Operator Instructions] The first question comes from Mike Crawford, B. Riley &amp; Company. Please go ahead. Mike Crawford Thank you. Phil, you mentioned that none of the patents have started in the second Blue Coat case or subject to any administrative challenges? Is that a function of these patents you’ve already survived prior challenges that are already cleared, or do you expect some challenges to potentially merge? Phil Hartstein That’s a good question, Mike, and thanks for asking, always happy to clarify things here. So in the second Blue Coat case, the vast majority of challenges that were filed by Blue Coat were Joinders, which mean, they actually used a petition from another party challenging Finjan’s patent. So, I guess, the answer to your question would be, yes, the Finjan patents have already been reviewed under an – an earlier IPR for which there – the Blue Coat Joinder motion was effectively quashed. Mike Crawford Okay. Thank you. And then do you have this 500,000 license from unnamed security company in Q2. How would you quantify the number and scope of such licensing discussions you currently have and might – that might lead to some other fruitful event like that? Phil Hartstein I think there’s two questions in there. First, let me see, if I can give you a little bit more color about that license, and then I think the second part of your question is, how do we give you some indication of whether or not we expect more licensing to come in over what period? To the first part of the question, each negotiation that we have with licensees is unique right? They’re all in different segments of the market. They all have perhaps various challenges to their own businesses. And that’s why I think you see a lot of flexibility from Finjan in terms of being flexible and payment structures. If you read the disclosure on that license, specifically you’ll note that it was a term license, which is again something that Finjan was willing to be flexible within that – in that instance. The second part is, we still believe that our licensing business has the potential to offset the entire operating expense for the company. To-date, I think we’ve communicated that on our previous call for sure, I recall this was that in 2015, I think, we did $5 million approximately of licensing revenue. To-date, we’ve already done seven, and I think we have contracted revenue now that maybe take even farther closer to 10. And with that, I would say, we’re only in the halfway part of the year. And as we’ve seen in prior years, especially in the fourth quarter, you do see some acceleration and additional motivation for parties that we’re talking to, to actually complete those deals. We’ve also disclosed recently that we have, at least, 25 negotiations ongoing, which is probably first time that we’ve actually disclosed numerically sort of the volume of ongoing negotiations with parties. And again, each of those is in a varying stage, some of those, for example, are advanced significantly, while others may just be beginning. Mike Crawford Okay. Thank you. And then just switching gears regarding the JV key fund, where there has already been one liquidity event out of their stay active. And I’m wondering if you can – to what – any, I would appreciate into any extent you can comment on the other investments that are in there whether any of those look promising? Phil Hartstein I’m sure I’ve learned something very interesting about being invested in a venture fund. And so I’ll have to keep my comment somewhat limited. It turns out they’re confidential information for which I’m not able to disclose. But you could very easily go to JVPs website and you could see that in their Cyber Strategic Partners Fund that they have made a total of six investments in company out of that fund to-date. You could sort through them and actually, I think, they follow a really good theme. But generally, the theme would be around data, Big Data, security, and consumer data security that’s really sort of – at a top level what the theme is – the type of investment company that they’re looking for. But we actually go a little over deeper and what they’re looking at is, what’s the next – the next state of the art. Mike Crawford And so we’ve talked a lot about when we were talking about antivirus that was really reactive technology, what Finjan developed was proactive behavior-based, and what JVP is looking to invest in is really kind of predictive right? What’s the next out there in the industry? Phil Hartstein And so, yes, I would tell you that, we’re happy with their investments. We’re excited about the direction of those companies are going. But you’d have to look at JVP’s website to get more information than that. Mike Crawford Okay, great. Thank you very much. Phil Hartstein Thank you. I appreciate it. Operator The next question comes from Lisa Thomson Zacks Investment Research. Please go ahead. Lisa Thomson Hello. Hi Phil, Michael, and Vanessa. Phil Hartstein
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://seekingalpha.com/article/3999067-finjan-holdings-fnjn-ceo-phil-hartstein-q2-2016-results-earnings-call-transcript</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0550</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Finjan Holdings, Inc. (NASDAQ: FNJN ) Q2 2016 Earnings Conference Call August 11, 2016 4:30 PM ET Executives Vanessa Winter - Director of Investor Relations &amp; Corporate Communications Phil Hartstein - President and Chief Executive Officer Michael Noonan - Chief Financial Officer and Treasurer Analysts Mike Crawford - B. Riley &amp; Co. LLC Lisa Thomson - Zacks Investment Research Operator Thank you for standing by. This is the conference operator. Welcome to the Finjan Second Quarter Earnings Update Call. As a reminder, all participants are in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions. [Operator Instructions] I would now like to turn the conference over to Vanessa Winter, Investor Relations. Please go ahead. Vanessa Winter Hello, everyone, and thank you for joining us this afternoon for a review of our second quarter 2016 results. Joining me on today’s call is Phil Hartstein, Finjan’s President and CEO; and Michael Noonan, CFO. As a reminder, this call is being webcast and a replay of the webcast will be available on our website. Before I begin, I would like to quickly make note of our Safe Harbor. During the course of this call, we may make statements related to the overall business outlook, future financial operating results, timing of redemption of shares of Series A preferred stock, outcomes of our pending and future litigation, accounting matters and future prospects. These are forward-looking statements based on certain assumptions and are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties that could cause future results to differ materially from our expectations. You can learn more about these risks in our most recent Form 10-K filed with the SEC on March 25, 2016 as well as our subsequent filings. These documents are available on the Investor Relations page of our website at www.finjan.com. We assume no obligation to update any forward-looking statements. I’d also like to mention, Finjan management will be presenting at a number of upcoming conferences, so we hope to get the opportunity to touch face with many of you in person. We will present at the [indiscernible] Investor Conference on September 7 at 2:30 PM in San Francisco; the Rodman Investor Conference at 3:30 PM Eastern Time on September 13, in New York; and the Aegis Capital Conference on September 21, at 10:00 AM in Las Vegas. We will also be presenting at the Microchip Conferences in Philadelphia on October 17, and the Drexel Hamilton Conference in New York on November 10. Please contact me vanessa@finjan.com to schedule a meeting. With that, I would like to turn the call over to Phil Hartstein, Finjan’s President and CEO. Phil? Phil Hartstein Thank you, Vanessa, and thank you all for joining today’s call. After what was probably one of the busiest quarters we’ve had in our licensing and enforcement program, I’m looking forward to sharing an update on our progress on all fronts. I will begin today’s call discussing our success in defending Finjan’s patent at the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office or USPTO, and The Patent Trial and Appeal Board or PTAB against administrative challenges, provide an update on our litigation schedule and offer some color on our continued licensing efforts before turning the call over to Michael, who will address the financial and operational sides of our business. If you spend anytime following the world of cybersecurity technology, you will likely run across Finjan’s name. This was the reason we were recently approached by Bloomberg at the subject matter of an in-depth article titled Cybersecurity’s Top Patent Litigator. In November, Finjan celebrates its 20th anniversary and it’s satisfying to see this both media and the overall investment community are calling out the fundamental distinctions of Finjan as an operating company against a narrower set of patent licensing company. Finjan spent over a decade developing and selling cybersecurity hardware and software technologies into the market. And today, that innovation sits at the core of modern security architectures. While we may have spun out this portion of our business in 2009, the underlying patents covering those very same technology are owned and enforced by our wholly-owned subsidiary Finjan, Inc. It’s noteworthy that these patents were not acquired from third parties, but the result of Finjan’s own R&amp;D investment now spend in two decades. More recently, our patents have proven to be durable, following numerous validity challenges by accused infringers or defendant and findings by the court the USPTO and the PTAB. While defendants have tried to invalidate 16 different Finjan patents, the PTAB has denied petitions to review 12 and has instituted a review on four. Looking ahead, while we remain committed to vigorously protecting our IP, one of our key objectives as a public company is to grow beyond licensing our patent, by continuing to invest in product development through Finjan mobile, advisory services through our CybeRisk division, and managing our investment in early-stage cybersecurity firms. As a public company, we understand the unpredictability of licensing events, and as we look to deliver the highest return to shareholders developing and fostering more predictable revenue streams is imperative, as we continue to build out our cybersecurity businesses. Returning to the USPTO and PTAB, there are a couple of different administrative pathways to challenge the validity of a patent. Today, Finjan is currently enforcing 22 U.S. patents across our litigation, with a total of 45 administrative challenges having been filed. Of those 45, 15 are Joinders, which means that it’s an attempt of one company to use another’s petition for an administrative challenge to which they can join. Of the 32 decisions received, 28 have been denied or rescinded by the petitioner leading to a strong 88% kill rate. Compare that to the USPTO statistics, which comparatively show the opposite that nearly 80% of challenge patents in an Inter Partes Review or IPR fail to survive. A fact that we think is significant and supports our claim to the quality and durability of our patent portfolio. The 12% institution rate applies to review of 4 Finjan patents, which now entered the standard process for administrative review. While challenges to patents can often lead to the diminishment of value of such assets forcing some companies out of business completely, Finjan has had the inversed experience. Although this barrage of challenges to our patents has been formidable, the silver lining is that the validity of nearly all of our patents challenged thus far has been confirmed either by the court, the USPTO or the PTAB. This leads us to a fast-approaching turning point, where the pool of prior art will be exhausted and the chances of invalidating Finjan’s patents becomes implausible. Turning to a review of our enforcement calendar, Finjan’s code of conduct is well-established through our licensing best practices, in which we clearly lay out our preference for a licensing pathway. Despite our preference to license, the need to enforce our patent through litigation to preserve the value and legitimacy of our innovations has become an unfortunate necessity. Unfortunate, because it burdens the court. It induces significant expense to be incurred by both sides, extends timeline and most significantly leads down an unpredictable path for both parties. With respect to our initial dispute with Blue Coat Systems, the $39.5 million jury award from the District Court is now final. In addition, the District Court granted Finjan pre and post judgment interest on the jury’s award. Blue Coat has the option to appeal to the Federal Circuit, which we would expect to run no less than one year from an anticipated Blue Coat notice of intent to appeal the decision. As many are aware, we have filed a second separate suit against Blue Coat, again, before judge Beth Labson Freeman, the same judge as in Blue Coat one. The second case was initiated, because Blue Coat continues to acquire new company wants new technology offering, and Finjan continues to be issued new patent. Judge Freeman recently denied Blue Coat’s motion to stay this second case, while we await final resolution of pending administrative challenges to certain claims of Finjan’s patents. Today, the remaining seven patents asserted in that second case against Blue Coat are not subject to any administrative challenges at the USPTO or PTAB. Separately, given Blue Coat’s continued and now willful infringement of Finjan’s patent, we filed a motion for preliminary injunction on July 29, to stop Blue Coat from selling or offering for sale its infringing WebPulse product. Hearing on this motion is scheduled to go before Judge Freeman on November 10, 2016. All of this aside, we remain committed to finding a mutually beneficial resolution with Blue Coat through a licensing and settlement agreement to resolve both cases. On a related note, Symantec’s recent acquisition of Blue Coat for more than $4.5 billion was completed earlier this month, just a week or so ago. We have a separate case against Symantec in which our stay was lifted on August 1, and order from the court on our Markman hearing is imminent and we expect to have a trial date for this case set for the first-half of 2018. I’d like to make some quick comments on our recent license and settled agreement with Proofpoint. This is the way results the both party. As Finjan is always there, we prefer to enter into licensing agreement for fair value rather than seek full value in front of the judge and jury. From a peer business perspective, disputes results through meaningful discussions between the parties and ending with a handshake is always our preference as it removes the uncertainties to both parties that you often encounter in courtroom. Next a brief update on our litigation with Sophos. This case is scheduled to go to trial beginning on September 6, 2016, letting infringement of six Finjan patents, which as expected was decreased from original eight patents in an effort to streamline the issues for jury. Despite the streamline and the case is expected to last at least until September 20, given the allocation of time to each side and the court available schedule. Finjan is confident of the merit of this case, comfortable with the various rulings by the court today and working to further streamline the case for trial. Turning to our recent lawsuit against ESET, after a year-and-a-half of meeting, the parties came to impasse in their licensing negotiation, as such we have sued ESET and its affiliate in the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California for infringement of, at least, six Finjan patent and in Germany for infringement of one of Finjan’s European patent. In the Northern California case Finjan is speaking among other things, a jury trial, damages of not less than $44 million, injunctive relief, enhanced damages and reasonable attorney fees and costs, a Case Management Conference or CMC is scheduled to take place on September 29, 2016. In Germany, the CMC has already been held and a trial date is set for July 6, 2017. ESET filed a contemporaneous territory relief action of non-infringement of Finjan asserted patent in the Southern District to California. Lastly, while the Palo Alto Networks and FireEye cases remains stayed pending administrative proceeding before the USPTO and PTAB. We will seek to lift the stay in our FireEye case over the next month or two as the USPTO finalizes its re-examination and review of two Finjan’s patent in that case. Again in Finjan’s favor with the claims being confirmed not changed in both patent. I would now like to turn the call over to Michael to run through our second-quarter results and our recently announced financing in more detail. Michael? Michael Noonan Thanks, Phil and I’d like to begin with an update of our second quarter results. Please note that unless otherwise stated, all comparisons are on a year-over-year basis. We had $6.5 million in revenues, primarily due to the initial payment from our license and settlement at Proofpoint, and two other licensing agreements in the quarter ended June 30, 2016. The other two licenses were $1.65 million from a December 2015 license agreement, contracted revenue and $565,000 from a license that we settled in that quarter. This compared to revenue $700,000 a year ago. Please note that we have already surpassed revenue for the full-year of 2015 and we expect additional revenue in both the third quarter and fourth quarter of this current fiscal year. Operating expenses was primarily consists of SG&amp;A, decreased 28% or $1.2 million to $3.3 million. Expenses for emerging businesses CybeRisk contingent on mobile increased by about $300,000 to $1 million. Despite our two emerging businesses increased revenue and coupled with prudent expense controls led to a nearly threefold improvement in our net income, which excluding the accretion for our Series A preferred financing with all most $900,000 or $0.04 a share. We ended the quarter with $17.2 million in cash and cash equivalents and $13.2 million in working capital. The $11.1 million cash increase from December 2015 is primarily due to our recent $10 million financing, which is the preferred Series A offering that I noted earlier and approximately $9 million received from licensing agreements in the first six months ending June 30, 2016. Again, we have worked diligently to manage expenses and costs across the organizations, helping us to achieve a flat to declining operating expense on a quarterly basis. Our agreement with our outside counsel as given us the opportunity to proactively manage our cash through e-payments, so in periods of trials, we’re not left with a one-time nasal [ph] payment and we are able to maintain our industry-leading gross margins. Now I’d like to offer an update on our emerging businesses. Turning to CybeRisk, we successfully amended our first client while we only recognized $50,000 in revenue in the second quarter. We succeeded in $150,000 in bookings for the total quarter. We will recognize revenue as work is completed with this client and other clients. We have proactively increased our social media efforts in offering weekly bought into share our cybersecurity advisory expertise with the industry and to help build the CybeRisk brand. Our increased outreach has certainly driven traffic to our site and we expect over time will help resource both customers and partners. Gary Moore, one of our Board Members continues to be an asset to Finjan and CybeRisk executive team as we grow this business. Turning to Finjan Mobile, we are working towards our third version of our mobile secure browser build-off Finjan patent technology. We expect this version to be available to the consumer by the end of September of this year. It will feature, among other things new branding, passcode access, menu bar, settings, browsing history and detailed virus information, projecting mobile devices in the workplace and securing data, so it doesn’t leave the network is next on our radar. We have conducted an initial research to find 88% of individuals share file through email and nearly 64% of those individuals are concerned about security and sending attachments, which shows that offering an application to protect both the center of the file in the be well received. Let’s move on nearly 50% of those respondents reported the share file through the mobile phone, showing once again mobile devices in the security and protection of them are essential. Now I’d like to turn to our investment in the cybersecurity of the future through Jerusalem Venture Partners or JVP. We made a $3,000 contribution to the fund in May of this year, bringing our total investment to $2 million. We have an additional $3 million outstanding capital commitment to JVP or Jerusalem Venture Partners fund. I’d like to now give an update on our Series A preferred financing, following the close of the quarter, be redeemed $2.6 million or 17,000 shares of the Series A preferred stock. As a reminder, these shares to be redeemed a liquidation price of 1.5 times the original purchase price within 90 days, 1.65 times the purchase price before 360 days and 1.75 times the purchase price before 720 days. Our momentum in the quarter has led to early redemption of the shares will continue to redeem shares as opportunities arise. We believe we are on track to redeem and retire all of those shares by the middle of 2017. We continue to believe the structure of this financing is ideal, so we’re not facing massive payment in the future as we had hire waterfall revenue events. Please recall, there were no warrants or revenue details with the preferred shares, once they are redeem, they are gone. Now with that, I’d like to turn the call back over to Vanessa to coordinate the Q&amp;A period. Vanessa Winter Thank you, Michael. Operator, can you please take our first question? Question-and-Answer Session Operator We will now begin the question-and-answer session. [Operator Instructions] The first question comes from Mike Crawford, B. Riley &amp; Company. Please go ahead. Mike Crawford Thank you. Phil, you mentioned that none of the patents have started in the second Blue Coat case or subject to any administrative challenges? Is that a function of these patents you’ve already survived prior challenges that are already cleared, or do you expect some challenges to potentially merge? Phil Hartstein That’s a good question, Mike, and thanks for asking, always happy to clarify things here. So in the second Blue Coat case, the vast majority of challenges that were filed by Blue Coat were Joinders, which mean, they actually used a petition from another party challenging Finjan’s patent. So, I guess, the answer to your question would be, yes, the Finjan patents have already been reviewed under an – an earlier IPR for which there – the Blue Coat Joinder motion was effectively quashed. Mike Crawford Okay. Thank you. And then do you have this 500,000 license from unnamed security company in Q2. How would you quantify the number and scope of such licensing discussions you currently have and might – that might lead to some other fruitful event like that? Phil Hartstein I think there’s two questions in there. First, let me see, if I can give you a little bit more color about that license, and then I think the second part of your question is, how do we give you some indication of whether or not we expect more licensing to come in over what period? To the first part of the question, each negotiation that we have with licensees is unique right? They’re all in different segments of the market. They all have perhaps various challenges to their own businesses. And that’s why I think you see a lot of flexibility from Finjan in terms of being flexible and payment structures. If you read the disclosure on that license, specifically you’ll note that it was a term license, which is again something that Finjan was willing to be flexible within that – in that instance. The second part is, we still believe that our licensing business has the potential to offset the entire operating expense for the company. To-date, I think we’ve communicated that on our previous call for sure, I recall this was that in 2015, I think, we did $5 million approximately of licensing revenue. To-date, we’ve already done seven, and I think we have contracted revenue now that maybe take even farther closer to 10. And with that, I would say, we’re only in the halfway part of the year. And as we’ve seen in prior years, especially in the fourth quarter, you do see some acceleration and additional motivation for parties that we’re talking to, to actually complete those deals. We’ve also disclosed recently that we have, at least, 25 negotiations ongoing, which is probably first time that we’ve actually disclosed numerically sort of the volume of ongoing negotiations with parties. And again, each of those is in a varying stage, some of those, for example, are advanced significantly, while others may just be beginning. Mike Crawford Okay. Thank you. And then just switching gears regarding the JV key fund, where there has already been one liquidity event out of their stay active. And I’m wondering if you can – to what – any, I would appreciate into any extent you can comment on the other investments that are in there whether any of those look promising? Phil Hartstein I’m sure I’ve learned something very interesting about being invested in a venture fund. And so I’ll have to keep my comment somewhat limited. It turns out they’re confidential information for which I’m not able to disclose. But you could very easily go to JVPs website and you could see that in their Cyber Strategic Partners Fund that they have made a total of six investments in company out of that fund to-date. You could sort through them and actually, I think, they follow a really good theme. But generally, the theme would be around data, Big Data, security, and consumer data security that’s really sort of – at a top level what the theme is – the type of investment company that they’re looking for. But we actually go a little over deeper and what they’re looking at is, what’s the next – the next state of the art. Mike Crawford And so we’ve talked a lot about when we were talking about antivirus that was really reactive technology, what Finjan developed was proactive behavior-based, and what JVP is looking to invest in is really kind of predictive right? What’s the next out there in the industry? Phil Hartstein And so, yes, I would tell you that, we’re happy with their investments. We’re excited about the direction of those companies are going. But you’d have to look at JVP’s website to get more information than that. Mike Crawford Okay, great. Thank you very much. Phil Hartstein Thank you. I appreciate it. Operator The next question comes from Lisa Thomson Zacks Investment Research. Please go ahead. Lisa Thomson Hello. Hi Phil, Michael, and Vanessa. Phil Hartstein
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://staticseekingalpha1.a.ssl.fastly.net/images/users_profile/000/101/639/big_pic.png?1361390405</main_image>
</document>
