<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Saratoga Chowderfest Champion to compete for Best in New England Title</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://news10.com/2016/08/11/saratoga-chowderfest-champion-to-compete-for-best-in-new-england-title/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
SARATOGA, N.Y. (NEWS10) — Gaffney’s Restaurant, the 2016 Saratoga Chowderfest champion, will be competing against the best of New England this fall! 
The event showcases 40 award winning restaurants representing every New England state as well as “America’s Favorite Chowder” who hails from Seattle Washington. The 9th annual event is to be held on Sunday October 2 at Sherwood Island State Park in Westport, CT. 
It includes champions from Vermont, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, Massachusetts, Connecticut and now – Saratoga Springs. Gaffneys Facebook Page 
“Foodies love to travel and we’ve arranged a special bus trip for chowder lovers from Saratoga to not just experience a tremendous event but to root on their home town champions” said Keenan. The bus trip will leave Gaffney’s at 8AM and the deal includes round trip transportation, ticket to the event, the official Chowdafest hat, muffin/coffee for the trip down and a sample holder for unlimited sampling at the event. The bus returns by 5pm with the hope of a victory celebration at Gaffney’s, all for $75. Space is limited and tickets are first come, first serve basis and can be found online at http://www.Chowdafest.org under the ticket and deals tab. “Knowing how much Saratogians love their chowder, we expect these tickets to be sold out quickly”. Initial ticket deadline is Sept 1st. “Depending on demand, we can add extra buses – we’ll seat 50 people per bus” said Keenan. 

Gaffney’s is entered in the very competitive creative chowder category and they’re not stopping with their chowder. Gaffney’s plans to have a very creative booth and are working with a local artisan on the design. 
Chowdafest has raised enough to fund over 400,000 meals in the ongoing fight against hunger and has a goal to reach a half million meals this fall. The event is also a model of sustainability as it’s a zero waste event where everything is composted, no garbage. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://news10.com/2016/08/11/saratoga-chowderfest-champion-to-compete-for-best-in-new-england-title/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Ali Stewart</username>
<post>
Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
SARATOGA, N.Y. (NEWS10) — Gaffney’s Restaurant, the 2016 Saratoga Chowderfest champion, will be competing against the best of New England this fall! 
The event showcases 40 award winning restaurants representing every New England state as well as “America’s Favorite Chowder” who hails from Seattle Washington. The 9th annual event is to be held on Sunday October 2 at Sherwood Island State Park in Westport, CT. 
It includes champions from Vermont, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, Massachusetts, Connecticut and now – Saratoga Springs. Gaffneys Facebook Page 
“Foodies love to travel and we’ve arranged a special bus trip for chowder lovers from Saratoga to not just experience a tremendous event but to root on their home town champions” said Keenan. The bus trip will leave Gaffney’s at 8AM and the deal includes round trip transportation, ticket to the event, the official Chowdafest hat, muffin/coffee for the trip down and a sample holder for unlimited sampling at the event. The bus returns by 5pm with the hope of a victory celebration at Gaffney’s, all for $75. Space is limited and tickets are first come, first serve basis and can be found online at http://www.Chowdafest.org under the ticket and deals tab. “Knowing how much Saratogians love their chowder, we expect these tickets to be sold out quickly”. Initial ticket deadline is Sept 1st. “Depending on demand, we can add extra buses – we’ll seat 50 people per bus” said Keenan. 

Gaffney’s is entered in the very competitive creative chowder category and they’re not stopping with their chowder. Gaffney’s plans to have a very creative booth and are working with a local artisan on the design. 
Chowdafest has raised enough to fund over 400,000 meals in the ongoing fight against hunger and has a goal to reach a half million meals this fall. The event is also a model of sustainability as it’s a zero waste event where everything is composted, no garbage. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://mgtvwten.files.wordpress.com/2016/02/chowder.jpg</main_image>
</document>
