<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Kayla Harrison makes judo history with another gold | wltx.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wltx.com/sports/olympics/kayla-harrison-makes-judo-history-with-another-gold/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wltx&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;kayla-harrison-makes-judo-history-with-another-gold&amp;#x2f;295198006</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Kayla Harrison makes judo history with another gold Kaylin Harris defends her 2012 gold medal by winning gold again in the 73Kg category in 2016. Dan Wolken, USA TODAY Sports , KING 9:48 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Kayla Harrison (USA, white) competes in a women&apos;s 78-kilogram quarterfinal judo contest at Carioca Arena 2 during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games on Aug. 11. (Photo: Kyle Terada-USA TODAY Sports) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
RIO DE JANEIRO - American Kayla Harrison has another gold medal. Call it one more for the road. 
Expected to retire following these Olympics and become the next female star in professional mixed martial arts, Harrison defeated France’s Audrey Tcheumeo to win a second judo gold medal in the 78-kilogram weight class in front of a disappointed Brazilian crowd that was hoping to watch Harrison take on Mayra Aguiar. 
Harrison, 26, had predicted a matchup with Aguiar more than a year ago as the two have been longtime rivals and had split their first 14 meetings. It would have recalled echoes of 2012, when she beat Britain’s Gemma Gibbons in London in the gold medal match. 
Instead, she faced Tcheumeo and did not seem to be getting the best of the action until the final minute when she finally got Tcheumeo on the ground for a decisive win by ippon. 
Harrison rolled into the semifinals, defeating Anamari Velensek of Slovenia in 1 minute, 43 seconds with an armbar move that immediately ended the match. Her earlier matches weren’t any longer, confirming her dominance in this tournament. 
Harrison is only the second American judoku ever to win two Olympic medals, following Jimmy Pedro (her coach) in 1996 and 2004. Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Simone Manuel (L) and Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak react after they equally won the Women&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / GABRIEL BOUYS (Photo credit should read GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images) GABRIEL BOUYS, This content is subject to copyright. Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Competitors sail during the men’s Finn opening series race at Marina da Gloria during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Mandatory Credit: Eric Seals-USA TODAY Sports Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; United States defender Katelyn Falgowski (23) and midfield Melissa Gonzalez (5) battle for the ball with India defender Namita Toppo (19) during women&apos;s field hockey pool play in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Hockey Centre. Mandatory Credit: John David Mercer-USA TODAY Sports John David Mercer, John David Mercer Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Nathan Adrian (USA) during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wltx.com/sports/olympics/kayla-harrison-makes-judo-history-with-another-gold/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wltx&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;kayla-harrison-makes-judo-history-with-another-gold&amp;#x2f;295198006</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Kayla Harrison makes judo history with another gold Kaylin Harris defends her 2012 gold medal by winning gold again in the 73Kg category in 2016. Dan Wolken, USA TODAY Sports , KING 9:48 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Kayla Harrison (USA, white) competes in a women&apos;s 78-kilogram quarterfinal judo contest at Carioca Arena 2 during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games on Aug. 11. (Photo: Kyle Terada-USA TODAY Sports) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
RIO DE JANEIRO - American Kayla Harrison has another gold medal. Call it one more for the road. 
Expected to retire following these Olympics and become the next female star in professional mixed martial arts, Harrison defeated France’s Audrey Tcheumeo to win a second judo gold medal in the 78-kilogram weight class in front of a disappointed Brazilian crowd that was hoping to watch Harrison take on Mayra Aguiar. 
Harrison, 26, had predicted a matchup with Aguiar more than a year ago as the two have been longtime rivals and had split their first 14 meetings. It would have recalled echoes of 2012, when she beat Britain’s Gemma Gibbons in London in the gold medal match. 
Instead, she faced Tcheumeo and did not seem to be getting the best of the action until the final minute when she finally got Tcheumeo on the ground for a decisive win by ippon. 
Harrison rolled into the semifinals, defeating Anamari Velensek of Slovenia in 1 minute, 43 seconds with an armbar move that immediately ended the match. Her earlier matches weren’t any longer, confirming her dominance in this tournament. 
Harrison is only the second American judoku ever to win two Olympic medals, following Jimmy Pedro (her coach) in 1996 and 2004. Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Simone Manuel (L) and Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak react after they equally won the Women&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / GABRIEL BOUYS (Photo credit should read GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images) GABRIEL BOUYS, This content is subject to copyright. Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Competitors sail during the men’s Finn opening series race at Marina da Gloria during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Mandatory Credit: Eric Seals-USA TODAY Sports Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; United States defender Katelyn Falgowski (23) and midfield Melissa Gonzalez (5) battle for the ball with India defender Namita Toppo (19) during women&apos;s field hockey pool play in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Hockey Centre. Mandatory Credit: John David Mercer-USA TODAY Sports John David Mercer, John David Mercer Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Nathan Adrian (USA) during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.king5.com/photo/2016/08/11/636065258302267499-USP-OLYMPICS-JUDO-84098972_1470947754950_5085090_ver1.0_640_360.JPG</main_image>
</document>
