<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.wfaa.com/_/20/110040338/wfaa/home</forum>
<forum_title>WFAA - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Warrant issued for Dallas protest leader</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.wfaa.com/_/20/110040338/wfaa/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wfaa&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;local&amp;#x2f;dallas-county&amp;#x2f;warrant-issued-for-protest-leader-who-says-message-is-being-lost&amp;#x2f;295352107</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Warrant issued for protest leader, who says message is being lost Dallas Activist Leader defends criminals past Rebecca Lopez, WFAA 7:18 PM. CDT August 11, 2016 Minister Dominique Alexander speaks to a protest crowd through a megaphone. (Photo: WFAA) 
DALLAS -- Minister Dominique Alexander, the leader of the Next Generation Action Network , repeatedly calls for police to be held accountable for their actions, but some say Alexander needs to be held accountable for his own. 
The Rev. Ronald Wright leads the Justice Seekers organization. He has advice for Alexander. 
&quot;You need to make sure your own house is clean before you worry about sweeping off somebody&apos;s else&apos;s porch,” he said. 
Rev. Ronald Wright (Photo: WFAA) 
Alexander is on probation for 10 years. He pleaded guilty in Dallas county to shaking a baby, causing the child severe bodily injury in 2009. 
Since then, court records show he has repeatedly violated probation. 
“Because he is human,” said his attorney, Kim T. Cole. “He&apos;s committed crimes, for which he has served his time and he&apos;s done his public service for.” 
But court records show Alexander misses supervision meetings, he leaves Dallas County, he doesn&apos;t pay his court-ordered fees, and hasn&apos;t finished required anger management courses. 
Dominique Alexander (Photo: WFAA) 
His attorney told us Alexander “is not in violation of his probation,” but the Dallas Co. District Attorney&apos;s Office disagrees. On Thursday afternoon, the office issued a warrant for his arrest for a probation violation. 
It comes hours after Alexander was released from Dallas County Jail after his arrest on Wednesday . 
Alexander’s whirlwind day on Wednesday began when he was removed from a Dallas City Council meeting after a confrontation with Mayor Mike Rawlings. For that, Alexander was issued a criminal trespassing warning. Later in the day, Alexander was arrested for nine outstanding warrants out of Dallas and one hold for the Collin County Sheriff’s Office. He was released from Dallas County Jail just before noon on Thursday. 
Throughout an impromptu news conference once Alexander was released Thursday, Cole wouldn&apos;t let her client answer questions about the violations or his criminal past, and repeatedly told Alexander to “be quiet.” 
The attorney accused the media and the Dallas Police Department of &quot;demonizing&quot; Alexander because he is holding marches in downtown and questioning police about excessive force. 
Dominique Alexander along with his attorney, Kim T. Cole, address the media. (Photo: WFAA) 
&quot;He is constantly in their face and constantly calling them on the carpet, so of course they are going to call him on the carpet,” Cole said. 
But, it&apos;s not just Dallas police growing tired of Alexander. Several civil rights leaders have severed their ties with him and his group, the Next Generation Action Network. 
Rev. Wright has fought for changes at DPD for years. 
&quot;What is the purpose of these marches that are taking place in the city of Dallas?&quot; he asks. 
Dallas Police Chief David Brown had earlier asked Alexander to move a march that was scheduled for Wednesday night in downtown Dallas, to a more &quot;tactically advantageous&quot; area for officers&apos; safety. The chief offered to meet with Alexander, if he and the Next Generation Action Network would discontinue protests in the downtown area. 
The protest group is the same that marched through downtown on July 7, when five officers were killed in a deadly ambush. The protest started peacefully but ended when a lone shooter killed five officers. 
Alexander told police he would not cancel Wednesday’s protest, but that protesters would not march in the streets. He was arrested before the protest began. 
Dominique Alexander&apos;s mugshot from his arrest on outstanding warrants on Wednesday. (Photo: WFAA) 
&quot;I will not allow anybody to dictate to whether I feel accountable to the actions,” Alexander said. 
The protest went ahead, with a small group gathering downtown then marching to Dallas County Jail where some called for Alexander’s release. 
Alexander and his attorney say his message is being lost. 
They say people should focus on his message of change, and not his continuous legal problems. 
Copyright 2016 WFAA
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.wfaa.com/_/20/110040338/wfaa/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wfaa&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;news&amp;#x2f;local&amp;#x2f;dallas-county&amp;#x2f;warrant-issued-for-protest-leader-who-says-message-is-being-lost&amp;#x2f;295352107</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0018</post_time>
<username>Rebecca Lopez</username>
<post>
Warrant issued for protest leader, who says message is being lost Dallas Activist Leader defends criminals past Rebecca Lopez, WFAA 7:18 PM. CDT August 11, 2016 Minister Dominique Alexander speaks to a protest crowd through a megaphone. (Photo: WFAA) 
DALLAS -- Minister Dominique Alexander, the leader of the Next Generation Action Network , repeatedly calls for police to be held accountable for their actions, but some say Alexander needs to be held accountable for his own. 
The Rev. Ronald Wright leads the Justice Seekers organization. He has advice for Alexander. 
&quot;You need to make sure your own house is clean before you worry about sweeping off somebody&apos;s else&apos;s porch,” he said. 
Rev. Ronald Wright (Photo: WFAA) 
Alexander is on probation for 10 years. He pleaded guilty in Dallas county to shaking a baby, causing the child severe bodily injury in 2009. 
Since then, court records show he has repeatedly violated probation. 
“Because he is human,” said his attorney, Kim T. Cole. “He&apos;s committed crimes, for which he has served his time and he&apos;s done his public service for.” 
But court records show Alexander misses supervision meetings, he leaves Dallas County, he doesn&apos;t pay his court-ordered fees, and hasn&apos;t finished required anger management courses. 
Dominique Alexander (Photo: WFAA) 
His attorney told us Alexander “is not in violation of his probation,” but the Dallas Co. District Attorney&apos;s Office disagrees. On Thursday afternoon, the office issued a warrant for his arrest for a probation violation. 
It comes hours after Alexander was released from Dallas County Jail after his arrest on Wednesday . 
Alexander’s whirlwind day on Wednesday began when he was removed from a Dallas City Council meeting after a confrontation with Mayor Mike Rawlings. For that, Alexander was issued a criminal trespassing warning. Later in the day, Alexander was arrested for nine outstanding warrants out of Dallas and one hold for the Collin County Sheriff’s Office. He was released from Dallas County Jail just before noon on Thursday. 
Throughout an impromptu news conference once Alexander was released Thursday, Cole wouldn&apos;t let her client answer questions about the violations or his criminal past, and repeatedly told Alexander to “be quiet.” 
The attorney accused the media and the Dallas Police Department of &quot;demonizing&quot; Alexander because he is holding marches in downtown and questioning police about excessive force. 
Dominique Alexander along with his attorney, Kim T. Cole, address the media. (Photo: WFAA) 
&quot;He is constantly in their face and constantly calling them on the carpet, so of course they are going to call him on the carpet,” Cole said. 
But, it&apos;s not just Dallas police growing tired of Alexander. Several civil rights leaders have severed their ties with him and his group, the Next Generation Action Network. 
Rev. Wright has fought for changes at DPD for years. 
&quot;What is the purpose of these marches that are taking place in the city of Dallas?&quot; he asks. 
Dallas Police Chief David Brown had earlier asked Alexander to move a march that was scheduled for Wednesday night in downtown Dallas, to a more &quot;tactically advantageous&quot; area for officers&apos; safety. The chief offered to meet with Alexander, if he and the Next Generation Action Network would discontinue protests in the downtown area. 
The protest group is the same that marched through downtown on July 7, when five officers were killed in a deadly ambush. The protest started peacefully but ended when a lone shooter killed five officers. 
Alexander told police he would not cancel Wednesday’s protest, but that protesters would not march in the streets. He was arrested before the protest began. 
Dominique Alexander&apos;s mugshot from his arrest on outstanding warrants on Wednesday. (Photo: WFAA) 
&quot;I will not allow anybody to dictate to whether I feel accountable to the actions,” Alexander said. 
The protest went ahead, with a small group gathering downtown then marching to Dallas County Jail where some called for Alexander’s release. 
Alexander and his attorney say his message is being lost. 
They say people should focus on his message of change, and not his continuous legal problems. 
Copyright 2016 WFAA
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.wfaa.com/photo/2016/08/11/0811%20protests%205_1470960840440_5100212_ver1.0_640_360.JPG</main_image>
</document>
