<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://m.meetingsnet.com/rss.xml</forum>
<forum_title>MeetingsNet</forum_title>
<discussion_title>How to Make Docs’ Maintenance of Certification Easy</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://meetingsnet.com/cme-design/how-make-docs-maintenance-certification-easy</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Building on Success 
Many medical societies are interested in providing the Maintenance of Certification credits physicians need to satisfy their specialty board’s requirements. And why not? Physicians already can obtain the continuing medical education credits they need at Accreditation Council for CME–accredited and state-accredited provider activities. Why not extend that into dual-credit sessions that would provide MOC points as well at medical society annual meetings? 
After all, it doubles the draw to register for a conference if a physician can knock off CME credits and MOC points by attending the same session, making it a pretty attractive proposition for most medical societies. 
It just can be a little tricky to pull off. Here’s how the Heart Rhythm Society integrated elements of MOC into sessions at its 2016 Annual Meeting, which drew 13,000 attendees to the Moscone Convention Center in San Francisco in May. Hint: It pays to have the right technology. 
MOC Off to a Rocky Start The CME community viewed it as a major opportunity when the American Board of Medical Specialties launched the four-part MOC framework in the early 2000s—one part of which, Part 4, lifelong learning and self-assessment, is directly tied to CME. And it was in fact a great opportunity for CME providers in theory. However, with each of the 24 boards of medicine putting together their own individual MOC programs within the overall ABMS framework, it got a little messy. 
For example, the lifelong learning portion of the American Board of Internal Medicine’s MOC required that ABIM review and approve each activity, resulting in a huge backlog and few options for physicians to choose from (see this article for more ). 
HRS had offered MOC points at the annual conference for a few sessions in the past, says HRS Director, Scientific Sessions Programs and Education, Chloé Thomas. They had to work directly with ABIM to get the sessions certified, and “the process was manual and time consuming,” she says. 
Collaboration to the Rescue Last fall, ACCME and ABIM collaborated to streamline the process, enabling providers to input all the information needed for both the accreditor and the board into ACCME’s Program and Activity Reporting System, or PARS. 
“One of the catalysts for HRS offering MOC points this year was the way the ACCME and ABIM collaborated,” says HRS Manager, CME Programs and Meetings Operations, Tracy Blithe, CMP. Now that ACCME-accredited providers like HRS are no longer required to submit applications for activity approval for peer review to ABIM, HRS was able to provide MOC points for 12 of its 199 sessions this year. They also offered American Board of Pediatrics MOC points for four additional sessions. 
“We uploaded [the session data] into PARS, pushed a button saying, ‘Yes, we want to offer MOC credits for this,’ then all we had to do is upload our final data at the completion of the meeting,” says Blithe. 
The unified system “also makes it easier for physicians to participate in dual MOC/CME credit activities because it streamlines the process for obtaining MOC points—they can earn MOC points for the CME activities they are already doing,” Blithe adds. PARS automatically links to the ABIM database, and the points show up in ABIM diplomates’ accounts in a matter days. It used to take months, she says. 1
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://meetingsnet.com/cme-design/how-make-docs-maintenance-certification-easy</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1345</post_time>
<username>spelletier</username>
<post>
Building on Success 
Many medical societies are interested in providing the Maintenance of Certification credits physicians need to satisfy their specialty board’s requirements. And why not? Physicians already can obtain the continuing medical education credits they need at Accreditation Council for CME–accredited and state-accredited provider activities. Why not extend that into dual-credit sessions that would provide MOC points as well at medical society annual meetings? 
After all, it doubles the draw to register for a conference if a physician can knock off CME credits and MOC points by attending the same session, making it a pretty attractive proposition for most medical societies. 
It just can be a little tricky to pull off. Here’s how the Heart Rhythm Society integrated elements of MOC into sessions at its 2016 Annual Meeting, which drew 13,000 attendees to the Moscone Convention Center in San Francisco in May. Hint: It pays to have the right technology. 
MOC Off to a Rocky Start The CME community viewed it as a major opportunity when the American Board of Medical Specialties launched the four-part MOC framework in the early 2000s—one part of which, Part 4, lifelong learning and self-assessment, is directly tied to CME. And it was in fact a great opportunity for CME providers in theory. However, with each of the 24 boards of medicine putting together their own individual MOC programs within the overall ABMS framework, it got a little messy. 
For example, the lifelong learning portion of the American Board of Internal Medicine’s MOC required that ABIM review and approve each activity, resulting in a huge backlog and few options for physicians to choose from (see this article for more ). 
HRS had offered MOC points at the annual conference for a few sessions in the past, says HRS Director, Scientific Sessions Programs and Education, Chloé Thomas. They had to work directly with ABIM to get the sessions certified, and “the process was manual and time consuming,” she says. 
Collaboration to the Rescue Last fall, ACCME and ABIM collaborated to streamline the process, enabling providers to input all the information needed for both the accreditor and the board into ACCME’s Program and Activity Reporting System, or PARS. 
“One of the catalysts for HRS offering MOC points this year was the way the ACCME and ABIM collaborated,” says HRS Manager, CME Programs and Meetings Operations, Tracy Blithe, CMP. Now that ACCME-accredited providers like HRS are no longer required to submit applications for activity approval for peer review to ABIM, HRS was able to provide MOC points for 12 of its 199 sessions this year. They also offered American Board of Pediatrics MOC points for four additional sessions. 
“We uploaded [the session data] into PARS, pushed a button saying, ‘Yes, we want to offer MOC credits for this,’ then all we had to do is upload our final data at the completion of the meeting,” says Blithe. 
The unified system “also makes it easier for physicians to participate in dual MOC/CME credit activities because it streamlines the process for obtaining MOC points—they can earn MOC points for the CME activities they are already doing,” Blithe adds. PARS automatically links to the ABIM database, and the points show up in ABIM diplomates’ accounts in a matter days. It used to take months, she says. 1
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://m.meetingsnet.com/site-files/meetingsnet.com/files/uploads/2016/08/moc.gif</main_image>
</document>
