<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.thehindubusinessline.com/companies/?service=rss</forum>
<forum_title>BusinessLine - Companies</forum_title>
<discussion_title>‘Maruti 2.0 on track to achieving its targets’</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.thehindubusinessline.com/companies/maruti-20-on-track-to-achieve-its-targetsto-add-more-hybrid-environmentfriendly-products/article8975134.ece</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Home News Markets Companies Money &amp; Banking Economy Info-tech Opinion Specials Luxe Portfolio Catalyst BLink Find Company: ‘Maruti 2.0 on track to achieving its targets’ Our Bureau RC Bhargava, Chairman of Maruti Suzuki India Ltd 
To add more hybrid and environment friendly products New Delhi, August 11: As technology advances towards ensuring a safer and cleaner environment, the country’s largest passenger vehicles manufacturer, Maruti Suzuki India (MSIL), said it will bring out more products in the hybrid range. In its annual report 2015-16, senior leaders of the company have stressed investments in hybrid technology and changes required to meet the advanced emission regulations in the country. The company, a key player in the Centre’s Make in India mission, said it should be ‘Make in India with Quality’. “We have been emphasising this message to all our suppliers and associates, because quality has to be the key in everything we do. In particular, we have launched several initiatives to help all our suppliers attain and maintain total consistency in the quality of their supplies to MSIL,” RC Bhargava, Chairman, MSIL, said in the report. Pollution problem The company complimented the Centre for recognising the dangers of the situation and taking a firm stand in favour of growth, while dealing with the real pollution problem. “I do believe that over time we will do what is really required, and the industry, as well as MSIL, will lead manufacturing growth in India,” he said. Bhargava also noted that investors are losing confidence and customers are unsure of what to do in the wake of diesel vehicles being targeted as the ‘main villain’ for air pollution, especially in Delhi-NCR. He said the growth of the industry and creation of jobs were likely to be adversely impacted due to targeting of diesel vehicles, adding that India seems to be applying ‘Western remedies for pollution to our problem’. On hybridisation in its products, Kenichi Ayukawa, MD and CEO, said: “The process of hybridisation will be expanded further in the next few years. We are providing factory-fitted CNG cars and are making efforts to expand their penetration.” While, MSIL offers CNG option is most of its cars, such as Alto, WagonR and Celerio, it offers mild hybrid technology in multi-purpose vehicle Ertiga and premium sedan Ciaz. The company, which has a target of selling 20 lakh vehicles by 2020, said it is expediting the process to operationalise its upcoming Gujarat plant by early next year.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.thehindubusinessline.com/companies/maruti-20-on-track-to-achieve-its-targetsto-add-more-hybrid-environmentfriendly-products/article8975134.ece</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1738</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Home News Markets Companies Money &amp; Banking Economy Info-tech Opinion Specials Luxe Portfolio Catalyst BLink Find Company: ‘Maruti 2.0 on track to achieving its targets’ Our Bureau RC Bhargava, Chairman of Maruti Suzuki India Ltd 
To add more hybrid and environment friendly products New Delhi, August 11: As technology advances towards ensuring a safer and cleaner environment, the country’s largest passenger vehicles manufacturer, Maruti Suzuki India (MSIL), said it will bring out more products in the hybrid range. In its annual report 2015-16, senior leaders of the company have stressed investments in hybrid technology and changes required to meet the advanced emission regulations in the country. The company, a key player in the Centre’s Make in India mission, said it should be ‘Make in India with Quality’. “We have been emphasising this message to all our suppliers and associates, because quality has to be the key in everything we do. In particular, we have launched several initiatives to help all our suppliers attain and maintain total consistency in the quality of their supplies to MSIL,” RC Bhargava, Chairman, MSIL, said in the report. Pollution problem The company complimented the Centre for recognising the dangers of the situation and taking a firm stand in favour of growth, while dealing with the real pollution problem. “I do believe that over time we will do what is really required, and the industry, as well as MSIL, will lead manufacturing growth in India,” he said. Bhargava also noted that investors are losing confidence and customers are unsure of what to do in the wake of diesel vehicles being targeted as the ‘main villain’ for air pollution, especially in Delhi-NCR. He said the growth of the industry and creation of jobs were likely to be adversely impacted due to targeting of diesel vehicles, adding that India seems to be applying ‘Western remedies for pollution to our problem’. On hybridisation in its products, Kenichi Ayukawa, MD and CEO, said: “The process of hybridisation will be expanded further in the next few years. We are providing factory-fitted CNG cars and are making efforts to expand their penetration.” While, MSIL offers CNG option is most of its cars, such as Alto, WagonR and Celerio, it offers mild hybrid technology in multi-purpose vehicle Ertiga and premium sedan Ciaz. The company, which has a target of selling 20 lakh vehicles by 2020, said it is expediting the process to operationalise its upcoming Gujarat plant by early next year.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://www.thehindubusinessline.com/multimedia/dynamic/02968/rc-bhargava_2968175g.jpg</main_image>
</document>
