<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://electricalnews.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Electrical News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Buffalo Sabres Enhance Fan Experience and Energy Efficiency at the First Niagara Center with Eaton’s Advanced LED Lighting and Controls System</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://electricalnews.com/buffalo-sabres-enhance-fan-experience-energy-efficiency-first-niagara-center-eatons-advanced-led-lighting-controls-system/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Eastern Subscribe Newsletter Buffalo Sabres Enhance Fan Experience and Energy Efficiency at the First Niagara Center with Eaton’s Advanced LED Lighting and Controls System 

SYRACUSE, N.Y. – Eaton announced that owners of the First Niagara Center in Buffalo, New York, home of the National Hockey League’s (NHL ® ) Buffalo Sabres, are installing its advanced Ephesus sports lighting light-emitting diode (LED) and controls system. Featuring industry-leading controls functions, the LED system enhances the viewing experience for spectators while reducing energy use by as much as 75 percent. 

The Sabres will play their first pre-season game under the new lights on September 27, welcoming the Ottawa Senators, who were the first NHL team to install Ephesus LED sports lighting in 2014 at the Canadian Tire Centre arena. 
“We’ve seen firsthand how Eaton’s Ephesus sports LED lighting system can improve visibility both on the ice and in the arena bowl,” said Michael Gilbert, vice president, Administration, Buffalo Sabres. “Implementing this industry-leading system for First Niagara Center will allow us to continue to provide a world-class venue for both players and fans.” 
The new solid-state lighting system features Ephesus Arena Pro luminaires with color temperature tuning capabilities and a wired DMX control system that will interface with the arena’s existing control system. The LED system is the only one available with 100 percent dimming capabilities. 
Despite installing significantly less fixtures than the previous lighting system, Eaton’s Ephesus sports lighting provides optimal lighting that illuminates more uniformly on the playing surface, creating an improved stage for players and fans watching live and on high-definition television. The Ephesus LED system is easy to install, virtually maintenance-free for years and offers the lowest total operating costs compared to other traditional sports lighting systems. 
“Since we installed the first solid-state lighting system in a North American sports arena, facility operators have come to understand that Eaton’s digital lighting solutions create an enhanced stage for fans and performers,” said Mike Lorenz, president, Eaton’s Ephesus Lighting business. “As in many other hockey venues that our products are illuminating, we are confident that Sabres fans, broadcasters, players and even their opponents will see the game better with our industry-leading digital lighting and controls system.” 
This Ephesus solution continues the rapid acceptance of LED lighting at sports and entertainment venues of all sizes across North America. Hundreds of facilities have made the switch to Eaton’s LED sports lighting system including the University of Phoenix Stadium (Arizona Cardinals); U.S. Bank Stadium (Miami Dolphins); Bridgestone Arena (Nashville Predators); Globe Life Park (Texas Rangers) and many more. 
Eaton’s Ephesus Lighting business manufactures high-output solid-state lighting solutions for challenging applications in the industrial and sporting markets. The business is focused on innovating advanced lighting solutions that will enrich and illuminate the world, by creating brighter, more vibrant and sustainable environments. For more information, visit: www.eaton.com/ephesus . Share this:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://electricalnews.com/buffalo-sabres-enhance-fan-experience-energy-efficiency-first-niagara-center-eatons-advanced-led-lighting-controls-system/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0034</post_time>
<username>Electrical News</username>
<post>
Eastern Subscribe Newsletter Buffalo Sabres Enhance Fan Experience and Energy Efficiency at the First Niagara Center with Eaton’s Advanced LED Lighting and Controls System 

SYRACUSE, N.Y. – Eaton announced that owners of the First Niagara Center in Buffalo, New York, home of the National Hockey League’s (NHL ® ) Buffalo Sabres, are installing its advanced Ephesus sports lighting light-emitting diode (LED) and controls system. Featuring industry-leading controls functions, the LED system enhances the viewing experience for spectators while reducing energy use by as much as 75 percent. 

The Sabres will play their first pre-season game under the new lights on September 27, welcoming the Ottawa Senators, who were the first NHL team to install Ephesus LED sports lighting in 2014 at the Canadian Tire Centre arena. 
“We’ve seen firsthand how Eaton’s Ephesus sports LED lighting system can improve visibility both on the ice and in the arena bowl,” said Michael Gilbert, vice president, Administration, Buffalo Sabres. “Implementing this industry-leading system for First Niagara Center will allow us to continue to provide a world-class venue for both players and fans.” 
The new solid-state lighting system features Ephesus Arena Pro luminaires with color temperature tuning capabilities and a wired DMX control system that will interface with the arena’s existing control system. The LED system is the only one available with 100 percent dimming capabilities. 
Despite installing significantly less fixtures than the previous lighting system, Eaton’s Ephesus sports lighting provides optimal lighting that illuminates more uniformly on the playing surface, creating an improved stage for players and fans watching live and on high-definition television. The Ephesus LED system is easy to install, virtually maintenance-free for years and offers the lowest total operating costs compared to other traditional sports lighting systems. 
“Since we installed the first solid-state lighting system in a North American sports arena, facility operators have come to understand that Eaton’s digital lighting solutions create an enhanced stage for fans and performers,” said Mike Lorenz, president, Eaton’s Ephesus Lighting business. “As in many other hockey venues that our products are illuminating, we are confident that Sabres fans, broadcasters, players and even their opponents will see the game better with our industry-leading digital lighting and controls system.” 
This Ephesus solution continues the rapid acceptance of LED lighting at sports and entertainment venues of all sizes across North America. Hundreds of facilities have made the switch to Eaton’s LED sports lighting system including the University of Phoenix Stadium (Arizona Cardinals); U.S. Bank Stadium (Miami Dolphins); Bridgestone Arena (Nashville Predators); Globe Life Park (Texas Rangers) and many more. 
Eaton’s Ephesus Lighting business manufactures high-output solid-state lighting solutions for challenging applications in the industrial and sporting markets. The business is focused on innovating advanced lighting solutions that will enrich and illuminate the world, by creating brighter, more vibrant and sustainable environments. For more information, visit: www.eaton.com/ephesus . Share this:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://17131-presscdn-0-38.pagely.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Eaton-1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
