<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>What happens to children when they receive aluminum containing vaccines? - CMSRI</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.cmsri.org/what-happens-to-children-when-they-receive-aluminum-containing-vaccines/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Home » What happens to children when they receive aluminum containing vaccines? What happens to children when they receive aluminum containing vaccines? 
In their landmark 2013 paper, Canadian scientists Professor Christopher Shaw and Dr. Lucija Tomljenovic show that the more children receive vaccines with aluminum adjuvants, the greater their chance is of developing autism, autoimmune diseases and neurological problems later in life. A demonstrated neurotoxin, Aluminum is the only approved adjuvant in the US. Its use presents the risk of brain inflammation, autoimmunity and other adverse health consequences. Combining Multiple Childhood Vaccines Not Safe, According to Article in the Journal of American Physicians and Surgeons June 16, 2016 TUCSON, Ariz., June 14, 2016 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Multiple childhood vaccines are often given at one visit, but contrary to the claims of public health officials there is evidence that this practice is unsafe, writes medical research journalist Neil Z. Miller in the summer issue of the Journal of American Physicians and Surgeons. Parental Rights and Religious Freedom Under Attack in Virginia January 27, 2016 URGENT ACTION ALERT: Vaccine Exemptions in Virginia Gutted by HB 1342Contact State Legislators Immediately We are requesting your immediate communication with your state legislators to OPPOSE HB 1342 sponsored by Delegate Eileen Filler-Corn(chief patron) and co-sponsored by Delegate Christopher P. Stolle (chief co-patron). Innovative Study on Alzheimer’s Treatment is Subject of Crowd Funding Campaign July 15, 2015 Innovative Study on Alzheimer&apos;s Treatment is Subject of Crowd Funding Campaign Conclusive Research on Correlation of Aluminum and Alzheimer’s Disease to be Conducted Washington, DC (July 16, 2015) One of the world’s leading experts on aluminum and aluminum-related illnesses is seeking funding for a study on the potentially lifesaving impact of removing aluminum from Alzheimer’s disease […] 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.cmsri.org/what-happens-to-children-when-they-receive-aluminum-containing-vaccines/</post_url>
<post_date>20160616</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Home » What happens to children when they receive aluminum containing vaccines? What happens to children when they receive aluminum containing vaccines? 
In their landmark 2013 paper, Canadian scientists Professor Christopher Shaw and Dr. Lucija Tomljenovic show that the more children receive vaccines with aluminum adjuvants, the greater their chance is of developing autism, autoimmune diseases and neurological problems later in life. A demonstrated neurotoxin, Aluminum is the only approved adjuvant in the US. Its use presents the risk of brain inflammation, autoimmunity and other adverse health consequences. Combining Multiple Childhood Vaccines Not Safe, According to Article in the Journal of American Physicians and Surgeons June 16, 2016 TUCSON, Ariz., June 14, 2016 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Multiple childhood vaccines are often given at one visit, but contrary to the claims of public health officials there is evidence that this practice is unsafe, writes medical research journalist Neil Z. Miller in the summer issue of the Journal of American Physicians and Surgeons. Parental Rights and Religious Freedom Under Attack in Virginia January 27, 2016 URGENT ACTION ALERT: Vaccine Exemptions in Virginia Gutted by HB 1342Contact State Legislators Immediately We are requesting your immediate communication with your state legislators to OPPOSE HB 1342 sponsored by Delegate Eileen Filler-Corn(chief patron) and co-sponsored by Delegate Christopher P. Stolle (chief co-patron). Innovative Study on Alzheimer’s Treatment is Subject of Crowd Funding Campaign July 15, 2015 Innovative Study on Alzheimer&apos;s Treatment is Subject of Crowd Funding Campaign Conclusive Research on Correlation of Aluminum and Alzheimer’s Disease to be Conducted Washington, DC (July 16, 2015) One of the world’s leading experts on aluminum and aluminum-related illnesses is seeking funding for a study on the potentially lifesaving impact of removing aluminum from Alzheimer’s disease […] 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.cmsri.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/shutterstock_159421490.jpg</main_image>
</document>
