<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Blazing ahead for fire base | Central Western Daily</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.centralwesterndaily.com.au/story/4092463/blazing-ahead-for-fire-base/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Orange makes a red-hot go of bringing the NSW Rural Fire Service headquarters to Orange Tanya Marschke 12 Aug 2016, 12:25 p.m. The push to have a Rural Fire Service headquarters in Orange has been renewed IDEAL LOCATION: Orange councillor Reg Kidd is renewing a push to have part of the Rural Fire Service headquarters be relocated to Orange to boost employment in the region. 
THE push to have a Rural Fire Service [RFS] headquarters based in Orange has been renewed with fresh appeals being made to the minister in charge. 
Orange City councillor Reg Kidd has been campaigning for years for at least part of the NSW RFS head quarters to be based in the regional city. 
The issue arose when it was announced the lease would not be renewed in 2018 at the current headquarters in Lidcombe. 
Cr Kidd said Orange City Council wrote to Minister for Emergency Services David Elliott about the issue about 10 days ago and he plans to raise the issue again at Tuesday’s council meeting and call for a meeting with the minister. 
Cr Kidd also met with the minister in February but said it is important to keep the issue in his mind. 
“We went and made our thoughts very clear on how decentralisation could work nearly three years ago and then subsequent to that the two coronial inquiries into fires in NSW bushland [at Goobang and Coonabarabran] said the RFS needs to be in areas that they are servicing which is rural NSW,” he said. 
“Subsequent to that when there was a change of minister, Minister Elliott, we met with him and put our case to him.” 
Cr Kidd said he agreed the command needs to be in Sydney where it can work closely with other services and get messages out to media outlets in major emergencies. 
However, he said they could relocate the training headquarters, an equipment or vehicle base, or mapping station to Orange. 
“I still feel very strongly about it,” Cr Kidd said. 
Cr Kidd said there was already a high class complex at Forest Road and if it was developed as a training base it would draw in fire fighters from across the state who need training or upgrades to their training. 
“It would increase people who are working in our area, living in our area, shopping in our area, it’s also more people coming to our area and staying in our area and spending money,” he said. 
“It means more job opportunities, it could be more job opportunities for people coming out of school.” 
He said Orange was also ideal because it is central for roads, rail and has an airport. 
“It would be a good base for training purposes and all sorts of things,” Cr Kidd said. 
Dubbo and Parkes are also campaigning for an RFS base in their areas but Cr Kidd said he would not lose sleep if they were selected above Orange as there were still benefits to it being regionally based. 
“It gives a lot of confidence to people in rural NSW that the RFS is base in a rural area and that they understand the area they are servicing,” Cr Kidd said. Latest News 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.centralwesterndaily.com.au/story/4092463/blazing-ahead-for-fire-base/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Tanya Marschke</username>
<post>
Orange makes a red-hot go of bringing the NSW Rural Fire Service headquarters to Orange Tanya Marschke 12 Aug 2016, 12:25 p.m. The push to have a Rural Fire Service headquarters in Orange has been renewed IDEAL LOCATION: Orange councillor Reg Kidd is renewing a push to have part of the Rural Fire Service headquarters be relocated to Orange to boost employment in the region. 
THE push to have a Rural Fire Service [RFS] headquarters based in Orange has been renewed with fresh appeals being made to the minister in charge. 
Orange City councillor Reg Kidd has been campaigning for years for at least part of the NSW RFS head quarters to be based in the regional city. 
The issue arose when it was announced the lease would not be renewed in 2018 at the current headquarters in Lidcombe. 
Cr Kidd said Orange City Council wrote to Minister for Emergency Services David Elliott about the issue about 10 days ago and he plans to raise the issue again at Tuesday’s council meeting and call for a meeting with the minister. 
Cr Kidd also met with the minister in February but said it is important to keep the issue in his mind. 
“We went and made our thoughts very clear on how decentralisation could work nearly three years ago and then subsequent to that the two coronial inquiries into fires in NSW bushland [at Goobang and Coonabarabran] said the RFS needs to be in areas that they are servicing which is rural NSW,” he said. 
“Subsequent to that when there was a change of minister, Minister Elliott, we met with him and put our case to him.” 
Cr Kidd said he agreed the command needs to be in Sydney where it can work closely with other services and get messages out to media outlets in major emergencies. 
However, he said they could relocate the training headquarters, an equipment or vehicle base, or mapping station to Orange. 
“I still feel very strongly about it,” Cr Kidd said. 
Cr Kidd said there was already a high class complex at Forest Road and if it was developed as a training base it would draw in fire fighters from across the state who need training or upgrades to their training. 
“It would increase people who are working in our area, living in our area, shopping in our area, it’s also more people coming to our area and staying in our area and spending money,” he said. 
“It means more job opportunities, it could be more job opportunities for people coming out of school.” 
He said Orange was also ideal because it is central for roads, rail and has an airport. 
“It would be a good base for training purposes and all sorts of things,” Cr Kidd said. 
Dubbo and Parkes are also campaigning for an RFS base in their areas but Cr Kidd said he would not lose sleep if they were selected above Orange as there were still benefits to it being regionally based. 
“It gives a lot of confidence to people in rural NSW that the RFS is base in a rural area and that they understand the area they are servicing,” Cr Kidd said. Latest News 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://nnimgt-a.akamaihd.net/transform/v1/crop/frm/GpZJ7bTi6nvXt5tnNdnKeU/48922c4f-5f8b-44a6-95af-6daedfa9b90d.JPG/r219_698_3844_2746_w1200_h678_fmax.jpg</main_image>
</document>
