<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Armour: With Olympic gold, USA&apos;s Simone Biles simply greatest gymnast ever | wltx.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wltx.com/sports/olympics/armour-with-olympic-gold-usas-simone-biles-simply-greatest-gymnast-ever/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wltx&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;armour-with-olympic-gold-usas-simone-biles-simply-greatest-gymnast-ever&amp;#x2f;295412697</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Armour: With Olympic gold, USA&apos;s Simone Biles simply greatest gymnast ever Simone Biles and Team USA Gymnastics took a commanding lead after Sunday&apos;s All-Around competition. Nancy Armour, USA TODAY Sports , KING 8:04 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Simone Biles is simply the best. (Photo: Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sport) 
Simone Biles doesn’t want to get drawn into the debate of where she ranks in history. 
She doesn’t need to. 
The gold medal hanging around her neck says it all. The scoreboard added an exclamation point. 
Biles erased whatever lingering doubts there were about whether she’s the greatest gymnast of all time Thursday, winning the Olympic all-around title in a rout. She finished 2.1 points ahead of Final Five teammate Aly Raisman, by far her largest margin of victory in her three-year – and counting -- win streak. 
“I would say yes,” Martha Karolyi said when asked if Biles was the greatest ever. “For me, the most special was my first, from Nadia, and the last, from Simone. Those really stand out for me. 
“I would put Simone now on top,” she added. 
This was not a cliff-hanger, Biles having established her dominance long ago. She hasn’t lost an all-around competition since the spring of 2013, claiming three world titles and four U.S. crowns in the process. Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (R) of the United States is embraced by Alexandra Raisman (C) and coach Mihai Brestyan (L) after competing on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States waves to fans after winning the gold medal during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles (R) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro (Photo credit EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles reacts after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles (C) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman (R) after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and US gymnast Alexandra Raisman prepare to compete at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles&apos; painted toenails can be seen as she rests during the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States prepares to compete on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles takes part in the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States looks on while waiting for moving to the next apparatus during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the vault event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States prepares to compete on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions 
Biles packs so much difficulty into her routines that she starts with a point or two cushion. Other gymnasts have to hope she falls or is sloppy. Which she almost never does and rarely is. 
Even Raisman acknowledged she was fighting for second place – or first in the “non-Simone division,” as her fellow Americans have taken to describing it. 
&quot;Just because she wins every single competition,” Raisman said. 
Still, those expectations are as tall as they are weighty, especially for a 19-year-old who stands just 4-foot-8. 
When the standings after the second rotation flashed and Biles had slipped behind Russia’s Aliya Mustafina, the first time she had trailed in a competition – any competition – in almost three years, it would have been easy to wonder if a small crack was beginning to show. 
In a word, no. 
Not even close. 
“I don’t think she’s even reacting to it,” said Aimee Boorman, the only coach Biles has ever had. “That’s just her personality.” 
She was just 0.034 points behind – the equivalent of one wobble – and uneven bars are her “worst” event. Balance beam and floor exercise were still to come, and her difficulty on both of those events is so much higher than Mustafina’s, and even Raisman’s, that Biles could have afforded a fall or two and still won. 
Instead, she put on a show befitting a champion for the ages. 
With a wobble on an aerial somersault quickly righted, Biles spent the rest of the routine making the 4-inch-wide beam look more like a railroad tie. She tumbled and flipped and twisted with precision and confidence, moving more easily than us mere mortals do on flat ground. 
Her score of 15.433, combined with a 13.866 by Mustafina, put her comfortably in first place and she never looked back. 
It was fitting she ended on floor, where she soars so high she looks as if she could touch the sky. 
“I told her to do it for herself and do it from joy,” Boorman said. 
That she did, her smile as bright as the gold eyeliner she wore. Though her tricks are so difficult they defy the laws of both gravity and physics, she did them with the effort and lightness of the little girl who once delighted in doing back handsprings for a home video. 
When the last notes of her music finished, she gave one more big smile and then, looking at Boorman, began to cry. 
“I knew I had finally done it,” Biles said. “I felt every emotion at once.” 
It has not quite sunk in yet, Biles said. As Olympic champion, she’s now part of a proud lineage that traces from Nadia Comaneci to Mary Lou Retton to Gabby Douglas. And as the fourth American in a row to win gymnastics’ biggest prize, she gives the United States bragging rights no other country, in men’s or women’s gymnastics, can claim. 
“It’s such an honor to be under that name, I don’t know what to think,” Biles said. “It doesn’t even feel real. To me, I’m still the same Simone. 
“I just have two Olympic gold medals.” 
With more likely to come. 
Biles made the finals for vault, balance beam and floor exercise, giving her a chance to become the first woman to win five gold medals in a single Games. Given that she’s the reigning world champ on floor and beam and upgraded vault after winning bronze at last year’s worlds, she could leave Rio with more gold than some royal families. 
But those would only add to her legend. To be considered the greatest, you have to have the greatest title. 
“A lot of people have said she won’t be the greatest until she wins the Olympic all-around,” Boorman said. “So … mic drop.” 
No one is better than Biles. Not now, not ever. Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Simone Manuel (L) and Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak react after they equally won the Women&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / GABRIEL BOUYS (Photo credit should read GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images) GABRIEL BOUYS, This content is subject to copyright. Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Competitors sail during the men’s Finn opening series race at Marina da Gloria during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Mandatory Credit: Eric Seals-USA TODAY Sports Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; United States defender Katelyn Falgowski (23) and midfield Melissa Gonzalez (5) battle for the ball with India defender Namita Toppo (19) during women&apos;s field hockey pool play in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Hockey Centre. Mandatory Credit: John David Mercer-USA TODAY Sports John David Mercer, John David Mercer Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Nathan Adrian (USA) during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wltx.com/sports/olympics/armour-with-olympic-gold-usas-simone-biles-simply-greatest-gymnast-ever/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;wltx&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;armour-with-olympic-gold-usas-simone-biles-simply-greatest-gymnast-ever&amp;#x2f;295412697</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Armour: With Olympic gold, USA&apos;s Simone Biles simply greatest gymnast ever Simone Biles and Team USA Gymnastics took a commanding lead after Sunday&apos;s All-Around competition. Nancy Armour, USA TODAY Sports , KING 8:04 PM. EST August 11, 2016 Simone Biles is simply the best. (Photo: Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sport) 
Simone Biles doesn’t want to get drawn into the debate of where she ranks in history. 
She doesn’t need to. 
The gold medal hanging around her neck says it all. The scoreboard added an exclamation point. 
Biles erased whatever lingering doubts there were about whether she’s the greatest gymnast of all time Thursday, winning the Olympic all-around title in a rout. She finished 2.1 points ahead of Final Five teammate Aly Raisman, by far her largest margin of victory in her three-year – and counting -- win streak. 
“I would say yes,” Martha Karolyi said when asked if Biles was the greatest ever. “For me, the most special was my first, from Nadia, and the last, from Simone. Those really stand out for me. 
“I would put Simone now on top,” she added. 
This was not a cliff-hanger, Biles having established her dominance long ago. She hasn’t lost an all-around competition since the spring of 2013, claiming three world titles and four U.S. crowns in the process. Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (R) of the United States is embraced by Alexandra Raisman (C) and coach Mihai Brestyan (L) after competing on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States waves to fans after winning the gold medal during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles (R) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro (Photo credit EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles reacts after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles (C) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman (R) after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and US gymnast Alexandra Raisman prepare to compete at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles&apos; painted toenails can be seen as she rests during the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States prepares to compete on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles takes part in the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States looks on while waiting for moving to the next apparatus during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the vault event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States prepares to compete on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions 
Biles packs so much difficulty into her routines that she starts with a point or two cushion. Other gymnasts have to hope she falls or is sloppy. Which she almost never does and rarely is. 
Even Raisman acknowledged she was fighting for second place – or first in the “non-Simone division,” as her fellow Americans have taken to describing it. 
&quot;Just because she wins every single competition,” Raisman said. 
Still, those expectations are as tall as they are weighty, especially for a 19-year-old who stands just 4-foot-8. 
When the standings after the second rotation flashed and Biles had slipped behind Russia’s Aliya Mustafina, the first time she had trailed in a competition – any competition – in almost three years, it would have been easy to wonder if a small crack was beginning to show. 
In a word, no. 
Not even close. 
“I don’t think she’s even reacting to it,” said Aimee Boorman, the only coach Biles has ever had. “That’s just her personality.” 
She was just 0.034 points behind – the equivalent of one wobble – and uneven bars are her “worst” event. Balance beam and floor exercise were still to come, and her difficulty on both of those events is so much higher than Mustafina’s, and even Raisman’s, that Biles could have afforded a fall or two and still won. 
Instead, she put on a show befitting a champion for the ages. 
With a wobble on an aerial somersault quickly righted, Biles spent the rest of the routine making the 4-inch-wide beam look more like a railroad tie. She tumbled and flipped and twisted with precision and confidence, moving more easily than us mere mortals do on flat ground. 
Her score of 15.433, combined with a 13.866 by Mustafina, put her comfortably in first place and she never looked back. 
It was fitting she ended on floor, where she soars so high she looks as if she could touch the sky. 
“I told her to do it for herself and do it from joy,” Boorman said. 
That she did, her smile as bright as the gold eyeliner she wore. Though her tricks are so difficult they defy the laws of both gravity and physics, she did them with the effort and lightness of the little girl who once delighted in doing back handsprings for a home video. 
When the last notes of her music finished, she gave one more big smile and then, looking at Boorman, began to cry. 
“I knew I had finally done it,” Biles said. “I felt every emotion at once.” 
It has not quite sunk in yet, Biles said. As Olympic champion, she’s now part of a proud lineage that traces from Nadia Comaneci to Mary Lou Retton to Gabby Douglas. And as the fourth American in a row to win gymnastics’ biggest prize, she gives the United States bragging rights no other country, in men’s or women’s gymnastics, can claim. 
“It’s such an honor to be under that name, I don’t know what to think,” Biles said. “It doesn’t even feel real. To me, I’m still the same Simone. 
“I just have two Olympic gold medals.” 
With more likely to come. 
Biles made the finals for vault, balance beam and floor exercise, giving her a chance to become the first woman to win five gold medals in a single Games. Given that she’s the reigning world champ on floor and beam and upgraded vault after winning bronze at last year’s worlds, she could leave Rio with more gold than some royal families. 
But those would only add to her legend. To be considered the greatest, you have to have the greatest title. 
“A lot of people have said she won’t be the greatest until she wins the Olympic all-around,” Boorman said. “So … mic drop.” 
No one is better than Biles. Not now, not ever. Loading... Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Switzerland team members compete during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Simone Manuel (L) and Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak react after they equally won the Women&apos;s 100m Freestyle Final during the swimming event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / GABRIEL BOUYS (Photo credit should read GABRIEL BOUYS/AFP/Getty Images) GABRIEL BOUYS, This content is subject to copyright. Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Deutsch-USA TODAY Sports Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Competitors sail during the men’s Finn opening series race at Marina da Gloria during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Mandatory Credit: Eric Seals-USA TODAY Sports Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; United States defender Katelyn Falgowski (23) and midfield Melissa Gonzalez (5) battle for the ball with India defender Namita Toppo (19) during women&apos;s field hockey pool play in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Hockey Centre. Mandatory Credit: John David Mercer-USA TODAY Sports John David Mercer, John David Mercer Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Nathan Adrian (USA) during the men&apos;s 50m freestyle semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Simone Biles (USA) competes on the floor during the women&apos;s individual all-around final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena. Mandatory Credit: Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Aug 11, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Great Britain team members celebrate after the men&apos;s team sprint finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Mandatory Credit: Andrew P. Scott-USA TODAY Sports Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Aug 9, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Team USA including Robin Prendes , Anthony Fahden, Edward King and Tyler Nas during the men&apos;s lightweight four semifinal in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Lagoa Stadium. Kyle Terada, Kyle Terada RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.king5.com/photo/2016/08/11/636065340059795659-USP-Olympics--Gymnastics---Artistic-Women-s-Indivi_1470963808365_5100827_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
