<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Team USA’s Peters earns No. 3 spot in Grand Prix morning session | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/team-usas-peters-earns-no-3-spot-in-grand-prix-morning-session/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Team USA’s Peters earns No. 3 spot in Grand Prix morning session Team USA&apos;s Peters clams No. 3 Grand Prix spot NBC Olympics.com Published: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
Team USA’s Steffen Peters and horse Legolas make a big statement during their Grand Prix performance on Thursday morning, positioning the duo into the No. 3 spot on the leaderboard. The duo’s consistent display of balance, rhythm and subtleness in each movement earns them an impressive 77.614%. 
Steffen is off to a great start in making his fourth Olympic appearance his greatest. The 51-year-old currently holds a team Bronze from his inaugural 1996 Olympic appearance, but is looking to earn his first individual dressage medal and land Team USA a spot on the podium once again. 
Denmark’s Catherine Dufour ‘s dressage performance lands her the No. 5 spot on the leaderboard with a score of 76.657%. She currently holds the No. 36 FEI World Individual dressage rank. Dufour’s performance allows Denmark to have a real chance at advancing to Friday’s team Dressage Grand Prix Special. 
Germany continues to put their stamp on a gold medal. The team has an incredible Grand Prix round, with members holding three of the top four positions on the leaderboard. Kristina Boring-Sphere shocked the judges in Thursday morning’s Grand Prix round, claiming the No. 1 spot on the leaderboard, ahead of teammate Dorothee Schneider. The “Dressage Queen”, Isabel Werth will perform in the afternoon session, guaranteeing the team a spot in Friday’s Grand Prix Special. 
Steffen Peter’s performance puts the USA in a fighting position for the Bronze. The team holds a 75.176% average. Laura Graves and horse Diddy must ace their dressage performance this afternoon to earn the team a top three spot going into Friday’s Grand Prix Special. 
Great Britain must rely on reigning gold medalist, Charlotte Dujardin to do what she does best, wow the judges in this afternoon’s round. The team is hungry to defend their champion title. 
The final Grand Prix round will begin at 12:30 EST. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/team-usas-peters-earns-no-3-spot-in-grand-prix-morning-session/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Nbc Olympics.Com</username>
<post>
Team USA’s Peters earns No. 3 spot in Grand Prix morning session Team USA&apos;s Peters clams No. 3 Grand Prix spot NBC Olympics.com Published: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
Team USA’s Steffen Peters and horse Legolas make a big statement during their Grand Prix performance on Thursday morning, positioning the duo into the No. 3 spot on the leaderboard. The duo’s consistent display of balance, rhythm and subtleness in each movement earns them an impressive 77.614%. 
Steffen is off to a great start in making his fourth Olympic appearance his greatest. The 51-year-old currently holds a team Bronze from his inaugural 1996 Olympic appearance, but is looking to earn his first individual dressage medal and land Team USA a spot on the podium once again. 
Denmark’s Catherine Dufour ‘s dressage performance lands her the No. 5 spot on the leaderboard with a score of 76.657%. She currently holds the No. 36 FEI World Individual dressage rank. Dufour’s performance allows Denmark to have a real chance at advancing to Friday’s team Dressage Grand Prix Special. 
Germany continues to put their stamp on a gold medal. The team has an incredible Grand Prix round, with members holding three of the top four positions on the leaderboard. Kristina Boring-Sphere shocked the judges in Thursday morning’s Grand Prix round, claiming the No. 1 spot on the leaderboard, ahead of teammate Dorothee Schneider. The “Dressage Queen”, Isabel Werth will perform in the afternoon session, guaranteeing the team a spot in Friday’s Grand Prix Special. 
Steffen Peter’s performance puts the USA in a fighting position for the Bronze. The team holds a 75.176% average. Laura Graves and horse Diddy must ace their dressage performance this afternoon to earn the team a top three spot going into Friday’s Grand Prix Special. 
Great Britain must rely on reigning gold medalist, Charlotte Dujardin to do what she does best, wow the judges in this afternoon’s round. The team is hungry to defend their champion title. 
The final Grand Prix round will begin at 12:30 EST. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/usatsi_8696213.jpg</main_image>
</document>
