<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>National flag run pays tribute to the armed forces</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Community/National_flag_run_pays_tribute_to_the_armed_forces.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
National flag run pays tribute to the armed forces By Melissa Simon 
FOR VETERANS—Simi Valley Harley Owners Group member Gerry Lieberman, left, prepares to receive the Americanflag from Orange Coast Harley Owners Group member Lyle Michelson. Mel Fonseca of Orange Coast HOG reads from “The Rite of Passing” during the Nation of Patriots tour stop at Simi Valley Harley-Davidson dealership July 28 in Moorpark. MICHAEL COONS/Acorn Newspapers Dozens of motorcyclists escorted an American flag down Los Angeles Avenue in Simi Valley last month to its next stop at the Harley-Davidson dealership in Moorpark as part of the Nation of Patriots’ eighth annual flag tour. 
Led by Simi resident Gerry Lieberman of the Simi Valley Harley Owners Group and Lyle Michelson of the Orange Coast HOG, the motorcyclists took their turn traveling with the flag during its 100-day run across the country. 
Lieberman said the flag’s journey began on Memorial Day in Madison, Wis., and will travel through 48 states before completing its run on Labor Day in the very same place. 
REMEMBER—Mel Fonseca unrolls a banner during the Nation of Patriots tour at the Simi Valley Harley- Davidson dealership July 28 in Moorpark. MICHAEL COONS / Acorn Newspapers Founded in 2008, Nation of Patriots is a Wisconsin-based nonprofit that aims to provide financial support for wounded veterans and their families. 
During the tour, which honors the U.S. armed forces, the flag is escorted by various chapters of the Harley Owners Group, or HOG, across the states. 
As a veteran, Lieberman said participating in the tour gives him a sense of pride. 
“I get chills when (the Simi HOG) parades the flag down Los Angeles Avenue over to the Harley dealer in Moorpark,” said Lieberman, the assistant director of Simi HOG. “This is my sixth or seventh year participating in the flag run representing my fellow veterans.” 
Lieberman served as a mechanic in the U.S. Army from 1970 to 1972. He considers in Colorado Springs, Colo., rather than in Vietnam. He joined the 150-member Simi HOG chapter in 2003, around the same time he retired from Verizon. 
“The HOG chapter really is like a second family, and there’s a lot of camaraderie,” he said. “We find different things to get involved with, do a lot of community volunteer work.” 
Nationwide trip 
On July 28, Lieberman and 25 other Simi HOG members joined a group of at least a dozen Orange County HOG members, including Michelson, at the Shell station at 2627 Yosemite Ave. in Simi Valley to take the flag to the Harley dealership. 
Wes Sullins, director of the Santa Maria HOG chapter, said he joined the ride a day early so he could escort the flag the nearly 120 miles to his group. 
“My favorite part about the flag run is the patriotism and camaraderie you feel with fellow veterans,” Sullins, a Santa Maria resident, said. “This flag run is an important way to support our military men and women, and there’s such a sense of pride for all of us who participate.” 
Sullins was crew chief for the Flying Tigers in the U.S. Air Force during his 2003 tour in Afghanistan and Iraq. The combat veteran said he was responsible for maintaining flight controls, rigging and hydraulics for the aircraft. 
Once at the dealership, Moorpark Mayor Janice Parvin thanked the riders from Orange County and Simi Valley for escorting the flag on its journey. 
“This flag and those who have carried it have traveled across America in honor of our armed forces,” Parvin said at the ceremony. “I want to recognize all of you who have participated in what I consider a heartfelt recognition of the brave men and women in the military who have stood and died defending our great nation. And to those who continue to stand to protect the freedoms that we enjoy today.” 
Michelson, a Mission Viejo resident and retired Los Angeles Police Department officer, said the group received several thumbs up during their more than 80-mile journey from Orange County to Simi Valley, as well as to the dealership. 
“Being a police officer for 29 years, you feel akin to everybody who serves and protects, whether it’s firefighters or military,” Michelson, a former Thousand Oaks resident, said. 
“Nowadays . . . there’s no kindness anywhere for military, police or firefighters. People used to wave at me as I went down the street. Unfortunately, it’s changed and that doesn’t happen often anymore . . . so this is my way of giving back and saying thank you.” 
He added it was “an awesome feeling” to see people’s reaction to the flag during its journey to Simi.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Community/National_flag_run_pays_tribute_to_the_armed_forces.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0219</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
National flag run pays tribute to the armed forces By Melissa Simon 
FOR VETERANS—Simi Valley Harley Owners Group member Gerry Lieberman, left, prepares to receive the Americanflag from Orange Coast Harley Owners Group member Lyle Michelson. Mel Fonseca of Orange Coast HOG reads from “The Rite of Passing” during the Nation of Patriots tour stop at Simi Valley Harley-Davidson dealership July 28 in Moorpark. MICHAEL COONS/Acorn Newspapers Dozens of motorcyclists escorted an American flag down Los Angeles Avenue in Simi Valley last month to its next stop at the Harley-Davidson dealership in Moorpark as part of the Nation of Patriots’ eighth annual flag tour. 
Led by Simi resident Gerry Lieberman of the Simi Valley Harley Owners Group and Lyle Michelson of the Orange Coast HOG, the motorcyclists took their turn traveling with the flag during its 100-day run across the country. 
Lieberman said the flag’s journey began on Memorial Day in Madison, Wis., and will travel through 48 states before completing its run on Labor Day in the very same place. 
REMEMBER—Mel Fonseca unrolls a banner during the Nation of Patriots tour at the Simi Valley Harley- Davidson dealership July 28 in Moorpark. MICHAEL COONS / Acorn Newspapers Founded in 2008, Nation of Patriots is a Wisconsin-based nonprofit that aims to provide financial support for wounded veterans and their families. 
During the tour, which honors the U.S. armed forces, the flag is escorted by various chapters of the Harley Owners Group, or HOG, across the states. 
As a veteran, Lieberman said participating in the tour gives him a sense of pride. 
“I get chills when (the Simi HOG) parades the flag down Los Angeles Avenue over to the Harley dealer in Moorpark,” said Lieberman, the assistant director of Simi HOG. “This is my sixth or seventh year participating in the flag run representing my fellow veterans.” 
Lieberman served as a mechanic in the U.S. Army from 1970 to 1972. He considers in Colorado Springs, Colo., rather than in Vietnam. He joined the 150-member Simi HOG chapter in 2003, around the same time he retired from Verizon. 
“The HOG chapter really is like a second family, and there’s a lot of camaraderie,” he said. “We find different things to get involved with, do a lot of community volunteer work.” 
Nationwide trip 
On July 28, Lieberman and 25 other Simi HOG members joined a group of at least a dozen Orange County HOG members, including Michelson, at the Shell station at 2627 Yosemite Ave. in Simi Valley to take the flag to the Harley dealership. 
Wes Sullins, director of the Santa Maria HOG chapter, said he joined the ride a day early so he could escort the flag the nearly 120 miles to his group. 
“My favorite part about the flag run is the patriotism and camaraderie you feel with fellow veterans,” Sullins, a Santa Maria resident, said. “This flag run is an important way to support our military men and women, and there’s such a sense of pride for all of us who participate.” 
Sullins was crew chief for the Flying Tigers in the U.S. Air Force during his 2003 tour in Afghanistan and Iraq. The combat veteran said he was responsible for maintaining flight controls, rigging and hydraulics for the aircraft. 
Once at the dealership, Moorpark Mayor Janice Parvin thanked the riders from Orange County and Simi Valley for escorting the flag on its journey. 
“This flag and those who have carried it have traveled across America in honor of our armed forces,” Parvin said at the ceremony. “I want to recognize all of you who have participated in what I consider a heartfelt recognition of the brave men and women in the military who have stood and died defending our great nation. And to those who continue to stand to protect the freedoms that we enjoy today.” 
Michelson, a Mission Viejo resident and retired Los Angeles Police Department officer, said the group received several thumbs up during their more than 80-mile journey from Orange County to Simi Valley, as well as to the dealership. 
“Being a police officer for 29 years, you feel akin to everybody who serves and protects, whether it’s firefighters or military,” Michelson, a former Thousand Oaks resident, said. 
“Nowadays . . . there’s no kindness anywhere for military, police or firefighters. People used to wave at me as I went down the street. Unfortunately, it’s changed and that doesn’t happen often anymore . . . so this is my way of giving back and saying thank you.” 
He added it was “an awesome feeling” to see people’s reaction to the flag during its journey to Simi.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/13p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
