<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://mlb.mlb.com/partnerxml/gen/news/rss/mlb.xml</forum>
<forum_title>MLB News Index</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Cubs go for 11th straight win on MLB.TV</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://m.mlb.com/news/article/195114578/what-to-watch-for-friday-on-mlbtv</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Cubs go for 11th straight win on MLB.TV Arrieta, Wainwright duel this afternoon at Wrigley Field Arrieta, Wainwright to face off 0:48 A pitcher&apos;s duel is set for Friday in Chicago as Jake Arrieta of the Cubs will take on the Cardinals Adam Wainwright By Austin Laymance / MLB.com | + 0 COMMENTS 
The Cubs go for their 11th straight win this afternoon when they play the Cardinals at Wrigley Field in a rivalry game featuring a marquee pitching matchup between Jake Arrieta and Adam Wainwright . 
Today&apos;s full schedule of Major League games will also see Alex Rodriguez play his final game for the Yankees, Nationals ace Stephen Strasburg take the mound against the Braves and the opener of a critical Interleague series between the Orioles and Giants. 
And the best place to catch all the action is on MLB.TV . 
MLB.TV Premium has returned with the same features as last year, and is only $49.99 for the rest of the season. This package has the best value and provides access to more than 400 devices and a free subscription to the MLB.com At Bat Premium app (a $19.99 value). It offers the best picture quality ever -- a new 60 frames per second -- for supported devices. Monthly signups for MLB.TV Premium are now underway as well for $24.99. 
The new MLB.TV Single Team package is also available as a $39.99 yearly subscription. You can watch a single team&apos;s live out-of-market games in full HD. 
Here&apos;s what to watch for today in the Majors (all times ET): 
Cubs look to keep rolling: STL@CHC, 2:20 p.m. The Cubs are the hottest team in baseball thanks to a 10-game win streak, which was extended Thursday night with a walk-off win over the Cards in extra innings. It&apos;s the first time the Cubs have won 10 consecutive games in a single season since they reeled off 12 in a row in 2001. 
Wainwright and the Cardinals will look to spoil the party, though. The veteran starter has been dominant at Wrigley Field over his career, going 10-1 with a 3.38 ERA over 16 starts (21 appearances). Wainwright&apos;s .909 win percentage at the ballpark is the highest by any pitcher in MLB history at the Friendly Confines. 
The Cubs have to feel good with Arrieta on the mound. He&apos;s coming off a great start in Oakland that saw him allow just three hits in eight shutout innings. Arrieta is 4-3 with a 1.71 ERA in 10 starts at home this year. 
Stat that matters: Wainwright has 13 career wins against the Cubs, the most by any active pitcher. Arrieta goes eight strong OAK@CHC: Arrieta fans four in eight dominant frames Jake Arrieta pitches eight scoreless innings in the win, holding the Athletics to three hits and a walk while racking up four strikeouts 
Strasburg seeks 16th win: ATL@WSH, 7:05 p.m. Strasburg takes the mound for the first-place Nationals in the opener of a three-game series against the Braves, who are 10-6 since July 26. 
Strasburg, a candidate for the National League Cy Young, leads the NL with 15 wins. He&apos;s looking to bounce back after losing for only the second time this year in his last start, in which he allowed four runs in 4 2/3 innings against the Giants. Strasburg has allowed only three runs in 13 2/3 innings vs. the Braves this year. 
Mike Foltynewicz starts for Atlanta. He pitched six innings of one-run ball to beat the Cardinals his last time out. 
Stat that matters: Braves first baseman Freddie Freeman is 12-for-31 (.387) lifetime against Strasburg, with two doubles and three home runs. Strasburg strikes out eight SF@WSH: Strasburg strikes out eight Giants Stephen Strasburg strikes out eight over 4 2/3 innings in his start against the Giants 
A-Rod&apos;s final game in pinstripes: TB@NYY, 7:05 p.m. The Rays have grown accustomed to being at Yankee Stadium for some notable moments in Yankees history. 
Tampa Bay has been the visitor for the first game at old Yankee Stadium after Sept. 11, 2001; the night Derek Jeter tied Lou Gehrig for most hits by a Yankee; the first game played in the Bronx after the death of Yankees owner George Steinbrenner; the unveiling of Steinbrenner&apos;s plaque in Monument Park; Jeter&apos;s 3,000th hit; Hideki Matsui&apos;s retirement ceremony; and Mariano Rivera&apos;s final relief appearance. 
Now, it&apos;s Rodriguez&apos;s final game with the Yankees. The slugger has two homers and five strikeouts in 15 career at-bats against Rays starter Chris Archer . Rodriguez could be swinging for the fences in this one, as he&apos;s sitting on 696 career homers, fourth most all-time. 
Left-hander CC Sabathia starts for the Yankees. In his only other start against the Rays this season, Sabathia allowed three runs in 4 2/3 innings in a no-decision on April 22 at Yankee Stadium. 
Stat that matters: Rodriguez has 56 home runs and 159 RBIs in 873 career at-bats against the Rays, though he&apos;s hitting .107 against them this season. A-Rod&apos;s greatest moments A look through A-Rod&apos;s storied career From the Mariners to the Rangers and the Yankees, MLB.com looks at some of the biggest moments in Alex Rodriguez&apos;s career 
Contenders clash: BAL@SF, 10:15 p.m. The Giants and Orioles are each locked in close races for first place in their respective divisions entering this pivotal three-game Interleague series. 
Matt Cain starts for the Giants, who lead the Dodgers by one game in the NL West. Cain has won his last three starts and has tossed 10 consecutive scoreless innings. 
Dylan Bundy gets the ball for the O&apos;s, who are a 1/2 game behind the Blue Jays in the American League East. Bundy is 3-2 with a 3.00 ERA in five starts since joining the rotation. The 23-year-old struck out a career-high nine batters in his last start against the White Sox. 
Stat that matters: The Orioles lead MLB with 172 homers this season, and Giants pitching has allowed 35 homers in the second half. Cain&apos;s scoreless start SF@WSH: Cain holds Nationals scoreless over five-plus Matt Cain throws five-plus innings of scoreless ball, permitting five hits, walking three and striking out four 
MLB.TV Premium subscribers get the Mosaic View -- split screen or quad, available on PC or Mac only. That always comes in handy, especially when scoreboard-watching looms. MLB.TV Premium and MLB.TV Single Team subscribers both enjoy HD and both will get real-time highlights and player stats automatically loaded moments after they occur (only for the game you are watching with MLB.TV Single Team, and for all games with MLB.TV Premium). is a reporter for MLB.com. This story was not subject to the approval of Major League Baseball or its clubs. Share This
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://m.mlb.com/news/article/195114578/what-to-watch-for-friday-on-mlbtv</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0417</post_time>
<username>Austin Laymance</username>
<post>
Cubs go for 11th straight win on MLB.TV Arrieta, Wainwright duel this afternoon at Wrigley Field Arrieta, Wainwright to face off 0:48 A pitcher&apos;s duel is set for Friday in Chicago as Jake Arrieta of the Cubs will take on the Cardinals Adam Wainwright By Austin Laymance / MLB.com | + 0 COMMENTS 
The Cubs go for their 11th straight win this afternoon when they play the Cardinals at Wrigley Field in a rivalry game featuring a marquee pitching matchup between Jake Arrieta and Adam Wainwright . 
Today&apos;s full schedule of Major League games will also see Alex Rodriguez play his final game for the Yankees, Nationals ace Stephen Strasburg take the mound against the Braves and the opener of a critical Interleague series between the Orioles and Giants. 
And the best place to catch all the action is on MLB.TV . 
MLB.TV Premium has returned with the same features as last year, and is only $49.99 for the rest of the season. This package has the best value and provides access to more than 400 devices and a free subscription to the MLB.com At Bat Premium app (a $19.99 value). It offers the best picture quality ever -- a new 60 frames per second -- for supported devices. Monthly signups for MLB.TV Premium are now underway as well for $24.99. 
The new MLB.TV Single Team package is also available as a $39.99 yearly subscription. You can watch a single team&apos;s live out-of-market games in full HD. 
Here&apos;s what to watch for today in the Majors (all times ET): 
Cubs look to keep rolling: STL@CHC, 2:20 p.m. The Cubs are the hottest team in baseball thanks to a 10-game win streak, which was extended Thursday night with a walk-off win over the Cards in extra innings. It&apos;s the first time the Cubs have won 10 consecutive games in a single season since they reeled off 12 in a row in 2001. 
Wainwright and the Cardinals will look to spoil the party, though. The veteran starter has been dominant at Wrigley Field over his career, going 10-1 with a 3.38 ERA over 16 starts (21 appearances). Wainwright&apos;s .909 win percentage at the ballpark is the highest by any pitcher in MLB history at the Friendly Confines. 
The Cubs have to feel good with Arrieta on the mound. He&apos;s coming off a great start in Oakland that saw him allow just three hits in eight shutout innings. Arrieta is 4-3 with a 1.71 ERA in 10 starts at home this year. 
Stat that matters: Wainwright has 13 career wins against the Cubs, the most by any active pitcher. Arrieta goes eight strong OAK@CHC: Arrieta fans four in eight dominant frames Jake Arrieta pitches eight scoreless innings in the win, holding the Athletics to three hits and a walk while racking up four strikeouts 
Strasburg seeks 16th win: ATL@WSH, 7:05 p.m. Strasburg takes the mound for the first-place Nationals in the opener of a three-game series against the Braves, who are 10-6 since July 26. 
Strasburg, a candidate for the National League Cy Young, leads the NL with 15 wins. He&apos;s looking to bounce back after losing for only the second time this year in his last start, in which he allowed four runs in 4 2/3 innings against the Giants. Strasburg has allowed only three runs in 13 2/3 innings vs. the Braves this year. 
Mike Foltynewicz starts for Atlanta. He pitched six innings of one-run ball to beat the Cardinals his last time out. 
Stat that matters: Braves first baseman Freddie Freeman is 12-for-31 (.387) lifetime against Strasburg, with two doubles and three home runs. Strasburg strikes out eight SF@WSH: Strasburg strikes out eight Giants Stephen Strasburg strikes out eight over 4 2/3 innings in his start against the Giants 
A-Rod&apos;s final game in pinstripes: TB@NYY, 7:05 p.m. The Rays have grown accustomed to being at Yankee Stadium for some notable moments in Yankees history. 
Tampa Bay has been the visitor for the first game at old Yankee Stadium after Sept. 11, 2001; the night Derek Jeter tied Lou Gehrig for most hits by a Yankee; the first game played in the Bronx after the death of Yankees owner George Steinbrenner; the unveiling of Steinbrenner&apos;s plaque in Monument Park; Jeter&apos;s 3,000th hit; Hideki Matsui&apos;s retirement ceremony; and Mariano Rivera&apos;s final relief appearance. 
Now, it&apos;s Rodriguez&apos;s final game with the Yankees. The slugger has two homers and five strikeouts in 15 career at-bats against Rays starter Chris Archer . Rodriguez could be swinging for the fences in this one, as he&apos;s sitting on 696 career homers, fourth most all-time. 
Left-hander CC Sabathia starts for the Yankees. In his only other start against the Rays this season, Sabathia allowed three runs in 4 2/3 innings in a no-decision on April 22 at Yankee Stadium. 
Stat that matters: Rodriguez has 56 home runs and 159 RBIs in 873 career at-bats against the Rays, though he&apos;s hitting .107 against them this season. A-Rod&apos;s greatest moments A look through A-Rod&apos;s storied career From the Mariners to the Rangers and the Yankees, MLB.com looks at some of the biggest moments in Alex Rodriguez&apos;s career 
Contenders clash: BAL@SF, 10:15 p.m. The Giants and Orioles are each locked in close races for first place in their respective divisions entering this pivotal three-game Interleague series. 
Matt Cain starts for the Giants, who lead the Dodgers by one game in the NL West. Cain has won his last three starts and has tossed 10 consecutive scoreless innings. 
Dylan Bundy gets the ball for the O&apos;s, who are a 1/2 game behind the Blue Jays in the American League East. Bundy is 3-2 with a 3.00 ERA in five starts since joining the rotation. The 23-year-old struck out a career-high nine batters in his last start against the White Sox. 
Stat that matters: The Orioles lead MLB with 172 homers this season, and Giants pitching has allowed 35 homers in the second half. Cain&apos;s scoreless start SF@WSH: Cain holds Nationals scoreless over five-plus Matt Cain throws five-plus innings of scoreless ball, permitting five hits, walking three and striking out four 
MLB.TV Premium subscribers get the Mosaic View -- split screen or quad, available on PC or Mac only. That always comes in handy, especially when scoreboard-watching looms. MLB.TV Premium and MLB.TV Single Team subscribers both enjoy HD and both will get real-time highlights and player stats automatically loaded moments after they occur (only for the game you are watching with MLB.TV Single Team, and for all games with MLB.TV Premium). is a reporter for MLB.com. This story was not subject to the approval of Major League Baseball or its clubs. Share This
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://m.mlb.com/assets/images/0/2/0/192663020/cuts/GettyImages_584719484_master_d49phqy2_y2qnydhg.jpg</main_image>
</document>
