<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.wallstreet-online.de/rss/nachrichten-weitere-nachrichten.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Nachrichten Ticker  - Kategorie: Weitere Nachrichten - www.wallstreet-online.de</forum_title>
<discussion_title>DGAP-News: BAUER Aktiengesellschaft: BAUER AG enters the second half of the year with large order backlog</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wallstreet-online.de/nachricht/8842615-dgap-news-bauer-aktiengesellschaft-bauer-ag-enters-the-second-half-of-the-year-with-large-order-backlog</topic_url>
<topic_text>
| 12.08.2016, 07:00 | 113 | 0 | 0 DGAP-News: BAUER Aktiengesellschaft / Key word(s): Half Year Results/Financing BAUER Aktiengesellschaft: BAUER AG enters the second half of the year with large order backlog The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement. - Total Group revenues fall by 3.0 % to EUR 757.0 million; sales revenues increase by 1.2 % to EUR 649.8 million - EBIT improves by 14.8 % to EUR 18.4 million (previous year: EUR 16.0 million); earnings after tax according to plan at EUR -7.9 million (previous year: EUR -6.8 million) - Order backlog grows by 14.6 % to EUR 1,010.2 million - Syndicated loan agreement is renewed Schrobenhausen - The first half of 2016 went according to expectations for the BAUER Group. Thanks to the solid order situation, the international construction and machinery manufacturing concern remains optimistic for the rest of the fiscal year and reaffirmed its forecast. Total Group revenues were EUR 757.0 million at the end of the second quarter, down by 3.0 % from the previous year (EUR 780.4 million). In contrast, sales revenues rose slightly by 1.2 % from EUR 642.0 million to EUR 649.8 million. EBIT increased by 14.8 % from EUR 16.0 million to EUR 18.4 million. Earnings after tax were according to plan at EUR -7.9 million (previous year: EUR -6.8 million). The order backlog increased by 14.6 % to EUR 1,010.2 million (previous year: EUR 881.5 million). Business segments With its three segments - Construction, Equipment and Resources - and its broadly diversified business model, the Group operates through more than 110 subsidiaries in some 70 countries around the world. Several large projects in the Construction segment were delayed in the start-up phase, resulting in total Group revenues falling by 10.3 % to EUR 331.9 million in the first half of the year compared to the same period last year. As a result, EBIT decreased from EUR 10.4 million to EUR 5.3 million. The company is expected to recover in the second half of the year as a result of several ongoing major projects. The order backlog increased by another 4.4 % compared to the previous year and has reached EUR 574.8 million, a very high level. Total Group revenues in the Equipment segment decreased by 6.3 % from EUR 333.4 million to EUR 312.4 million. Some large and special machines were delivered at the beginning of the year, resulting in increased earnings. EBIT grew to EUR 13.4 million (previous year: EUR 8.4 million). The order backlog fell from EUR 157.0 million to EUR 141.1 million, which is mainly attributable to business in deep-drilling rigs. The deep drilling business was integrated into the joint venture with Schlumberger at the beginning of the year. Order intake for specialist foundation engineering equipment is on target. The Resources segment increased total Group revenues by 36.1 % from EUR 102.1 million to EUR 139.0 million as a result of major projects in the environmental business. EBIT was EUR -0.1 million (previous year: EUR -3.2 million). Totaling EUR 294.4 million, the segment&apos;s order backlog increased by 69.4 %. At the end of July, the BAUER Group replaced the existing syndicated loan agreement, which was concluded in April 2014, with a new agreement. It has a volume of EUR 430 million and a regular term of three years. Outlook The company is able to confirm its full-year forecast for 2016, predicting total Group revenues of around EUR 1.65 billion, earnings after tax of around EUR 20 to 25 million, and EBIT of around EUR 75 million. &quot;We are expecting a rise in revenues in the second half of the year, thanks to our good order backlog and projects that were launched in the Construction segment,&quot; says Prof. Thomas Bauer, Chairman of the Management Board of BAUER Aktiengesellschaft. &quot;The Resources segment is showing improvement thanks to new orders, but further efforts will also be necessary.&quot; You can read the full half-year financial report online at www.bauer.de. About Bauer The BAUER Group is a leading provider of services, equipment and products related to ground and groundwater. With over 110 subsidiaries, Bauer operates a worldwide network on all continents. The operations of the Group are divided into three future-oriented segments with high synergy potential: Construction, Equipment and Resources. The Construction segment offers new and innovative specialist foundation engineering services alongside the established ones, and carries out foundation and excavation work, cut-off walls and ground improvements worldwide. Bauer is a world market leader in the Equipment segment and provides a full range of equipment for specialist foundation engineering as well as for the exploration, mining and extraction of natural resources. In the Resources sector, Bauer focuses on highly innovative products and services in the areas of water, environment and mineral deposit reserves. Bauer profits greatly from the collaboration between its three separate segments, enabling the Group to position itself as an innovative, highly specialized provider of products and services for demanding projects in specialist foundation engineering and related markets. Bauer therefore offers suitable solutions to the greatest problems in the world, such as urbanization, the growing infrastructure needs, the environment and water, oil and gas. The BAUER Group was founded in 1790 and is based in Schrobenhausen, Bavaria. In 2015, it employed some 10,700 people in around 70 countries and achieved total Group revenues of EUR 1.66 billion. BAUER Aktiengesellschaft is listed in the Prime Standard of the German stock market. More information can be found at www.bauer.de. GROUP KEY FIGURES January - June 2016 (IFRS) 2015 2016 Change in EUR million in EUR millionTotal Group revenues 780.4 757.0 -3.0 %of which
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wallstreet-online.de/nachricht/8842615-dgap-news-bauer-aktiengesellschaft-bauer-ag-enters-the-second-half-of-the-year-with-large-order-backlog</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0500</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
| 12.08.2016, 07:00 | 113 | 0 | 0 DGAP-News: BAUER Aktiengesellschaft / Key word(s): Half Year Results/Financing BAUER Aktiengesellschaft: BAUER AG enters the second half of the year with large order backlog The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement. - Total Group revenues fall by 3.0 % to EUR 757.0 million; sales revenues increase by 1.2 % to EUR 649.8 million - EBIT improves by 14.8 % to EUR 18.4 million (previous year: EUR 16.0 million); earnings after tax according to plan at EUR -7.9 million (previous year: EUR -6.8 million) - Order backlog grows by 14.6 % to EUR 1,010.2 million - Syndicated loan agreement is renewed Schrobenhausen - The first half of 2016 went according to expectations for the BAUER Group. Thanks to the solid order situation, the international construction and machinery manufacturing concern remains optimistic for the rest of the fiscal year and reaffirmed its forecast. Total Group revenues were EUR 757.0 million at the end of the second quarter, down by 3.0 % from the previous year (EUR 780.4 million). In contrast, sales revenues rose slightly by 1.2 % from EUR 642.0 million to EUR 649.8 million. EBIT increased by 14.8 % from EUR 16.0 million to EUR 18.4 million. Earnings after tax were according to plan at EUR -7.9 million (previous year: EUR -6.8 million). The order backlog increased by 14.6 % to EUR 1,010.2 million (previous year: EUR 881.5 million). Business segments With its three segments - Construction, Equipment and Resources - and its broadly diversified business model, the Group operates through more than 110 subsidiaries in some 70 countries around the world. Several large projects in the Construction segment were delayed in the start-up phase, resulting in total Group revenues falling by 10.3 % to EUR 331.9 million in the first half of the year compared to the same period last year. As a result, EBIT decreased from EUR 10.4 million to EUR 5.3 million. The company is expected to recover in the second half of the year as a result of several ongoing major projects. The order backlog increased by another 4.4 % compared to the previous year and has reached EUR 574.8 million, a very high level. Total Group revenues in the Equipment segment decreased by 6.3 % from EUR 333.4 million to EUR 312.4 million. Some large and special machines were delivered at the beginning of the year, resulting in increased earnings. EBIT grew to EUR 13.4 million (previous year: EUR 8.4 million). The order backlog fell from EUR 157.0 million to EUR 141.1 million, which is mainly attributable to business in deep-drilling rigs. The deep drilling business was integrated into the joint venture with Schlumberger at the beginning of the year. Order intake for specialist foundation engineering equipment is on target. The Resources segment increased total Group revenues by 36.1 % from EUR 102.1 million to EUR 139.0 million as a result of major projects in the environmental business. EBIT was EUR -0.1 million (previous year: EUR -3.2 million). Totaling EUR 294.4 million, the segment&apos;s order backlog increased by 69.4 %. At the end of July, the BAUER Group replaced the existing syndicated loan agreement, which was concluded in April 2014, with a new agreement. It has a volume of EUR 430 million and a regular term of three years. Outlook The company is able to confirm its full-year forecast for 2016, predicting total Group revenues of around EUR 1.65 billion, earnings after tax of around EUR 20 to 25 million, and EBIT of around EUR 75 million. &quot;We are expecting a rise in revenues in the second half of the year, thanks to our good order backlog and projects that were launched in the Construction segment,&quot; says Prof. Thomas Bauer, Chairman of the Management Board of BAUER Aktiengesellschaft. &quot;The Resources segment is showing improvement thanks to new orders, but further efforts will also be necessary.&quot; You can read the full half-year financial report online at www.bauer.de. About Bauer The BAUER Group is a leading provider of services, equipment and products related to ground and groundwater. With over 110 subsidiaries, Bauer operates a worldwide network on all continents. The operations of the Group are divided into three future-oriented segments with high synergy potential: Construction, Equipment and Resources. The Construction segment offers new and innovative specialist foundation engineering services alongside the established ones, and carries out foundation and excavation work, cut-off walls and ground improvements worldwide. Bauer is a world market leader in the Equipment segment and provides a full range of equipment for specialist foundation engineering as well as for the exploration, mining and extraction of natural resources. In the Resources sector, Bauer focuses on highly innovative products and services in the areas of water, environment and mineral deposit reserves. Bauer profits greatly from the collaboration between its three separate segments, enabling the Group to position itself as an innovative, highly specialized provider of products and services for demanding projects in specialist foundation engineering and related markets. Bauer therefore offers suitable solutions to the greatest problems in the world, such as urbanization, the growing infrastructure needs, the environment and water, oil and gas. The BAUER Group was founded in 1790 and is based in Schrobenhausen, Bavaria. In 2015, it employed some 10,700 people in around 70 countries and achieved total Group revenues of EUR 1.66 billion. BAUER Aktiengesellschaft is listed in the Prime Standard of the German stock market. More information can be found at www.bauer.de. GROUP KEY FIGURES January - June 2016 (IFRS) 2015 2016 Change in EUR million in EUR millionTotal Group revenues 780.4 757.0 -3.0 %of which
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>DE</country>
<main_image>http://assets.wallstreet-online.de/frontend/img/wso-news-default-645x355.jpg</main_image>
</document>
