<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://seekingalpha.com/atom.xml</forum>
<forum_title>All Articles on Seeking Alpha</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Here&apos;s Some Good News For Data Center REIT CoreSite Realty Shareholders</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://seekingalpha.com/article/3999059-good-news-data-center-reit-coresite-realty-shareholders</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tools4Investing.com Summary 
Data center REIT CoreSite Realty shares been under pressure recently, in part due to a perceived lack of urgency regarding acquiring additional land for expansions. 
CoreSite had been reaping the rewards of a virtuous cycle of allocating capital to the last phases of existing data center campuses. 
However, I pointed out in several articles written early this year that CoreSite was at risk of becoming a victim of its own success. 
An announcement after the bell on Thursday, August 11, 2016 should help to halt the recent bleeding. The suspense of when CoreSite Realty (NYSE: COR ) would announce an expansion in one of its key markets is finally over. I believe that this waiting game ultimately became a headwind which blunted the upward momentum in CoreSite shares. Source: www.nbcumv.com / Prior to the past few weeks, CoreSite Realty had literally become the darling of Wall Street. In all fairness to CoreSite, the entire data centor REIT sector had gotten a bit frothy, suffering from a bit of irrational exuberance. However, I pointed out issues specific to CoreSite a couple of weeks ago, in what turned out to be a timely SA piece: Data Center REITs Have Surged 50% YTD - Is CoreSite Priced For Perfection? The article was written on July 12, and tagged as a Must Read, so I am not sure if it is still available to non-PRO readers. Either way, this article will reinforce many of the same themes I wrote about in the previous article. One main difference is that a month ago, my regular SA readers had the information to decide whether to trim COR shares at ~$90.00, near all-time highs prior to Q2 earnings. Another element discussed in the prior article was the rationale behind the Stifel downgrade to &quot;Sell,&quot; with a prescient $79 target price. Notably, on July 29, after the Q2 earnings call, Stifel reiterated its Sell rating, and lowered its price target to $75 per share. However, the latest move by CoreSite might help to establish a floor underneath COR shares. Tale Of The Tape - Is Camelot Over? During the past 52-weeks, CoreSite Realty shares have traded in a range of $44.86 to $91.91 per share. The recent 13% pullback might not be particularly newsworthy for most publicly traded companies. But it certainly is news when CoreSite was the &quot;defending champion&quot; among all REITs, having delivered a total return of 50% in 2015. I believe the recent pullback was a signal that the investing thesis had changed, because there was no longer a sufficient runway to support CoreSite&apos;s impressive growth. A Longer View In a world dominated by a 24/7 news cycle, influenced by 15 minutes of fame, and subject to a &quot;what you done lately&quot; quarterly reporting mentality on Wall Street, it is very easy to lose sight of longer term performance. Source: Extra Space Storage presentation The undisputed equity REIT champion during the past five years has been CoreSite. All six data center REITs have all benefited from secular drivers of cloud computing, streaming media, wireless data and rise of IoT (Internet of Things), or machine-to-machine communication. This has resulted in a huge run-up in shares during the first half of 2016, (on top of CoreSite&apos;s 50% total return in 2015). What Fuels The Success? During the past 18 months CoreSite shares have been an unstoppable juggernaut. CoreSite has managed to consistently deliver some jaw-dropping results when it comes to metrics that matter to REIT investors, such as growing FFO per share and the quarterly dividend. I recently wrote up CoreSite&apos;s Q2 results for Data Center Knowledge , including these highlights: Reported second-quarter funds from operations (&quot;FFO&quot;) of $0.89 per diluted share and unit, representing 30.9% growth year over year. Reported second-quarter total operating revenues of $96.1 million, representing an 18.1 percent increase year over year. Executed a record 171 new and expansion data center leases comprising 48,147 net rentable square feet (NRSF), representing $7.7 million of annualized GAAP rent at a rate of $159 per square foot. CoreSite is increasing its 2016 guidance of FFO per diluted share and unit to a range of $3.56 to $3.64 from the previous range of $3.52 to $3.60. I had pointed out the previous quarter that CoreSite was at risk of becoming a victim of its own success . I concluded after the Q1 2016 call: 
&quot;On the earnings call CoreSite acknowledged the need to put new pins in the map in Santa Clara, Northern Virginia, and Chicago; but similar to last quarter, management continues to keep those cards close to the vest.&quot; In fact, this has been an obvious issue for several quarters. When CoreSite reported earnings for Q4 2015, I wrote: CoreSite Reports Strong Q4 but Shell Capacity in Key Markets Short . As the months have rolled by, the demand for space by public cloud providers created unprecedented leasing opportunities. While this is great news, it also served to exacerbate the CoreSite space/time dilemma. Lack Of Room At The Inn CoreSite had been reaping the rewards of a virtuous cycle of allocating capital to the latter phases of existing data center campuses. That is where the highest ROIC occurs because there is less capital spent on final phases. Additionally, there is operating leverage gained from these highly utilized campuses which can help to boost margins. Banking land for future development and/or building infrastructure to launch the initial phase of a new campus would have negatively impacted ROIC slightly in the short-term. However, it also would have provided a runway for future growth, and likely moderated the recent sell-off. On the latest earnings call, this issue became a bit more urgent when long-time CEO Tom Ray announced he was stepping down . The suddenness of his departure came as a shock to analysts and investors alike. Ray had been delivering the best returns of any REIT CEO. At least in the short-run, it will be difficult for a new CEO to deliver similar results because of a lack of powered shell inventory and land for expansions. I wrote in late-July: 
&quot;CoreSite facilities are currently at 92 percent occupied, up 140 bps sequentially from Q1 2016. Filling up the final phases of large data center campuses is a low risk way to deliver high margins and ROIC for shareholders. However, by always allocating capital to the existing footprint, CoreSite would be unable to maintain the growth which supports the high earnings multiples for the stock. 
It remains to be seen what direction the board will take with Paul Szurek at the helm. Chairman of CoreSite&apos;s board of directors, Robert Stuckey, said in the announcement that &apos;Paul, an active and valuable contributor to the CoreSite Board, has been instrumental in providing oversight of the company&apos;s growth and strategic direction.&apos; 
In my view, CoreSite is now behind the curve when it comes to banking land for expansion in existing US markets. This is a situation which must be dealt with swiftly in order to deliver the growth that shareholders have enjoyed under Ray&apos;s rock-solid leadership.&quot; Only the CoreSite board members are privy to the dynamics behind the sudden change at the helm. It is hard to second guess an industry leader that has delivered such outstanding results. However, the need to make some significant expansion moves has also been crystal clear, and the wait has been puzzling. A Strong Move In NoVA That is why the CoreSite announcement after the closing bell was great news for shareholders. The waiting game is now over when it comes to the red-hot Northern Virginia &quot;data center alley&quot; market. After the bell on August 11, CoreSite revealed that they had entered into an agreement to purchase Sunrise Technology Park, a 21.75 acre light-industrial/flex office park located 0.3 miles from CoreSite&apos;s existing VA1 and VA2 buildings: The Sunrise Tech Park currently has four building totaling 315,000 SF. CoreSite estimates that it can build up to 660,000 SF of data center space utilizing a phased approach. CoreSite expects to invest $60 million plus transaction costs to acquire STP, followed by an additional $90 million to complete Phase 1 of the master-planned development. CoreSite expects to begin construction of Phase 1 during the third quarter of 2017, and substantially complete that Phase in the second quarter of 2018. Phase 1 will be comprised of a) redeveloping an existing 48,000 square-foot industrial building to data center use, b) building a ground-up 92,000 square-foot data center shell, and c) building a 92,000 square-foot structure to house centralized infrastructure intended to support needs across the planned full build-out of the campus, according to the release. The total investment to build out the entire multiphase project is estimated to be $400-$500 million. CoreSite expects to close the Sunrise Tech Park acquisition during Q4 2016. Bottom Line This is great news for CoreSite shareholders. The proximity to CoreSite&apos;s existing network and cloud dense campus will make it easy for current customers to expand in the future, as well as provide build-to-suit opportunities in 2018 and beyond. However, it still means that CoreSite might miss out on the current public could leasing frenzy in Northern Virginia. There is certainly no lack of competition , as a bevy of private and publicly traded peers are building powered shells, moving dirt, and have future expansions already on the drawing board. On the other hand, the lack of &quot;land&quot; in California&apos;s Silicon Valley, another key market for CoreSite, might be a more difficult problem to solve. CoreSite&apos;s next door neighbor, privately held Vantage Data Centers, has an expansion underway and recently announced a new 51 MW campus. It remains to be seen if CoreSite will undertake additional projects in Santa Clara. The Bay Area/Santa Clara market is one of the larger US data center markets, but it is nowhere as robust as Northern Virginia. In the past, it has been more susceptible to over building of wholesale space. CoreSite still has space remaining in its final Santa Clara phase for its bread and butter, connectivity-focused, retail colocation and interconnection business. That is a different kettle of fish than 100% wholesale-focused DuPont Fabros Technology (NYSE: DFT ), another REIT out of land in the Silicon Valley. Investor Takeaway As a practical matter, the announcement of the CoreSite Northern Virginia expansion will not change analyst estimates for the next few quarters. However, this long awaited new campus is a huge &quot;psychological&quot; lift for investors who have eagerly been listening to earnings calls, and coming away disappointed. There is still plenty of work to be done in other markets, and perhaps even internationally. Additionally, CoreSite investors need to be reassured what the priorities will be for the incoming CEO. CoreSite was priced for perfection, and the gap in new projects will likely reduce the growth rate for the next few quarters. Even after the recent pullback, COR shares are still priced ~22x FFO estimates. Early this week I wrote a focus piece on CyrusOne (NASDAQ: CONE ), laying out my rationale why this data center REIT was a &quot;Buy&quot; on its recent pullback. If you are considering buying a data center REIT today, I would encourage readers to take a long look at this article first . I relentlessly hunt for diamonds in the rough and rising stars, in addition to closely following data centers, covering REIT blue chips and breaking news. Please consider following me as a Seeking Alpha author if you would like to be notified when my future articles are published. Disclosure: I/we have no positions in any stocks mentioned, but may initiate a long position in CONE over the next 72 hours. I wrote this article myself, and it expresses my own opinions. I am not receiving compensation for it (other than from Seeking Alpha). I have no business relationship with any company whose stock is mentioned in this article. About this article: Expand Author payment: $35 + $0.01/page view. Authors of PRO articles receive a minimum guaranteed payment of $150-500. Become a contributor » Tagged: Dividends &amp; Income , REITs , Financial , Real Estate Development , Alternative Investing
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://seekingalpha.com/article/3999059-good-news-data-center-reit-coresite-realty-shareholders</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0550</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Tools4Investing.com Summary 
Data center REIT CoreSite Realty shares been under pressure recently, in part due to a perceived lack of urgency regarding acquiring additional land for expansions. 
CoreSite had been reaping the rewards of a virtuous cycle of allocating capital to the last phases of existing data center campuses. 
However, I pointed out in several articles written early this year that CoreSite was at risk of becoming a victim of its own success. 
An announcement after the bell on Thursday, August 11, 2016 should help to halt the recent bleeding. The suspense of when CoreSite Realty (NYSE: COR ) would announce an expansion in one of its key markets is finally over. I believe that this waiting game ultimately became a headwind which blunted the upward momentum in CoreSite shares. Source: www.nbcumv.com / Prior to the past few weeks, CoreSite Realty had literally become the darling of Wall Street. In all fairness to CoreSite, the entire data centor REIT sector had gotten a bit frothy, suffering from a bit of irrational exuberance. However, I pointed out issues specific to CoreSite a couple of weeks ago, in what turned out to be a timely SA piece: Data Center REITs Have Surged 50% YTD - Is CoreSite Priced For Perfection? The article was written on July 12, and tagged as a Must Read, so I am not sure if it is still available to non-PRO readers. Either way, this article will reinforce many of the same themes I wrote about in the previous article. One main difference is that a month ago, my regular SA readers had the information to decide whether to trim COR shares at ~$90.00, near all-time highs prior to Q2 earnings. Another element discussed in the prior article was the rationale behind the Stifel downgrade to &quot;Sell,&quot; with a prescient $79 target price. Notably, on July 29, after the Q2 earnings call, Stifel reiterated its Sell rating, and lowered its price target to $75 per share. However, the latest move by CoreSite might help to establish a floor underneath COR shares. Tale Of The Tape - Is Camelot Over? During the past 52-weeks, CoreSite Realty shares have traded in a range of $44.86 to $91.91 per share. The recent 13% pullback might not be particularly newsworthy for most publicly traded companies. But it certainly is news when CoreSite was the &quot;defending champion&quot; among all REITs, having delivered a total return of 50% in 2015. I believe the recent pullback was a signal that the investing thesis had changed, because there was no longer a sufficient runway to support CoreSite&apos;s impressive growth. A Longer View In a world dominated by a 24/7 news cycle, influenced by 15 minutes of fame, and subject to a &quot;what you done lately&quot; quarterly reporting mentality on Wall Street, it is very easy to lose sight of longer term performance. Source: Extra Space Storage presentation The undisputed equity REIT champion during the past five years has been CoreSite. All six data center REITs have all benefited from secular drivers of cloud computing, streaming media, wireless data and rise of IoT (Internet of Things), or machine-to-machine communication. This has resulted in a huge run-up in shares during the first half of 2016, (on top of CoreSite&apos;s 50% total return in 2015). What Fuels The Success? During the past 18 months CoreSite shares have been an unstoppable juggernaut. CoreSite has managed to consistently deliver some jaw-dropping results when it comes to metrics that matter to REIT investors, such as growing FFO per share and the quarterly dividend. I recently wrote up CoreSite&apos;s Q2 results for Data Center Knowledge , including these highlights: Reported second-quarter funds from operations (&quot;FFO&quot;) of $0.89 per diluted share and unit, representing 30.9% growth year over year. Reported second-quarter total operating revenues of $96.1 million, representing an 18.1 percent increase year over year. Executed a record 171 new and expansion data center leases comprising 48,147 net rentable square feet (NRSF), representing $7.7 million of annualized GAAP rent at a rate of $159 per square foot. CoreSite is increasing its 2016 guidance of FFO per diluted share and unit to a range of $3.56 to $3.64 from the previous range of $3.52 to $3.60. I had pointed out the previous quarter that CoreSite was at risk of becoming a victim of its own success . I concluded after the Q1 2016 call: 
&quot;On the earnings call CoreSite acknowledged the need to put new pins in the map in Santa Clara, Northern Virginia, and Chicago; but similar to last quarter, management continues to keep those cards close to the vest.&quot; In fact, this has been an obvious issue for several quarters. When CoreSite reported earnings for Q4 2015, I wrote: CoreSite Reports Strong Q4 but Shell Capacity in Key Markets Short . As the months have rolled by, the demand for space by public cloud providers created unprecedented leasing opportunities. While this is great news, it also served to exacerbate the CoreSite space/time dilemma. Lack Of Room At The Inn CoreSite had been reaping the rewards of a virtuous cycle of allocating capital to the latter phases of existing data center campuses. That is where the highest ROIC occurs because there is less capital spent on final phases. Additionally, there is operating leverage gained from these highly utilized campuses which can help to boost margins. Banking land for future development and/or building infrastructure to launch the initial phase of a new campus would have negatively impacted ROIC slightly in the short-term. However, it also would have provided a runway for future growth, and likely moderated the recent sell-off. On the latest earnings call, this issue became a bit more urgent when long-time CEO Tom Ray announced he was stepping down . The suddenness of his departure came as a shock to analysts and investors alike. Ray had been delivering the best returns of any REIT CEO. At least in the short-run, it will be difficult for a new CEO to deliver similar results because of a lack of powered shell inventory and land for expansions. I wrote in late-July: 
&quot;CoreSite facilities are currently at 92 percent occupied, up 140 bps sequentially from Q1 2016. Filling up the final phases of large data center campuses is a low risk way to deliver high margins and ROIC for shareholders. However, by always allocating capital to the existing footprint, CoreSite would be unable to maintain the growth which supports the high earnings multiples for the stock. 
It remains to be seen what direction the board will take with Paul Szurek at the helm. Chairman of CoreSite&apos;s board of directors, Robert Stuckey, said in the announcement that &apos;Paul, an active and valuable contributor to the CoreSite Board, has been instrumental in providing oversight of the company&apos;s growth and strategic direction.&apos; 
In my view, CoreSite is now behind the curve when it comes to banking land for expansion in existing US markets. This is a situation which must be dealt with swiftly in order to deliver the growth that shareholders have enjoyed under Ray&apos;s rock-solid leadership.&quot; Only the CoreSite board members are privy to the dynamics behind the sudden change at the helm. It is hard to second guess an industry leader that has delivered such outstanding results. However, the need to make some significant expansion moves has also been crystal clear, and the wait has been puzzling. A Strong Move In NoVA That is why the CoreSite announcement after the closing bell was great news for shareholders. The waiting game is now over when it comes to the red-hot Northern Virginia &quot;data center alley&quot; market. After the bell on August 11, CoreSite revealed that they had entered into an agreement to purchase Sunrise Technology Park, a 21.75 acre light-industrial/flex office park located 0.3 miles from CoreSite&apos;s existing VA1 and VA2 buildings: The Sunrise Tech Park currently has four building totaling 315,000 SF. CoreSite estimates that it can build up to 660,000 SF of data center space utilizing a phased approach. CoreSite expects to invest $60 million plus transaction costs to acquire STP, followed by an additional $90 million to complete Phase 1 of the master-planned development. CoreSite expects to begin construction of Phase 1 during the third quarter of 2017, and substantially complete that Phase in the second quarter of 2018. Phase 1 will be comprised of a) redeveloping an existing 48,000 square-foot industrial building to data center use, b) building a ground-up 92,000 square-foot data center shell, and c) building a 92,000 square-foot structure to house centralized infrastructure intended to support needs across the planned full build-out of the campus, according to the release. The total investment to build out the entire multiphase project is estimated to be $400-$500 million. CoreSite expects to close the Sunrise Tech Park acquisition during Q4 2016. Bottom Line This is great news for CoreSite shareholders. The proximity to CoreSite&apos;s existing network and cloud dense campus will make it easy for current customers to expand in the future, as well as provide build-to-suit opportunities in 2018 and beyond. However, it still means that CoreSite might miss out on the current public could leasing frenzy in Northern Virginia. There is certainly no lack of competition , as a bevy of private and publicly traded peers are building powered shells, moving dirt, and have future expansions already on the drawing board. On the other hand, the lack of &quot;land&quot; in California&apos;s Silicon Valley, another key market for CoreSite, might be a more difficult problem to solve. CoreSite&apos;s next door neighbor, privately held Vantage Data Centers, has an expansion underway and recently announced a new 51 MW campus. It remains to be seen if CoreSite will undertake additional projects in Santa Clara. The Bay Area/Santa Clara market is one of the larger US data center markets, but it is nowhere as robust as Northern Virginia. In the past, it has been more susceptible to over building of wholesale space. CoreSite still has space remaining in its final Santa Clara phase for its bread and butter, connectivity-focused, retail colocation and interconnection business. That is a different kettle of fish than 100% wholesale-focused DuPont Fabros Technology (NYSE: DFT ), another REIT out of land in the Silicon Valley. Investor Takeaway As a practical matter, the announcement of the CoreSite Northern Virginia expansion will not change analyst estimates for the next few quarters. However, this long awaited new campus is a huge &quot;psychological&quot; lift for investors who have eagerly been listening to earnings calls, and coming away disappointed. There is still plenty of work to be done in other markets, and perhaps even internationally. Additionally, CoreSite investors need to be reassured what the priorities will be for the incoming CEO. CoreSite was priced for perfection, and the gap in new projects will likely reduce the growth rate for the next few quarters. Even after the recent pullback, COR shares are still priced ~22x FFO estimates. Early this week I wrote a focus piece on CyrusOne (NASDAQ: CONE ), laying out my rationale why this data center REIT was a &quot;Buy&quot; on its recent pullback. If you are considering buying a data center REIT today, I would encourage readers to take a long look at this article first . I relentlessly hunt for diamonds in the rough and rising stars, in addition to closely following data centers, covering REIT blue chips and breaking news. Please consider following me as a Seeking Alpha author if you would like to be notified when my future articles are published. Disclosure: I/we have no positions in any stocks mentioned, but may initiate a long position in CONE over the next 72 hours. I wrote this article myself, and it expresses my own opinions. I am not receiving compensation for it (other than from Seeking Alpha). I have no business relationship with any company whose stock is mentioned in this article. About this article: Expand Author payment: $35 + $0.01/page view. Authors of PRO articles receive a minimum guaranteed payment of $150-500. Become a contributor » Tagged: Dividends &amp; Income , REITs , Financial , Real Estate Development , Alternative Investing
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://staticseekingalpha3.a.ssl.fastly.net/uploads/2016/8/12205311_14709673296432_rId4.jpg</main_image>
</document>
