<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/rssfeeds/5575607.cms</forum>
<forum_title>Small Biz-The Economic Times</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Old is Gold: Startups for elderly hold a huge business opportunity in India</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/small-biz/startups/old-is-gold-startups-for-elderly-hold-a-huge-business-opportunity-in-india/articleshow/53664247.cms</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Which stage of life is most difficult? 

Answers may vary according to perception, but there is little doubt that old-age is a very difficult phase in one&apos;s life. 

On one hand, advances in medical technology have led to increased life expectancy, at the other end of the spectrum, with families largely becoming nuclear and children moving all over the world , many seniors who may not be very active or mobile, face loneliness and care giving issues. 

Bridging the gaps and tackling issues are startups such as Senior Shelf , Silver Talkies and BeautifulYears among others who are doing their best to improve the lives of the elderly and of those who take care of them. A bit ahead of the curve, the startups for the elderly feel the domain is compelling because it combines two aspects: a human need and a business opportunity. 

Senior Shelf 
An online shopping portal, Senior Shelf primarily aggregates products and services for senior citizens, which are not easily accessible offline or are not available in offline retail channel. 

It was a hot and dusty afternoon in Patna when Senior Shelf founder Rahul Upadhyay had gone on a brief visit to his parents and set out to buy a blood pressure machine. In a city of a few million people, it took four hours of hunting before discovering a small surgical store near a hospital. That set him thinking about all the millions of elderly who are today living alone - people who, despite having the means, are unable to access even the basic products beyond what is available at the neighbourhood stores. 

In some cases, they are not even aware of any of the products which can make their life easier. For example a safety rail for the toilet that can support elderly and prevent falls and accidents, a multi-reacher that can enable elderly to pick up anything without having to bend down or reach out, a landline phone with super large buttons, emergency dial and hearing aid compatibility and a reclining wheelchair that is a lot more comfortable than the usual straight backed wheelchair. 

Upadhyay says, among products, toilet safety is a prime concern and hence products like safety rail, grab bar etc. are very popular. According to one study in the US, almost one in three elderly have a fall in the bathroom which can lead to many complications. &quot;We also aggregate other products like wheelchairs, walking sticks, products for bed ridden elderly like bed safety railing etc. Among the services offered are senior care at home, nursing care services and travel packages for elderly - all of these are aggregated from third party partner,&quot; he adds. 

The startup has grown almost three times year-on-year and see more than 40000 visits in a month. &quot;Being a bootstrapped company, our primary traffic driver has been word of mouth and social networks,&quot; says Upadhyay. 

Talking about the business opportunity that the startups in the senior care space holds in India, Upadhyay says, &quot;Frankly - the industry does not quite exist in India as yet and neither do all the products. The awareness and consciousness is also not there. In that sense, we are a bit ahead of the curve,&quot; he says. 

Upadhyay adds that with a 10 crore population of elderly, the market is huge and will grow exponentially once there is greater awareness. &quot;There is a large population of tech savvy retirees coming up in the next 5-7 years - people who were in 40&apos;s when the Internet boom happened in late 90&apos;s and early 2000. These are a tech savvy, aware generation of retirees who would demand products and services they see available outside India and that is where I see real growth coming in.&quot; 

Senior Shelf is now mulling to go offline with a network of stores to sell directly to elderly. &quot;When we started off, being online, our primary targets are the children of the elderly who are not able to live with their parents, but would still like to support and help them as much as possible regardless of geography. However, we have also discovered a large number of elderly who want to purchase the products for their own consumption - but are not online enabled hence find it difficult. Hence we are now contemplating an offline model to cater to them,&quot; says Upadhyay. With 17 years of sales and marketing experience, Upadhyay has worked in eight start-up ventures for brands like Times FM, Times Music , Times Multimedia, Radio Mirchi, Big FM and Vodafone Corporate. 

Silver Talkies 
Co-founded by Nidhi Chawla and Reshmi Chakraborty, Silver Talkies is an online magazine and multi-dimensional platform for urban Indians over 60 years of age and their families, who may be looking for avenues to enrich their parents&apos; lives. 

Nidhi Chawla and Reshmi Chakraborty started Silver Talkies as a blog before officially launching an online magazine in 2014. &quot;Both of us live away from our parents and as they grew older, we saw the need to enhance various aspects in their lives and felt there was a lacunae in meeting the needs of senior citizens.We felt the need for an online platform that provided exclusive information on everything relevant to the 60 plus age group. The events were a natural progression as we observed the lack of focused, informative and enriching activities for seniors in our cities ,&quot; says Chakraborty. 

Today the services are both online and offline. Online the startup provides information on topics relevant to the 60 plus age group. &quot;Our aim from the beginning has been to highlight the amazing potential, enterprise and talent among senior citizens in India, something that often gets sidelined. Offline, we bring exclusive, tailor made events and workshops for the 60 plus, ranging from art workshops to heritage walks to a carnival featuring senior entrepreneur,&quot; says Chakraborty. 

One of the popular sections on the website highlights senior entrepreneurs who started a business in their sixties or after retirement. Another popular section is called People and Passion that showcases extraordinary achievements by the 60 plus, right from social work to being one of the country&apos;s leading rose breeders to running marathons. &quot;These sections usually get us very positive feedback and are popular reads,&quot; informs Chakraborty. 

Chawla is a former financial services sector professional, having worked with SREI International Securities and McKinsey &amp; Co and Chakraborty is a former journalist. 

Self funded at the moment, Silver Talkies plans to build a community of &apos;silvers&apos; across Bangalore , in the form of a club and gradually move on to other cities. &quot;We are constantly working to bring diverse and entertaining events for seniors and plan to increase our focus on that area. For our website, we aim to have more interactive sections and also forums that enable senior citizens to discuss their issues and needs. Plans are also on for a dedicated YouTube channel highlighting senior achievers, conserving oral histories and other activities across various media platforms,&quot; says Chakraborty. 

BeautifulYears 
With an aim to improve lives of the elderly and of those who take care of them, Bangalore-based Vladi Ruppo co-founded BeautifulYears Ltd along with Pavithra Reddy in January 2016. The startup provides online elderly care products and solutions. 

BeautifulYears offers to make your home senior-friendly. &quot;As we all know, every third elderly person falls at least once a year and 20 % of these falls are life-threatening. More than 50 % of falls could be prevented. There are at least 10 companies in Bangalore offering to make your home kids-friendly, baby-proofing it for your kids. We are the first to make your home senior friendly, &quot;elder-proofing&quot; it for your aging parents. We come over and suggest best ways to make your home safe, secure, and comfortable for seniors. We have also created an online forum for people taking care of their parents, to share experiences and to help each other take better care of our seniors,&quot; says Vladi Ruppo. 

The startup does not limit itself to making suggestions. It sells innovative elder care products online and offline, at its Experience Store in Koramangala. There are alarm pendants and watches so if your mom or dad falls, they can call for help. There are GPS trackers for people with Alzheimer&apos;s, to assist in case they leave home unexpectedly and do not know their way back. There are multiple anti-skid and fall prevention solutions. There are home automation systems very pertinent for the elderly. The list of products is long and exhaustive. 

&quot;Secondly, we help people find the best services - be it a physiotherapist, a nurse or an attendant, or a senior living facility. We know almost everyone in the market, and we help you choose - free of charge,&quot; he adds. 

In the offline world, BeautifulYears conducts classes and activities for senior citizens, for a symbolic fee or free of charge. Ruppo says their workshops on using smartphones sessions or legal aspects of aging and last wills were a big hit. 

Born and brought up in Russia, Ruppo came to India in 2000, to set up an R&amp;D centre of a software product company he was working for. Cofounder Reddy, on the other hand worked with Ruppo for about eight years in the software industry but has a lot of personal experience in caregiving and a deep understanding of human needs and elderly care realities. 

Sharing the idea behind BeautifulYears, Ruppo says, &quot;When we started thinking about our proposition in 2014, there have been very few startups in this area. As it often happens in this domain, it was a combination of two factors - first, it was about very personal experiences of co-founders with elders in their families. We just wanted to help, to do something meaningful. Second, it was about a business opportunity - there was hardly anything in this area, and the gap between India and the West was much wider in elder care than in any other domain.&quot; 

Initially, with the cofounders expertise in technology, they wanted to come up with new high-tech products in the domain of elder care and independent living for seniors. &quot;Then we realized that there were already about 1,500 startups around the world working on innovative technologies for seniors. The issue was not with the products, but with bringing them to the market. So we decided that BeautifulYears, instead of competing with others, would help those startups build their marketing channels,&quot; says Ruppo. 

The startup sees a lot of traction in their Experience store in Koramangala, with revenues growing about 30 percent month-on-month. &quot;Home modifications are doing very well too,&quot; says Ruppo. 

Ruppo conservatively estimates the market for home modifications at 1,250 crore and the market for their products and services at 1,830 crore, and growing at about 20 % annually. Self-funded at the moment, BeautifulYears founders are considering raising funds to scale up faster.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/small-biz/startups/old-is-gold-startups-for-elderly-hold-a-huge-business-opportunity-in-india/articleshow/53664247.cms</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>1055</post_time>
<username>Nandini Upreti</username>
<post>
It will be of great help for all those Senior Citizens are left alone because of various Circumstances.,There will be growing need for such facilities
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/thumb/msid-53664296,width-600,resizemode-4,imglength-158844/small-biz/startups/old-is-gold-startups-for-elderly-hold-a-huge-business-opportunity-in-india/thinkstockphotos-md00250666666.jpg</main_image>
</document>
