<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.nwherald.com/?rss=news/local</forum>
<forum_title>Local News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>McHenry Township Fire Protection District to offer seniors fire, fall prevention program</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.nwherald.com/2016/08/10/mchenry-township-fire-protection-district-to-offer-seniors-fire-fall-prevention-program/adj8hv0/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
McHenry Township Fire Protection District to offer seniors fire, fall prevention program Published: Friday, Aug. 12, 2016 12:31 a.m. CDT • Updated: Friday, Aug. 12, 2016 12:33 a.m. CDT Caption (Sarah Nader) Sarah Nader - snader@shawmedia.com McHenry firefighters Joe Winkelman (left), Andrew Horist and Jeremy Pieper load 75 smoke alarms into their truck at Meijer in McHenry Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016. McHenry Township Fire Protection District received a $500 gift card from Meijer to buy the smoke alarms. The alarms are going to be used fro the fire departments &quot;Remembering When&quot; program that starts in September and is aimed at helping elderly people prevent falls and fires. Caption (Sarah Nader) Sarah Nader - snader@shawmedia.com McHenry firefighters Jeremy Pieper (left), Joe Wonkelman and Andrew Horist ltake 75 smoke alarms to their truck at Meijer in McHenry Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016. McHenry Township Fire Protection District received a $500 gift card from Meijer to buy the smoke alarms. The alarms are going to be used fro the fire departments &quot;Remembering When&quot; program that starts in September and is aimed at helping elderly people prevent falls and fires. By HANNAH PROKOP hprokop 
McHENRY – A group of McHenry Township Fire Protection District employees went shopping Thursday morning for an item that some of its most high-risk callers don’t have – smoke alarms. 
Seniors are some of the most frequent callers to the department, and the reason why it’s implementing the “Remembering When” program starting in September. 
The four-day program will bring in presenters to educate seniors and their caregivers on ways to prevent falls and fires. 
“We’re just trying to help them stay safe and not visit the ER,” said Rebecca Rosner, McHenry Township Fire Protection District public education coordinator. “That’s the No. 1 reason they go to the ER, is falls.” 
People 60 and older made up about 45 percent of the department’s EMS calls in 2015, Rosner said. McHenry County experts also have said that senior falls lead to higher rates of injury and death . 
“The No. 1 goal there, obviously, is to make sure that our seniors are safe,” McHenry Township Fire Protection District Chief Tony Huemann said. “The secondary part of the byproduct of that is it reduces our call volume and allows us to answer other calls.” 
Huemann said sometimes when the department responds to a senior’s home, a smoke alarm may be beeping because it’s out of battery, but the senior does not hear it. 
Part of the “Remembering When” program will include house visits to seniors, Rosner said, where firefighters will meet with seniors to make sure their alarms are working and help make a fire exit plan. 
If alarms need to be replaced, the fire department will use the 75 smoke alarms they picked up Thursday through a $500 donation from Meijer in McHenry. 
“Remembering When” was developed by the National Fire Protection Association’s Center for High-Risk Outreach and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Rosner said. 
Huemann said the department decided to host the program when Rosner, the department’s first public education coordinator, saw it was an area they needed to focus on more. 
“We’re recognizing the fact that we need take care of the at-risk people in our community,” Huemann said. 
The “Remembering When” sessions will be from 10 to 11:30 a.m. Sept. 10 and 24 and Oct. 1 and 8 at the McHenry Recreation Center, 3636 Municipal Drive, McHenry. 
For information or to RSVP, contact Rosner at 815-669-5379 or .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.nwherald.com/2016/08/10/mchenry-township-fire-protection-district-to-offer-seniors-fire-fall-prevention-program/adj8hv0/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0531</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
McHenry Township Fire Protection District to offer seniors fire, fall prevention program Published: Friday, Aug. 12, 2016 12:31 a.m. CDT • Updated: Friday, Aug. 12, 2016 12:33 a.m. CDT Caption (Sarah Nader) Sarah Nader - snader@shawmedia.com McHenry firefighters Joe Winkelman (left), Andrew Horist and Jeremy Pieper load 75 smoke alarms into their truck at Meijer in McHenry Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016. McHenry Township Fire Protection District received a $500 gift card from Meijer to buy the smoke alarms. The alarms are going to be used fro the fire departments &quot;Remembering When&quot; program that starts in September and is aimed at helping elderly people prevent falls and fires. Caption (Sarah Nader) Sarah Nader - snader@shawmedia.com McHenry firefighters Jeremy Pieper (left), Joe Wonkelman and Andrew Horist ltake 75 smoke alarms to their truck at Meijer in McHenry Thursday, Aug. 11, 2016. McHenry Township Fire Protection District received a $500 gift card from Meijer to buy the smoke alarms. The alarms are going to be used fro the fire departments &quot;Remembering When&quot; program that starts in September and is aimed at helping elderly people prevent falls and fires. By HANNAH PROKOP hprokop 
McHENRY – A group of McHenry Township Fire Protection District employees went shopping Thursday morning for an item that some of its most high-risk callers don’t have – smoke alarms. 
Seniors are some of the most frequent callers to the department, and the reason why it’s implementing the “Remembering When” program starting in September. 
The four-day program will bring in presenters to educate seniors and their caregivers on ways to prevent falls and fires. 
“We’re just trying to help them stay safe and not visit the ER,” said Rebecca Rosner, McHenry Township Fire Protection District public education coordinator. “That’s the No. 1 reason they go to the ER, is falls.” 
People 60 and older made up about 45 percent of the department’s EMS calls in 2015, Rosner said. McHenry County experts also have said that senior falls lead to higher rates of injury and death . 
“The No. 1 goal there, obviously, is to make sure that our seniors are safe,” McHenry Township Fire Protection District Chief Tony Huemann said. “The secondary part of the byproduct of that is it reduces our call volume and allows us to answer other calls.” 
Huemann said sometimes when the department responds to a senior’s home, a smoke alarm may be beeping because it’s out of battery, but the senior does not hear it. 
Part of the “Remembering When” program will include house visits to seniors, Rosner said, where firefighters will meet with seniors to make sure their alarms are working and help make a fire exit plan. 
If alarms need to be replaced, the fire department will use the 75 smoke alarms they picked up Thursday through a $500 donation from Meijer in McHenry. 
“Remembering When” was developed by the National Fire Protection Association’s Center for High-Risk Outreach and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Rosner said. 
Huemann said the department decided to host the program when Rosner, the department’s first public education coordinator, saw it was an area they needed to focus on more. 
“We’re recognizing the fact that we need take care of the at-risk people in our community,” Huemann said. 
The “Remembering When” sessions will be from 10 to 11:30 a.m. Sept. 10 and 24 and Oct. 1 and 8 at the McHenry Recreation Center, 3636 Municipal Drive, McHenry. 
For information or to RSVP, contact Rosner at 815-669-5379 or .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.nwherald.com/_internal/cimg!0/5awbwejx7saqeufji42hzx8a6w1z4k6</main_image>
</document>
