<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/109575288/wxia-sports</forum>
<forum_title>WXIA - Sports</forum_title>
<discussion_title>&apos;Final Five&apos; brings coach to tears</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/109575288/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;11alive&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;final-five-nickname-creates-surprising-moment-in-krolyi-marriage&amp;#x2f;295217816</topic_url>
<topic_text>
&apos;Final Five&apos; nickname creates surprising moment in Károlyi marriage USA Women gymnasts inspire local gymnasts Alec McQuade, WXIA 6:49 PM. EDT August 11, 2016 Gabrielle Douglas of the United States celebrates winning the gold medal with coach Liang Chow and team coordinator Martha Karolyi after the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Individual All-Around final (Photo by Streeter Lecka/Getty Images) (Photo: Streeter Lecka, 2012 Getty Images) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
Béla Károlyi has known his wife, Márta Károlyi for a long time. 
Before Tuesday, he had only seen his wife cry one time in 53 years of marriage. It was when her father passed away. 
&quot;Other than that, I&apos;ve never seen her cry. She&apos;s a very strong character,&quot; Béla said in a Facebook Live with former gymnast Samantha Peszek for NBC Olympics. 
That changed when the U.S. women&apos;s gymnastics team made up of Simone Biles, Aly Raisman, Laurie Hernanez, Gabby Douglas and Madison Kocian won the Gold medal in the team gymnastics competition Tuesday. 
After the team won, they revealed their nickname, &apos;The Final Five,&apos; in honor of the team coach and coordinator Márta Károlyi who is retiring after Rio. They also named themselves that because after Rio only four gymnasts will compete from each country in the Olympics. 
After the competition, Béla went down to congratulate his wife not knowing what the team&apos;s name was yet. 
&quot;At the time I went down to meet her, hug her, she wanted to tell me the name of the team, and she never could get further than, &apos;You know the name of the team...&apos;&quot; 
Béla kept trying to get it out of Márta, begging her to tell him 
&quot;She choked up so hard that finally she broke out in crying and said, &apos;The Final Five.&apos;&quot; 
Béla said he got emotional at that moment, too. final five | we dedicated our team name to The Legend Marta, so when we told her she started crying. WE LOVE HER ❤️ pic.twitter.com/p8lYVzKMbR — Simone Biles (@Simone_Biles) August 10, 2016 
Both of them have been coaching gymnastics for more than half a century. They defected from Romania in 1981, and both have coached the U.S. team at some point. Márta has been a coordinator for the team since 2001. Since then, the U.S. has won 87 World Championship and Olympic medals going into Rio. 
Now, Béla wants to spend more time doing hobbies like hunting, and Márta wants to visit family in Romania. They&apos;ll still attend gymnastics events from time to time, but Béla says it is time to step back for good. 
&quot;There is a goodbye we&apos;ve got to say to the sport, to the athletes and also to the sport that we love so much, gymnastics.&quot; PHOTOS | Biles, Raisman compete in all-around final % Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (R) of the United States is embraced by Alexandra Raisman (C) and coach Mihai Brestyan (L) after competing on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States waves to fans after winning the gold medal during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles (R) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro (Photo credit EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles reacts after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles (C) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman (R) after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and US gymnast Alexandra Raisman prepare to compete at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles&apos; painted toenails can be seen as she rests during the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States prepares to compete on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles takes part in the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States looks on while waiting for moving to the next apparatus during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the vault event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States prepares to compete on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.11alive.com/_/20/109575288/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;11alive&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;final-five-nickname-creates-surprising-moment-in-krolyi-marriage&amp;#x2f;295217816</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2249</post_time>
<username>Alec McQuade</username>
<post>
&apos;Final Five&apos; nickname creates surprising moment in Károlyi marriage USA Women gymnasts inspire local gymnasts Alec McQuade, WXIA 6:49 PM. EDT August 11, 2016 Gabrielle Douglas of the United States celebrates winning the gold medal with coach Liang Chow and team coordinator Martha Karolyi after the Artistic Gymnastics Women&apos;s Individual All-Around final (Photo by Streeter Lecka/Getty Images) (Photo: Streeter Lecka, 2012 Getty Images) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
Béla Károlyi has known his wife, Márta Károlyi for a long time. 
Before Tuesday, he had only seen his wife cry one time in 53 years of marriage. It was when her father passed away. 
&quot;Other than that, I&apos;ve never seen her cry. She&apos;s a very strong character,&quot; Béla said in a Facebook Live with former gymnast Samantha Peszek for NBC Olympics. 
That changed when the U.S. women&apos;s gymnastics team made up of Simone Biles, Aly Raisman, Laurie Hernanez, Gabby Douglas and Madison Kocian won the Gold medal in the team gymnastics competition Tuesday. 
After the team won, they revealed their nickname, &apos;The Final Five,&apos; in honor of the team coach and coordinator Márta Károlyi who is retiring after Rio. They also named themselves that because after Rio only four gymnasts will compete from each country in the Olympics. 
After the competition, Béla went down to congratulate his wife not knowing what the team&apos;s name was yet. 
&quot;At the time I went down to meet her, hug her, she wanted to tell me the name of the team, and she never could get further than, &apos;You know the name of the team...&apos;&quot; 
Béla kept trying to get it out of Márta, begging her to tell him 
&quot;She choked up so hard that finally she broke out in crying and said, &apos;The Final Five.&apos;&quot; 
Béla said he got emotional at that moment, too. final five | we dedicated our team name to The Legend Marta, so when we told her she started crying. WE LOVE HER ❤️ pic.twitter.com/p8lYVzKMbR — Simone Biles (@Simone_Biles) August 10, 2016 
Both of them have been coaching gymnastics for more than half a century. They defected from Romania in 1981, and both have coached the U.S. team at some point. Márta has been a coordinator for the team since 2001. Since then, the U.S. has won 87 World Championship and Olympic medals going into Rio. 
Now, Béla wants to spend more time doing hobbies like hunting, and Márta wants to visit family in Romania. They&apos;ll still attend gymnastics events from time to time, but Béla says it is time to step back for good. 
&quot;There is a goodbye we&apos;ve got to say to the sport, to the athletes and also to the sport that we love so much, gymnastics.&quot; PHOTOS | Biles, Raisman compete in all-around final % Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles (R) of the United States is embraced by Alexandra Raisman (C) and coach Mihai Brestyan (L) after competing on the floor during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States waves to fans after winning the gold medal during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Alexandra Raisman competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles (R) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro (Photo credit EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles reacts after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles (C) embraces US gymnast Alexandra Raisman (R) after seeing her score in the uneven bars event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles (R) and US gymnast Alexandra Raisman prepare to compete at the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the beam event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Ben STANSALL (Photo credit should read BEN STANSALL/AFP/Getty Images) BEN STANSALL, This content is subject to copyright. US gymnast Simone Biles&apos; painted toenails can be seen as she rests during the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the balance beam during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States prepares to compete on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images Alexandra Raisman of the United States competes on the uneven bars during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Richard Heathcote/Getty Images) Richard Heathcote, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles takes part in the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / EMMANUEL DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Alexandra Raisman of the United States looks on while waiting for moving to the next apparatus during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images US gymnast Simone Biles competes in the vault event of the women&apos;s individual all-around final of the Artistic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 11, 2016. / AFP / Emmanuel DUNAND (Photo credit should read EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP/Getty Images) EMMANUEL DUNAND, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States prepares to compete on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 11: Simone Biles of the United States competes on the vault during the Women&apos;s Individual All Around Final on Day 6 of the 2016 Rio Olympics at Rio Olympic Arena on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Harry How/Getty Images) Harry How, 2016 Getty Images of
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.11alive.com/photo/2016/08/11/GettyImages-149701072_1470950804709_5095050_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
