<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.thv11.com/_/20/109681432/kthv/sports</forum>
<forum_title>KTHV - Sports</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Michael Phelps wins gold in men&apos;s 200 IM</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.thv11.com/_/20/109681432/kthv/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;thv11&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;michael-phelps-wins-gold-in-mens-200-im&amp;#x2f;295500950</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Michael Phelps wins gold in men&apos;s 200 IM Nicole Auerbach, USA TODAY Sports , KING 10:16   Michael Phelps (USA, right)) and Ryan Lochte (USA) after the men&apos;s 200m individual medley semifinals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. (Photo: Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
RIO DE JANEIRO - Michael Phelps is getting closer and closer to finishing off these Games exactly the way he wants. 
So far: Four event finals down, four gold medals in hand. Phelps’s latest came in the 200-meter individual medley, an event Phelps has now won in four consecutive Olympics. Ryan Lochte failed to win a medal in the race, finishing fifth. 
Thursday night’s race was the final one between Lochte and Phelps, who have been squaring off in this particular event for 12 years. 
The most decorated Olympian in history, Phelps now has 22 gold medals and 26 medals overall. He is expected to swim next in the men’s 100 butterfly final Friday night, and then the medley relay Saturday evening. Loading... Michael Phelps in action during the Mens 200m Butterfly Heats at the Sydney International Aquatic Centre on Day Three of the Sydney 2000 Olympic Games in Sydney, Australia. (Photo by Ross Kinnaird /Allsport) Ross Kinnaird /Allsport Michael Phelps of USA celebrates winning the gold medal in the men&apos;s swimming 400 metre individual medley final on August 14, 2004 during the Athens 2004 Summer Olympic Games. (Photo by Adam Pretty/Getty Images) Adam Pretty/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s swimming 200m individual medley final on August 19, 2004, in Athens. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s swimming 200m freestyle final on August 16, 2004, during the Athens Olympics. (Photo by Stuart Hannagan/Getty Images) Stuart Hannagan/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims to a gold medal in the 100-meter butterfly in Athens on August 20, 2004. Phelps won his fifth gold medal when he clinched victory with a Olympic Games record. (Photo by Mark J. Terril/AFP/Getty Images) Mark J. Terril/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes during the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final at the Athens Olympics on August 16, 2004. (Photo by Tim Clary/AFP/Getty Images) Tim Clary/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps celebrates on the podium during the medal ceremony of the men&apos;s swimming 200m butterfly event on August 17, 2004, during the Athens Olympics. (Photo by Stuart Hannagan/Getty Images) Stuart Hannagan/Getty Images Michael Phelps smiles as he stands on the podium during the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 100m Butterfly duringthe Beijing Olympics on August 16, 2008. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the Men&apos;s 200m Individual Medley Semifinal during the Beijing Olympics on August 14, 2008. (Photo by Clive Brunskill/Getty Images) Clive Brunskill/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims to gold in the men&apos;s 200m individual medley final during the Beijing Olympics on August 15, 2008. Phelps set a new world record. (Photo by Michael Kappeler/AFP/Getty Images) Michael Kappeler/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims to win the men&apos;s 200m individual medley final during the 2008 Beijing Olympic Games on August 15, 2008. Phelps set a new world record in the men&apos;s 200 metres individual medley. (Photo by Michael Kappeler/AFP/ Getty Images) Michael Kappeler/AFP/ Getty Images Michael Phelps poses with the gold medal during the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 200m Butterfly at the Beijing Olympics on August 13, 2008. Phelps set a new world record. (Photo by Adam Pretty/Getty Images) Photo by Adam Pretty/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly swimming final during the Beijing Olympics on August 16, 2008. Phelps set an Olympic record (Photo by Pedro Ugarte/AFP/Getty Images) Pedro Ugarte/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps waves after winning gold and setting the Olympic record in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly swimming final medal ceremony at the 2008 Beijing Olympic Games on August 16, 2008. (Photo by Pedro Ugarte/AFP/Getty Images) Pedro Ugarte/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps of the United States celebrates victory in the Men&apos;s 100m Butterfly Final at the Beijing Olympics on August 16, 2008. Phelps tied the record of winning seven gold medals in a single Olympic Games. (Photo by Adam Pretty/Getty Images) Adam Pretty/Getty Images Michael Phelps reacts during the men&apos;s 4 x 100m medley relay swimming final at the 2008 Beijing Olympics. He become the first man to win eight gold medals when the US set a new world record in the 4 x 100m. (Photo by Timothy Clary/AFP/Getty Images) Timothy Clary/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps stands on the podium for the men&apos;s 4 x 100m medley relay swimming final medal ceremony at Beijing Olympics on August 17, 2008. Phelps became the first man to win eight gold medals. (Photo by Timothy Clary/AFP/Getty Images) Timothy Clary/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims the diving pool after winning gold in the Men&apos;s 200m Individual Medley final on Day 6 of the London 2012 Olympic Games at the Aquatics Centre on August 2, 2012 in London, England. (Photo by Clive Rose/Getty Images) Clive Rose/Getty Images Michael Phelps dives into the pool in the Men&apos;s 100m Meldey Final at the London Olympics on August 4, 2012. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps after wining the men&apos;s 200m individual medley final in London on August 2, 2012. Phelps won his 20th Olympic medal and completed a historic third consecutive 200m IM Olympic win. (Photo by Christophe Simon/AFP/GettyImages) Christophe Simon/AFP/GettyImages Michael Phelps prepares to compete in the Men&apos;s 200m Individual Medley final at the London Olympics on August 2, 2012. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps posing on the podium with the gold medal after winning the men&apos;s 100m butterfly final swimming event at the London 2012 Olympic Games on August 3, 2012. (Photo by Christophe/AFP/Getty Images) Christophe/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semi-finals swimming event at the London 2012 Olympic Games on August 2, 2012. (Photo by Christophe Simon/AFP/Getty Images) Christophe Simon/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly final during the swimming event at the London 2012 Olympic Games at the Olympic Park on August 3, 2012 in London. He won gold. (Photo by Francois Xavier Marit/AFP/Getty Images) Francois Xavier Marit/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps celebrates after he won gold in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly final during the swimming event at the London 2012 Olympic Games on August 3, 2012. (Photo by Christophe Simon/AFP/Getty Images) Christophe Simon/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims the butterfly leg in the men&apos;s 4x100m medley relay final during the swimming event at the London Olympic Games on August 4, 2012. (Photo by Francois Xavier Marit/AFP/Getty Images) Francois Xavier Marit/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps kisses his medal following the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 4x100m medley Relay Final at the London Olympics on August 4, 2012. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps poses with a special award presented by FINA for his career achievements on Day 8 of the London 2012 Olympic Games at the Aquatics Centre on August 4, 2012, in London, England. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps participates in the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 100m Butterfly during the 2016 U.S. Olympic Team Swimming trials at CenturyLink Center on July 2, 2016. (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington/Getty Images Michael Phelps trains during the 2016 U.S. Olympic Swimming Team Training Camp Media Day on July 16, 2016 in San Antonio, Texas. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez/Getty Images Michael Phelps trains during the 2016 U.S. Olympic Swimming Team Training Camp Media Day on July 16, 2016 in San Antonio, Texas. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez/Getty Images Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions Loading... Hali Flickinger (USA) greets Cammille Adams (USA) after the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly final. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) greets Kyle Chalmers (AUS) after the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Adrian took third. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Kyle Chalmers (AUS) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mireia Belmonte Garcia (ESP) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Mirela Belmonte Garcia (ESP) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Josh Prenot swam to a second-place finish in the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dmitriy Balandin (KAZ) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Guangyuan Li (CHN) reacts after the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Jacob Pebley (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 200m individual medley heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200m freestyle semifinals on Monday. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) competes during the men&apos;s 200m butterfly semifinals. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates on the podium after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) with his bronze medal after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Kathleen Baker (USA) celebrates on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims in the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) and Ryan Murphy (USA) react after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) celebrates with David Plummer (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Murphy won, and Plummer placed second. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) and David Plummer (USA) pose with their medals after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) races during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) and Katie Meili (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) blows a kiss after the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) during the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel (USA) and Nathan Adrian (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m freestyle heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel of the U.S. competes in the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen of China during the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps during the 200-meter butterfly final. He won the race for his 20th career gold medal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) reacts after winning the women&apos;s 200m individual medley final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) , Katie Ledecky (USA) and Emma Mckeon (AUS) with their medals after the women&apos;s 200m freestyle final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) , Masato Sakai (JPN) and Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) with their medals after the men&apos;s 200m butterfly final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Abbey Weitzeil (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Rexford Tullius (ISV) during the men&apos;s 200m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Japan&apos;s Kosuke Hagino (JPN) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) dives in at the start of the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Daynara de Paula (BRA) reacts after winning a women&apos;s 100m butterfly heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Ziao Qiu (CHN) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) reacts after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (Hungary) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Ross Murdoch (GBR) in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Connor Jaeger (USA) and Yang Sun (CHN) after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) stretches before the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) celebrates after the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Australia team members celebrate after winning the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports USA team members Simone Manuel , Abbey Weitzeil , Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky on the podium with their medals after the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) during the women&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Corey Main (NZL) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Jimmy Feigen (USA) greets Anthony Ervin (USA) after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mitchell Larkin (AUS) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) swims during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) reacts after placing third in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) reacts after setting a world record during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) receives her bronze medal on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) and Cody Miller (USA) celebrate after the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Miller came in third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Cody Miller (USA) celebrates on the podium after placing third in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) preps for the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final, breaking her own world record in the process. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates with Leah Smith (USA) after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Leah Smith (USA) and Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Ledecky won, and Smith placed third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) leads his relay teammates to the pool before the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps preps for the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps swam the second leg for the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps helped the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team take gold. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian celebrates after anchoring the USA to victory during the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Caeleb Dressel (USA) celebrate after winning the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Nathan Adrian , Ryan Held , Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel celebrate with their gold medals after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Katie Ledecky and Leah Smith celebrate with their medals after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Camille Cheng (HKG) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen (CHN) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m individual medley heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Missy Franklin (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports of
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.thv11.com/_/20/109681432/kthv/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;thv11&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;michael-phelps-wins-gold-in-mens-200-im&amp;#x2f;295500950</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0233</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Michael Phelps wins gold in men&apos;s 200 IM Nicole Auerbach, USA TODAY Sports , KING 10:16   Michael Phelps (USA, right)) and Ryan Lochte (USA) after the men&apos;s 200m individual medley semifinals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. (Photo: Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports) CONNECT TWEET LINKEDIN GOOGLE+ PINTEREST 
RIO DE JANEIRO - Michael Phelps is getting closer and closer to finishing off these Games exactly the way he wants. 
So far: Four event finals down, four gold medals in hand. Phelps’s latest came in the 200-meter individual medley, an event Phelps has now won in four consecutive Olympics. Ryan Lochte failed to win a medal in the race, finishing fifth. 
Thursday night’s race was the final one between Lochte and Phelps, who have been squaring off in this particular event for 12 years. 
The most decorated Olympian in history, Phelps now has 22 gold medals and 26 medals overall. He is expected to swim next in the men’s 100 butterfly final Friday night, and then the medley relay Saturday evening. Loading... Michael Phelps in action during the Mens 200m Butterfly Heats at the Sydney International Aquatic Centre on Day Three of the Sydney 2000 Olympic Games in Sydney, Australia. (Photo by Ross Kinnaird /Allsport) Ross Kinnaird /Allsport Michael Phelps of USA celebrates winning the gold medal in the men&apos;s swimming 400 metre individual medley final on August 14, 2004 during the Athens 2004 Summer Olympic Games. (Photo by Adam Pretty/Getty Images) Adam Pretty/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s swimming 200m individual medley final on August 19, 2004, in Athens. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s swimming 200m freestyle final on August 16, 2004, during the Athens Olympics. (Photo by Stuart Hannagan/Getty Images) Stuart Hannagan/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims to a gold medal in the 100-meter butterfly in Athens on August 20, 2004. Phelps won his fifth gold medal when he clinched victory with a Olympic Games record. (Photo by Mark J. Terril/AFP/Getty Images) Mark J. Terril/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes during the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final at the Athens Olympics on August 16, 2004. (Photo by Tim Clary/AFP/Getty Images) Tim Clary/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps celebrates on the podium during the medal ceremony of the men&apos;s swimming 200m butterfly event on August 17, 2004, during the Athens Olympics. (Photo by Stuart Hannagan/Getty Images) Stuart Hannagan/Getty Images Michael Phelps smiles as he stands on the podium during the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 100m Butterfly duringthe Beijing Olympics on August 16, 2008. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the Men&apos;s 200m Individual Medley Semifinal during the Beijing Olympics on August 14, 2008. (Photo by Clive Brunskill/Getty Images) Clive Brunskill/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims to gold in the men&apos;s 200m individual medley final during the Beijing Olympics on August 15, 2008. Phelps set a new world record. (Photo by Michael Kappeler/AFP/Getty Images) Michael Kappeler/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims to win the men&apos;s 200m individual medley final during the 2008 Beijing Olympic Games on August 15, 2008. Phelps set a new world record in the men&apos;s 200 metres individual medley. (Photo by Michael Kappeler/AFP/ Getty Images) Michael Kappeler/AFP/ Getty Images Michael Phelps poses with the gold medal during the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 200m Butterfly at the Beijing Olympics on August 13, 2008. Phelps set a new world record. (Photo by Adam Pretty/Getty Images) Photo by Adam Pretty/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly swimming final during the Beijing Olympics on August 16, 2008. Phelps set an Olympic record (Photo by Pedro Ugarte/AFP/Getty Images) Pedro Ugarte/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps waves after winning gold and setting the Olympic record in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly swimming final medal ceremony at the 2008 Beijing Olympic Games on August 16, 2008. (Photo by Pedro Ugarte/AFP/Getty Images) Pedro Ugarte/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps of the United States celebrates victory in the Men&apos;s 100m Butterfly Final at the Beijing Olympics on August 16, 2008. Phelps tied the record of winning seven gold medals in a single Olympic Games. (Photo by Adam Pretty/Getty Images) Adam Pretty/Getty Images Michael Phelps reacts during the men&apos;s 4 x 100m medley relay swimming final at the 2008 Beijing Olympics. He become the first man to win eight gold medals when the US set a new world record in the 4 x 100m. (Photo by Timothy Clary/AFP/Getty Images) Timothy Clary/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps stands on the podium for the men&apos;s 4 x 100m medley relay swimming final medal ceremony at Beijing Olympics on August 17, 2008. Phelps became the first man to win eight gold medals. (Photo by Timothy Clary/AFP/Getty Images) Timothy Clary/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims the diving pool after winning gold in the Men&apos;s 200m Individual Medley final on Day 6 of the London 2012 Olympic Games at the Aquatics Centre on August 2, 2012 in London, England. (Photo by Clive Rose/Getty Images) Clive Rose/Getty Images Michael Phelps dives into the pool in the Men&apos;s 100m Meldey Final at the London Olympics on August 4, 2012. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps after wining the men&apos;s 200m individual medley final in London on August 2, 2012. Phelps won his 20th Olympic medal and completed a historic third consecutive 200m IM Olympic win. (Photo by Christophe Simon/AFP/GettyImages) Christophe Simon/AFP/GettyImages Michael Phelps prepares to compete in the Men&apos;s 200m Individual Medley final at the London Olympics on August 2, 2012. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps posing on the podium with the gold medal after winning the men&apos;s 100m butterfly final swimming event at the London 2012 Olympic Games on August 3, 2012. (Photo by Christophe/AFP/Getty Images) Christophe/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly semi-finals swimming event at the London 2012 Olympic Games on August 2, 2012. (Photo by Christophe Simon/AFP/Getty Images) Christophe Simon/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps competes in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly final during the swimming event at the London 2012 Olympic Games at the Olympic Park on August 3, 2012 in London. He won gold. (Photo by Francois Xavier Marit/AFP/Getty Images) Francois Xavier Marit/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps celebrates after he won gold in the men&apos;s 100m butterfly final during the swimming event at the London 2012 Olympic Games on August 3, 2012. (Photo by Christophe Simon/AFP/Getty Images) Christophe Simon/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps swims the butterfly leg in the men&apos;s 4x100m medley relay final during the swimming event at the London Olympic Games on August 4, 2012. (Photo by Francois Xavier Marit/AFP/Getty Images) Francois Xavier Marit/AFP/Getty Images Michael Phelps kisses his medal following the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 4x100m medley Relay Final at the London Olympics on August 4, 2012. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps poses with a special award presented by FINA for his career achievements on Day 8 of the London 2012 Olympic Games at the Aquatics Centre on August 4, 2012, in London, England. (Photo by Al Bello/Getty Images) Al Bello/Getty Images Michael Phelps participates in the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 100m Butterfly during the 2016 U.S. Olympic Team Swimming trials at CenturyLink Center on July 2, 2016. (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington/Getty Images Michael Phelps trains during the 2016 U.S. Olympic Swimming Team Training Camp Media Day on July 16, 2016 in San Antonio, Texas. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez/Getty Images Michael Phelps trains during the 2016 U.S. Olympic Swimming Team Training Camp Media Day on July 16, 2016 in San Antonio, Texas. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images) Ronald Martinez/Getty Images Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions Loading... Hali Flickinger (USA) greets Cammille Adams (USA) after the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly final. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian (USA) greets Kyle Chalmers (AUS) after the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle final. Adrian took third. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Kyle Chalmers (AUS) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mireia Belmonte Garcia (ESP) swims during the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Mirela Belmonte Garcia (ESP) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Josh Prenot swam to a second-place finish in the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dmitriy Balandin (KAZ) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Guangyuan Li (CHN) reacts after the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Jacob Pebley (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinals. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) during the men&apos;s 200m individual medley heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 200m freestyle semifinals on Monday. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) competes during the men&apos;s 200m butterfly semifinals. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates on the podium after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Yang Sun (CHN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) with his bronze medal after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Kathleen Baker (USA) celebrates on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) swims in the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) and Ryan Murphy (USA) react after the men&apos;s 200m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) celebrates with David Plummer (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Murphy won, and Plummer placed second. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Ryan Murphy (USA) and David Plummer (USA) pose with their medals after the men&apos;s 100m backstroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) races during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) and Katie Meili (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) celebrates winning during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) blows a kiss after the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Natalie Adams (USA) during the women&apos;s 200m butterfly heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel (USA) and Nathan Adrian (USA) after the men&apos;s 100m freestyle heats in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Caeleb Dressel of the U.S. competes in the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle semifinal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen of China during the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps during the 200-meter butterfly final. He won the race for his 20th career gold medal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) reacts after winning the women&apos;s 200m individual medley final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) , Katie Ledecky (USA) and Emma Mckeon (AUS) with their medals after the women&apos;s 200m freestyle final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) , Masato Sakai (JPN) and Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) with their medals after the men&apos;s 200m butterfly final in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Simone Manuel (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Abbey Weitzeil (USA) during the women&apos;s 100m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Rexford Tullius (ISV) during the men&apos;s 200m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Japan&apos;s Kosuke Hagino (JPN) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) dives in at the start of the men&apos;s 400m individual medley heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Daynara de Paula (BRA) reacts after winning a women&apos;s 100m butterfly heat. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Ziao Qiu (CHN) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) reacts after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (Hungary) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) swims in the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Mandatory Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Ross Murdoch (GBR) in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Conor Dwyer (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Connor Jaeger (USA) and Yang Sun (CHN) after the men&apos;s 400m freestyle heats during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) stretches before the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Chase Kalisz (USA) in the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly semifinals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Kosuke Hagino (JPN) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) in the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) celebrates after the women&apos;s 400m individual medley final during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports Australia team members celebrate after winning the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Aquatics Stadium. Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports USA team members Simone Manuel , Abbey Weitzeil , Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky on the podium with their medals after the women&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay finals Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Katinka Hosszu (HUN) during the women&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Corey Main (NZL) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Jimmy Feigen (USA) greets Anthony Ervin (USA) after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Mitchell Larkin (AUS) during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports David Plummer (USA) swims during the men&apos;s 100m backstroke heats. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Lilly King (USA) swims during the women&apos;s 100m breaststroke heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) swims during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) reacts after placing third in the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) reacts after setting a world record during the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Dana Vollmer (USA) receives her bronze medal on the podium after the women&apos;s 100m butterfly final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) and Cody Miller (USA) celebrate after the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Miller came in third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Adam Peaty (GBR) celebrates after winning the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Cody Miller (USA) celebrates on the podium after placing third in the men&apos;s 100m breaststroke final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) preps for the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final, breaking her own world record in the process. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrates with Leah Smith (USA) after winning the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Leah Smith (USA) and Katie Ledecky (USA) celebrate after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Ledecky won, and Smith placed third. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) leads his relay teammates to the pool before the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps preps for the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps swam the second leg for the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps helped the U.S. men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay team take gold. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Nathan Adrian celebrates after anchoring the USA to victory during the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) and Caeleb Dressel (USA) celebrate after winning the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Nathan Adrian , Ryan Held , Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel celebrate with their gold medals after the men&apos;s 4x100m freestyle relay final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports USA&apos;s Katie Ledecky and Leah Smith celebrate with their medals after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle final. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Camille Cheng (HKG) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Sarah Sjostrom (SWE) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Tamas Kenderesi (HUN) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Melania Costa Schmid (ESP) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Duo Shen (CHN) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Maya Dirado (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m individual medley heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Missy Franklin (USA) in the women&apos;s 200m freestyle preliminary heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Michael Phelps (USA) in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly heats. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports of
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.king5.com/photo/2016/08/11/636065421668980796-USATSI-9445489_1470968133199_5106038_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
