<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.eco-business.com/feeds/all/</forum>
<forum_title>Eco-Business</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Business Development Manager</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.eco-business.com/jobs/business-development-manager-6/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Scope: IPEx Cleantech Asia is recruiting a Business Development Manager who will work closely with senior management to support the operation of a business advisory and brokerage service, that accelerates the transfer of commercialized Clean Technologies/ IP into Asia. 
Key activities: Identify and reach-out to providers and adopters of Clean Technologies. Conduct deal origination, market the services offered and close mandates. Prepare proposals, teasers and project/investment memos. Perform market research, competitive analysis and due diligence (technical, commercial/financial and legal). Advise both providers and adopters of technologies. Support negotiations. Assist in structuring and closing transactions (e.g. project, licensing, joint venture, IP sale) Prepare periodic reports, organize team meetings, compose media articles, and update website content. Build and maintain good working relationships with the joint venture partners (world-class engineering consulting firm DNV GL, and leading clean energy investment bank ReEx Capital Asia), regional partners/representatives, as well as with the development financial institution Asian Development Bank, which has been providing partial grant funding to the operation. Work closely with the core and extended team, for executing the assigned tasks as well as supervising/coordinating others when needed, to ensure timely, cost effective and efficient completion. 
Candidates should be available and ready to start immediately. The job will be based in Singapore and will require extensive traveling within Asia, and occasionally outside. Candidates should be allowed to work in Singapore. 
Qualifications required : Business Development, sales and account management experience in the consulting service industry 7-8 years job experience Prior experience in renewable energy and cleantech sectors is required. Knowledge of low carbon technologies IP transfer is preferred. Experience as a broker and/or investment banker and/or technology incubator is a big plus Must possess strong investment/commercial judgment, solid technical knowledge, deal-maker mindset and excellent interpersonal skills Ideal candidate will preferably have a double degree in Finance and Engineering Should have an established relevant network with technology providers, cleantech startups and VCs in developed countries (including US and Europe) Should have an established relevant network with Project developers and System integrators in developing Asia (including India, China, Thailand, Indonesia, Philippines) where the clean technologies are to be deployed. Excellent understanding of Developing Asia markets (e.g. natural resources, energy prices, regulatory/legal frameworks, key industrial players) Strong quantitative, analytical, and financial modeling skills Excellent oral and written communication skills Ability to handle multiple responsibilities in a small, fast-paced multi-cultural environment Highly motivated individual. Team player. Flexibility to perform a variety of tasks and roles, as needed to support the operations of a young organization with flat hierarchy Proven experience in a flexible environment with team and partners in several locations Ability to start immediately and travel extensively 
Send CV + Cover Letter stating earliest start date. Applications without cover letter will not be considered. Only shortlisted candidates will be contacted. Why this is a green job 
This is a key role at IPEx Cleantech Asia, a technology matching, business advisory and deal facilitation firm, focused on the deployment and transfer of commercialized clean technologies into Asia. Our one-stop shop approach combines market development with the technical, commercial, financial, and legal services needed to structure and execute a bankable deal. This helps technology/IP owners worldwide efficiently monetize their product or solution in Asia. It also guides project owners and developers in finding, due diligencing and negotiating the best suited technology for their requirements.The broad areas we work in are Solar; Energy storage; Energy efficiency; Waste-to-Energy; Water technologies and Pollution control. The emphasis is on helping to diffuse such products/solutions into a variety of end-use applications/industries, in a way that reduces the overall carbon footprint in a financially, operationally and socially sustainable manner. 
IPEx was formed in 2014 and is based in Singapore. It is a consortium of ReEx Capital Asia (boutique fund raising firm focused on Cleantech in Asia) and DNV GL Clean Technologies Center (of the renowned global advisory and certification firm), with initial operational funding from Asian Development Bank (ADB). Share
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.eco-business.com/jobs/business-development-manager-6/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0518</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Scope: IPEx Cleantech Asia is recruiting a Business Development Manager who will work closely with senior management to support the operation of a business advisory and brokerage service, that accelerates the transfer of commercialized Clean Technologies/ IP into Asia. 
Key activities: Identify and reach-out to providers and adopters of Clean Technologies. Conduct deal origination, market the services offered and close mandates. Prepare proposals, teasers and project/investment memos. Perform market research, competitive analysis and due diligence (technical, commercial/financial and legal). Advise both providers and adopters of technologies. Support negotiations. Assist in structuring and closing transactions (e.g. project, licensing, joint venture, IP sale) Prepare periodic reports, organize team meetings, compose media articles, and update website content. Build and maintain good working relationships with the joint venture partners (world-class engineering consulting firm DNV GL, and leading clean energy investment bank ReEx Capital Asia), regional partners/representatives, as well as with the development financial institution Asian Development Bank, which has been providing partial grant funding to the operation. Work closely with the core and extended team, for executing the assigned tasks as well as supervising/coordinating others when needed, to ensure timely, cost effective and efficient completion. 
Candidates should be available and ready to start immediately. The job will be based in Singapore and will require extensive traveling within Asia, and occasionally outside. Candidates should be allowed to work in Singapore. 
Qualifications required : Business Development, sales and account management experience in the consulting service industry 7-8 years job experience Prior experience in renewable energy and cleantech sectors is required. Knowledge of low carbon technologies IP transfer is preferred. Experience as a broker and/or investment banker and/or technology incubator is a big plus Must possess strong investment/commercial judgment, solid technical knowledge, deal-maker mindset and excellent interpersonal skills Ideal candidate will preferably have a double degree in Finance and Engineering Should have an established relevant network with technology providers, cleantech startups and VCs in developed countries (including US and Europe) Should have an established relevant network with Project developers and System integrators in developing Asia (including India, China, Thailand, Indonesia, Philippines) where the clean technologies are to be deployed. Excellent understanding of Developing Asia markets (e.g. natural resources, energy prices, regulatory/legal frameworks, key industrial players) Strong quantitative, analytical, and financial modeling skills Excellent oral and written communication skills Ability to handle multiple responsibilities in a small, fast-paced multi-cultural environment Highly motivated individual. Team player. Flexibility to perform a variety of tasks and roles, as needed to support the operations of a young organization with flat hierarchy Proven experience in a flexible environment with team and partners in several locations Ability to start immediately and travel extensively 
Send CV + Cover Letter stating earliest start date. Applications without cover letter will not be considered. Only shortlisted candidates will be contacted. Why this is a green job 
This is a key role at IPEx Cleantech Asia, a technology matching, business advisory and deal facilitation firm, focused on the deployment and transfer of commercialized clean technologies into Asia. Our one-stop shop approach combines market development with the technical, commercial, financial, and legal services needed to structure and execute a bankable deal. This helps technology/IP owners worldwide efficiently monetize their product or solution in Asia. It also guides project owners and developers in finding, due diligencing and negotiating the best suited technology for their requirements.The broad areas we work in are Solar; Energy storage; Energy efficiency; Waste-to-Energy; Water technologies and Pollution control. The emphasis is on helping to diffuse such products/solutions into a variety of end-use applications/industries, in a way that reduces the overall carbon footprint in a financially, operationally and socially sustainable manner. 
IPEx was formed in 2014 and is based in Singapore. It is a consortium of ReEx Capital Asia (boutique fund raising firm focused on Cleantech in Asia) and DNV GL Clean Technologies Center (of the renowned global advisory and certification firm), with initial operational funding from Asian Development Bank (ADB). Share
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SG</country>
<main_image>http://www.eco-business.com/media/cache/94/35/94355b62ae021fcfae4433b7280aaf94.png</main_image>
</document>
