<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Musketeers’ Daland seals legacy in pool</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Sports/Musketeers_Daland_seals_legacy_in_pool.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Musketeers’ Daland seals legacy in pool Moorpark water polo, swim star is back on dry land, but coaching is close to her heart Jonathan Andrade @J_ Andrade_ on Twitter 
IN THE ZONE—Caeley Daland, who graduated from Moorpark High in the spring, starred for the Musketeer girls’ water polo and swim teams. BOBBY CURTIS/Acorn Newspapers One of the most prolific athletes in Moorpark High girls’ water polo history is taking a “dry period.” 
“I’ve been in the water my whole life,” said Caeley Daland, who graduated from Moorpark in the spring. “I can’t remember a time when I wasn’t playing, surfing or swimming. I feel like I want to take 10 months to not play competitively.” 
The two-time team MVP and two-time All-Coastal Canyon first team 2-meter passed on scholarship offers to smaller colleges— ones with names she can’t even remember— to chase her dream of becoming a hair stylist. Daland, who started playing splash ball and swimming competitively at age 5, is moving to Provo, Utah, on Sept. 5 to study cosmetology in a 10-month program at the Renaissance Academie. 
Daland, 19, plans to return to the pool after completing cosmetology school. 
Former Moorpark teammate Autumn McCabe, a goalie who also recently graduated, said she believes Daland won’t stay away too long. 
“I feel she’ll have a future in the water,” McCabe said. “She’ll probably also end up being a coach.” 
Coaching is in her blood. 
Daland’s father, Peter Daland Jr., an All-American water polo star at Westlake High, directs Moorpark’s swim and water polo squads. He started the Musketeers’ aquatics program in 1999. Her grandfather Peter Daland Sr. led the USC men’s swimming program to nine NCAA team championships in 35 years guiding the Trojans. Her grandfather also coached the U.S. women swimmers to six Olympic gold medals in 1964, and the U.S. men to nine gold medals in the 1972 Olympics. 
“Being a Daland, with my grandfather being who he was, it’s a big name to live up to,” Caeley Daland said. “Coaching would be so cool.” 
The young Musketeer also had to follow in the footsteps of her older brother, C.J., who played water polo at Thousand Oaks before graduating in 2013. 
C.J. Daland took a hiatus from the sport after high school, but he recently returned from a two-year mission in Romania and Moldova. He suits up for Ventura College, and he wants to play for Cal Lutheran in 2017. 
Caeley Daland started carving her own legacy after transferring from Thousand Oaks to Moorpark before her sophomore season. 
“It was a little nerve-wracking coming into a school where I didn’t know anyone,” she said. “I wanted to prove myself. I didn’t want everyone thinking I was on varsity because my dad was the coach. I had to work hard to show my stuff.” 
The star went on to lead the team in scoring for three seasons. She owns single-season school records in steals (108), goals (96) and assists (56). 
The coach said his daughter improved throughout her career. 
“From her freshman year, her confidence level went way up,” Peter Daland Jr. said. “She knew she had the ability. Then she took that leadership role and became the leader of the team and the program. 
“She was the face of the program, in a lot of ways, for Moorpark.” 
Caeley Daland, who competed in the 100-yard backstroke, 200 individual medley and 100 butterfly in swimming, spread the word about the off-campus water polo program. She recruited friends to join the team. 
“I got girls that had never played water polo to come out and play,” she said, adding that her friend Kassidy Simons, a former Moorpark star softball pitcher, provided depth to a small water polo roster in 2014. 
Moorpark narrowly missed the postseason the last two years, but Daland has helped change the team’s reputation. The Musketeers are no longer cellar dwellers. 
“She was the leader,” McCabe said of Daland. “She told everyone what to do. If they didn’t understand, she’d try to help them. She’s just an outstanding person.” 
Daland’s impact can be felt from the locker room to the pool deck— and beyond. 
“The atmosphere at the pool has changed,” Daland said. “Everyone is coming together to win and be the best they can be.” 
She expects college coaches to keep Moorpark on the radar as a hotbed for future talent. 
Daland, who works as an assistant at Serendipity Salon in Westlake, said she’ll keep an eye on younger sisters Chloe, a senior at Moorpark, Claire, 12, and Cate, 11, as they add their own chapters to the Daland family legacy. 
“(Caeley) has set the tone for the other three sisters to live up to,” Peter Daland Jr. said, “which is going to be a difficult task. It’s kind of fun.” 
Taking a break from the sport she loves will be tough, Caeley Daland said, but she’s excited for what the future has in store. She’s proud about the influence she’s had at Moorpark. 
“I definitely put a lot of my heart and soul into it,” she said. 
Email Jonathan Andrade at .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Sports/Musketeers_Daland_seals_legacy_in_pool.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
Musketeers’ Daland seals legacy in pool Moorpark water polo, swim star is back on dry land, but coaching is close to her heart Jonathan Andrade @J_ Andrade_ on Twitter 
IN THE ZONE—Caeley Daland, who graduated from Moorpark High in the spring, starred for the Musketeer girls’ water polo and swim teams. BOBBY CURTIS/Acorn Newspapers One of the most prolific athletes in Moorpark High girls’ water polo history is taking a “dry period.” 
“I’ve been in the water my whole life,” said Caeley Daland, who graduated from Moorpark in the spring. “I can’t remember a time when I wasn’t playing, surfing or swimming. I feel like I want to take 10 months to not play competitively.” 
The two-time team MVP and two-time All-Coastal Canyon first team 2-meter passed on scholarship offers to smaller colleges— ones with names she can’t even remember— to chase her dream of becoming a hair stylist. Daland, who started playing splash ball and swimming competitively at age 5, is moving to Provo, Utah, on Sept. 5 to study cosmetology in a 10-month program at the Renaissance Academie. 
Daland, 19, plans to return to the pool after completing cosmetology school. 
Former Moorpark teammate Autumn McCabe, a goalie who also recently graduated, said she believes Daland won’t stay away too long. 
“I feel she’ll have a future in the water,” McCabe said. “She’ll probably also end up being a coach.” 
Coaching is in her blood. 
Daland’s father, Peter Daland Jr., an All-American water polo star at Westlake High, directs Moorpark’s swim and water polo squads. He started the Musketeers’ aquatics program in 1999. Her grandfather Peter Daland Sr. led the USC men’s swimming program to nine NCAA team championships in 35 years guiding the Trojans. Her grandfather also coached the U.S. women swimmers to six Olympic gold medals in 1964, and the U.S. men to nine gold medals in the 1972 Olympics. 
“Being a Daland, with my grandfather being who he was, it’s a big name to live up to,” Caeley Daland said. “Coaching would be so cool.” 
The young Musketeer also had to follow in the footsteps of her older brother, C.J., who played water polo at Thousand Oaks before graduating in 2013. 
C.J. Daland took a hiatus from the sport after high school, but he recently returned from a two-year mission in Romania and Moldova. He suits up for Ventura College, and he wants to play for Cal Lutheran in 2017. 
Caeley Daland started carving her own legacy after transferring from Thousand Oaks to Moorpark before her sophomore season. 
“It was a little nerve-wracking coming into a school where I didn’t know anyone,” she said. “I wanted to prove myself. I didn’t want everyone thinking I was on varsity because my dad was the coach. I had to work hard to show my stuff.” 
The star went on to lead the team in scoring for three seasons. She owns single-season school records in steals (108), goals (96) and assists (56). 
The coach said his daughter improved throughout her career. 
“From her freshman year, her confidence level went way up,” Peter Daland Jr. said. “She knew she had the ability. Then she took that leadership role and became the leader of the team and the program. 
“She was the face of the program, in a lot of ways, for Moorpark.” 
Caeley Daland, who competed in the 100-yard backstroke, 200 individual medley and 100 butterfly in swimming, spread the word about the off-campus water polo program. She recruited friends to join the team. 
“I got girls that had never played water polo to come out and play,” she said, adding that her friend Kassidy Simons, a former Moorpark star softball pitcher, provided depth to a small water polo roster in 2014. 
Moorpark narrowly missed the postseason the last two years, but Daland has helped change the team’s reputation. The Musketeers are no longer cellar dwellers. 
“She was the leader,” McCabe said of Daland. “She told everyone what to do. If they didn’t understand, she’d try to help them. She’s just an outstanding person.” 
Daland’s impact can be felt from the locker room to the pool deck— and beyond. 
“The atmosphere at the pool has changed,” Daland said. “Everyone is coming together to win and be the best they can be.” 
She expects college coaches to keep Moorpark on the radar as a hotbed for future talent. 
Daland, who works as an assistant at Serendipity Salon in Westlake, said she’ll keep an eye on younger sisters Chloe, a senior at Moorpark, Claire, 12, and Cate, 11, as they add their own chapters to the Daland family legacy. 
“(Caeley) has set the tone for the other three sisters to live up to,” Peter Daland Jr. said, “which is going to be a difficult task. It’s kind of fun.” 
Taking a break from the sport she loves will be tough, Caeley Daland said, but she’s excited for what the future has in store. She’s proud about the influence she’s had at Moorpark. 
“I definitely put a lot of my heart and soul into it,” she said. 
Email Jonathan Andrade at .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/36p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
