<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Around the Piste: Junghwan Kim wins bronze for South Korea | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/around-the-piste-junghwan-kim-wins-bronze-for-south-korea/</topic_url>
<topic_text>

Check back for lives updates throughout the day. You can stream all the action on NBCOlympics.com. 
Bronze medal match 
Kim scored six consecutive points to open his bronze bout with Abedini and never looked back as he went on to defeat Abedini 15-8 to earn South Korea its second medal of the Rio Games. Sangyoung Park won gold in the men’s epee the day prior. This is South Korea’s first medal in the individual sabre. 
Semifinals 
Aron Szilagyi and Junghwan Kim were the first to toe the piste to determine who would get the chance to fence for gold. Szilagyi began with five consecutive points before Kim managed a score. 
Down 11-13, Kim launched a ferocious attack the netted him a point to move within a point but Szilagyi scored two consecutive touches to earn his place in the gold medal match. 
Homer and Abedini took the piste in the second match. Abedini went up 6-3 but Homer, as we had seen in some of his earlier matches, employed some of his most aggressive attacked to get right back into the match. 
Homer went up 12-9 but Abedini tied the match. Homer scored another point but again Abedini came back to tie it. Knotted at 13, Homer scored his 14th point, need just one more for victory, but again Abedini responded to knot it at 14. But Homer wouldn’t be denied and he scored the last point to advance to the gold medal match. 
Quarterfinals 
Homer faced off against Szabo and scored 6 of the matches first 7 points. Homer took the bout 15-12. 
Szilagyi and Kim also won their respective bouts 15-10. 
French fencer Vincent Anstett took on Iranian fencer Mojtaba Abedini. Abedini won 15-13. 
Round of 16 
Homer went to the piste against Germany’s Max Hartung. Hartung had the early advantage but Homer came back to tie the bout and take a 7-6 lead midway through the first period. 
The fencers continued to trade points and leads several more times. Homer broke a 12-12 tie with a flying attack and followed that up with two more touches to win. 
Second ranked fencer Junghwan Kim of South Korea faced Georgian fencer Sandro Bazadze. Bazadze was seen arguing with officials throughout the match over what appeared to be issues related to equipment. 
With Bazadze down 13-14, Kim thought he had scored the bout winning point. Instead the point was given to Bazadze whom the referee determined to have the right of way. Kim scored the final touch to advance to the quarterfinals. 
Fresh off his upset of Yakimenko, Paskov toed the piste against Matyas Szabo of Germany. His performance proved to be a stark contrast to his earlier finish as Szabo took a commanding 12-4 lead midway through the second period. 
Paskov scored consecutive touches to pull closer but it was too little, too late as Szabo handily won 15-6. 
Szilagyi returned to face Aliaksandr Buikevich of Belarus. The men traded leads late in the bout before Szilagyi built a four point lead, eventually winning 15-12. 
Round of 32 
United States fencer Daryl Homer faced Ilya Mokretcov of Kazakhstan in his first bout of the day. Homer looked to be in control for most of the bout as he went on to win 15-11. 
Teammate Eli Dershwitz trailed 4-8 at the start of the second period against Seppe van Holsbeke of Belgium. Homer had described Dershwitz as a “fighter” and his words proved true. 
Dershwitz had a spirited comeback and got within reach of the veteran but van Holsbeke scored the final touch to beat the American 15-12. 
Gold medal favorite Alexey Yakimenko of Russia took on 302nd ranked fencer Pancho Paskov of Bulgaria. The 22-year-old Paskov gave Yakimenko trouble late in the match, tying at 13 and going up a point on consecutive touches. The 2015 World Championships sabre winner came back to tie however it was Paskov that would come out on top in a tight 15-14 battle. 
Hungary’s Aron Szilagyi, another favorite to earn a medal, drew Mexico’s Julian Ayala. Szilagyi won 15-9. 

</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/around-the-piste-junghwan-kim-wins-bronze-for-south-korea/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Nbc Olympics.Com</username>
<post>

Check back for lives updates throughout the day. You can stream all the action on NBCOlympics.com. 
Bronze medal match 
Kim scored six consecutive points to open his bronze bout with Abedini and never looked back as he went on to defeat Abedini 15-8 to earn South Korea its second medal of the Rio Games. Sangyoung Park won gold in the men’s epee the day prior. This is South Korea’s first medal in the individual sabre. 
Semifinals 
Aron Szilagyi and Junghwan Kim were the first to toe the piste to determine who would get the chance to fence for gold. Szilagyi began with five consecutive points before Kim managed a score. 
Down 11-13, Kim launched a ferocious attack the netted him a point to move within a point but Szilagyi scored two consecutive touches to earn his place in the gold medal match. 
Homer and Abedini took the piste in the second match. Abedini went up 6-3 but Homer, as we had seen in some of his earlier matches, employed some of his most aggressive attacked to get right back into the match. 
Homer went up 12-9 but Abedini tied the match. Homer scored another point but again Abedini came back to tie it. Knotted at 13, Homer scored his 14th point, need just one more for victory, but again Abedini responded to knot it at 14. But Homer wouldn’t be denied and he scored the last point to advance to the gold medal match. 
Quarterfinals 
Homer faced off against Szabo and scored 6 of the matches first 7 points. Homer took the bout 15-12. 
Szilagyi and Kim also won their respective bouts 15-10. 
French fencer Vincent Anstett took on Iranian fencer Mojtaba Abedini. Abedini won 15-13. 
Round of 16 
Homer went to the piste against Germany’s Max Hartung. Hartung had the early advantage but Homer came back to tie the bout and take a 7-6 lead midway through the first period. 
The fencers continued to trade points and leads several more times. Homer broke a 12-12 tie with a flying attack and followed that up with two more touches to win. 
Second ranked fencer Junghwan Kim of South Korea faced Georgian fencer Sandro Bazadze. Bazadze was seen arguing with officials throughout the match over what appeared to be issues related to equipment. 
With Bazadze down 13-14, Kim thought he had scored the bout winning point. Instead the point was given to Bazadze whom the referee determined to have the right of way. Kim scored the final touch to advance to the quarterfinals. 
Fresh off his upset of Yakimenko, Paskov toed the piste against Matyas Szabo of Germany. His performance proved to be a stark contrast to his earlier finish as Szabo took a commanding 12-4 lead midway through the second period. 
Paskov scored consecutive touches to pull closer but it was too little, too late as Szabo handily won 15-6. 
Szilagyi returned to face Aliaksandr Buikevich of Belarus. The men traded leads late in the bout before Szilagyi built a four point lead, eventually winning 15-12. 
Round of 32 
United States fencer Daryl Homer faced Ilya Mokretcov of Kazakhstan in his first bout of the day. Homer looked to be in control for most of the bout as he went on to win 15-11. 
Teammate Eli Dershwitz trailed 4-8 at the start of the second period against Seppe van Holsbeke of Belgium. Homer had described Dershwitz as a “fighter” and his words proved true. 
Dershwitz had a spirited comeback and got within reach of the veteran but van Holsbeke scored the final touch to beat the American 15-12. 
Gold medal favorite Alexey Yakimenko of Russia took on 302nd ranked fencer Pancho Paskov of Bulgaria. The 22-year-old Paskov gave Yakimenko trouble late in the match, tying at 13 and going up a point on consecutive touches. The 2015 World Championships sabre winner came back to tie however it was Paskov that would come out on top in a tight 15-14 battle. 
Hungary’s Aron Szilagyi, another favorite to earn a medal, drew Mexico’s Julian Ayala. Szilagyi won 15-9. 

</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/usatsi_9443646cropped.jpg</main_image>
</document>
