<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>A Heat Advisory in effect for this afternoon - WFSB 3 Connecticut</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wfsb.com/story/32732324/a-heat-advisory-in-effect-for-this-afternoon</topic_url>
<topic_text>
A Heat Advisory in effect for this afternoon Posted: HARTFORD, CT (WFSB) - 1PM UPDATE... The current heat index value in Hartford is 103! That&apos;s the &quot;feels like&quot; temperature you combine the heat and humidity. Meriden is in second place with a heat index value of 100! Along with the oppressive heat, we also have the threat of more storms today. A nasty cell moved across SE CT this morning dropping a quick .25+&quot; of rain, and over a hundred strikes of lightning. We&apos;ll be keeping a close eye on Doppler Radar this afternoon as more storms will likely fire up in this soupy air mass. The greatest threat from any storm that develops will be copious amounts of rain. Not much relief in sight over the next several days- in fact each day through Sunday will feature temperatures in the 90&apos;s with very high humidity, and the threat of showers and storms. A TORNADO IN CONNECTICUT YESTERDAY… A short lived tornado touched down in the Montowese section of North Haven around or just before 1:30 yesterday afternoon. Channel 3 received video confirmation of the tornado and there were strong indications of severe thunderstorm winds on Doppler radar. We also received photographs of trees uprooted and snapped. Power lines were downed and several homes were damaged. The National Weather Service out of Upton, New York has also confirmed a tornado touched down in North Haven. It was an EF-0 tornado with 70 mph winds. The path width was 50 yards and it was on the ground for 2.16 miles. At least the severe weather was isolated. The rest of the state received a beneficial rainfall. We received reports of 2.16” in the Woodmont section of Milford. Other rainfall totals include: Old Lyme 1.79”, Higganum 1.27”, New London 1.14”, Union 0.92”, Staffordville 0.68”, Hampton 0.40”, and Wethersfield 0.34”. INTENSE HEAT BEGINS TODAY… The National Weather Service has issued a Heat Advisory for Hartford, Tolland, and Windham Counties from Noon today until 7:00pm. Temperatures will soar into the 90s this afternoon, but the heat index will reach 100-105 degrees due to the high humidity. This is what it will feel like to you and your pets! Scattered showers and thunderstorms will develop this afternoon and some of these storms will produce torrential downpours and perhaps gusty winds. Showers and storms will gradually dissipate tonight and it will be another very uncomfortable night with low temperatures in the 70s. THE HEAT CONTINUES… Tomorrow and Saturday will be a lot like today, dangerously hot. Temperatures should reach the middle to perhaps upper 90s and the heat index will reach triple digits. Showers and thunderstorms will threaten will torrential downpours and gusty winds each afternoon and evening. A cold front will slide southward across Southern New England on Sunday. Still, temperatures could reach the 90s before the front arrives. The humidity will remain high. The front will trigger another round of showers and storms, some of which could pack a pretty good punch. It looks like the front will move off to the south and east of Connecticut Sunday night and Monday. Therefore, we should get into a drier air mass, but it will remain hot. Temperatures are expected to top 90 degrees Monday afternoon and we may have a shot at 90 degrees on Tuesday as well. The arrival of showers and thunderstorms on Wednesday should keep temperatures in the 80s. We have now had 23 days this year with a high temperature of at least 90 degrees at Bradley International Airport. By the time this next heat wave ends, the tally could grow to 28 days, perhaps 29 days. The record for a year is 38 days set in 1983. AUGUST NORMALS AND EXTREMES… While August can be a very hot month, temperatures do trend downward. The normal (or average) high on August 1 st is 85 degrees, but by the 31 st it dips to 80 degrees. Low temperatures follow and similar path. The normal low on the 1 st is 63 degrees then it drops to 58 degrees by the 31 st . We also lose 1 hour and 15 minutes of daylight over the course of August’s 31 days. The hottest temperature on record this month is 102 degrees, set on August 9 th in 2002. The record low is 36 degrees, set on August 31 st in 1965. Average rainfall in August is 3.93”, but 21.87” of rain fell in August of 1955 thanks to a one two punch from Tropical Storm Connie and Tropical Storm Diane! August 1955 was by far the all-time wettest month on record. JULY 2016 IN REVIEW… The average temperature this July at Bradley International Airport was 76.4 degrees, which is 2.8 degrees warmer than normal. However, July was not the hottest on record. The hottest July was in 2013 when the average temperature was 77.9 degrees. July 1994 and July 2010 are in 2 nd place with an average temperature was 77.1 degrees. July 1995 is in 3rd place with an average temperature of 77.0 degrees, and 4 th place goes to July 1949 with an average temperature was 76.8. July 2006 is in 5 th place with an average temperature of 76.5. This July almost made it into the top 5. We missed a tie for 5 th place by just 0.1 degrees. However, a record was set for the most days in July with high temperatures in the 90s. The grand total was 17 days! The previous record was 16 days in July 1955 and July 1966. Plus, we had a record tying 10 day heat wave that equaled the heat wave we had in summer of 1995. That heat wave started on July 24 th and it ended on August 2 nd . Rainfall in July was quite variable. Some towns and cities received a lot of rain, while others did not. At Bradley International Airport, total rainfall for the month was 2.20”, which is 1.98” below normal. However, Bridgeport received 4.80” of rain, which is 1.34” above normal. Chief Meteorologist Bruce DePrest “Copyright 2016 WFSB (Meredith Corporation). All rights reserved” Technical Discussion A Heat Advisory in effect for this afternoon More&gt;&gt; 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wfsb.com/story/32732324/a-heat-advisory-in-effect-for-this-afternoon</post_url>
<post_date>20160810</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Scot Haney</username>
<post>
A Heat Advisory in effect for this afternoon Posted: HARTFORD, CT (WFSB) - 1PM UPDATE... The current heat index value in Hartford is 103! That&apos;s the &quot;feels like&quot; temperature you combine the heat and humidity. Meriden is in second place with a heat index value of 100! Along with the oppressive heat, we also have the threat of more storms today. A nasty cell moved across SE CT this morning dropping a quick .25+&quot; of rain, and over a hundred strikes of lightning. We&apos;ll be keeping a close eye on Doppler Radar this afternoon as more storms will likely fire up in this soupy air mass. The greatest threat from any storm that develops will be copious amounts of rain. Not much relief in sight over the next several days- in fact each day through Sunday will feature temperatures in the 90&apos;s with very high humidity, and the threat of showers and storms. A TORNADO IN CONNECTICUT YESTERDAY… A short lived tornado touched down in the Montowese section of North Haven around or just before 1:30 yesterday afternoon. Channel 3 received video confirmation of the tornado and there were strong indications of severe thunderstorm winds on Doppler radar. We also received photographs of trees uprooted and snapped. Power lines were downed and several homes were damaged. The National Weather Service out of Upton, New York has also confirmed a tornado touched down in North Haven. It was an EF-0 tornado with 70 mph winds. The path width was 50 yards and it was on the ground for 2.16 miles. At least the severe weather was isolated. The rest of the state received a beneficial rainfall. We received reports of 2.16” in the Woodmont section of Milford. Other rainfall totals include: Old Lyme 1.79”, Higganum 1.27”, New London 1.14”, Union 0.92”, Staffordville 0.68”, Hampton 0.40”, and Wethersfield 0.34”. INTENSE HEAT BEGINS TODAY… The National Weather Service has issued a Heat Advisory for Hartford, Tolland, and Windham Counties from Noon today until 7:00pm. Temperatures will soar into the 90s this afternoon, but the heat index will reach 100-105 degrees due to the high humidity. This is what it will feel like to you and your pets! Scattered showers and thunderstorms will develop this afternoon and some of these storms will produce torrential downpours and perhaps gusty winds. Showers and storms will gradually dissipate tonight and it will be another very uncomfortable night with low temperatures in the 70s. THE HEAT CONTINUES… Tomorrow and Saturday will be a lot like today, dangerously hot. Temperatures should reach the middle to perhaps upper 90s and the heat index will reach triple digits. Showers and thunderstorms will threaten will torrential downpours and gusty winds each afternoon and evening. A cold front will slide southward across Southern New England on Sunday. Still, temperatures could reach the 90s before the front arrives. The humidity will remain high. The front will trigger another round of showers and storms, some of which could pack a pretty good punch. It looks like the front will move off to the south and east of Connecticut Sunday night and Monday. Therefore, we should get into a drier air mass, but it will remain hot. Temperatures are expected to top 90 degrees Monday afternoon and we may have a shot at 90 degrees on Tuesday as well. The arrival of showers and thunderstorms on Wednesday should keep temperatures in the 80s. We have now had 23 days this year with a high temperature of at least 90 degrees at Bradley International Airport. By the time this next heat wave ends, the tally could grow to 28 days, perhaps 29 days. The record for a year is 38 days set in 1983. AUGUST NORMALS AND EXTREMES… While August can be a very hot month, temperatures do trend downward. The normal (or average) high on August 1 st is 85 degrees, but by the 31 st it dips to 80 degrees. Low temperatures follow and similar path. The normal low on the 1 st is 63 degrees then it drops to 58 degrees by the 31 st . We also lose 1 hour and 15 minutes of daylight over the course of August’s 31 days. The hottest temperature on record this month is 102 degrees, set on August 9 th in 2002. The record low is 36 degrees, set on August 31 st in 1965. Average rainfall in August is 3.93”, but 21.87” of rain fell in August of 1955 thanks to a one two punch from Tropical Storm Connie and Tropical Storm Diane! August 1955 was by far the all-time wettest month on record. JULY 2016 IN REVIEW… The average temperature this July at Bradley International Airport was 76.4 degrees, which is 2.8 degrees warmer than normal. However, July was not the hottest on record. The hottest July was in 2013 when the average temperature was 77.9 degrees. July 1994 and July 2010 are in 2 nd place with an average temperature was 77.1 degrees. July 1995 is in 3rd place with an average temperature of 77.0 degrees, and 4 th place goes to July 1949 with an average temperature was 76.8. July 2006 is in 5 th place with an average temperature of 76.5. This July almost made it into the top 5. We missed a tie for 5 th place by just 0.1 degrees. However, a record was set for the most days in July with high temperatures in the 90s. The grand total was 17 days! The previous record was 16 days in July 1955 and July 1966. Plus, we had a record tying 10 day heat wave that equaled the heat wave we had in summer of 1995. That heat wave started on July 24 th and it ended on August 2 nd . Rainfall in July was quite variable. Some towns and cities received a lot of rain, while others did not. At Bradley International Airport, total rainfall for the month was 2.20”, which is 1.98” below normal. However, Bridgeport received 4.80” of rain, which is 1.34” above normal. Chief Meteorologist Bruce DePrest “Copyright 2016 WFSB (Meredith Corporation). All rights reserved” Technical Discussion A Heat Advisory in effect for this afternoon More&gt;&gt; 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://wfsb.images.worldnow.com/images/10940159_G.jpg</main_image>
</document>
