<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Philippines&apos; Ascendant Technologies bags the first Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://kabayantech.com/2016/08/philippines-ascendant-technologies-bags-first-takeda-digital-healthcare-innovation-challenge/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Philippines’ Ascendant Technologies bags the first Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge Posted Thursday, Aug 11, 2016 
TechTalks and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Ltd. recently concluded the first Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge weekend and Ascendant Technologies is the company who took home the grand prize of US$10,000, for their web app EMR Doc Assistant. 
A total of 21 startups from around the world applied for the first Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge, when it was first announced last May 2016. The 21 startups where later narrowed down to 10 finalist for the Pitching Event which was held at the AIM Conference Center in Makati City, last August 6, 2016. 
Aside from Ascendant’s EMR Doc Assistant, here are the other 9 finalist went on to the Pitching Event of Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge; Blood Hero (PH) – A web and mobile application that will make blood donation social through gamification and easy accessibility. It will foster collaboration amongst hospitals, organizations and blood donors in order to meet the needs for blood supply. CarinMED (Malaysia) – A mobile application that enables doctors to take history quicker, more intuitively and with better flexibility by using machine learning to help with their diagnosis, especially in the area of oncology. docHERs (USA) – A patient-centered, nurse-assisted digital health platform that enables physicians to navigate, diagnose &amp; treat patients from remote locations. This is especially useful for chronic disease management (cancer, diabetes, CVD/stroke and neurological disease, etc). Handy Pharmacy Onco (Thailand) – An online-based individual health consulting application for patients to connect directly to Pharmacists. HealthInsight for Oncology (PH) – A digital platform for the oncology ecosystem to empower patients and care providers along the cancer patient journey, from dealing with actual patients already receiving care to providing primary care. Hybrid Fusion FISH™ (USA) – A web application using simple and cost-efficient “colored dots” to detect cancer genes for early cancer detection and diagnosis, disease stratification, and companion diagnostics for targeted therapies and precision medicine. KnowCo (PH) – A mobile application for information collation, dissemination, and clarification on what to expect in a life with Cancer. MyLabs (PH) – An Electronic Medical Records and Laboratory Result Management System that leverages on predictive and prescriptive analytics. Renal Tracker (PH) – A web-based program with remote patient monitoring, daily nutrition tracking, constant cancer care program, and dietitian-created cancer recipes. 
Ascendant Technologies is not actually a startup, since the company have been providing IT solutions to medium sized company who are in the medical industry for more than 13 years. Aside from taking from the cash prize Ascendant Technologies will also have a chance to work with the Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Ltd., one of Japan’s leading Pharmaceutical company. 
Ascendant’s EMR Doc Assistant is a cloud based Electronic Medical Record Solution which can catch red flags in a basic patient examination and forward them to the doctor specialists for further examination. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://kabayantech.com/2016/08/philippines-ascendant-technologies-bags-first-takeda-digital-healthcare-innovation-challenge/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Philippines’ Ascendant Technologies bags the first Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge Posted Thursday, Aug 11, 2016 
TechTalks and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Ltd. recently concluded the first Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge weekend and Ascendant Technologies is the company who took home the grand prize of US$10,000, for their web app EMR Doc Assistant. 
A total of 21 startups from around the world applied for the first Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge, when it was first announced last May 2016. The 21 startups where later narrowed down to 10 finalist for the Pitching Event which was held at the AIM Conference Center in Makati City, last August 6, 2016. 
Aside from Ascendant’s EMR Doc Assistant, here are the other 9 finalist went on to the Pitching Event of Takeda Digital Healthcare Innovation Challenge; Blood Hero (PH) – A web and mobile application that will make blood donation social through gamification and easy accessibility. It will foster collaboration amongst hospitals, organizations and blood donors in order to meet the needs for blood supply. CarinMED (Malaysia) – A mobile application that enables doctors to take history quicker, more intuitively and with better flexibility by using machine learning to help with their diagnosis, especially in the area of oncology. docHERs (USA) – A patient-centered, nurse-assisted digital health platform that enables physicians to navigate, diagnose &amp; treat patients from remote locations. This is especially useful for chronic disease management (cancer, diabetes, CVD/stroke and neurological disease, etc). Handy Pharmacy Onco (Thailand) – An online-based individual health consulting application for patients to connect directly to Pharmacists. HealthInsight for Oncology (PH) – A digital platform for the oncology ecosystem to empower patients and care providers along the cancer patient journey, from dealing with actual patients already receiving care to providing primary care. Hybrid Fusion FISH™ (USA) – A web application using simple and cost-efficient “colored dots” to detect cancer genes for early cancer detection and diagnosis, disease stratification, and companion diagnostics for targeted therapies and precision medicine. KnowCo (PH) – A mobile application for information collation, dissemination, and clarification on what to expect in a life with Cancer. MyLabs (PH) – An Electronic Medical Records and Laboratory Result Management System that leverages on predictive and prescriptive analytics. Renal Tracker (PH) – A web-based program with remote patient monitoring, daily nutrition tracking, constant cancer care program, and dietitian-created cancer recipes. 
Ascendant Technologies is not actually a startup, since the company have been providing IT solutions to medium sized company who are in the medical industry for more than 13 years. Aside from taking from the cash prize Ascendant Technologies will also have a chance to work with the Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Ltd., one of Japan’s leading Pharmaceutical company. 
Ascendant’s EMR Doc Assistant is a cloud based Electronic Medical Record Solution which can catch red flags in a basic patient examination and forward them to the doctor specialists for further examination. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SG</country>
<main_image>http://kabayantech.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Ascendant-Technologies-500x281.jpg</main_image>
</document>
