<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.scnow.com/search/?q=&amp;t=article&amp;l=100&amp;d=&amp;d1=&amp;d2=&amp;s=start_time&amp;sd=desc&amp;nsa=eedition&amp;c[]=living,living/*&amp;f=rss</forum>
<forum_title>www.scnow.com - RSS Results in living,living/* of type article</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Shady Rest customers enjoy home cooking, good customer care</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.scnow.com/townnews/commerce/article_aa5ed20a-5fc8-11e6-8668-77ba809f76ad.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
The Shady Rest has been opened in Johnsonville for nearly 22 years. Shady Rest customers enjoy home cooking, good customer care Buy Now By Dianne Poston Owens 
Among Buddy Dennis’ specialties at the Shady Rest in Johnsonville is his baking and serving of his signature 10-layer caramel cake. Dianne Poston Owens 
The Shady Rest has been opened in Johnsonville for nearly 22 years. 
JOHNSONVILLE, S.C. – Once upon a time Buddy Dennis came to Johnsonville on a Monday to pick up a package from the local post office. 
As the post office was closed for lunch, Dennis, an area contractor at the time, decided to find a quick meal. He couldn’t find one he liked. As Dennis tells the story, he found food, a burger, but it was not to his liking. 
In fact, if there had been a restaurant in town offering him the kind of food he wanted, likely he would not have gone on to open the Shady Rest. 
That was 1994, 22 years ago. Now, the Shady Rest, where Dennis offers his own take on down-home recipes and bakes up the desserts himself, serves meals breakfast, lunch and dinner nearly all day long, nearly every day. 
“I thought it was a shame I couldn’t get a decent meal at 1 p.m. on a Monday. That got my brain to working,” Dennis said. 
Recently named the Johnsonville Business of the Month by the Johnsonville Area Chamber of Commerce and City officials, Shady Rest Family Restaurant and Games has changed little since it opened. Dennis’ daughters Shannon and Bridget have worked alongside him in the business as well. 
Dennis found the lots on which he built a group of buildings, and though some may have thought him crazy, his hard work and diligence paid off. Of course, in the early weeks after opening, Dennis had help from his sister JoAnn Elliott. She runs the Ball &amp; Que restaurant in Georgetown. 
“We took a chance. We got things going,” he said. “One of her cooks came and with her help, and my families’ help, we got to going.” 
Dennis said he has no regrets – whatsoever. He enjoys visiting with the customers, most of whom are regulars and many of whom travel 40-50 miles or minutes to eat with him and visit with the 20-30 member staff. 
“We’ve been blessed,” he said. “The community has supported us. It’s been rewarding. I get to meet lots of people I might not otherwise.” 
Dennis said he is about ready to let Shannon and the grands “Grab it and go.” But for now, you can find him most mornings opening the restaurant and chatting with customers. 
The Shady Rest is open 6 a.m.-9 p.m. or later (as long as there are customers) every day except Wednesdays. Each Wednesday the business closes at 3 p.m. The business also closed this past summer for a week around the 4th of July. 
“There must have been pent-up need to eat fried chicken,” Dennis said laughing. “The Sunday we opened back up after being closed was our biggest day we’ve ever had. They must have been glad to see us open.” 
During that time, Dennis said, though the business was closed, the parking lot was resurfaced and he got several days of maintenance and other work done, which he wouldn’t have been able to do, if the business had been open. 
“I love my customers and the community. I love knowing that when someone gets up and comes to Johnsonville, they have a place where they can eat,” Dennis said. 
Dianne Poston Owens is editor of the Lake City News &amp; Post and the Weekly Observer, which serve Lake City, Johnsonville and Hemingway and their surrounding communities in South Carolina. Tags
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.scnow.com/townnews/commerce/article_aa5ed20a-5fc8-11e6-8668-77ba809f76ad.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>1336</post_time>
<username>Dianne Owens</username>
<post>
The Shady Rest has been opened in Johnsonville for nearly 22 years. Shady Rest customers enjoy home cooking, good customer care Buy Now By Dianne Poston Owens 
Among Buddy Dennis’ specialties at the Shady Rest in Johnsonville is his baking and serving of his signature 10-layer caramel cake. Dianne Poston Owens 
The Shady Rest has been opened in Johnsonville for nearly 22 years. 
JOHNSONVILLE, S.C. – Once upon a time Buddy Dennis came to Johnsonville on a Monday to pick up a package from the local post office. 
As the post office was closed for lunch, Dennis, an area contractor at the time, decided to find a quick meal. He couldn’t find one he liked. As Dennis tells the story, he found food, a burger, but it was not to his liking. 
In fact, if there had been a restaurant in town offering him the kind of food he wanted, likely he would not have gone on to open the Shady Rest. 
That was 1994, 22 years ago. Now, the Shady Rest, where Dennis offers his own take on down-home recipes and bakes up the desserts himself, serves meals breakfast, lunch and dinner nearly all day long, nearly every day. 
“I thought it was a shame I couldn’t get a decent meal at 1 p.m. on a Monday. That got my brain to working,” Dennis said. 
Recently named the Johnsonville Business of the Month by the Johnsonville Area Chamber of Commerce and City officials, Shady Rest Family Restaurant and Games has changed little since it opened. Dennis’ daughters Shannon and Bridget have worked alongside him in the business as well. 
Dennis found the lots on which he built a group of buildings, and though some may have thought him crazy, his hard work and diligence paid off. Of course, in the early weeks after opening, Dennis had help from his sister JoAnn Elliott. She runs the Ball &amp; Que restaurant in Georgetown. 
“We took a chance. We got things going,” he said. “One of her cooks came and with her help, and my families’ help, we got to going.” 
Dennis said he has no regrets – whatsoever. He enjoys visiting with the customers, most of whom are regulars and many of whom travel 40-50 miles or minutes to eat with him and visit with the 20-30 member staff. 
“We’ve been blessed,” he said. “The community has supported us. It’s been rewarding. I get to meet lots of people I might not otherwise.” 
Dennis said he is about ready to let Shannon and the grands “Grab it and go.” But for now, you can find him most mornings opening the restaurant and chatting with customers. 
The Shady Rest is open 6 a.m.-9 p.m. or later (as long as there are customers) every day except Wednesdays. Each Wednesday the business closes at 3 p.m. The business also closed this past summer for a week around the 4th of July. 
“There must have been pent-up need to eat fried chicken,” Dennis said laughing. “The Sunday we opened back up after being closed was our biggest day we’ve ever had. They must have been glad to see us open.” 
During that time, Dennis said, though the business was closed, the parking lot was resurfaced and he got several days of maintenance and other work done, which he wouldn’t have been able to do, if the business had been open. 
“I love my customers and the community. I love knowing that when someone gets up and comes to Johnsonville, they have a place where they can eat,” Dennis said. 
Dianne Poston Owens is editor of the Lake City News &amp; Post and the Weekly Observer, which serve Lake City, Johnsonville and Hemingway and their surrounding communities in South Carolina. Tags
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/scnow.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/f/87/f87d5816-5fc9-11e6-ad75-ebd81e515c5d/57acb0dc5f303.preview.jpg?resize=750%2C560</main_image>
</document>
