<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Trump Tower climber inspires internet jokes and memes | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/trump-tower-climber-follies/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Trump Tower climber inspires internet jokes and memes Jeanne Moos Published: August 11, 2016, 9:30 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
(CNN) – The 19-year old who scaled Trump tower Wednesday is now charged with reckless endangerment and criminal trespass. His climb also inspired a lot of internet jokes. 
Your dog would bark too if a guy with suction cups showed up outside your trump tower window. The climber’s slow ascent made even the slightest move riveting, when he took off his backpack, when he put on a hat and when he had a drink. There were moments of true drama when emergency services knocked out glass to get to him. 
When they finally dragged him in. it was one of those summer stories made for internet jokesters. “Live footage from Trump tower” tweeted a Batman and Robin fan. “Watches the Olympics once” and it inspires this. The climber was inserted behind the Donald in his famous taco bowl photo. Before everyone learned that he was Steve from Virginia, there were guesses. Was it Chris Christie suctioning up to the Donald. Or Ted Cruz looking for delegates. 
The daily news bellowed “hey Donald will your wall stop suction cups?” 
The climber was accused of copying Toy Story. Some saw a resemblance between the climbers and “supernatural” star Jared Padalecki. 
The actor resorted to Facebook, “To clear things up, this is not me trying to scale the trump tower in NYC…so please stop asking.” Police grab man climbing Trump Tower in New York City 
The number one meme, the visual joke that really left a mark was this. The climber suctioning the back of Olympic swimmer Michael Phelps. Here you thought the circles were from cupping therapy. At least the climber got closer to the top of Phelps than he did to the top of Trump tower. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/trump-tower-climber-follies/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Jeanne Moos</username>
<post>
Trump Tower climber inspires internet jokes and memes Jeanne Moos Published: August 11, 2016, 9:30 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
(CNN) – The 19-year old who scaled Trump tower Wednesday is now charged with reckless endangerment and criminal trespass. His climb also inspired a lot of internet jokes. 
Your dog would bark too if a guy with suction cups showed up outside your trump tower window. The climber’s slow ascent made even the slightest move riveting, when he took off his backpack, when he put on a hat and when he had a drink. There were moments of true drama when emergency services knocked out glass to get to him. 
When they finally dragged him in. it was one of those summer stories made for internet jokesters. “Live footage from Trump tower” tweeted a Batman and Robin fan. “Watches the Olympics once” and it inspires this. The climber was inserted behind the Donald in his famous taco bowl photo. Before everyone learned that he was Steve from Virginia, there were guesses. Was it Chris Christie suctioning up to the Donald. Or Ted Cruz looking for delegates. 
The daily news bellowed “hey Donald will your wall stop suction cups?” 
The climber was accused of copying Toy Story. Some saw a resemblance between the climbers and “supernatural” star Jared Padalecki. 
The actor resorted to Facebook, “To clear things up, this is not me trying to scale the trump tower in NYC…so please stop asking.” Police grab man climbing Trump Tower in New York City 
The number one meme, the visual joke that really left a mark was this. The climber suctioning the back of Olympic swimmer Michael Phelps. Here you thought the circles were from cupping therapy. At least the climber got closer to the top of Phelps than he did to the top of Trump tower. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/trump-tower-climber-1.jpg?w=1200</main_image>
</document>
