<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Special:NewPages&amp;feed=atom</forum>
<forum_title>Wikipedia - New pages [en]</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Nature of Assessment of Learning</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nature_of_Assessment_of_Learning</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nature of Assessment of Learning From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Jump to: navigation , search This page is a new unreviewed article . This template should be removed once the page has been reviewed by someone other than its creator; if necessary the page should be appropriately tagged for cleanup . (August 2016) 
As teaching is causing learning among learners (Carlito D. Garcia Ed D, 2013), teachers need to be cognizant of the processes that affect teaching - learning, and the necessary instrument in determining the success of such endeavor. It is a necessary for them to know whether or not their learners are successfully achieving the intended lesson objectives. Thus, the need for assessing learners&apos; performances is a necessary step to determine the effectiveness of strategies employed in the teaching process, and to offer constructive criticism for the learner&apos;s achievement in order to direct learning at an optimum level. To understand the nature of the process of assessment, the following terms needs to be clarified... 
Measurement is the quantification of what students learned through the use of tests, questionnaires, rating scales, checklists, and other devices. (Carlito D. Garcia, Ed., D.,2013) 
Assessment refers to the full range of information gathered and synthesized by teachers about their students and their classrooms (Arends, 1994 as cited by Garcia). 
Evaluation refers to the process of arriving at judgments about the abstract entities such as students&apos; performance, programs, curricula, organizations, and institutions. Moreover, it refers to the consideration of evidence in the light of value standards and in terms of the particular situations and the goals, which the group of individuals are striving to attain. It can be both quantitative descriptions (measurement) or qualitative descriptions (non-measurement) of students. It constantly includes value judgment concerning the desirability of the results. (Gronlund, 1985 as cited by Barbacena Et.al) 
Testing refers to the process of administering a test to measure one or more concepts, usually under standardized conditions (Barbacena Et.al) 
Test refers to an instrument for measuring a sample behaviour. (Gronlund, 1985) 
Norm- referenced and Criterion-referenced According to Escarilla and Gonzales (1990) as cited by Barbacena and Calayag (2013), there are two approaches to evaluation, namely: norm-referenced is one wherein the performance of a student in a test is compared with the performance of the other students who took d same examination. Examples: Karl&apos;s score in the periodical examination is below the mean Cynthia ranked fifth in the unit test in Physics. Grey&apos;s percentile rank in math in Math achievement test is 88. 
Criterion referenced evaluation, on the other hand, is an approach to evaluation when a student&apos;s performance is compared against a predetermined or agreed upon standard. Examples: Said can construct a pie graph with 75% accuracy Yves scored 7 out of 10 in the spelling test Lito can encode an article with no more than 5 errors in spelling. 
Approaches to Evaluation Types of Evaluation To plan and monitor the teaching- learning process, teachers needs feedbacks. Evaluation then is instrumental in obtaining feedbacks that may direct learning goals at the desired learning outcomes. Evaluative process may take on different types: diagnostic, formative, and summative. 
Diagnostic Evaluation According to Barbacena and Calayag (2013), diagnostic evaluation is normally undertaken before instruction, in order to assess students&apos; prior knowledge of a particular topic or lesson. It is also called pre- assessment, since it is designed to check the ability level of students in some areas so that instructional starting point can be established. Carlito D. Garcia Ed D, 2013 Gronlund, 1985
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nature_of_Assessment_of_Learning</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0530</post_time>
<username>Richardmeriveles</username>
<post>
Nature of Assessment of Learning From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Jump to: navigation , search This page is a new unreviewed article . This template should be removed once the page has been reviewed by someone other than its creator; if necessary the page should be appropriately tagged for cleanup . (August 2016) 
As teaching is causing learning among learners (Carlito D. Garcia Ed D, 2013), teachers need to be cognizant of the processes that affect teaching - learning, and the necessary instrument in determining the success of such endeavor. It is a necessary for them to know whether or not their learners are successfully achieving the intended lesson objectives. Thus, the need for assessing learners&apos; performances is a necessary step to determine the effectiveness of strategies employed in the teaching process, and to offer constructive criticism for the learner&apos;s achievement in order to direct learning at an optimum level. To understand the nature of the process of assessment, the following terms needs to be clarified... 
Measurement is the quantification of what students learned through the use of tests, questionnaires, rating scales, checklists, and other devices. (Carlito D. Garcia, Ed., D.,2013) 
Assessment refers to the full range of information gathered and synthesized by teachers about their students and their classrooms (Arends, 1994 as cited by Garcia). 
Evaluation refers to the process of arriving at judgments about the abstract entities such as students&apos; performance, programs, curricula, organizations, and institutions. Moreover, it refers to the consideration of evidence in the light of value standards and in terms of the particular situations and the goals, which the group of individuals are striving to attain. It can be both quantitative descriptions (measurement) or qualitative descriptions (non-measurement) of students. It constantly includes value judgment concerning the desirability of the results. (Gronlund, 1985 as cited by Barbacena Et.al) 
Testing refers to the process of administering a test to measure one or more concepts, usually under standardized conditions (Barbacena Et.al) 
Test refers to an instrument for measuring a sample behaviour. (Gronlund, 1985) 
Norm- referenced and Criterion-referenced According to Escarilla and Gonzales (1990) as cited by Barbacena and Calayag (2013), there are two approaches to evaluation, namely: norm-referenced is one wherein the performance of a student in a test is compared with the performance of the other students who took d same examination. Examples: Karl&apos;s score in the periodical examination is below the mean Cynthia ranked fifth in the unit test in Physics. Grey&apos;s percentile rank in math in Math achievement test is 88. 
Criterion referenced evaluation, on the other hand, is an approach to evaluation when a student&apos;s performance is compared against a predetermined or agreed upon standard. Examples: Said can construct a pie graph with 75% accuracy Yves scored 7 out of 10 in the spelling test Lito can encode an article with no more than 5 errors in spelling. 
Approaches to Evaluation Types of Evaluation To plan and monitor the teaching- learning process, teachers needs feedbacks. Evaluation then is instrumental in obtaining feedbacks that may direct learning goals at the desired learning outcomes. Evaluative process may take on different types: diagnostic, formative, and summative. 
Diagnostic Evaluation According to Barbacena and Calayag (2013), diagnostic evaluation is normally undertaken before instruction, in order to assess students&apos; prior knowledge of a particular topic or lesson. It is also called pre- assessment, since it is designed to check the ability level of students in some areas so that instructional starting point can be established. Carlito D. Garcia Ed D, 2013 Gronlund, 1985
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>NL</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
