<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.naturalhealth365.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Natural Health 365</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mother says Gardasil vaccine robbed her daughter’s life</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.naturalhealth365.com/gardasil-vaccine-dangers-1932.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Posted by: Jonathan Landsman in Vaccine Dangers August 12, 2016 0 
(NaturalHealth365) A family in Aiken, South Carolina will never be the same since their 12-year-old daughter was given the Gardasil vaccine for HPV. Her health declined immediately , and she has been dealing with HPV vaccine side effects ever since. 
For a time, 12-year-old Georgia could not walk. Now that she can, doing so is a big challenge. Since being vaccinated with the HPV vaccine, she has postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS), which affects heart rate, blood flow and brain functioning. This syndrome is a cardiovascular disorder that also happens to be one of the known Gardasil side effects . Gardasil vaccine side effects and health risks far outweigh the benefits 
Gardasil was approved in 2006 by the FDA to prevent human papillomavirus, or HPV. The vaccine requires three shots given over a period of six months. Drug maker Merck claims the vaccine protects adolescents from cervical, penile, vaginal and anal cancers related to HPV. (But, we know that’s not true) 
The vaccine can be administered from age 9 to 26; however, when Georgia received it at age 12, the vaccine dangers were immediately evident. 
Georgia’s skin color turned what her mother said looked like a shade of green, and she fell to the ground. The family was told by doctors that this was normal after receiving the HPV vaccine! Sure enough, dizziness, fainting and even seizures are listed as “normal” Gardasil HPV vaccine side effects. (Injecting toxins into people must become unacceptable!) Quality of life profoundly reduced by vaccine dangers 
Georgia’s mother says continued symptoms of the HPV vaccine have robbed her daughter of her quality of life. She once had a seizure in front of 200 of her classmates at a musical event. Georgia’s cousin also had a reaction immediately after receiving the Gardasil vaccine. 
The vaccine dangers of Gardasil have been documented in numerous studies and medical journals. It has been linked with both POTS and chronic fatigue . Its side effects include fever, pain, lower limb paralysis, Guillain-Barré syndrome, MS, encephalitis and even sudden death. 
Georgia now takes various medications in an attempt to control her own symptoms. However, these drugs also have side effects, including nausea, fatigue and hallucinations. At this point, Georgia and her family aren’t sure where the HPV vaccine side effects leave off and the medication side effects begin. Even former Merck physicians warn against taking the company’s vaccines 
Ever since Gardasil was approved in 2006, there has been an ongoing publicity campaign by Merck pressuring parents to get their adolescent children vaccinated. However, little emphasis has been placed upon vaccine dangers associated with Gardasil and HPV vaccine side effects. 
Even a former Merck pharmaceutical physician, Dr. Bernard Dalbergue, has criticized the Gardasil vaccine, calling it “useless” against HPV, too expensive, and having dangerous side effects. Educate yourself and others about vaccine dangers 
Meanwhile, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) praises Gardasil and encourages young girls and boys to receive the vaccine before becoming sexually active. They even created a DVD specifically made to downplay Gardasil side effects. 
Are the profits associated with vaccines really worth the human toll these drugs take? Has the Hippocratic oath to “do no harm” become meaningless? I hope not. 
Help us spread the word about the dangers of Gardasil to everyone you know with young children. Their health and quality of life could depend on it. 
Editor’s note : The Vaccine World Summit is free and online to help educate the public about vaccine safety issues and reveals effective ways to protect your health. Gain INSTANT access here . 
References:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.naturalhealth365.com/gardasil-vaccine-dangers-1932.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0511</post_time>
<username>Jonathan Landsman</username>
<post>
Posted by: Jonathan Landsman in Vaccine Dangers August 12, 2016 0 
(NaturalHealth365) A family in Aiken, South Carolina will never be the same since their 12-year-old daughter was given the Gardasil vaccine for HPV. Her health declined immediately , and she has been dealing with HPV vaccine side effects ever since. 
For a time, 12-year-old Georgia could not walk. Now that she can, doing so is a big challenge. Since being vaccinated with the HPV vaccine, she has postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (POTS), which affects heart rate, blood flow and brain functioning. This syndrome is a cardiovascular disorder that also happens to be one of the known Gardasil side effects . Gardasil vaccine side effects and health risks far outweigh the benefits 
Gardasil was approved in 2006 by the FDA to prevent human papillomavirus, or HPV. The vaccine requires three shots given over a period of six months. Drug maker Merck claims the vaccine protects adolescents from cervical, penile, vaginal and anal cancers related to HPV. (But, we know that’s not true) 
The vaccine can be administered from age 9 to 26; however, when Georgia received it at age 12, the vaccine dangers were immediately evident. 
Georgia’s skin color turned what her mother said looked like a shade of green, and she fell to the ground. The family was told by doctors that this was normal after receiving the HPV vaccine! Sure enough, dizziness, fainting and even seizures are listed as “normal” Gardasil HPV vaccine side effects. (Injecting toxins into people must become unacceptable!) Quality of life profoundly reduced by vaccine dangers 
Georgia’s mother says continued symptoms of the HPV vaccine have robbed her daughter of her quality of life. She once had a seizure in front of 200 of her classmates at a musical event. Georgia’s cousin also had a reaction immediately after receiving the Gardasil vaccine. 
The vaccine dangers of Gardasil have been documented in numerous studies and medical journals. It has been linked with both POTS and chronic fatigue . Its side effects include fever, pain, lower limb paralysis, Guillain-Barré syndrome, MS, encephalitis and even sudden death. 
Georgia now takes various medications in an attempt to control her own symptoms. However, these drugs also have side effects, including nausea, fatigue and hallucinations. At this point, Georgia and her family aren’t sure where the HPV vaccine side effects leave off and the medication side effects begin. Even former Merck physicians warn against taking the company’s vaccines 
Ever since Gardasil was approved in 2006, there has been an ongoing publicity campaign by Merck pressuring parents to get their adolescent children vaccinated. However, little emphasis has been placed upon vaccine dangers associated with Gardasil and HPV vaccine side effects. 
Even a former Merck pharmaceutical physician, Dr. Bernard Dalbergue, has criticized the Gardasil vaccine, calling it “useless” against HPV, too expensive, and having dangerous side effects. Educate yourself and others about vaccine dangers 
Meanwhile, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) praises Gardasil and encourages young girls and boys to receive the vaccine before becoming sexually active. They even created a DVD specifically made to downplay Gardasil side effects. 
Are the profits associated with vaccines really worth the human toll these drugs take? Has the Hippocratic oath to “do no harm” become meaningless? I hope not. 
Help us spread the word about the dangers of Gardasil to everyone you know with young children. Their health and quality of life could depend on it. 
Editor’s note : The Vaccine World Summit is free and online to help educate the public about vaccine safety issues and reveals effective ways to protect your health. Gain INSTANT access here . 
References:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.naturalhealth365.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Georgia-Wall.jpg</main_image>
</document>
