<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Women’s individual archery: South Korea dominates again, coming away with two medals | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/womens-individual-archery-south-korea-dominates-again-coming-away-with-two-medals/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) Round of 16 
Simply put, the Round of 16 was uneventful. Rankings held their form, and those whom were expected to move on to the quarterfinals did. However, it did remind us just how powerful these Olympic Games are. 
The last match of the morning saw Chang Hyejin of South Korea and Kang Un-ju of North Korea go up against each other. Chang came away with the victory, but when the match was finished, the two athletes bowed and shook hands, illustrating just how good the Olympics are at bringing the world together, if only just for two weeks. Quarterfinals 
Unlike the Round of 16, the quarterfinals got off to a dramatic start. 
In the first match of the afternoon, Germany’s Lisa Unruh upset Tan Ya-Ting of Chinese Taipei , currently ranked No. 2 in the world. 
Then, immediately following that match, Alejandra Valencia of Mexico defeated Choi Misun from South Korea, the world No. 1. 
In the ranking round, Misun and Ya-Ting were No. 1 and No. 4 respectively; their losses opened the door for South Korea’s Ki Bobae – who defeated China’s Wu Jiaxin and is the reigning Olympic champion – and Chang Hyejin, who defeated Great Britain’s Naomi Folkard. Semifinals 
Bobae and Chang’s wins in the quarterfinal matches, though, set up a showdown between the two teammates in their semifinal match. 
Bobae took the first set 25-19, but Chang came back, taking the next two. A tie in the fourth left the match to be decided in the fifth, which Chang won 28-26, taking away Bobae’s chances of becoming the first archer to win gold in the individual competition in back-to-back Olympic Games. 
In the other semifinal match, Unruh defeated Valencia 6-2, advancing to the gold medal match. Bronze Medal Match 
Bobae may have been taken out of the race for gold, but she will not be left off the podium. 
She shot a perfect 30 in the fifth set against Valencia, taking it 6-4 and taking the bronze medal with her. 
Her win assured there would be two women from South Korea receiving medals, though what the second one would be was up to Chang. Gold Medal Match 
The final match of the women’s individual archery competition pitted the world No. 6, Chang, against Unruh, the world No. 16. 
After two sets, the score was tied 2-2. 
But Chang was able to close the match out, winning the next two sets and the gold medal in the process and putting South Korea on the top of podium once again. 
Archery coverage resumes tomorrow morning at 8AM ET for the men’s individual Round of 16. 

</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/womens-individual-archery-south-korea-dominates-again-coming-away-with-two-medals/</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Nbc Olympics.Com</username>
<post>
Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) Round of 16 
Simply put, the Round of 16 was uneventful. Rankings held their form, and those whom were expected to move on to the quarterfinals did. However, it did remind us just how powerful these Olympic Games are. 
The last match of the morning saw Chang Hyejin of South Korea and Kang Un-ju of North Korea go up against each other. Chang came away with the victory, but when the match was finished, the two athletes bowed and shook hands, illustrating just how good the Olympics are at bringing the world together, if only just for two weeks. Quarterfinals 
Unlike the Round of 16, the quarterfinals got off to a dramatic start. 
In the first match of the afternoon, Germany’s Lisa Unruh upset Tan Ya-Ting of Chinese Taipei , currently ranked No. 2 in the world. 
Then, immediately following that match, Alejandra Valencia of Mexico defeated Choi Misun from South Korea, the world No. 1. 
In the ranking round, Misun and Ya-Ting were No. 1 and No. 4 respectively; their losses opened the door for South Korea’s Ki Bobae – who defeated China’s Wu Jiaxin and is the reigning Olympic champion – and Chang Hyejin, who defeated Great Britain’s Naomi Folkard. Semifinals 
Bobae and Chang’s wins in the quarterfinal matches, though, set up a showdown between the two teammates in their semifinal match. 
Bobae took the first set 25-19, but Chang came back, taking the next two. A tie in the fourth left the match to be decided in the fifth, which Chang won 28-26, taking away Bobae’s chances of becoming the first archer to win gold in the individual competition in back-to-back Olympic Games. 
In the other semifinal match, Unruh defeated Valencia 6-2, advancing to the gold medal match. Bronze Medal Match 
Bobae may have been taken out of the race for gold, but she will not be left off the podium. 
She shot a perfect 30 in the fifth set against Valencia, taking it 6-4 and taking the bronze medal with her. 
Her win assured there would be two women from South Korea receiving medals, though what the second one would be was up to Chang. Gold Medal Match 
The final match of the women’s individual archery competition pitted the world No. 6, Chang, against Unruh, the world No. 16. 
After two sets, the score was tied 2-2. 
But Chang was able to close the match out, winning the next two sets and the gold medal in the process and putting South Korea on the top of podium once again. 
Archery coverage resumes tomorrow morning at 8AM ET for the men’s individual Round of 16. 

</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/160811_archery_gold_womens.jpg</main_image>
</document>
