<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Patriots’ fans excited and ready for the season to start | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/patriots-fans-excited-and-ready-for-the-season-to-start/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Patriots’ fans excited and ready for the season to start Tom Brady is serving a 4 game suspension to start the season Ashley Afonso Published: August 11, 2016, 11:05 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
FOXBOROUGH, Mass. (WWLP) – The New England Patriots faced the New Orleans Saints at Gillette Stadium on Thursday, for the team’s first preseason game of the 2016 NFL season. 
This was also the first game since the announcement that Quarterback Tom Brady would have to serve a 4 game suspension for the “Deflategate” investigation . Coach Bill Belicheck named Jimmy Garoppolo as the starting quarterback, while Brady serves his suspension. New England Patriots News 
22News traveled to Foxborough two weeks ago when the Patriots training camp began. Garoppolo said then this opportunity is one that he’s been preparing for since his NFL career began. 
Fans told us on Thursday that they have faith in Garopallo, but they can’t wait to get to Week 5, when Brady returns. Tori Ladroga of Virginia said, “I’m looking forward to Week 5, and I’m greatly looking forward to us whooping Cleveland. I don’t think it’s fair but I can’t wait to see what happens when he comes back.” 
We also found a least one Patriots fan, he may be the only, not upset about Brady’s suspension. Rick Ladroga of Athol said, “He gets very fired up, he gets invested into the emotional aspect and I don’t think there’s anything that could get him more fired up and bring the team together in the locker room than his suspension. I think it’s going to be great. It’s going to be a great season and a great run.” 
Although it’s been over a month since Brady’s suspension became finalized, a lot of fans are still very upset about it. Justin Mello of Dartmouth said, “I’m not happy about it Goodell…ugh Goodell…I think Garoppolo will do well for us and hopefully he does enough for us to get a couple wins, I’d like four, but I’ll take three or four and I think Brady will carry us the rest of the way.” 
NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell has received a lot of criticism from patriot’s fans for the Deflategate scandal. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/patriots-fans-excited-and-ready-for-the-season-to-start/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Ashley Afonso</username>
<post>
Patriots’ fans excited and ready for the season to start Tom Brady is serving a 4 game suspension to start the season Ashley Afonso Published: August 11, 2016, 11:05 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) 
FOXBOROUGH, Mass. (WWLP) – The New England Patriots faced the New Orleans Saints at Gillette Stadium on Thursday, for the team’s first preseason game of the 2016 NFL season. 
This was also the first game since the announcement that Quarterback Tom Brady would have to serve a 4 game suspension for the “Deflategate” investigation . Coach Bill Belicheck named Jimmy Garoppolo as the starting quarterback, while Brady serves his suspension. New England Patriots News 
22News traveled to Foxborough two weeks ago when the Patriots training camp began. Garoppolo said then this opportunity is one that he’s been preparing for since his NFL career began. 
Fans told us on Thursday that they have faith in Garopallo, but they can’t wait to get to Week 5, when Brady returns. Tori Ladroga of Virginia said, “I’m looking forward to Week 5, and I’m greatly looking forward to us whooping Cleveland. I don’t think it’s fair but I can’t wait to see what happens when he comes back.” 
We also found a least one Patriots fan, he may be the only, not upset about Brady’s suspension. Rick Ladroga of Athol said, “He gets very fired up, he gets invested into the emotional aspect and I don’t think there’s anything that could get him more fired up and bring the team together in the locker room than his suspension. I think it’s going to be great. It’s going to be a great season and a great run.” 
Although it’s been over a month since Brady’s suspension became finalized, a lot of fans are still very upset about it. Justin Mello of Dartmouth said, “I’m not happy about it Goodell…ugh Goodell…I think Garoppolo will do well for us and hopefully he does enough for us to get a couple wins, I’d like four, but I’ll take three or four and I think Brady will carry us the rest of the way.” 
NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell has received a lot of criticism from patriot’s fans for the Deflategate scandal. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2015/01/outside-gillette-stadium-on-a-cloudy-day-web.jpg</main_image>
</document>
