<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://prsync.com/rss/</forum>
<forum_title>PR sync</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Geoffrey Lafond-Pre-pregnancy Tips That Lead to an Easier Time</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://prsync.com/pz-media-inc/geoffrey-lafond-pre-pregnancy-tips-that-lead-to-an-easier-time-1065351/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Submitted by Geoffrey Lafond . As a general obstetrics and gynecology specialist, Geoffrey Lafond is well-trained to take care of women’s health, including pregnancy, reproductive health, and general care. Pregnancy is an exciting time for a woman and often presents unique challenges to their health. With a few tips, however, it’s possible to ensure that things go smoothly. Get active Before you start painting the nursery or settle on a name, you should think about how to prepare your body for what’s to come. Start by getting active to make the pregnancy easier. At least half an hour of exercise every day is beneficial. Walking, swimming and cycling are good workouts that get the blood flowing. Maintain a good diet Before the ice cream cravings kick in, you should focus on maintaining a healthy diet. You should eat foods rich in calcium, proteins, folic acid, and iron. This means a lot of leafy greens, veggies, nuts, fruits, low-fat dairy products and whole grains. Reduce on the empty calories that come from junk foods, baked goods, and fizzy drinks. Buy folic acid supplements Folic acid is essential in preventing birth defects. This vitamin is present in many foods like beans, citrus fruits, and leafy greens, but many women also opt to take it in the form of pills. During pregnancy, your body will require lots of folic acid, so speak to your doctor about which multivitamin can work best. Maintain a good weight Being too skinny can make pregnancy harder. Being overweight can bring a host of other issues as well, including high blood pressure or diabetes. Too much weight can also prolong labor, which is something you don’t want to happen. Consult with your doctor about the appropriate weight levels to maintain. Adopt a healthy lifestyle It’s essential you cut back on caffeine, especially if you are trying to get pregnant or during the pregnancy period. If you can’t do without your cup of coffee, limit it to just one cup, or reduce the amount taken. Obviously, smoking and consuming alcohol make life harder during pregnancy. From causing problems like premature birth, miscarriage, and birth defects, you are better off avoiding alcohol and tobacco entirely. For More Information Visit Here - https://about.me/geoffreylafond About PZ Media Inc PZ Media INC provides professional and quality content writing service that helps our clients for improving their personal and websites information on search engines.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://prsync.com/pz-media-inc/geoffrey-lafond-pre-pregnancy-tips-that-lead-to-an-easier-time-1065351/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0150</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Submitted by Geoffrey Lafond . As a general obstetrics and gynecology specialist, Geoffrey Lafond is well-trained to take care of women’s health, including pregnancy, reproductive health, and general care. Pregnancy is an exciting time for a woman and often presents unique challenges to their health. With a few tips, however, it’s possible to ensure that things go smoothly. Get active Before you start painting the nursery or settle on a name, you should think about how to prepare your body for what’s to come. Start by getting active to make the pregnancy easier. At least half an hour of exercise every day is beneficial. Walking, swimming and cycling are good workouts that get the blood flowing. Maintain a good diet Before the ice cream cravings kick in, you should focus on maintaining a healthy diet. You should eat foods rich in calcium, proteins, folic acid, and iron. This means a lot of leafy greens, veggies, nuts, fruits, low-fat dairy products and whole grains. Reduce on the empty calories that come from junk foods, baked goods, and fizzy drinks. Buy folic acid supplements Folic acid is essential in preventing birth defects. This vitamin is present in many foods like beans, citrus fruits, and leafy greens, but many women also opt to take it in the form of pills. During pregnancy, your body will require lots of folic acid, so speak to your doctor about which multivitamin can work best. Maintain a good weight Being too skinny can make pregnancy harder. Being overweight can bring a host of other issues as well, including high blood pressure or diabetes. Too much weight can also prolong labor, which is something you don’t want to happen. Consult with your doctor about the appropriate weight levels to maintain. Adopt a healthy lifestyle It’s essential you cut back on caffeine, especially if you are trying to get pregnant or during the pregnancy period. If you can’t do without your cup of coffee, limit it to just one cup, or reduce the amount taken. Obviously, smoking and consuming alcohol make life harder during pregnancy. From causing problems like premature birth, miscarriage, and birth defects, you are better off avoiding alcohol and tobacco entirely. For More Information Visit Here - https://about.me/geoffreylafond About PZ Media Inc PZ Media INC provides professional and quality content writing service that helps our clients for improving their personal and websites information on search engines.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
