<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.joplinglobe.com/search/?q=&amp;t=article&amp;l=100&amp;d=&amp;d1=&amp;d2=&amp;s=start_time&amp;sd=desc&amp;nsa=eedition&amp;c%5B%5D=news,news/*&amp;f=rss</forum>
<forum_title>www.joplinglobe.com - RSS Results in news,news/* of type article</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Large classrooms at Seneca seek to solve real-world problems</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.joplinglobe.com/news/local_news/large-classrooms-at-seneca-seek-to-solve-real-world-problems/article_0dcb3494-e9c4-5c80-9abb-c15f383bd84b.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Ariel Cooley 1 hr ago 
Third-grader Aedric Batson, 8, listens to instructions for a team-building exercise Thursday in Heather Lankford and Gwyn Osborne&apos;s class at Seneca Elementary. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
Fifth-grade teacher Holli Sears speaks to her class Thursday, the first day of school, at Seneca Elementary. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
Seneca Elementary third-graders return to their classrooms after recess Thursday, the first day of school. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
Students in a combined classroom listen to their teachers on the first day of school at Seneca Elementary. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
Students pass through the hallway on the first day of school Thursday at Seneca Elementary. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
SENECA, Mo. — Forty-eight students sat at their desks in Gwen Osborne and Heather Lankford’s combined third-grade classroom. Aedric Batson stacked red Solo cups into a pyramid in anticipation of a team-building activity for the first day of school. 
He knocked down his pyramid and the eight students at his table begin building a pyramid together, but they were not allowed to touch the cups with their hands. String and rubber bands were used to grip the cups and place them on top of each other. 
“We did this the first time with four students,” Lankford said. “So now we’re showing them that when you add more people into the equation you get more ideas and also more problems. They’re struggling with the bigger groups.” 
On Thursday, Seneca was one of the first districts to return to school for the year. It was accompanied by Galena, Kansas, and Miami, Oklahoma. 
Lankford and Osborne, who are two of the four instructors for a project-based learning classroom, spent the first day of school setting up procedures and getting their students accustomed to the large classroom. The wall between the two rooms was knocked down, and now the teachers will instruct the mass of students as a team. 
“We’re just trying to organize everything right now,” Lankford said. “It’s going to take us all week just to get all the procedures down. We’re just so anxious to get all that done so we can get to the real stuff.” 
The instruction will be based on real-world problems. The classes will work with local businesses to help solve problems and learn at the same time. 
“These kids are never going to say, ‘Why am I learning this?’” said Shanna Eidson, elementary school principal. 
The two teachers will spend some time teaching the entire class but will spend the majority of the time in small groups that rotate through stations. 
“The thing that really excites me is it’s the same projects we’ve been doing but with a whole new twist,” Osborne said. 
Osborne and Lankford were second-grade teachers last year, so their third-grade classroom is made up of many students they already had. This, they said, means a lot of their students already know what’s expected of them. 
Eidson said Osborne and Lankford were specifically chosen for the project-based learning classroom because of their experience and their expertise. Lankford’s strength is literature, and Osborne’s is math. 
“We are a professional learning community, which means we are constantly learning from each other,” Eidson said. “They have that built in all day every day.” 
There is also a double-sized fifth-grade classroom run by Holli Sears and Anne Soden, who are just as excited as the third-grade teachers. 
“I think it will actually be really helpful to have another person here to answer questions and work with the kids,” Sears said. Story continues below video 
Sears and Soden have more than 20 years of experience combined. 
“I don’t think it will be overwhelming,” Sears said. “It’s definitely different and going to take some time to get used to, but we’ve worked with kids for a long time and I’m excited to try out this type of classroom.” 
The two teachers are already finding their grooves and working together. When Sears made her way to the front of the classroom to begin a lesson, Soden caught the attention of a few chatting students and focused their attention on the front of the extra long room. 
“There’s more people and a lot more talking,” said fifth-grader Juli Lowe. She and the students at her table think their “big classroom” will be more fun than a regular classroom. 
The four teachers, along with Eidson and two others, spent a week in Indianapolis for training. 
“We do a lot of STEM (science, technology, engineering and math) activities, but this is just taking it a step further,” Eidson said. 
The students will work on big projects that show them how their schooling is used in everyday life, Eidson said. They will work with local businesses to help solve problems. 
“In the meantime, you’re covering your math and science standards and of course the reading standards,” Eidson said. “We are really thrilled to be doing this.” 
First days of school 
Two districts, Lamar and Golden City, start Aug. 15. Districts starting Aug. 16 are East Newton, Jasper, Pierce City, Purdy, Monett and Wheaton. 
Aug. 17 will see school starting in Baxter Springs, Columbus and Riverton in Kansas, McDonald County, Neosho, Sarcoxie and Webb City in Missouri, and Peoria in Oklahoma. 
Aug. 18 will be the first day of school for Carl Junction, Carthage, Diamond, Joplin and Pittsburg, Kansas, and for the private schools of College Heights Christian School and McAuley Catholic High School. 
Thomas Jefferson Independent Day School will begin the school year Aug. 22. 
The last district in the area to return to school is Avilla, which has an Aug. 24 start date. Sign Up / Sign In With your existing account from... {* loginWidget *}
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.joplinglobe.com/news/local_news/large-classrooms-at-seneca-seek-to-solve-real-world-problems/article_0dcb3494-e9c4-5c80-9abb-c15f383bd84b.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0400</post_time>
<username>Ariel Cooley acooley@joplinglobe.com</username>
<post>
Ariel Cooley 1 hr ago 
Third-grader Aedric Batson, 8, listens to instructions for a team-building exercise Thursday in Heather Lankford and Gwyn Osborne&apos;s class at Seneca Elementary. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
Fifth-grade teacher Holli Sears speaks to her class Thursday, the first day of school, at Seneca Elementary. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
Seneca Elementary third-graders return to their classrooms after recess Thursday, the first day of school. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
Students in a combined classroom listen to their teachers on the first day of school at Seneca Elementary. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
Students pass through the hallway on the first day of school Thursday at Seneca Elementary. Globe | Laurie Sisk 
SENECA, Mo. — Forty-eight students sat at their desks in Gwen Osborne and Heather Lankford’s combined third-grade classroom. Aedric Batson stacked red Solo cups into a pyramid in anticipation of a team-building activity for the first day of school. 
He knocked down his pyramid and the eight students at his table begin building a pyramid together, but they were not allowed to touch the cups with their hands. String and rubber bands were used to grip the cups and place them on top of each other. 
“We did this the first time with four students,” Lankford said. “So now we’re showing them that when you add more people into the equation you get more ideas and also more problems. They’re struggling with the bigger groups.” 
On Thursday, Seneca was one of the first districts to return to school for the year. It was accompanied by Galena, Kansas, and Miami, Oklahoma. 
Lankford and Osborne, who are two of the four instructors for a project-based learning classroom, spent the first day of school setting up procedures and getting their students accustomed to the large classroom. The wall between the two rooms was knocked down, and now the teachers will instruct the mass of students as a team. 
“We’re just trying to organize everything right now,” Lankford said. “It’s going to take us all week just to get all the procedures down. We’re just so anxious to get all that done so we can get to the real stuff.” 
The instruction will be based on real-world problems. The classes will work with local businesses to help solve problems and learn at the same time. 
“These kids are never going to say, ‘Why am I learning this?’” said Shanna Eidson, elementary school principal. 
The two teachers will spend some time teaching the entire class but will spend the majority of the time in small groups that rotate through stations. 
“The thing that really excites me is it’s the same projects we’ve been doing but with a whole new twist,” Osborne said. 
Osborne and Lankford were second-grade teachers last year, so their third-grade classroom is made up of many students they already had. This, they said, means a lot of their students already know what’s expected of them. 
Eidson said Osborne and Lankford were specifically chosen for the project-based learning classroom because of their experience and their expertise. Lankford’s strength is literature, and Osborne’s is math. 
“We are a professional learning community, which means we are constantly learning from each other,” Eidson said. “They have that built in all day every day.” 
There is also a double-sized fifth-grade classroom run by Holli Sears and Anne Soden, who are just as excited as the third-grade teachers. 
“I think it will actually be really helpful to have another person here to answer questions and work with the kids,” Sears said. Story continues below video 
Sears and Soden have more than 20 years of experience combined. 
“I don’t think it will be overwhelming,” Sears said. “It’s definitely different and going to take some time to get used to, but we’ve worked with kids for a long time and I’m excited to try out this type of classroom.” 
The two teachers are already finding their grooves and working together. When Sears made her way to the front of the classroom to begin a lesson, Soden caught the attention of a few chatting students and focused their attention on the front of the extra long room. 
“There’s more people and a lot more talking,” said fifth-grader Juli Lowe. She and the students at her table think their “big classroom” will be more fun than a regular classroom. 
The four teachers, along with Eidson and two others, spent a week in Indianapolis for training. 
“We do a lot of STEM (science, technology, engineering and math) activities, but this is just taking it a step further,” Eidson said. 
The students will work on big projects that show them how their schooling is used in everyday life, Eidson said. They will work with local businesses to help solve problems. 
“In the meantime, you’re covering your math and science standards and of course the reading standards,” Eidson said. “We are really thrilled to be doing this.” 
First days of school 
Two districts, Lamar and Golden City, start Aug. 15. Districts starting Aug. 16 are East Newton, Jasper, Pierce City, Purdy, Monett and Wheaton. 
Aug. 17 will see school starting in Baxter Springs, Columbus and Riverton in Kansas, McDonald County, Neosho, Sarcoxie and Webb City in Missouri, and Peoria in Oklahoma. 
Aug. 18 will be the first day of school for Carl Junction, Carthage, Diamond, Joplin and Pittsburg, Kansas, and for the private schools of College Heights Christian School and McAuley Catholic High School. 
Thomas Jefferson Independent Day School will begin the school year Aug. 22. 
The last district in the area to return to school is Avilla, which has an Aug. 24 start date. Sign Up / Sign In With your existing account from... {* loginWidget *}
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://bloximages.chicago2.vip.townnews.com/joplinglobe.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/d/d2/dd202154-2d74-54cb-90af-934c583237c6/57ad2329847cd.image.jpg?resize=777%2C600</main_image>
</document>
