<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.politico.com/tipsheets/morning-cybersecurity/archive</forum>
<forum_title>Morning Cybersecurity Archive - POLITICO</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Pence blames media for Trump&apos;s &apos;Obama founded ISIS&apos; flap</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/08/mike-pence-obama-isis-media-226928</topic_url>
<topic_text>
LA CROSSE, Wisc. — Gov. Mike Pence on Thursday blamed the media for making an issue out of Donald Trump’s claim that President Barack Obama “founded ISIS,” saying they were nitpicking at Trump&apos;s wording while missing the larger truth of Trump&apos;s remarks. “The media’s talking today about another controversy over semantics,” Pence said at a town hall here. “Let’s be very clear: It was Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton who helped undo all the hard fought gains in Operation Iraqi Freedom that our soldiers won and secured that nation.&quot;
Pence continued: &quot;When President Obama became president, it’s important to remember, that Iraq was essentially stable and it was Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton that withdrew American forces precipitously without what’s called a status of forces agreement, and they created the very vacuum in which ISIS was able to be spawned and conjured up as it were, compromising large areas of Iraq and bringing violence to that part of the world, to our allies in Europe and inspiring violence here at home.”
Trump said Obama was the founder of ISIS on Wednesday at a Florida rally, and he reiterated them on Hugh Hewitt’s radio show Thursday — where he seemed to differ with Pence’s interpretation of his remarks. After Hewitt suggested that Trump simply meant that Obama’s policies created the conditions in which ISIS could emerge, Trump contradicted him.
“No, I meant he’s the founder of ISIS,” Trump responded. “I do. He was the most valuable player. … He was the founder.”
Rep. Sean Duffy (R-Wisc.) also addressed the controversy when introducing Pence Thursday. “Maybe not literally, but if you look at the policies of Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton, they set the policy up that ISIS could rise,” he said.
The root causes of ISIS&apos; formation are hotly debated, and Pence is not alone in his contention that Obama and Clinton&apos;s handling of the end of the Iraq war led to the group&apos;s rise. Obama did not, however, personally found ISIS.
A poll from Marquette Law School released Wednesday found Clinton leading Trump by 15 points among likely voters in Wisconsin, 52 percent to 37 percent.
Pence&apos;s comments came at a town hall in this Wisconsin town, where he took questions from the crowd. During the discussion, Pence pledged that Trump “really is” in favor of free trade, but wants “smarter and tougher” trade deals. He also spoke about the proposed border wall, saying it will be “as big as it needs to be.”
The last question at the event was from a young child, who said he and his father drove to the event from Omaha, Nebraska — about six hours away.
“How big is that wall?” asked the boy, who was wearing a &apos;Make America Great Again&apos; hat and said his name was Mason, as the audience laughed and applauded.
“Mason let me tell you, how big is that wall going to be?” Pence said in response. “As big as it needs to be.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>24</post_num>
<post_id>post-24</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/08/mike-pence-obama-isis-media-226928</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2140</post_time>
<username>Daniel Williams</username>
<post>
G. W. Bush owns this Iraq War, Syria and ISIS. The PRESENT DAY issues with Iraq, Syria and ISIS can be traced back to the ORIGINAL BUSH BLUNDER taking the U.S. into an unnecessary Iraq War. Saddam Hussein, even with his brutal regime, was keeping many of these terrorists contained and under control until Bush took the U.S. into an unnecessary war, invaded Iraq and toppled Saddam, which destabilized the Middle East and gave more power to terrorists that CREATED ISIS. Also, Abu Bakr al Baghdadi (the leader of ISIS) was released under the 2008 agreement, SIGNED BY BUSH, between the U.S and Iraq that guaranteed that the U.S. would give up custody of detainees. This created the potential for ISIS to take over Syria, which is EXACTLY what they are trying to do now. If Bush didn’t take the U.S. into an unnecessary Iraq war and sign the 2008 agreement, odds are NONE of this would have happened and we wouldn’t have this more virulent strain of terrorism called ISIS - he set off a chain of events that the U.S. is still paying for today. During an interview with CBS Bob Schieffer on Face the Nation, Bush regretted that the Iraq war paved a way for the RISE of violent groups such as ISIS. Bush also said “My regret is that a violent group of people has risen up again. This is ‘Al-Qaeda plus’.&quot; President Obama was presented with the SOFA 2008 Agreement entitled &quot;Agreement Between the U.S. and the Republic of Iraq On the WITHDRAWAL of U.S Forces from Iraq&quot; that was signed by BUSH, and a situation where Al-Maliki alienated the Suni’s and Kurds, created a sectarian exclusionary gov’t, asked U.S. to leave, said they were capable of providing their own security, and refused to give U.S. soldiers immunity and said U.S. soldiers could have been tried under Iraq religious law (convicted, hanged, stoned, etc.) if they remained in Iraq. Giving U.S. soldiers immunity has been a U.S. CORE REQUIREMENT AND CONDITION through Republican and Democratic Administrations, and Obama AND other U.S. Commanders AGREED and were CORRECT to have the U.S. leave Iraq in 2011 in accordance with the SOFA agreement, after Al-Maliki refused to give U.S. soldiers immunity. Can you imagine if we had stayed there under Al-Maliki terms and be subjected to the spectacle of our U.S. soldiers being tried, sentenced, then imprisoned or killed, hanged, stoned, under Iraq law? . . . .Which then begs the question: Why do many Republicans or ANY American hate our military so much as to want to keep them in Iraq under those conditions? The same Republicans who are rabidly complaining about a “vacuum” and the U.S. leaving Iraq would have been rabidly complaining if Obama had ignored the U.S. core requirement and condition, and kept U.S. soldiers there with no immunity from being prosecuted under Iraq law, and Americans were subjected to punishment under Iraqi law. Al-Maliki did not have to do this and is to blame for the U.S. withdrawal – he could have allowed immunity and asked the U.S. to stay if he wanted to, but he did not - and his refusal and actions are NOT the fault of Obama, Hillary, and the U.S. Trump’s ignorant clueless comment is just another example of him demonstrating that he is UNFIT to be POTUS - and his supporters are just as ignorant and pathetic. People worldwide are aghast and horrified that the U.S. would have an ignorant sexist, racist, bigoted KKK welcoming scam artist sleaze buffoon and eyesore as Trump for a Presidential nominee. It would be tantamount to SUICIDE for the U.S. to trust an unhinged, insecure thin-skinned bigoted machismo obsessed blowhard like Trump with the nuclear key code and arsenal triad for nukes, which could blow-up the world several times over . . . .Americans, Trump is just another reason of many why you should go to the polls in droves and vote these Republicans down ballot OUT of office in upcoming Nov. election.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://static.politico.com/f6/2a/218946154dcaa9f0bd283ddbee8b/08-mike-pence-4-ap-1160.jpg</main_image>
</document>
