<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.metrowestdailynews.com/entertainment/arts?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Arts - MetroWest Daily News, Framingham, MA</forum_title>
<discussion_title>At Plymouth&apos;s Spire Center, saxman Henley Douglas embraces R</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.metrowestdailynews.com/entertainment/20160811/at-plymouths-spire-center-saxman-henley-douglas-embraces-rb</topic_url>
<topic_text>
log in 
Saxophonist Henley Douglas has had a lustrous music career, first as a founder of the Heavy Metal Horns, which delighted audiences around the country with its mix of rock, funk and jazz, from 1989 to 2000, and then later as a key member of The Boston Horns, the more funk-oriented group that evolved out of Heavy Metal Horns after 2000. 
But just a few years ago he contemplated what he really wanted to do musically and had an epiphany under rather difficult circumstances. 
“I had a tumor, and had to have it removed, so I was in the Intensive Care Unit for three or four days, with plenty of time to think,” Douglas said this week from his North Shore home. “You could say a moment of truth hit me. Life is so precious, you should take the time to do exactly what you want to do. Although I had almost always played in bands with vocalists, we had always had really strong instrumentals. I just decided what I really wanted was to build a band around that concept, just instrumental music that is strong and dynamic.” 
The result was the new HDRnB, which of course is Douglas’ initials plus “rhythm and blues,” and the septet, which includes Plymouth native Charlie O’Neal on guitar, has a busy weekend, performing at Ryles Jazz Club in Cambridge tonight and at The Spire Center in Plymouth on Saturday night. 
“I left the Boston Horns five years ago, intending to move in this more instrumental direction,” Douglas explained. “The basic style is still r-and-b and funk, but not as loud and bombastic. We also use a lot of two-guitar formats, and this weekend we’ll have three guitars, so that gives it a much different sound. Usually though, we have a two-guitar/three horns frontline, with a percussionist and rhythm section, and we love to use a lot of textures and strong dynamics. 
“Four months ago we released our album “Vital Signs I,” and we all contributed and wrote music for it,” said Douglas. “I was lucky enough to do an interview over Sirius radio with hall of fame DJ Meg Griffin, who hosts a program called The Loft, that has helped us sell a lot of units nationwide. I was really honored to get the chance to talk with her, and we’re probably one of the only instrumental acts they’ve featured, but they have re-broadcast it a couple times, so we just keep getting more and more fans that way. It was a very cool thing to happen to us.” 
Of course local fans know Charlie O’Neal from his band with his brother Rick, the Delta Generators, but he and Douglas have been performing together for many years too. 
“Oh Charlie and I have done a lot of work together, especially now that he lives in Salem,” Douglas noted. “I played with a lot of rock bands in my day, and I know Charlie is an amazing musician. The other cool thing about this Plymouth date is that O’Neal-Armstrong, the trio Charlie and Rick have with their drummer pal Jeff Armstrong, is opening this Saturday show. The Delta Generators are still going strong too, and now using Brian Templeton (the ex-Radio King) as their vocalist, so Charlie is in all three of these bands. We have done shows with the Delta generators, but the neat thing about this is that O’Neal-Armstrong is also an all-instrumental band.” 
Initially HDRnB did use a vocalist 
when Douglas founded it about five years ago. 
“The first two-and-half, or three years, we had a vocalist too,” said Douglas. “But my thoughts had been turning towards instrumentals, and when that singer left, and then I had that time to think about things in the hospital, we made the change to all instrumentals.” 
HDRnB has been able to draw on Douglas’ reputation from his other bands to quickly establish a regular rotation of New England gigs, playing at Ryles every four months or so, and at places like Chianti in Beverly. Offers come in from around the country now too, but since Douglas still works days as an engineer, and most of his bandmates have day jobs as well, their touring is mostly limited to New England, or the occasional long weekend on the road. 
“We’ve been really fortunate in finding the real listening rooms, where people seem to really get into the music,” Douglas said. “We pack them into spaces like Chianti, where the music can be appreciated. It does get pretty funky too, so we also usually get people up and dancing a lot.” 
The lineup in Plymouth will not include regular trumpeter Garret Savluk, Douglas old cohort from both of his previous bands, but it will have those three guitarslingers, Charlie O’Neal, Peter Fedele and Brandon Tarricone. 
“Brandon Tarricone is someone we played with at the New Orleans Jazzfest about three years ago,” Douglas pointed out. “Now he has moved up here to Boston, and has his own band, Krewe de Groove, and half of us in HDRnB also play in that, although the shows we put on are totally different. Playing with people of that caliber really teaches you a lot. All three guitarists have very separate and distinct styles, and hearing them work off each other should be a real thrill. Without Garret, we will have a pared down horn section, just me and Scronch on trombone, but it will be fun.” 
Naturally, writing all instrumentals demands a new kind of focus on melody and flow, but Douglas and his mates have adapted to that, he said, and songs are set up so that soloists can take their improvisation wherever they want to go. 
“I think all the bands I’ve been in have concentrated on strong melodies and a lot of dynamics,” Douglas mused. “Saturday night will be special, because sometimes one of those three guitars will sound like a horn, while another guitar is playing straight rhythm, and the other guitar is doing something else, totally different. The audiences pick up on these dynamics, and then when a solo starts, the soloist might take the groove in a whole new direction.” 
“All of our material is very much written out and composed,” Douglas added, “but when it gets to the solos, it can really open up. All these guys can really play, and the audience really reacts. I’m just very lucky to be surrounded by such musicians, and, we always try to shake up the songbook a little, show to show, so it never gets stale.” 
HDRnB is slated to hit the studio in September to put the finishing touches on “Vital Signs II,” an album of material they had left over from the previous sessions but didn’t have room for on the first CD. Beyond that, Douglas is still smiling over the Heavy Metal Horns’ 25th Anniversary show that was staged in February as part of Johnny D’s last string of shows. 
“That was a wonderful reunion for all of us,” said Douglas. “I had not seen four of those guys for 20 years, but when we got together and started playing, it was right in the pocket. It was a huge lesson in music and experience; when you have that connection with people it is always there. That club was jammed that night, and it became quite an emotional evening for us all. We’re all getting emails and everything begging us for another reunion, so we are going to try to do another one in November at the Cabot Theater in Beverly.” 


About Us
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.metrowestdailynews.com/entertainment/20160811/at-plymouths-spire-center-saxman-henley-douglas-embraces-rb</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time>2028</post_time>
<username>Jay N. Miller/The Patriot Ledger</username>
<post>
log in 
Saxophonist Henley Douglas has had a lustrous music career, first as a founder of the Heavy Metal Horns, which delighted audiences around the country with its mix of rock, funk and jazz, from 1989 to 2000, and then later as a key member of The Boston Horns, the more funk-oriented group that evolved out of Heavy Metal Horns after 2000. 
But just a few years ago he contemplated what he really wanted to do musically and had an epiphany under rather difficult circumstances. 
“I had a tumor, and had to have it removed, so I was in the Intensive Care Unit for three or four days, with plenty of time to think,” Douglas said this week from his North Shore home. “You could say a moment of truth hit me. Life is so precious, you should take the time to do exactly what you want to do. Although I had almost always played in bands with vocalists, we had always had really strong instrumentals. I just decided what I really wanted was to build a band around that concept, just instrumental music that is strong and dynamic.” 
The result was the new HDRnB, which of course is Douglas’ initials plus “rhythm and blues,” and the septet, which includes Plymouth native Charlie O’Neal on guitar, has a busy weekend, performing at Ryles Jazz Club in Cambridge tonight and at The Spire Center in Plymouth on Saturday night. 
“I left the Boston Horns five years ago, intending to move in this more instrumental direction,” Douglas explained. “The basic style is still r-and-b and funk, but not as loud and bombastic. We also use a lot of two-guitar formats, and this weekend we’ll have three guitars, so that gives it a much different sound. Usually though, we have a two-guitar/three horns frontline, with a percussionist and rhythm section, and we love to use a lot of textures and strong dynamics. 
“Four months ago we released our album “Vital Signs I,” and we all contributed and wrote music for it,” said Douglas. “I was lucky enough to do an interview over Sirius radio with hall of fame DJ Meg Griffin, who hosts a program called The Loft, that has helped us sell a lot of units nationwide. I was really honored to get the chance to talk with her, and we’re probably one of the only instrumental acts they’ve featured, but they have re-broadcast it a couple times, so we just keep getting more and more fans that way. It was a very cool thing to happen to us.” 
Of course local fans know Charlie O’Neal from his band with his brother Rick, the Delta Generators, but he and Douglas have been performing together for many years too. 
“Oh Charlie and I have done a lot of work together, especially now that he lives in Salem,” Douglas noted. “I played with a lot of rock bands in my day, and I know Charlie is an amazing musician. The other cool thing about this Plymouth date is that O’Neal-Armstrong, the trio Charlie and Rick have with their drummer pal Jeff Armstrong, is opening this Saturday show. The Delta Generators are still going strong too, and now using Brian Templeton (the ex-Radio King) as their vocalist, so Charlie is in all three of these bands. We have done shows with the Delta generators, but the neat thing about this is that O’Neal-Armstrong is also an all-instrumental band.” 
Initially HDRnB did use a vocalist 
when Douglas founded it about five years ago. 
“The first two-and-half, or three years, we had a vocalist too,” said Douglas. “But my thoughts had been turning towards instrumentals, and when that singer left, and then I had that time to think about things in the hospital, we made the change to all instrumentals.” 
HDRnB has been able to draw on Douglas’ reputation from his other bands to quickly establish a regular rotation of New England gigs, playing at Ryles every four months or so, and at places like Chianti in Beverly. Offers come in from around the country now too, but since Douglas still works days as an engineer, and most of his bandmates have day jobs as well, their touring is mostly limited to New England, or the occasional long weekend on the road. 
“We’ve been really fortunate in finding the real listening rooms, where people seem to really get into the music,” Douglas said. “We pack them into spaces like Chianti, where the music can be appreciated. It does get pretty funky too, so we also usually get people up and dancing a lot.” 
The lineup in Plymouth will not include regular trumpeter Garret Savluk, Douglas old cohort from both of his previous bands, but it will have those three guitarslingers, Charlie O’Neal, Peter Fedele and Brandon Tarricone. 
“Brandon Tarricone is someone we played with at the New Orleans Jazzfest about three years ago,” Douglas pointed out. “Now he has moved up here to Boston, and has his own band, Krewe de Groove, and half of us in HDRnB also play in that, although the shows we put on are totally different. Playing with people of that caliber really teaches you a lot. All three guitarists have very separate and distinct styles, and hearing them work off each other should be a real thrill. Without Garret, we will have a pared down horn section, just me and Scronch on trombone, but it will be fun.” 
Naturally, writing all instrumentals demands a new kind of focus on melody and flow, but Douglas and his mates have adapted to that, he said, and songs are set up so that soloists can take their improvisation wherever they want to go. 
“I think all the bands I’ve been in have concentrated on strong melodies and a lot of dynamics,” Douglas mused. “Saturday night will be special, because sometimes one of those three guitars will sound like a horn, while another guitar is playing straight rhythm, and the other guitar is doing something else, totally different. The audiences pick up on these dynamics, and then when a solo starts, the soloist might take the groove in a whole new direction.” 
“All of our material is very much written out and composed,” Douglas added, “but when it gets to the solos, it can really open up. All these guys can really play, and the audience really reacts. I’m just very lucky to be surrounded by such musicians, and, we always try to shake up the songbook a little, show to show, so it never gets stale.” 
HDRnB is slated to hit the studio in September to put the finishing touches on “Vital Signs II,” an album of material they had left over from the previous sessions but didn’t have room for on the first CD. Beyond that, Douglas is still smiling over the Heavy Metal Horns’ 25th Anniversary show that was staged in February as part of Johnny D’s last string of shows. 
“That was a wonderful reunion for all of us,” said Douglas. “I had not seen four of those guys for 20 years, but when we got together and started playing, it was right in the pocket. It was a huge lesson in music and experience; when you have that connection with people it is always there. That club was jammed that night, and it became quite an emotional evening for us all. We’re all getting emails and everything begging us for another reunion, so we are going to try to do another one in November at the Cabot Theater in Beverly.” 


About Us
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.metrowestdailynews.com/storyimage/WL/20160811/ENTERTAINMENT/160818837/AR/0/AR-160818837.jpg</main_image>
</document>
