<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Broken Record: Heat, Humidity, Storms... - WFSB 3 Connecticut</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wfsb.com/story/32741943/broken-record-heat-humidity-storms</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Broken Record: Heat, Humidity, Storms... - WFSB 3 Connecticut Member Center: Broken Record: Heat, Humidity, Storms... Posted: HARTFORD, CT (WFSB) - 
LATE EVENING UPDATE: 
As of 11pm, NO alerts were in effect in the state pertaining to severe weather, or flooding. While a bit more rain will fall overnight (and you may hear a rumble of thunder), the atmosphere is stabilizing a bit and the intensity of what remains will diminish. 
Tomorrow, we&apos;ll do it all over again with more heat, humidity and thunderstorms. Scot Haney will have the very latest on Eyewitness News starting at 430am! 
Meteorologist Mark Dixon 

WHAT A THURSDAY! 
After a very warm and muggy start to the day, one storm developed over south-central Connecticut and moved toward the Rhode Island border in the mid-morning hours. THEN, during the afternoon with the peak of the daytime heating, numerous thunderstorms broke out across the central part of the state producing very heavy rain, a tremendous amount of lightning and gusty wind. Several Severe Thunderstorm Warnings were issued. Some towns were even hit with multiple rounds of intense thunderstorm activity. The rain was so heavy, with the slow moving nature of the storms, Flood Advisories and Flash Flood Warnings were issued for the areas hardest hit. There were many parts of the state that did not pick up on much needed rain. 
While we have received NUMEROUS pictures from Manchester, South Windsor, Vernon, and Tolland of what we will call a ‘lowering’ from the cloud base, no tornadoes touched down today in Connecticut. At times there was some weak rotation aloft indicated by Doppler radar, but it never reached the ground, to our knowledge. 
Temperature-wise, prior to the arrival of rain… and in those spots that didn’t receive any at all, temperatures hit 90 or higher; factoring in the high humidity (dew point values in the mid-70s for many, in fact 81 was achieved in Willimantic), the heat index went up to between 105 and 110! 
THIS EVENING AND TONIGHT… 
Isolated thunderstorms will continue through the evening hours. Much like last night, areas of dense fog could be problematic for the morning commute, especially in the areas that received heavy rain today. Overnight it will be warm and muggy with lows only in the mid-70s by daybreak. 
FRIDAY… 
The nasty combination of high heat and high humidity will continue as we close out the week tomorrow. In fact, the National Weather Service has already issued a Heat Advisory for much of the state. Temperatures will again soar into the 90s tomorrow afternoon, but the heat index will reach 100-110 degrees. This is what it will feel like to you and your pets! 
Scattered showers and thunderstorms will develop during the afternoon and some of these storms will produce torrential downpours and perhaps gusty wind. Like today, frequent lightning will also be likely. 
Showers and storms will gradually dissipate tomorrow night and it will be another very uncomfortable night with low temperatures in the 70s. 
THIS WEEKEND, THE HEAT CONTINUES… 
Saturday and Sunday, we expect more of the same: a dangerous combo of heat and humidity with an ongoing threat for thunderstorms (especially during the afternoon/evening hours). In fact, an Excessive Heat Watch has already been posted for part of the state throughout the weekend! 
Temperatures should reach the middle to perhaps upper 90s (with enough sunshine) and the heat index will reach triple digits. Thunderstorms will threaten will torrential downpours and gusty wind each afternoon and evening. 
A cold front will slide southward across Southern New England as we close out the weekend. The front will trigger another round of showers and storms, some of which could pack a pretty good punch. 
NEXT WEEK… 
By Monday, in the wake of the front, the humidity drops a bit… but it will still be hot. We expect temperatures to top 90 degrees Monday afternoon and we may have a shot at 90 degrees on Tuesday as well. The arrival of showers and thunderstorms on Wednesday should keep temperatures in the 80s. 

90° TALLY 
We have now had 24 days this year with a high temperature of at least 90 degrees at Bradley International Airport. By the time this next heat wave ends, the tally could grow to 28 days, perhaps 29 days. The record for a year is 38 days set in 1983. 
AUGUST NORMALS AND EXTREMES… 
While August can be a very hot month, temperatures do trend downward. The normal (or average) high on August 1 st is 85 degrees, but by the 31 st it dips to 80 degrees. Low temperatures follow and similar path. The normal low on the 1 st is 63 degrees then it drops to 58 degrees by the 31 st . We also lose 1 hour and 15 minutes of daylight over the course of August’s 31 days. 
The hottest temperature on record this month is 102 degrees, set on August 9 th in 2002. The record low is 36 degrees, set on August 31 st in 1965. 
Average rainfall in August is 3.93”, but 21.87” of rain fell in August of 1955 thanks to a one two punch from Tropical Storm Connie and Tropical Storm Diane! August 1955 was by far the all-time wettest month on record. 
Meteorologist Mark Dixon 
RECAP OF WEDNESDAY’S NORTH HAVEN TORNADO 
A short lived tornado touched down in the Montowese section of North Haven around or just before 1:30 on the 10 th of August. Channel 3 received video confirmation of the tornado and there were strong indications of severe thunderstorm winds on Doppler radar. We also received photographs of trees uprooted and snapped. Power lines were downed and several homes were damaged. The National Weather Service out of Upton, New York has also confirmed a tornado touched down in North Haven. It was an EF-0 tornado with wind up to 70 mph. The path width was 50 yards and it was on the ground for 2.16 miles. 
“Copyright 2016 WFSB (Meredith Corporation). All rights reserved” Technical Discussion Broken Record: Heat, Humidity, Storms... More&gt;&gt; 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wfsb.com/story/32741943/broken-record-heat-humidity-storms</post_url>
<post_date>20160811</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Mark Dixon</username>
<post>
Broken Record: Heat, Humidity, Storms... - WFSB 3 Connecticut Member Center: Broken Record: Heat, Humidity, Storms... Posted: HARTFORD, CT (WFSB) - 
LATE EVENING UPDATE: 
As of 11pm, NO alerts were in effect in the state pertaining to severe weather, or flooding. While a bit more rain will fall overnight (and you may hear a rumble of thunder), the atmosphere is stabilizing a bit and the intensity of what remains will diminish. 
Tomorrow, we&apos;ll do it all over again with more heat, humidity and thunderstorms. Scot Haney will have the very latest on Eyewitness News starting at 430am! 
Meteorologist Mark Dixon 

WHAT A THURSDAY! 
After a very warm and muggy start to the day, one storm developed over south-central Connecticut and moved toward the Rhode Island border in the mid-morning hours. THEN, during the afternoon with the peak of the daytime heating, numerous thunderstorms broke out across the central part of the state producing very heavy rain, a tremendous amount of lightning and gusty wind. Several Severe Thunderstorm Warnings were issued. Some towns were even hit with multiple rounds of intense thunderstorm activity. The rain was so heavy, with the slow moving nature of the storms, Flood Advisories and Flash Flood Warnings were issued for the areas hardest hit. There were many parts of the state that did not pick up on much needed rain. 
While we have received NUMEROUS pictures from Manchester, South Windsor, Vernon, and Tolland of what we will call a ‘lowering’ from the cloud base, no tornadoes touched down today in Connecticut. At times there was some weak rotation aloft indicated by Doppler radar, but it never reached the ground, to our knowledge. 
Temperature-wise, prior to the arrival of rain… and in those spots that didn’t receive any at all, temperatures hit 90 or higher; factoring in the high humidity (dew point values in the mid-70s for many, in fact 81 was achieved in Willimantic), the heat index went up to between 105 and 110! 
THIS EVENING AND TONIGHT… 
Isolated thunderstorms will continue through the evening hours. Much like last night, areas of dense fog could be problematic for the morning commute, especially in the areas that received heavy rain today. Overnight it will be warm and muggy with lows only in the mid-70s by daybreak. 
FRIDAY… 
The nasty combination of high heat and high humidity will continue as we close out the week tomorrow. In fact, the National Weather Service has already issued a Heat Advisory for much of the state. Temperatures will again soar into the 90s tomorrow afternoon, but the heat index will reach 100-110 degrees. This is what it will feel like to you and your pets! 
Scattered showers and thunderstorms will develop during the afternoon and some of these storms will produce torrential downpours and perhaps gusty wind. Like today, frequent lightning will also be likely. 
Showers and storms will gradually dissipate tomorrow night and it will be another very uncomfortable night with low temperatures in the 70s. 
THIS WEEKEND, THE HEAT CONTINUES… 
Saturday and Sunday, we expect more of the same: a dangerous combo of heat and humidity with an ongoing threat for thunderstorms (especially during the afternoon/evening hours). In fact, an Excessive Heat Watch has already been posted for part of the state throughout the weekend! 
Temperatures should reach the middle to perhaps upper 90s (with enough sunshine) and the heat index will reach triple digits. Thunderstorms will threaten will torrential downpours and gusty wind each afternoon and evening. 
A cold front will slide southward across Southern New England as we close out the weekend. The front will trigger another round of showers and storms, some of which could pack a pretty good punch. 
NEXT WEEK… 
By Monday, in the wake of the front, the humidity drops a bit… but it will still be hot. We expect temperatures to top 90 degrees Monday afternoon and we may have a shot at 90 degrees on Tuesday as well. The arrival of showers and thunderstorms on Wednesday should keep temperatures in the 80s. 

90° TALLY 
We have now had 24 days this year with a high temperature of at least 90 degrees at Bradley International Airport. By the time this next heat wave ends, the tally could grow to 28 days, perhaps 29 days. The record for a year is 38 days set in 1983. 
AUGUST NORMALS AND EXTREMES… 
While August can be a very hot month, temperatures do trend downward. The normal (or average) high on August 1 st is 85 degrees, but by the 31 st it dips to 80 degrees. Low temperatures follow and similar path. The normal low on the 1 st is 63 degrees then it drops to 58 degrees by the 31 st . We also lose 1 hour and 15 minutes of daylight over the course of August’s 31 days. 
The hottest temperature on record this month is 102 degrees, set on August 9 th in 2002. The record low is 36 degrees, set on August 31 st in 1965. 
Average rainfall in August is 3.93”, but 21.87” of rain fell in August of 1955 thanks to a one two punch from Tropical Storm Connie and Tropical Storm Diane! August 1955 was by far the all-time wettest month on record. 
Meteorologist Mark Dixon 
RECAP OF WEDNESDAY’S NORTH HAVEN TORNADO 
A short lived tornado touched down in the Montowese section of North Haven around or just before 1:30 on the 10 th of August. Channel 3 received video confirmation of the tornado and there were strong indications of severe thunderstorm winds on Doppler radar. We also received photographs of trees uprooted and snapped. Power lines were downed and several homes were damaged. The National Weather Service out of Upton, New York has also confirmed a tornado touched down in North Haven. It was an EF-0 tornado with wind up to 70 mph. The path width was 50 yards and it was on the ground for 2.16 miles. 
“Copyright 2016 WFSB (Meredith Corporation). All rights reserved” Technical Discussion Broken Record: Heat, Humidity, Storms... More&gt;&gt; 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://wfsb.images.worldnow.com/images/11308653_G.jpg</main_image>
</document>
