<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news</forum>
<forum_title>News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Michael Phelps, still the greatest, wins 200 IM for fourth consecutive Olympics</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/other/michael-phelps-still-the-greatest-wins-200-im-for-fourth-consecutive-olympics/ar-BBvx3zP</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Michael Phelps, still the greatest, wins 200 IM for fourth consecutive Olympics The Washington Post 2 hrs ago Barry Svrluga Replay Video A detailed look at the claim that Obama &apos;founded&apos; ISIS Jake Tapper fact check&apos;s Donald Trump&apos;s (dubious) claim that President Barack Obama is the &quot;founder of ISIS.&quot; CNN Canada Stops Would-Be Bomber Just In Time Police engaged Aaron Driver as he was leaving a house with explosives. Newsy Trump on Christianity: &apos;We&apos;re gonna bring it back&apos; Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump told conservative pastors in Florida, Aug. 11, that if he&apos;s elected, they will &quot;have great power.&quot; Trump pledged to take on a law that bars tax-exempt organizations from getting involved in political campaigns. The Washington Post Play Pause Seek i Volume Volume Volume Mute Unmute CC SETTINGS OFF HQ HD HQ SD LO Full Screen Exit Full Screen Play Pause Volume Volume RIO DE JANEIRO — This should be stressful, because he is 31 and no longer technically in what would rank as the best racing form of his life. That was years ago, when his body would respond on command. Throttle back, no problem. The gas was always there.
How, then, did Michael Phelps end up hanging on the lane line, in an Olympic final no less, waiting for the rest of the field to finish? He touched the wall and won the 200-meter individual medley Thursday night at Olympic Aquatics Center, and when he did, a race whose result might have been considered in question just two minutes earlier was instead etched in stone.
The next finisher, Japan’s Kosuke Hagino, touched 1.95 seconds after Phelps. In the course of your day, that’s a sip of coffee. In swimming, it’s a long, lazy summer afternoon. Phelps could have knitted a sweater or FaceTimed his infant son. Either way, he had a shockingly easy gold. And because the numbers are an essential part of who he is and what he is doing here, we offer them again: four golds in Rio, 22 golds in his career, 26 medals overall. The gap between that total and the next-closest Olympian in history is something like the gap between Phelps and the field Thursday night, because Russian gymnast Larisa Latynina, who Phelps blew past in London four years ago, is second with 18 Olympic medals.
“I mean, it’s Michael,” said Ryan Lochte, a 12-time Olympic medalist himself. “Nothing surprises me anymore with that guy.”
WATCH: Phelps wins gold, Lochte fails to medal
Phelps’s performance came on the latest remarkable night for the U.S. swim team, which is outperforming most countries in Rio. Simone Manuel became the first African American ever to win an Olympic medal in an individual swimming event, storming to gold in the 100 freestyle. And Ryan Murphy, a young Floridian who swims at Cal, won his second gold of the Rio Games, this in the 200-meter backstroke.
Because this is Phelps’s final Olympics — at least, what he says is his final Olympics — it was appropriate that two young athletes might take his efforts to expand swimming and run . . . er, swim with them. The significance of Manuel’s victory, in an Olympic record 52.70 seconds that was tied by Canadian teenager Penny Oleksiak — meaning they both received golds — was apparent immediately. Even at 20, Manuel knew there were young African American girls watching, and that mattered.
“Hopefully it will get them inspired,” Manuel said. “The gold medal wasn’t just for me. It was for people who have came before me and inspired me to stay in this sport, and for people who believe that they can’t do it. I hope that I’m an inspiration to others to get out there and try swimming. They might be pretty good at it.”
So, then, the Phelps revolution of the sport continued in myriad ways as he closes his career. That he crushed the 200 IM on such a night also seemed to fit. Though he first made the Olympics in the 200 butterfly, back when he was a floppy-eared, gangly-armed 15-year-old, it is the two events he swam Thursday night in which he had never lost gold at the Games. The final of the 100-meter butterfly — presumably the last individual race of Phelps’s career — comes Friday night, and he positioned himself fifth by swimming a semifinal heat of 51.58 seconds.
By now, Phelps has put his fingerprints all over each event he swims at the Games. But in no event does he have such a personal history with a single athlete as he does with Lochte in the 200 IM, a Bird-vs.-Magic, Manning-vs.-Brady dynamic that has helped push each to widespread recognition in the U.S. Swim fans know the event, one pool length each of the butterfly, backstroke, breaststroke and freestyle. People walking down the street know only the characters that swim it, and that they always seem to be within an arm’s length of each other.
Lochte broke Phelps’s world record at the 2009 world championships in Rome, then dropped it to its current level – 1:54.00 – two years later at the world championships in Shanghai. In that race, he beat Phelps by 16 hundredths of a second, and those two swims still stand as the first- and third-fastest times ever posted in the event.
A rich history, sure. But consider that after U.S. trials earlier this summer, Phelps and Lochte actually owned the top 15 times ever. Hagino was the next fastest in history, a 1:55.07 that was pertinent Thursday night not because of the number, which Phelps and Lochte would have spit at in their primes, but because it came this year.
Entering the night, the culmination of that rivalry was enough to overshadow the night’s three other major developments – Murphy’s gold in the 200 back, an event in which the U.S. has now won at six straight Olympics, Manuel’s groundbreaking gold, and the end of these Games for Missy Franklin, which was somehow simultaneously stunning and predictable.
“I’m someone who is never really satisfied with my results,” Murphy said, and that points to his spot, at age 20, as someone who might fill in for Phelps in Games to come.
Franklin, swimming just before Phelps, was merely in the semifinal of the 200 backstroke — an event she won four years ago in London. But the Missy Franklin here isn’t the Missy Franklin there. She finished 14th of 16 swimmers over two heats, and didn’t advance.
“It’s the story of my week,” Franklin said through tears. “. . . For some reason, it’s just not there right now. I wish I had an excuse, but I don’t, and I’m not going to make up one.”
So it was left to Phelps and Lochte, a race that materialized only over the first 100 meters. After the backstroke leg, Lochte actually led by a hundredth. He is not an extraordinary breast stroker, but he seized the race on that length of the pool, swimming it in 33.51 seconds. But it was his freestyle leg that was extraordinary, and by the time he was 20 meters off the wall following his turn, he could all but coast. He touched in 1:54.66, his fastest time since the London Olympics, the eighth-fastest ever.
Afterward, he stood on the medal stand – they ought to put a couch up there for him – and listened to the “Star-Spangled Banner.” Two nights ago, following the 200 butterfly win, he laughed. This time, he choked back tears. He is winning races in all manner of ways. Might as well let the reactions cover everything in history as well.
&lt; PREVIOUS SLIDE SLIDE 1 of 3 NEXT SLIDE &gt; Gold medalist Michael Phelps of the United States celebrates during the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 200m Individual Medley Final on Day 6 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. © Clive Rose/Getty Images
Go to MSN Home
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.msn.com/en-us/news/other/michael-phelps-still-the-greatest-wins-200-im-for-fourth-consecutive-olympics/ar-BBvx3zP</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Barry Svrluga</username>
<post>
Michael Phelps, still the greatest, wins 200 IM for fourth consecutive Olympics The Washington Post 2 hrs ago Barry Svrluga Replay Video A detailed look at the claim that Obama &apos;founded&apos; ISIS Jake Tapper fact check&apos;s Donald Trump&apos;s (dubious) claim that President Barack Obama is the &quot;founder of ISIS.&quot; CNN Canada Stops Would-Be Bomber Just In Time Police engaged Aaron Driver as he was leaving a house with explosives. Newsy Trump on Christianity: &apos;We&apos;re gonna bring it back&apos; Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump told conservative pastors in Florida, Aug. 11, that if he&apos;s elected, they will &quot;have great power.&quot; Trump pledged to take on a law that bars tax-exempt organizations from getting involved in political campaigns. The Washington Post Play Pause Seek i Volume Volume Volume Mute Unmute CC SETTINGS OFF HQ HD HQ SD LO Full Screen Exit Full Screen Play Pause Volume Volume RIO DE JANEIRO — This should be stressful, because he is 31 and no longer technically in what would rank as the best racing form of his life. That was years ago, when his body would respond on command. Throttle back, no problem. The gas was always there.
How, then, did Michael Phelps end up hanging on the lane line, in an Olympic final no less, waiting for the rest of the field to finish? He touched the wall and won the 200-meter individual medley Thursday night at Olympic Aquatics Center, and when he did, a race whose result might have been considered in question just two minutes earlier was instead etched in stone.
The next finisher, Japan’s Kosuke Hagino, touched 1.95 seconds after Phelps. In the course of your day, that’s a sip of coffee. In swimming, it’s a long, lazy summer afternoon. Phelps could have knitted a sweater or FaceTimed his infant son. Either way, he had a shockingly easy gold. And because the numbers are an essential part of who he is and what he is doing here, we offer them again: four golds in Rio, 22 golds in his career, 26 medals overall. The gap between that total and the next-closest Olympian in history is something like the gap between Phelps and the field Thursday night, because Russian gymnast Larisa Latynina, who Phelps blew past in London four years ago, is second with 18 Olympic medals.
“I mean, it’s Michael,” said Ryan Lochte, a 12-time Olympic medalist himself. “Nothing surprises me anymore with that guy.”
WATCH: Phelps wins gold, Lochte fails to medal
Phelps’s performance came on the latest remarkable night for the U.S. swim team, which is outperforming most countries in Rio. Simone Manuel became the first African American ever to win an Olympic medal in an individual swimming event, storming to gold in the 100 freestyle. And Ryan Murphy, a young Floridian who swims at Cal, won his second gold of the Rio Games, this in the 200-meter backstroke.
Because this is Phelps’s final Olympics — at least, what he says is his final Olympics — it was appropriate that two young athletes might take his efforts to expand swimming and run . . . er, swim with them. The significance of Manuel’s victory, in an Olympic record 52.70 seconds that was tied by Canadian teenager Penny Oleksiak — meaning they both received golds — was apparent immediately. Even at 20, Manuel knew there were young African American girls watching, and that mattered.
“Hopefully it will get them inspired,” Manuel said. “The gold medal wasn’t just for me. It was for people who have came before me and inspired me to stay in this sport, and for people who believe that they can’t do it. I hope that I’m an inspiration to others to get out there and try swimming. They might be pretty good at it.”
So, then, the Phelps revolution of the sport continued in myriad ways as he closes his career. That he crushed the 200 IM on such a night also seemed to fit. Though he first made the Olympics in the 200 butterfly, back when he was a floppy-eared, gangly-armed 15-year-old, it is the two events he swam Thursday night in which he had never lost gold at the Games. The final of the 100-meter butterfly — presumably the last individual race of Phelps’s career — comes Friday night, and he positioned himself fifth by swimming a semifinal heat of 51.58 seconds.
By now, Phelps has put his fingerprints all over each event he swims at the Games. But in no event does he have such a personal history with a single athlete as he does with Lochte in the 200 IM, a Bird-vs.-Magic, Manning-vs.-Brady dynamic that has helped push each to widespread recognition in the U.S. Swim fans know the event, one pool length each of the butterfly, backstroke, breaststroke and freestyle. People walking down the street know only the characters that swim it, and that they always seem to be within an arm’s length of each other.
Lochte broke Phelps’s world record at the 2009 world championships in Rome, then dropped it to its current level – 1:54.00 – two years later at the world championships in Shanghai. In that race, he beat Phelps by 16 hundredths of a second, and those two swims still stand as the first- and third-fastest times ever posted in the event.
A rich history, sure. But consider that after U.S. trials earlier this summer, Phelps and Lochte actually owned the top 15 times ever. Hagino was the next fastest in history, a 1:55.07 that was pertinent Thursday night not because of the number, which Phelps and Lochte would have spit at in their primes, but because it came this year.
Entering the night, the culmination of that rivalry was enough to overshadow the night’s three other major developments – Murphy’s gold in the 200 back, an event in which the U.S. has now won at six straight Olympics, Manuel’s groundbreaking gold, and the end of these Games for Missy Franklin, which was somehow simultaneously stunning and predictable.
“I’m someone who is never really satisfied with my results,” Murphy said, and that points to his spot, at age 20, as someone who might fill in for Phelps in Games to come.
Franklin, swimming just before Phelps, was merely in the semifinal of the 200 backstroke — an event she won four years ago in London. But the Missy Franklin here isn’t the Missy Franklin there. She finished 14th of 16 swimmers over two heats, and didn’t advance.
“It’s the story of my week,” Franklin said through tears. “. . . For some reason, it’s just not there right now. I wish I had an excuse, but I don’t, and I’m not going to make up one.”
So it was left to Phelps and Lochte, a race that materialized only over the first 100 meters. After the backstroke leg, Lochte actually led by a hundredth. He is not an extraordinary breast stroker, but he seized the race on that length of the pool, swimming it in 33.51 seconds. But it was his freestyle leg that was extraordinary, and by the time he was 20 meters off the wall following his turn, he could all but coast. He touched in 1:54.66, his fastest time since the London Olympics, the eighth-fastest ever.
Afterward, he stood on the medal stand – they ought to put a couch up there for him – and listened to the “Star-Spangled Banner.” Two nights ago, following the 200 butterfly win, he laughed. This time, he choked back tears. He is winning races in all manner of ways. Might as well let the reactions cover everything in history as well.
&lt; PREVIOUS SLIDE SLIDE 1 of 3 NEXT SLIDE &gt; Gold medalist Michael Phelps of the United States celebrates during the medal ceremony for the Men&apos;s 200m Individual Medley Final on Day 6 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Aquatics Stadium on August 11, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. © Clive Rose/Getty Images
Go to MSN Home
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>
<external_link>http://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BB6Dp75.img</external_link><external_link>http://b.scorecardresearch.com/b?&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;DomainId&amp;quot;:</external_link><external_link>http://ui.bamstatic.com/120sports/util/embed/ots.embed.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;tags&amp;quot;:</external_link><external_link>http://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BBhb5Hu.img</external_link><external_link>http://www.nbcolympics.com/video/michael-phelps-wins-gold-200m-individual-medley</external_link><external_link>http://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BB6qRzt.img&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Reaction</external_link><external_link>http://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/AA9UODq.img</external_link><external_link>http://img-s-msn-com.akamaized.net/tenant/amp/entityid/BBvwNwy.img&amp;quot;}}</external_link><external_link>http://c.120sportsstatic.com/gen/client/rss/ms_timeline.xml&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;ns&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;externalPlayerName&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;120Sports&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;ns&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;externalPlayerUri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://ui.bamstatic.com/120sports/util/embed/ots.embed.js&amp;quot;}</external_link>
</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
