<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://lankanewsweb.net/itemlist?format=feed&amp;type=atom</forum>
<forum_title>Lanka News Web</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mahasweta Devi: a writer of blood, protest and grief</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://lankanewsweb.net/featured/item/3865-mahasweta-devi-a-writer-of-blood-protest-and-grief</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Mahasweta Devi: a writer of blood, protest and grief - Aug 12, 2016 Twitter 
Mhasweta Devi, a Bengali writer who died on July 28th, was one of independent India’s most moving and important writers, admired as much for her fiction as for being a fearless chronicler of social injustice. Goaded by an inner voice—which she referred to as “the person sitting within”—she wrote over 100 novellas and short stories peopled by the poorest Indians. Her subjects were the cycle rickshaw puller and the bricklayer working on boiling city streets, farmers threatened by factories, peasant communist guerrillas wielding sickles against the State and impoverished wet nurses hired out to suckle wealthy babies. Above all, Adivasis were her great love: India’s indigenous tribal communities whose forest homelands are increasingly targeted by mining consortiums. For these “invisible” Indians, she said, independence was a chimera. 
Born in Dhaka in 1926, Mahasweta Devi came from impeccable protest stock: her father was a poet, her mother a social worker and her uncle the eminent arthouse film-maker Ritwick Ghatak. She studied at Shantiniketan, the university established by the great poet Rabindranath Tagore. She saw the persistence of hunger in a democracy as unforgiveable and, though her activism was forged by communism, she was no blind party loyalist. She railed at the Marxist chief minister of West Bengal when he succumbed to demands by extremist mullahs that Taslima Nasreen, a Bangladeshi writer, leave Kolkata. 
Of all the eclectic characters she created, two of her most unforgettable were women. The first was the dignified, upper class Sujata Chatterjee in “Mother of 1084”. The novel follows Chatterjee as she grieves the death of her son, a political Naxalite guerrilla who has been beaten to death in police custody, identified as corpse No. 1084. Filtered through Chatterjee’s anguished consciousness, she comes to an understanding that her son’s radicalisation is rooted as much in his hatred of his loathsome father as of the iniquitous system. The story ends with her falling to the ground with a cosmic cry of pain that “smelt of blood, protest, grief”. 
The other woman is Draupadi, a young tribal guerrilla widowed by the police then gang-raped by them. In the “Mahabharata”, a Sanskrit epic, Draupadi’s honour is saved by the intervention of Lord Krishna who clothes her in an infinite sari. Mahasweta Devi’s Draupadi refuses to cover herself. Instead, she scorns her torn garment and weaponises her nakedness. She confronts the police chief who has ordered her rape: “Thigh and pubic hair matted with dry blood. Two breasts, two wounds.” Defiantly, she butts him with her bloodied breasts and, for the first time, the chief “is afraid to stand before an unarmed target, terribly afraid”. Of all the stories Mahasweta Devi wrote, “Draupadi”, with its raw moral power, is one for the ages. 
When she wasn’t writing, reading, protesting or editing her grassroots newspaper, Mahasweta Devi walked, like Gandhi, for mile on indefatigable mile through the villages of Bengal and the forests of central and eastern India. She lived with different tribes—observing their “scientific and sophisticated” methods of cooking—and gathering research for her fiction and activism. But she was never happier than when behind her desk in her rented flat in Kolkata. She flung herself into words, “writing, writing, writing”, sometimes 18 hours a day, through heartbreak, injury, loneliness and scathing reviews. 
Once she had the seed of a story in her head, she did her research and wrote it out in a dead heat. “Mother of 1084” was written over two-and-a-half days. Three years later, in 1976, “Draupadi” erupted in a night. After her works were written, she barely revisited them—which often led to clumsy lines such as: “It was all like a festering, malignant cancer.” But what her writing lacked in polish it made up for in power. And it wasn’t all dark rage and injustice; her children’s stories ripple with nuance. One such tale, “Why Why Girl”, features a chatterbox heroine named Moyna, who drives her family mad with a deluge of questions. “Why can’t I catch a cobra? Why can’t fish talk?” And then with sudden, swift poignancy, “Why can’t we eat rice twice a day?” Even her most passionate fictions are illuminated with streaks of sardonic humour: in “Draupadi” opaque “government procedures” are compared to the enigmatic Michelangelo “Antonioni’s early films”. 
Mahasweta Devi’s view of her country was enshrined in her keynote speech at the Frankfurt Book Fair in 2006. Embracing the giant contradictions that are woven into the tapestry called India, she quoted from Tagore, and said that Rabindrasangeet and rap, khadi saris and miniskirts, the multiplex and maharishi are all India. “Somewhere dark, somewhere light, somewhere saffron, somewhere as green as the fields of new paddy, somewhere flecked with blood, somewhere washed cool by the waters of a Himalayan spring…Somewhere the cloth frays. Somewhere the threads tear. But still it holds. Still. It holds.” Mahasweta Devi could have been referring to her own compelling works.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://lankanewsweb.net/featured/item/3865-mahasweta-devi-a-writer-of-blood-protest-and-grief</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0151</post_time>
<username>esha (eshalondon@gmail.com)</username>
<post>
Mahasweta Devi: a writer of blood, protest and grief - Aug 12, 2016 Twitter 
Mhasweta Devi, a Bengali writer who died on July 28th, was one of independent India’s most moving and important writers, admired as much for her fiction as for being a fearless chronicler of social injustice. Goaded by an inner voice—which she referred to as “the person sitting within”—she wrote over 100 novellas and short stories peopled by the poorest Indians. Her subjects were the cycle rickshaw puller and the bricklayer working on boiling city streets, farmers threatened by factories, peasant communist guerrillas wielding sickles against the State and impoverished wet nurses hired out to suckle wealthy babies. Above all, Adivasis were her great love: India’s indigenous tribal communities whose forest homelands are increasingly targeted by mining consortiums. For these “invisible” Indians, she said, independence was a chimera. 
Born in Dhaka in 1926, Mahasweta Devi came from impeccable protest stock: her father was a poet, her mother a social worker and her uncle the eminent arthouse film-maker Ritwick Ghatak. She studied at Shantiniketan, the university established by the great poet Rabindranath Tagore. She saw the persistence of hunger in a democracy as unforgiveable and, though her activism was forged by communism, she was no blind party loyalist. She railed at the Marxist chief minister of West Bengal when he succumbed to demands by extremist mullahs that Taslima Nasreen, a Bangladeshi writer, leave Kolkata. 
Of all the eclectic characters she created, two of her most unforgettable were women. The first was the dignified, upper class Sujata Chatterjee in “Mother of 1084”. The novel follows Chatterjee as she grieves the death of her son, a political Naxalite guerrilla who has been beaten to death in police custody, identified as corpse No. 1084. Filtered through Chatterjee’s anguished consciousness, she comes to an understanding that her son’s radicalisation is rooted as much in his hatred of his loathsome father as of the iniquitous system. The story ends with her falling to the ground with a cosmic cry of pain that “smelt of blood, protest, grief”. 
The other woman is Draupadi, a young tribal guerrilla widowed by the police then gang-raped by them. In the “Mahabharata”, a Sanskrit epic, Draupadi’s honour is saved by the intervention of Lord Krishna who clothes her in an infinite sari. Mahasweta Devi’s Draupadi refuses to cover herself. Instead, she scorns her torn garment and weaponises her nakedness. She confronts the police chief who has ordered her rape: “Thigh and pubic hair matted with dry blood. Two breasts, two wounds.” Defiantly, she butts him with her bloodied breasts and, for the first time, the chief “is afraid to stand before an unarmed target, terribly afraid”. Of all the stories Mahasweta Devi wrote, “Draupadi”, with its raw moral power, is one for the ages. 
When she wasn’t writing, reading, protesting or editing her grassroots newspaper, Mahasweta Devi walked, like Gandhi, for mile on indefatigable mile through the villages of Bengal and the forests of central and eastern India. She lived with different tribes—observing their “scientific and sophisticated” methods of cooking—and gathering research for her fiction and activism. But she was never happier than when behind her desk in her rented flat in Kolkata. She flung herself into words, “writing, writing, writing”, sometimes 18 hours a day, through heartbreak, injury, loneliness and scathing reviews. 
Once she had the seed of a story in her head, she did her research and wrote it out in a dead heat. “Mother of 1084” was written over two-and-a-half days. Three years later, in 1976, “Draupadi” erupted in a night. After her works were written, she barely revisited them—which often led to clumsy lines such as: “It was all like a festering, malignant cancer.” But what her writing lacked in polish it made up for in power. And it wasn’t all dark rage and injustice; her children’s stories ripple with nuance. One such tale, “Why Why Girl”, features a chatterbox heroine named Moyna, who drives her family mad with a deluge of questions. “Why can’t I catch a cobra? Why can’t fish talk?” And then with sudden, swift poignancy, “Why can’t we eat rice twice a day?” Even her most passionate fictions are illuminated with streaks of sardonic humour: in “Draupadi” opaque “government procedures” are compared to the enigmatic Michelangelo “Antonioni’s early films”. 
Mahasweta Devi’s view of her country was enshrined in her keynote speech at the Frankfurt Book Fair in 2006. Embracing the giant contradictions that are woven into the tapestry called India, she quoted from Tagore, and said that Rabindrasangeet and rap, khadi saris and miniskirts, the multiplex and maharishi are all India. “Somewhere dark, somewhere light, somewhere saffron, somewhere as green as the fields of new paddy, somewhere flecked with blood, somewhere washed cool by the waters of a Himalayan spring…Somewhere the cloth frays. Somewhere the threads tear. But still it holds. Still. It holds.” Mahasweta Devi could have been referring to her own compelling works.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://lankanewsweb.net/media/k2/items/cache/f8bcd4658f70bd8a859b57787d226a7b_M.jpg</main_image>
</document>
