<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>New details released on case against 5 alleged mobsters | WWLP.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/new-details-released-on-case-against-5-alleged-mobsters/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
New details released on case against 5 alleged mobsters The detention hearing continues Friday morning August 11, 2016, 11:07 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) U.S. District Court in Springfield is seen here in a WWLP file image. 
SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (WWLP) – Five alleged members of the Genovese crime family were in federal court in Springfield, Thursday afternoon, to find out whether they will get bail. After two plus hours in the courtroom, the judge suspended the bail, or detention hearing, until Friday. 
The men who were arrested a week ago are Ralph Santaniello, Frank Depergola, Johnny Calabrese, Richie Valentini and Gerald Daniele. It was part of a sweep of alleged mobsters along the entire East Coast. 
5 alleged organized crime figures arrested in Springfield 
Ralph Santaniello and Johnny Calabrese are accused of threatening the owner of a towing company at his home in Hampden and attempting to extort the owner for $50,000; money he hadn’t paid since former mob boss Al Bruno was killed. 
Court documents say that they told the victim they would cut his head off and bury him in the woods if he didn’t pay. Documents say the tow company owner had contracts with the city and Santaniello allegedly told him he can “take care of the mayor.” 
Valentini and Calabrese are alleged to have collected $20,000 from the victim in 2013. 
A few weeks later, at a meeting at the Starbucks in Longmeadow, Depergola, Santaniello and Calabrese told the victim that it was not a shakedown and they were trying to help him get a contract for the Massachusetts Turnpike. That conversation was recorded. 
The second victim owed gambling debts, and its alleged that Daniele threatened him at his workplace. 
The feds also say that Depergola and Santaniello gave a $30,000 extortionate loan to another victim in New York City with 78% interest on it acting on the orders of a Genovese Family Captain. 
22News wasn’t allowed to take video inside the federal court, but More than 30 family and friends of the defendants packed the courtroom. 
The Government showed several wire taps, including audio and video. Jared Olanoff, the attorney for Richard Valentini, told 22News those videos will help his client’s case to be released on Friday. “He really didn’t speak or say anything of any significance, he was simply there. And as I said on one occasion out of several there’s really no evidence that there was anything more than that.” 
The detention hearing continues Friday morning at 9:00 a.m., and 22News will be here. Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.50</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://wwlp.com/2016/08/11/new-details-released-on-case-against-5-alleged-mobsters/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Ryan Walsh</username>
<post>
New details released on case against 5 alleged mobsters The detention hearing continues Friday morning August 11, 2016, 11:07 pm Updated: Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) U.S. District Court in Springfield is seen here in a WWLP file image. 
SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (WWLP) – Five alleged members of the Genovese crime family were in federal court in Springfield, Thursday afternoon, to find out whether they will get bail. After two plus hours in the courtroom, the judge suspended the bail, or detention hearing, until Friday. 
The men who were arrested a week ago are Ralph Santaniello, Frank Depergola, Johnny Calabrese, Richie Valentini and Gerald Daniele. It was part of a sweep of alleged mobsters along the entire East Coast. 
5 alleged organized crime figures arrested in Springfield 
Ralph Santaniello and Johnny Calabrese are accused of threatening the owner of a towing company at his home in Hampden and attempting to extort the owner for $50,000; money he hadn’t paid since former mob boss Al Bruno was killed. 
Court documents say that they told the victim they would cut his head off and bury him in the woods if he didn’t pay. Documents say the tow company owner had contracts with the city and Santaniello allegedly told him he can “take care of the mayor.” 
Valentini and Calabrese are alleged to have collected $20,000 from the victim in 2013. 
A few weeks later, at a meeting at the Starbucks in Longmeadow, Depergola, Santaniello and Calabrese told the victim that it was not a shakedown and they were trying to help him get a contract for the Massachusetts Turnpike. That conversation was recorded. 
The second victim owed gambling debts, and its alleged that Daniele threatened him at his workplace. 
The feds also say that Depergola and Santaniello gave a $30,000 extortionate loan to another victim in New York City with 78% interest on it acting on the orders of a Genovese Family Captain. 
22News wasn’t allowed to take video inside the federal court, but More than 30 family and friends of the defendants packed the courtroom. 
The Government showed several wire taps, including audio and video. Jared Olanoff, the attorney for Richard Valentini, told 22News those videos will help his client’s case to be released on Friday. “He really didn’t speak or say anything of any significance, he was simply there. And as I said on one occasion out of several there’s really no evidence that there was anything more than that.” 
The detention hearing continues Friday morning at 9:00 a.m., and 22News will be here. Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://lintvwwlp.files.wordpress.com/2016/08/us-district-court-springfield-federal-courthouse.jpg?w=1200</main_image>
</document>
