<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.siasat.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>The Siasat Daily</forum_title>
<discussion_title>BJP slams authorities, politicos for trying to demolish portion of Pathankot hero’s house</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.siasat.com/news/bjp-slams-authorities-politicos-trying-demolish-portion-pathankot-heros-house-1000377/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Home / News / BJP slams authorities, politicos for trying to demolish portion of Pathankot hero’s house BJP slams authorities, politicos for trying to demolish portion of Pathankot hero’s house August 12, 2016 News , Politics Leave a comment 
Mumbai (Maharashtra): The Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) on Friday slammed the administrative authorities and political class of Karnataka for trying to raze a portion of the house of martyred NSG commando Niranjan Kumar and dubbed the whole episode as an act of injustice. 
BJP leader Shaina NC told ANI that Kumar died for the nation and that it was time the Chief Minister Siddaramaiah-led government leave behind the hypocrisy and double standards. 
“Niranjan Kumar was not just a martyr but somebody who died for the country and you have the municipal corporation of Bangalore going and trying to demolish his house and saying that the Chief Minister will give an alternate plot and then accommodate him at a later stage. I want to say it’s time we give up this hypocrisy and double standards,” said NC. 
“Clearly there is collusion between the bureaucracy, the administration and the political class in this particular case. And it’s a shame that we have done injustice to a martyr who died for the country,” she added. 
However, Kumar’s family yesterday said that Niranjan was a national hero and sought more time from the government. 
“This is a national hero’s house and he has sacrificed for the nation. He has sacrificed dying for the country during a terror attack. He was one of the top NSGs. He was a leader of bomb squad. He disposed nearly 3000 cases of bombs. He has been trained in FPI. He was a one respectful man and one brave soldier. So we can take him as just another person in the public. He is a martyr and the nation should think about this and support us,” Niranjan’s brother Shashank told ANI. 
The ongoing demolition drive by the Bruhat Bangalore Mahanagara Palike (BBMP) for encroachment on storm water drains in the city also marked Niranjan’s house under its demolition list. 
BBMP has also marked many other buildings for demolition in Vidyaranyapura. 
It had identified and marked properties at Yelahanka, Rajarajeshwari Nagar, Bommanahalli, Mahadevapura and Yeshwantpur. 
The residents of these areas have strongly criticised the BBMP officials for asking them to make alternative arrangements. 
Karnataka’s Home Minister G. Parameshwara on Thursday said if the house built by the family of Pathankot terror attack hero Niranjan Kumar is illegal, it has to be demolished. 
He further said that the family of the late NSG Commando can be provided with alternate accommodation, or the government can help them construct a new house. 
Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah had earlier ordered action against 20 government officials for their involvement in encroachment of storm water drains in the city. (ANI)
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.siasat.com/news/bjp-slams-authorities-politicos-trying-demolish-portion-pathankot-heros-house-1000377/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0542</post_time>
<username>neha</username>
<post>
Home / News / BJP slams authorities, politicos for trying to demolish portion of Pathankot hero’s house BJP slams authorities, politicos for trying to demolish portion of Pathankot hero’s house August 12, 2016 News , Politics Leave a comment 
Mumbai (Maharashtra): The Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) on Friday slammed the administrative authorities and political class of Karnataka for trying to raze a portion of the house of martyred NSG commando Niranjan Kumar and dubbed the whole episode as an act of injustice. 
BJP leader Shaina NC told ANI that Kumar died for the nation and that it was time the Chief Minister Siddaramaiah-led government leave behind the hypocrisy and double standards. 
“Niranjan Kumar was not just a martyr but somebody who died for the country and you have the municipal corporation of Bangalore going and trying to demolish his house and saying that the Chief Minister will give an alternate plot and then accommodate him at a later stage. I want to say it’s time we give up this hypocrisy and double standards,” said NC. 
“Clearly there is collusion between the bureaucracy, the administration and the political class in this particular case. And it’s a shame that we have done injustice to a martyr who died for the country,” she added. 
However, Kumar’s family yesterday said that Niranjan was a national hero and sought more time from the government. 
“This is a national hero’s house and he has sacrificed for the nation. He has sacrificed dying for the country during a terror attack. He was one of the top NSGs. He was a leader of bomb squad. He disposed nearly 3000 cases of bombs. He has been trained in FPI. He was a one respectful man and one brave soldier. So we can take him as just another person in the public. He is a martyr and the nation should think about this and support us,” Niranjan’s brother Shashank told ANI. 
The ongoing demolition drive by the Bruhat Bangalore Mahanagara Palike (BBMP) for encroachment on storm water drains in the city also marked Niranjan’s house under its demolition list. 
BBMP has also marked many other buildings for demolition in Vidyaranyapura. 
It had identified and marked properties at Yelahanka, Rajarajeshwari Nagar, Bommanahalli, Mahadevapura and Yeshwantpur. 
The residents of these areas have strongly criticised the BBMP officials for asking them to make alternative arrangements. 
Karnataka’s Home Minister G. Parameshwara on Thursday said if the house built by the family of Pathankot terror attack hero Niranjan Kumar is illegal, it has to be demolished. 
He further said that the family of the late NSG Commando can be provided with alternate accommodation, or the government can help them construct a new house. 
Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah had earlier ordered action against 20 government officials for their involvement in encroachment of storm water drains in the city. (ANI)
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://i2.wp.com/www.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/shinancaug.jpg?resize=600%2C330</main_image>
</document>
