<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mpacorn.com/news.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Moorpark Acorn</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Autism center to open in T.O.</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Health_%28and%29_Wellness/Autism_center_to_open_in_TO.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Autism center to open in T.O. Grand opening is Sept. 29 By Sylvie Belmond 
IN THIS TOGETHER—Edlyn Peña, shown with her son, Diego, is one of the founders of Cal Lutheran’s new Autism and Communication Center. Courtesy of Brian Stethem/Cal Lutheran Why does she cry? 
How does she feel when she’s alone at night? 
Is she aware of how different she is? 
Communicating with someone who doesn’t speak can be difficult. It isn’t always easy to understand their nonverbal cues. 
Two women at Cal Lutheran University in Thousand Oaks are on a mission to give a voice to people who have nonverbal autism. 
Beth Brennan and Edlyn Peña, founders of the Autism and Communication Center at CLU, are exploring ways to help children and young adults with autism learn to communicate and connect with others. 
Some people assume that a person who is nonverbal is unintelligent, but the two do not go hand in hand, said Brennan, the associate dean of the Graduate School of Education and director of special education programs at CLU. 
Like anyone else, people with autism yearn to express themselves, and many of them are not only smart but exceptionally gifted, she said. 
They may need special tools to help them be understood. Determining which tools will work for each person can be tricky. 
“A person can have significant motor difficulties that make it impossible for them to use their mouth to communicate, but they are learning from their environment all the time and are very intelligent people,” Brennan said. 
Besides using existing tools, such as keyboards, letter boards and icon-driven computer software, the center will research brain-computer interface systems and promote practices that will allow people with autism to take part in school and social activities. 
“It’s exciting to know that we can provide opportunities for people to express themselves in more complex ways,” said Peña, director of doctoral studies and an associate professor of higher education leadership at CLU, whose son Diego, 8, is on the autistic spectrum. 
A brain-computer interface program that the center is studying can identify brain- wave patterns and, in a limited capacity, translate them into speech on an iPad. 
Peña, who lives in Camarillo, said she’s passionate about giving communication tools not only to her son but to all children and students in the community, “so they can meaningfully participate with others and the curriculum and have a better quality of life.” 
When Diego, who doesn’t speak, was younger, he learned to express certain wants and needs, such as what he wanted to eat or what activity he wanted to do, through hand gestures and by touching icons on an iPad. 
Peña said these basic forms of communication aren’t suitable for the long term because they offer limited responses. 
But a letter board, basically an 8-by-10-inch piece of cardboard with the alphabet and a few other symbols printed on it, has allowed her son to express himself more fully by pointing at the board to spell out words. 
“Now that Diego uses a letter board to communicate . . . my understanding of him and relationship with him is much deeper,” Peña said, adding that the letter board has allowed her to learn that her son values friendships and fitting in with his peers. 
“He writes incredible and witty stories about being nonspeaking. Getting to know my son is everything to me,” she said. 
She added that many service providers discouraged her from using such forms of communication. When Diego was 2, therapists told his parents not to speak to him in Spanish or use icons to communicate. 
“Both, we were told, would stunt his speech development,” she said. “There is no evidence that supports this argument. When families and parents ask for support in using . . . alternative forms of communication, professionals and educators should see these requests as an opportunity rather than a limitation.” 
According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the number of children identified with autism spectrum disorders in 2016 was one in 68, and about a third of these children speak minimally or not at all. 
These children are likely to grow up to be nonverbal adults. 
At the new center at CLU, faculty members from several disciplines will conduct research, present workshops and conferences, and provide information and support to individuals with autism, their teachers, families, caregivers and school leaders. 
“It’s trying to help anybody who is unable to communicate or speak but yet has complex thought,” Brennan said. 
Peña invites families with nonverbal children and young adults to join the center’s mailing list for information about events and resources available to them. 
She was recognized last year by the American College Personnel Association for her research on college students with autism. She is involved with local and national autism research and support groups. 
Brennan, a Westlake Village resident, has a master’s degree and a doctorate in special education. 
The idea for the center grew out of the response to the Spectrum of Opportunity: Autism, Inclusion and Communication Conference presented by CLU in March. 
Over 400 people attended the event, which had educators and speakers with autism who have learned to communicate through alternative methods. A second conference is planned for Oct. 8. 
A grand opening for the new center will be at 5:30 p.m. Sept. 29. The free event, which is open to the public, will include a keynote presentation by Steve Silberman, author of “NeuroTribes: The Legacy of Autism and the Future of Neurodiversity.” 
For more information, email or visit callutheran.edu/autism.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mpacorn.com/news/2016-08-12/Health_%28and%29_Wellness/Autism_center_to_open_in_TO.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0220</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
Autism center to open in T.O. Grand opening is Sept. 29 By Sylvie Belmond 
IN THIS TOGETHER—Edlyn Peña, shown with her son, Diego, is one of the founders of Cal Lutheran’s new Autism and Communication Center. Courtesy of Brian Stethem/Cal Lutheran Why does she cry? 
How does she feel when she’s alone at night? 
Is she aware of how different she is? 
Communicating with someone who doesn’t speak can be difficult. It isn’t always easy to understand their nonverbal cues. 
Two women at Cal Lutheran University in Thousand Oaks are on a mission to give a voice to people who have nonverbal autism. 
Beth Brennan and Edlyn Peña, founders of the Autism and Communication Center at CLU, are exploring ways to help children and young adults with autism learn to communicate and connect with others. 
Some people assume that a person who is nonverbal is unintelligent, but the two do not go hand in hand, said Brennan, the associate dean of the Graduate School of Education and director of special education programs at CLU. 
Like anyone else, people with autism yearn to express themselves, and many of them are not only smart but exceptionally gifted, she said. 
They may need special tools to help them be understood. Determining which tools will work for each person can be tricky. 
“A person can have significant motor difficulties that make it impossible for them to use their mouth to communicate, but they are learning from their environment all the time and are very intelligent people,” Brennan said. 
Besides using existing tools, such as keyboards, letter boards and icon-driven computer software, the center will research brain-computer interface systems and promote practices that will allow people with autism to take part in school and social activities. 
“It’s exciting to know that we can provide opportunities for people to express themselves in more complex ways,” said Peña, director of doctoral studies and an associate professor of higher education leadership at CLU, whose son Diego, 8, is on the autistic spectrum. 
A brain-computer interface program that the center is studying can identify brain- wave patterns and, in a limited capacity, translate them into speech on an iPad. 
Peña, who lives in Camarillo, said she’s passionate about giving communication tools not only to her son but to all children and students in the community, “so they can meaningfully participate with others and the curriculum and have a better quality of life.” 
When Diego, who doesn’t speak, was younger, he learned to express certain wants and needs, such as what he wanted to eat or what activity he wanted to do, through hand gestures and by touching icons on an iPad. 
Peña said these basic forms of communication aren’t suitable for the long term because they offer limited responses. 
But a letter board, basically an 8-by-10-inch piece of cardboard with the alphabet and a few other symbols printed on it, has allowed her son to express himself more fully by pointing at the board to spell out words. 
“Now that Diego uses a letter board to communicate . . . my understanding of him and relationship with him is much deeper,” Peña said, adding that the letter board has allowed her to learn that her son values friendships and fitting in with his peers. 
“He writes incredible and witty stories about being nonspeaking. Getting to know my son is everything to me,” she said. 
She added that many service providers discouraged her from using such forms of communication. When Diego was 2, therapists told his parents not to speak to him in Spanish or use icons to communicate. 
“Both, we were told, would stunt his speech development,” she said. “There is no evidence that supports this argument. When families and parents ask for support in using . . . alternative forms of communication, professionals and educators should see these requests as an opportunity rather than a limitation.” 
According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the number of children identified with autism spectrum disorders in 2016 was one in 68, and about a third of these children speak minimally or not at all. 
These children are likely to grow up to be nonverbal adults. 
At the new center at CLU, faculty members from several disciplines will conduct research, present workshops and conferences, and provide information and support to individuals with autism, their teachers, families, caregivers and school leaders. 
“It’s trying to help anybody who is unable to communicate or speak but yet has complex thought,” Brennan said. 
Peña invites families with nonverbal children and young adults to join the center’s mailing list for information about events and resources available to them. 
She was recognized last year by the American College Personnel Association for her research on college students with autism. She is involved with local and national autism research and support groups. 
Brennan, a Westlake Village resident, has a master’s degree and a doctorate in special education. 
The idea for the center grew out of the response to the Spectrum of Opportunity: Autism, Inclusion and Communication Conference presented by CLU in March. 
Over 400 people attended the event, which had educators and speakers with autism who have learned to communicate through alternative methods. A second conference is planned for Oct. 8. 
A grand opening for the new center will be at 5:30 p.m. Sept. 29. The free event, which is open to the public, will include a keynote presentation by Steve Silberman, author of “NeuroTribes: The Legacy of Autism and the Future of Neurodiversity.” 
For more information, email or visit callutheran.edu/autism.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.mpacorn.com/sites/www.mpacorn.com/files/images/2016-08-12/35p1.jpg</main_image>
</document>
