<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Special:NewPages&amp;feed=atom</forum>
<forum_title>Wikipedia - New pages [en]</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Sayfty</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sayfty</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Jump to: navigation , search 
An organisation for women with a mission is to educate, equip and empower girls and women so that they can better protect themselves.Their vision is to make the world a safer place for women. They aim to educate women about the issue of violence against women through our online and offline campaigns. Equip them with safety tools and products so that they are better prepared for unforeseen situations. Empower women and girls through our self-defense workshops so that they are more aware and alert of their surroundings and an do something about their safety. Women should always feel safe and have the confidence to to protect themselves and not rely on others for help. 
WHAT DO WE WANT TO DO? We want to educate girls and women about their rights against any form of violence We want to equip women with safe, reliable and affordable tools like pepper sprays, safety alarms etc. to protect themselves We want to educate and train women on basic self-defense skills so that they can face perpetrators with confidence We want to help women take responsibility of their own safety and not rely on others We want to support open conversations with boys and men to bring about a fundamental shift in how violence against women is perceived Create a community which is safer and eager to help each other 
WHY DO WE WANT TO DO IT? A woman in India is raped every 20 mins! That means that within the next hour 3 women will be raped in India. That’s a serious issue and it needs our attention Women in India feel unsafe and scared. They are making small lifestyle changes because they don’t have options The law and order fails to protect them. The government and our leaders corrupt and people in general don’t care The current system is ineffective and inefficient. There is a fragmented market for personal safety products and women rely on the inefficient judicial system to protect them Women lack awareness and the resources to protect themselves and be responsible for their own safety 
They spread the word about their various programs through social media 
.1 .Sayfty Cha t - #SayftyChat is a weekly, hour-long, Twitter chat every Monday at 11am ET created by 1. Sayfty that will explore topics related to women’s safety and preventing violence against women. Each week, we have an organization/guest who is involved in bringing awareness to women’s issues and we field questions to them (and you). Together, we answer these questions and develop a dialogue about these important issues. 
2. I feel unsafe when... The 16 Days of Activism Against Gender-Based Violence is an international campaign started by the first Women’s Global Leadership Institute coordinated by the Center for Women’s Global Leadership in 1991. The 16 days from November 25 – International Day Against Violence Against Women- to December 10 – International Human Rights Day symbolically link violence against women and human rights and emphasize that such violence is a violation of human rights. 
To contribute to the #16DaysOfActivism Against Gender-Based Violence, Sayfty decided to start a campaign and share what makes us feel unsafe. Here are few submissions from all over the world on what makes people unsafe. If you would like to be a part of this campaign please send a selfie along with a line on “ I feel unsafe when… “. This is an ongoing campaign and there is no submission deadline. #IFeelUnsafe 
3. Zero tolerance - #ZeroTolerance is a collaborative campaign by Sayfty and The Red Elephant Foundation (REF). Rhetoric and conversation on women’s rights have often been seen as paper tigers: being confined to paper, and available within the actionable domain of only a few. Taking these rights and legal freedoms outside the confines of legal curriculums and jargon, this campaign serves to speak to every citizen: man and woman alike, to create awareness that can lead to action. Starting June 1, 2015, and drawing out over a year, REF and Sayfty will put together a series of posters focused on specific forms of Violence against Women, with a complete insight into provisions of law, how one may access the law and what one can do to keep themselves safe. 
To view the posters, right click to open in a new tab, or download and view in full size. of the 
4. Voice of the Week - Their #VoiceofTheWeek picks one person on Twitter every week to express their opinions on Violence Against Women (#VAW) using our platform. It means for a week you will be in charge of curating our twitter account and speaking out to spread awareness on women related topics you are most passionate about. 
Your topics can range from important issues like #VAW, sexual harassment, marital rape to women&apos;s empowerment and inspirational stories. The curation gives you an opportunity to raise awareness, interact with our followers and express your opinion.Over the past year, we have had our curators from not only various cities, but different countries and continents. 
5. With its Meet the People Extraordinaire series, Sayfty takes further, its march to help inspire and bring out the modern, thinking individual in each of us. These are stories of inspirational figures who’ve broken barriers in their personal and professional lives, challenged stereotypes and fought against prejudice in the various forms it is prevalent in our social environment. The people we feature are not just gender-sensitive but also extremely resilient and passionate in their endeavour to support whatever cause they believe in- be it education, health or trafficking. Their tales of finding their voice are not just to instil a sense of awe in others but to show that accomplishments and achievements are possible despite the inevitable struggles life throws at us. We hope to empower all our readers so that they are able to see themselves potentially as these achievers who, by sharing their journey, are hoping to give back to the community by mentoring, educating, sharing knowledge and experience and in turn, building future leaders. Let the quest towards discovering oneself begin. 
The Issue
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sayfty</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time>0546</post_time>
<username>Sammy Sahni</username>
<post>
Jump to: navigation , search 
An organisation for women with a mission is to educate, equip and empower girls and women so that they can better protect themselves.Their vision is to make the world a safer place for women. They aim to educate women about the issue of violence against women through our online and offline campaigns. Equip them with safety tools and products so that they are better prepared for unforeseen situations. Empower women and girls through our self-defense workshops so that they are more aware and alert of their surroundings and an do something about their safety. Women should always feel safe and have the confidence to to protect themselves and not rely on others for help. 
WHAT DO WE WANT TO DO? We want to educate girls and women about their rights against any form of violence We want to equip women with safe, reliable and affordable tools like pepper sprays, safety alarms etc. to protect themselves We want to educate and train women on basic self-defense skills so that they can face perpetrators with confidence We want to help women take responsibility of their own safety and not rely on others We want to support open conversations with boys and men to bring about a fundamental shift in how violence against women is perceived Create a community which is safer and eager to help each other 
WHY DO WE WANT TO DO IT? A woman in India is raped every 20 mins! That means that within the next hour 3 women will be raped in India. That’s a serious issue and it needs our attention Women in India feel unsafe and scared. They are making small lifestyle changes because they don’t have options The law and order fails to protect them. The government and our leaders corrupt and people in general don’t care The current system is ineffective and inefficient. There is a fragmented market for personal safety products and women rely on the inefficient judicial system to protect them Women lack awareness and the resources to protect themselves and be responsible for their own safety 
They spread the word about their various programs through social media 
.1 .Sayfty Cha t - #SayftyChat is a weekly, hour-long, Twitter chat every Monday at 11am ET created by 1. Sayfty that will explore topics related to women’s safety and preventing violence against women. Each week, we have an organization/guest who is involved in bringing awareness to women’s issues and we field questions to them (and you). Together, we answer these questions and develop a dialogue about these important issues. 
2. I feel unsafe when... The 16 Days of Activism Against Gender-Based Violence is an international campaign started by the first Women’s Global Leadership Institute coordinated by the Center for Women’s Global Leadership in 1991. The 16 days from November 25 – International Day Against Violence Against Women- to December 10 – International Human Rights Day symbolically link violence against women and human rights and emphasize that such violence is a violation of human rights. 
To contribute to the #16DaysOfActivism Against Gender-Based Violence, Sayfty decided to start a campaign and share what makes us feel unsafe. Here are few submissions from all over the world on what makes people unsafe. If you would like to be a part of this campaign please send a selfie along with a line on “ I feel unsafe when… “. This is an ongoing campaign and there is no submission deadline. #IFeelUnsafe 
3. Zero tolerance - #ZeroTolerance is a collaborative campaign by Sayfty and The Red Elephant Foundation (REF). Rhetoric and conversation on women’s rights have often been seen as paper tigers: being confined to paper, and available within the actionable domain of only a few. Taking these rights and legal freedoms outside the confines of legal curriculums and jargon, this campaign serves to speak to every citizen: man and woman alike, to create awareness that can lead to action. Starting June 1, 2015, and drawing out over a year, REF and Sayfty will put together a series of posters focused on specific forms of Violence against Women, with a complete insight into provisions of law, how one may access the law and what one can do to keep themselves safe. 
To view the posters, right click to open in a new tab, or download and view in full size. of the 
4. Voice of the Week - Their #VoiceofTheWeek picks one person on Twitter every week to express their opinions on Violence Against Women (#VAW) using our platform. It means for a week you will be in charge of curating our twitter account and speaking out to spread awareness on women related topics you are most passionate about. 
Your topics can range from important issues like #VAW, sexual harassment, marital rape to women&apos;s empowerment and inspirational stories. The curation gives you an opportunity to raise awareness, interact with our followers and express your opinion.Over the past year, we have had our curators from not only various cities, but different countries and continents. 
5. With its Meet the People Extraordinaire series, Sayfty takes further, its march to help inspire and bring out the modern, thinking individual in each of us. These are stories of inspirational figures who’ve broken barriers in their personal and professional lives, challenged stereotypes and fought against prejudice in the various forms it is prevalent in our social environment. The people we feature are not just gender-sensitive but also extremely resilient and passionate in their endeavour to support whatever cause they believe in- be it education, health or trafficking. Their tales of finding their voice are not just to instil a sense of awe in others but to show that accomplishments and achievements are possible despite the inevitable struggles life throws at us. We hope to empower all our readers so that they are able to see themselves potentially as these achievers who, by sharing their journey, are hoping to give back to the community by mentoring, educating, sharing knowledge and experience and in turn, building future leaders. Let the quest towards discovering oneself begin. 
The Issue
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>NL</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
